<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Dianna Johnston "Compulsive Reader"</user>
	<review>

I just finished this book a few moments ago, and I am completely awed by this story.  Harper Lee has done an excellent job bringing this 1930s Alabama childhood to life.  I can see why To Kill a Mockingbird has won the Pulitzer Prize, garnered an Academy Award for the movie version, and ultimately become a timely classic enjoyed by many generations.To Kill a Mockingbird tells the story of two children, sister Scout and brother Jem, and their childhood during three years in the midst of the Great Depression.  Scout and Jem spend most of their summers with their summer-neighbor, Dill, making up plays and spying on the town recluse, Boo Radley.  During the school year (minus Dill, who goes back home to Mississippi), Scout finds herself in trouble one too many times and struggles with the concept of being a lady, especially when all she wants to do is wear overalls and beat up her classmates.Then everything changes one fall....  Scout and Jem's father, Atticus Finch, a lawyer in their town of Maycomb, Alabama, is appointed to the defense of Tom Robinson, a black man accused of raping a white woman (although not of the highest caliber), Mayella Ewell.  The fact of this case rocks the town of Maycomb, and with Scout and Jem feeling the brunt of their classmates ridicule when they realize Atticus is on Tom's side.I was simply floored while reading this novel.  I wasn't expecting a equot;classicequot; to be so readable.  Now I know what I've been missing!  To Kill a Mockingbird is a piece of our American history that depicts racism and prejudice, childhood innocence, and the perseverence of a man who risked it all to stand up for what he believed in.  Wonderful portrayal and one I will read again.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>William Errickson, Jr. "Will Errickson"</user>
	<review>

Oddly, I'd never read To Kill a Mockingbird as a high school student. Nor had I ever seen the famous film with Gregory Peck. Fortunately, I also avoided learning the entire plot through cultural osmosis. Sure, I knew who Boo Radley was-- didn't I? Atticus Finch... yeah, I know who that is... right?Boy, was I wrong. Last week I finally decided it'd been long enough, and I sank into Harper Lee's only novel with high expectations. And I was certainly not disappointed. With its slow, warm and evocative opening chapters, Mockingbird starts off like a sulty summer day in the South. Lee depicts a South of "whistling bob white," biscuits and warm milk, and ladies who on the hottest days bathe twice by noon and then douse themselves in lavender-smelling powder. Jean-Louise Finch, better known as Scout, narrates the story with the keen eye of an adult looking back on a childhood rich with incidents that shaped who she has become. Scout reminded me of some of Carson McCullers's heroines (Member of the Wedding, The Heart is a Lonely Hunter), but without the morbid loneliness and heartbreak. Scout might be described as a tomboy, but that would be doing her a disservice. Her adventures with her older brother Jem, and their dimunitive friend Dill (real name: Charles Baker Harris. "Your name's longer'n you are," Jem points out) evoke the timeless place of childhood.As for Atticus Finch, what can one say about a father who seems to embody the greatest of virtues? He is tolerant, patient, kind, and understanding. He does not meddle with his children's affairs, he speaks to them as fellow adults (he allows them to call him "Atticus"), and his skill as a lawyer is legendary. Lee presents Atticus in a tough and sensitive manner, so that his believability is paramount.The other characters in the book are also depicted with great skill: Aunt Alexandra, bane of Scout's existence; Miss Maudie, who gives as good as she gets when harassed by intolerant neighbors; Calpurnia, the ever-present black maid who has as much a hand in Jem and Scout's well-being as Atticus; and of course the Ewells, whose poverty and ignorance help set the plot in motion.Harper Lee has written a wonderful book that pulses with life, with compassion, and easy good humor. Watching Atticus face down an angry mob set on lynching a black man, or racing with Jem as he escapes gunshots from the Radley house, or sitting with Scout as she forced to join her aunt's church lady reception, or taking that long midnight walk with Jem and Scout, is pure joy; these are scenes that reverberate in the reader's mind and surely in the minds of several generations of readers. I'm glad I can now say I'm one of them.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bensmomma "bensmomma"</user>
	<review>

Somehow my education did not impose on me a reading of Harper Lee's "To Kill a Mockingbird," although I saw the excellent movie based on it several times.  What a pleasure to discover, when finally picking up the book in my middle age, that the people who inhabit this book spring fully grown directly from the mind of Harper Lee herself, rather than just the actors in the film.  Harper Lee has written not a single one-dimensional character, and has created a few of the best realized and strongest characters ever put into print: not just Atticus, Jem, and Scout Finch, but also the dignified Calpurnia, the eager Dill, the peaceful but ghostly Boo Radley, even the degraded and predatory Ewell family.  These characters jump off the page like in no other novel I can recall.  There is no doubt in my mind that these folks are as real as any of the people I see walking down the street, and I feel for Atticus in particular a similar sort of astonished respect as I do for my own father. If somehow the book itself has passed you by, or if (sadly) it was imposed on you for a class assignment when you were young, revisit it.  It's one of the best ever written.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>anna-joelle</user>
	<review>

This classic should be made required reading for every person in every culture and in every country. If only everyone would read it, and truly understand, identify with and 'learn' from the story and the message found  within its pages, I believe the world would be a happier and peaceful place  to live in for all.equot;To Kill a Mockingbirdequot; is a 'rich' and  compelling story set in 1930s Alabama. It's a story about the purity and  innocence of children, about justice (or the lack of it), racism,  hypocrisy, human compassion, trust and love (all issues we can relate to)  told from the experiences and perspectives of a small child (Scout).The  writing is wonderfully beautiful and charming. You'll fall in love with the  depth of inner beauty and innocence found in the 2 children (Jem, and  especially his sister, Scout/Jean Louis). You'll find yourself rooting  passionately for their father (Atticus Finch) to win his case when he  chooses to defend a black man on trial for life, despite much social  pressure on Finch to give up the case and veiled threats against him and  his family. Watch for the part where Finch cross-examines the  equot;victimequot; (a white girl who accuses the black man of rape) and  during his closing speech. Both are excellent courtroom drama (the best  I've come across) and they also reveal a lot of the (ugly) truth behind the  case.Atticus Finch's sense of justice, perseverence and fighting spirit  (the way he stood his ground) are most inspiring and touching. Based on  what he believes in, he knows he must equot;do the right thingequot;, all  the more since he has 2 young children who look up to him for guidance on  the difference between right and wrong.I also loved reading the precious  scenes involving Atticus and his children - Atticus is really a  equot;beautifulequot; person and a perfect role-model of a dad - at once  loving and understanding and patience and fair.And what about the  mysterious recluse, Arthur equot;Booequot; Radley who hasn't left his house  in years and has become some sort of a terrifying yet intriguing  equot;legendequot; among the neighbourhood children? Is he really the  madman or evil spirit that the children believe him to be?This book (and  another winner, equot;Angela's Ashesequot; by Frank McCourt) should rank  highly in everyone's list of must-reads. What a true gem! Read it and be  charmed.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BookMania</user>
	<review>

This book is absolutely brilliant.  I've read the book three times in my life, at ages 13, 18, and 22.  With each reading I gain a better appreciation for the storyline, the author, and the moral beliefs that are challenged within these pages.  There are few books that increase in complexity the more they are read, and this happens to be one of them.  Harper Lee seems to speak to readers of all ages, and no matter how many times this novel is read, the reader will never cease to feel compelled by the message that it delivers.The story is narrated by Scout, the daughter of Atticus Finch, a criminal defense attorney in the Deep South who is assigned to defend a black man in his trial for raping a white girl.  The novel tells the story of how Scout and her family endure the threatening ridicule from their community for Atticus' loyalty to this man.  While Harper Lee delivers the message that black people were discriminated against in the Deep South, the more notable message was the struggle that whites endured when they chose to side with the blacks.  There are some extremely comical moments in this book involving Scout and her brother.  Therre are also several other interesting sub-plots that help describe the morals, beliefs, and problems in the Deep South during that period of time.  Though, my favorite part was Atticus Finch's closing argument during the trial.  His monologue constitutes some of the best pages of literature I've ever read.This was the only novel that Harper Lee ever wrote.  Maybe it is best that she never published again.  There's no way that she could have ever topped this novel.  Not many authors can.  This novel will always remain a permanent member of my book collection, and I'm sure I'll be reading it a few more times in my life and gaining something new ever time.  Everyone should read this book.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Andalucia "neko99"</user>
	<review>

Harper Lee's, To Kill a Mockingbird, is a wonderful and touching book that offers a beautiful theme that you discover early on in the book. The book  is narrated by eight year old Scout and she tells of the adventures that  she faced while trying to figure the identity of Boo Radley. Her brother,  Jem, and her friend, Dill, join in on the fun. Scout's father, Atticus, is  a respected lawyer in the tiny town of Maycomb, Alabama. Atticus is working  on a case involving the rape of a young white woman. The defendant is a  black man. The two storylines tie together in the end and reveals the  universal theme of the entire book. Harper Lee does a meticulous job of  developing characters and plot. The book is so enthralling, I found myself  reading the whole book, cover to cover, in three hours! I recommended the  book to my family and friends and they all thoroughly enjoyed it. Overall,  the book takes readers to the roots of human behavior, and uncovers a  message that all should keep in mind. This book is certainly a literary  masterpiece and all should read it.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>"mfshermantank"</user>
	<review>

In a recent writing assignment, my son noted:My mom chose Harper Lee's To Kill a Mockingbird as our family book club's March book. I flipped through, saw the number of pages, and thought, "Boring!" Later that night, I read the first page and discovered that the main character's brother was about my age and wanted to play football and own an air rifle. Then, a few days later, I continued reading and even though I found the writing a little "fancy," I was finally able to find the beauty of Lee's book - it's a pretty "grown-up" story, but it's seen through the eyes of kids like me. That makes hard subjects easier to understand, which makes the book so much more interesting.The novel is told from a young girl's perspective. Because the theme of racism, the subject of rape, and the idea of injustice are a little "over the top" - even for bright readers -Lee chose a young narrator to tell the story of a black man falsely accused of raping a young white woman and one man's fight to free him. If the story had been told by an adult, readers would have to suffer through the unnecessary chit-chat, opinions, and worries of that perspective. Seeing Maycomb County through Scout's innocent eyes, however, prevents this "masterpiece of American literature" from being an "I-had-to-read-it" sort of book.Scout, her brother Jem, and their father form one of many families of Maycomb County, Alabama. In that southern state during the Great Depression, "[t]here was no hurry for there was nowhere to go, nothing to buy, and no money to buy it with, nothing to see outside the boundaries of Maycomb County." As the novel begins, Scout is six and about to start school, where she will be criticized for coming to class already knowing how to read and write. Her young teacher scolds Scout: "Now you tell your father not to teach you anymore. It's best to begin reading with a fresh mind. You tell him I'll take over from here and try to undo the damage." (p. 17) Jem, a fifth-grader, allows his sister to join him in many of his adventures, including his plans with Dill to make Boo Radley come out. But he thinks Scout "is getting more like a girl every day." (p. 52) The children's father, Atticus Finch, is a state legislator and one of the county's leading lawyers. He is selected to defend Tom Robinson, a Negro accused of rape.Racism still exists today, but the problems don't compare to those described in To Kill a Mocking Bird. The main problem seems to be that Negroes are considered the least human of four kinds of people. As Jem tells Scout, "There's four kinds of folks in the world. There's the ordinary kind like us and the neighbors, there's the kind like the Cunninghams out in the woods, the kind like the Ewells down at the dump, and the Negroes." (p. 226) To make the point about Negroes being somehow less important than other folks, the author tells Tom's story. He is a Negro whose left arm is stripped of muscle from a childhood accident. He stops to help nineteen-year-old Mayella Ewell with several chores because, as Tom admits at his trial, "I felt right sorry for her, she seemed to try more'n the rest of `em" - referring to her family, who gathers their supplies from the nearby dump and whose father is a drunkard who beats them. When Bob Ewell catches his daughter hugging the black man, he accuses Tom of raping Mayella to save their family from disgrace. "And so a quiet, respectable, humble Negro who had the unmitigated temerity to `feel sorry' for a white woman has had to put his word against two white people's." (p. 204) Atticus Finch does his best to make Tom a free man. His efforts, though, only buy more time from the jury, which still returns a guilty verdict. Unlike her brother, Scout believes that "there's just one kind of folks. Folks." But Tom still ends up dead - shot as he tries to escape from punishment for a crime he did not (could not) commit. 	 To Kill a Mockingbird could be a pretty "heavy" book for young readers if it only concentrated on racism, rape, and Atticus Finch's unsuccessful attempt to free an innocent man. So Lee combines the story of Tom Robinson with the mythology surrounding the inscrutable Mr. Arthur Radley, whom Jem, Scout, and their summertime friend Dill call Boo Radley. One story about Boo is that he stabbed his father with scissors while cutting newspapers for his scrapbook. Another story has Boo scratching neighbors' door screens. Yet another says that he eats squirrels. Kids love creepy stories, and the antics of the three friends as they try to make Boo come out of his house give the novel light and humor.Although I had a rough time "getting into" To Kill a Mockingbird, when I finally did I was surprised by how good it was. By the way, the book has such a cool title. I didn't understand it at all when I began the book. Then, in chapter 10, I realized where the title came from. "Mockingbirds don't do one thing but make music for us to enjoy. They don't eat up people's gardens, don't nest in corncribs, they don't do one thing but sing their hearts out for us. That's why it's a sin to kill a mockingbird." (p. 90) But not until Scout says to her father, "Well, it'd be sort of like shootin' a mockingbird, wouldn't it?" (p. 270), did I realize who the book's mockingbirds were. I will read this book with my children someday and hope they will with theirs.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Joanna Daneman</user>
	<review>

Harper Lee only wrote one novel, To Kill A Mockingbird. I think she only wrote one book because it was perfect.This is a story set the South of the Depression era. It's a story about injustice and prejudice and one man's attempt to stand up and do what is right. It is also about growing up and losing childhood innocence, about terror and about mis-judging all kinds of people. The theme of intolerance and fear plays itself out on many stages in this book, from the frightening character Boo Radley who is a strange recluse and a fairy-tale monster to the town's children, the black man Tom Robinson unjustly accused of raping a white woman, to the white-trash Ewells and Mayella Ewell herself, the supposed victim. All the horrors you usually hear about on daytime television are in this book, however their portrayal and the revelations are not shock TV but lessons about human weakness and human nobility.It's a great novel, written in such style that you can smell the dust, feel the humid heat and experience life in a small Southern town in the '30's. Just as an interesting bit of trivia, the character Dill, childhood friend of Scout and Jem, was in real life Truman Capote, a childhood friend of Harper Lee.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Patricia A. Powell</user>
	<review>

equot;It is a sin to kill a mockingbird.equot;  This book is about  justice, and conscience... it is about race, and bigotry... it is about  courage, and cowardice... it is about values of the family, and the culture...  it is about humanity.   The novel speaks through the 8-year-old voice of  Scout Finch, the youngest child of a widower, Atticus Finch.  There are two  stories being told.  One story is about Scout, her older brother Jem and  their summertime friend Dill Harris as they pass three summers together in  a small town in Alabama, when they focused much of their energy on a  reclusive, neighbor, Boo Radley.  The other story is about the trial of Tom  Robinson, a black man accused of raping a white woman in 1930's Alabama.   Atticus is appointed to represent the accused.  The seamless writing brings  both stories together in perfect accord by the conclusion.At first it  would seem unbelievable that "To Kill a Mockingbird" was written by a  Southern author, but upon reflection, it could have only been written by  someone from the South.  Harper Lee had one incredible story to tell and  she told it well.  Don't read this novel for inventiveness.  Read it for  the near perfect writing.  Read it to be moved.  Read "To Kill a  Mockingbird" because it is a sin not to.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Busy Mom</user>
	<review>

With 700 plus reviews, I will keep this one short. I must confess I have read this book either in high school or junior high, but I barely remember it. After reading it again the second time, I have to say, that it is one of those books that every time you read it, it leaves with a greater impact on your soul. I plan to read this book again in 10 or 20 years just to see what new insights I can glean from this book.The story is told from a young girl's eyes, as she witnesses some doings in Maycomb. Scout and her brother Jem are the town's lawyer's children. While growing up, they begin to discover why their father is really a gentleman, especially when he defends a black man accused of rape. That trial is not only felt throughout the town, but it affected Jem and Scout too in coloring their viewpoints of the world around them. This is not your typical coming-of-age book. This is a book meant to provoke people to think and ponder on some of the issues she deals with in this book. It is a book I think every one should read ~~ regardless of their values and beliefs. I know that it is one book I plan to have my children to read as well as the nieces and nephews in my family. It is a book designed to get people to think and act ~~ not to live life passively.It's a book for the classics. One for the ages ahead to read as well as those in the present too.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>