<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Your Sources</user>
	<review>[The author]'s hypnotic history of his Buendias family, founders of Macondo, a remote South American settlement, is a charged chronicle of fantasy and realism...Farce and laughter vien his world...[the author] is a poet nearly, a seer, an alchemist...A tour de force, enchanting, convoluted and barbarous' – The Times Educational Supplement'Reality and fantasy are indistinguishable: a Spanish galleon beached in the jungle, a flying carpet, a cloud of yellow flowers, an iguana in a woman's womb, are more real than guerrilla coups, banana company massacres, and the coming of the steam-engine...As an experience it is enormously, kaleidoscopically, mysteriously alive' – Guardian'You emerge from this marvelous novel as if from a dream, the mind on fire: with a single bound [the author] leaps on to the stage with Gunter Grass and Vladimir Nabokov, his appetites as enormous as his imagination, his fatalism greater than either.  Dazzling' – The New York Times 'One of a glittering constellation of contemporary Latin American novelists...He is the author of a classic on the grandest scale...the  most obvious comparison is with Homer's Odyssey...[The author] is a spellbinder' - Spectator</review>
	<rating>0</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Katelyn</user>
	<review>This book manifested itself in my dreams...it was that fantastic (and fantastical).</review>
	<rating>0</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jacoutofthebox</user>
	<review>This is one of those books that you ABSOLUTELY need to read before you die (hic).</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>davd</user>
	<review>I love this book</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kazul80 </user>
	<review>"IL" racconto!</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Katysimpson</user>
	<review>Struggled - need to try again!</review>
	<rating>0</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Amusaur83</user>
	<review>it's taking me forever to finish reading the book!!! dont know if it's just the translation or that the author is excessively wordy by nature.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>domenico79</user>
	<review>letto in italiano prima o poi dovrò provarlo aleggere in inglese anche se tutti i nomi della dinastia da ricordare un pò mi spaventano ;)</review>
	<rating>0</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>escafeld67</user>
	<review>Just couldn't get into it. Tried for three days but gave up in the end.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>.bing</user>
	<review>I like Marquez and have enjoyed almost everything I've read by him, but 100 Years of Solitude was difficult to get through.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Sthomson06</user>
	<review>When looking over the Amazon.com reviews for this book, I see that many people love it and more people hate it (usually for its descriptions of incest, intergenerational marriages, and even a brief mention of bestiality). I would be terribly wrong, however, to judge this book based on a sensationalized account of the sins contained therein. Yes, the Buendia family is deeply troubled, each member acting out his or her internal terrors in a different way. In Macondo, everything beautiful becomes twisted. This is the real tragedy of this sometimes humorous, sometimes troubling novel. Anyone who comes away hating the Buendias was just treading the surface of meaning and missed the underlying madness that haunted the town of Macondo since its founding.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kkkkk</user>
	<review>The plot is intriguing, but the language makes it quite a heavy read. Gabriel Garcia Marquez is one of the reasons why i am learning spanish!</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fruit</user>
	<review></review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
</result>