<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>06nwingert</user>
	<review>Who can't resist this timeless classic?  To Kill a Mockingbird  is an epic  tale of 11-year-old Scout Finch, whose father, Atticus, is a lawyer charged with defending an African- American. The book takes us back to a time most Americans would like to forget: the time when racism was rampant; the time when African-Americans were brutally treated in various facets of everyday life; and the time when African-Americans were denied the liberty and justice granted to Caucasians. Readers watch Scout and her brother, Jem, grow up and mature and handle the blatant racism in the world around them. To Kill a Mockingbird  is the story of parent-child relationships, handling hard times and standing up for yourself and others. It is the heartbreaking story that should-- and  must -- be passed down from generation to generation, parent to child. And it should bring tears to your eyes. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hampusforev</user>
	<review>An engrossing tale of racism, which to be honest, is a theme I find rather hackneyed and not always that enlightening. I mean it's easy to get blase about it since it's like "Yeah, who doesn't think racism is bad?". But of course you have to view this book in it's context, and given the fact that it's written from a child's point of view makes it modest and honest, not too judgmental. Of course she wrote it in hindsight, but Lee captures the workings of a child's mind brilliantly. I was captured from moment one and it's not a chore to read at any point. Rarely comes a character along that's so boringly sanctimonious like Atticus without being trite, but Atticus was likeable and made me feel pathos about the human condition. I think the book changed some of my outlooks and, like a great book should, will hopefully make me thing twice in a situation that requires great civil courage. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kristenhazard</user>
	<review>I just finished To Kill A Mockingbird last night. Somehow I missed it as required reading in my education. I can see how this would be a great book to have to read while growing up especially as a white person. It's such an amazing example of the gross injustice pressed upon people for the sole and sickening reason of skin color. Many of our Pulitzer Prize winners tackle racism and slavery. I wonder if this 1961 winner was the first winner to do so? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>edgeworth</user>
	<review>It's always nice to read a classic, revered work of literature and find that you agree with the consensus. To Kill A Mockingbird is a fantastic piece of writing, and its message is nearly as important today as it was when written.I knew the book followed a white lawyer representing a black man in a racist Southern town; what I didn't know was that it's narrated by the lawyer's young daughter. Scout Finch is as naive as you'd expect a six or seven year-old girl to be, but she's intelligent. She asks questions that challenge the 1930's status quo, making people re-examine their fundamental beliefs in the way that only a child's honest question can. Her father Atticus Finch - who is clearly, even from the very opening pages, a Great Man - does his best to raise her and her brother Jem in the absence of their mother, to conduct himself well as a father, a person and a lawyer, and to teach her about the world as best he can.The novel could have been quite depressing. It's about a black man accused of rape on circumstantial evidence, an innocent man who suffers greatly because of the prejudices and stupidity of the white community. Yet there's a warmth to the book, a great sense of kindness, a call to be fair and courageous and a good human being. Atticus Finch may have gained fame for his personification of Justice, for his selfless defence of an innocent black man, but I found his most beautiful and touching character trait to be his determination to instill these values in his children.Lee tells her story simply. There's no great visual language or metaphor or particular skill with prose. This creates an appropriate comfortable sense to the book, as though it's being related by the fireplace in that homely Southern house. And behind the seemingly simple words are an ocean's worth of symbolism and thematic depth. This is not just a book about racism; it's about prejudice in general, about how ignorant and bigoted humans can be, and for that it has a timeless resonance. I read A Passage To India last year, about an Indian man unjustly accused of rape in the 1920's, and I didn't review it - partly because I read a lot of books while camping and didn't want to face a stack of reviews upon return, and partly because I wasn't sure how to approach it. It's a great novel, but it rests largely upon its social commentary about the disparity of the British and the Indians, a disparity that history resolved more than sixty years ago.Has America's racial problem been solved since 1960? Many people said, following Obama's election, that the US had moved "beyond race." The outpouring of xenophobia and hatred towards Obama (slotting in neatly with American Islamophobia, despite the fact that he's not Muslim) is evidence that no, it hasn't. Things may be better than in 1960, but the US is a long way from perfect racial harmony.Even if it were, To Kill A Mockingbird would still be an important book, not just for historical reasons but because of prejudice and ignorance in general. I noted that several times throughout the book, Atticus tells Scout that you should never judge somebody until you've walked in their shoes or put yourself in their skin - you may not agree with them, or like what they're doing, but it's vital to try to understand their motives. Even if America was a racial paradise, I'm sure the government would still be peddling the notion that Islamic terrorists attack the US simply because "they hate us."Courage, compassion, respect, honour, dignity, honesty, integrity and love in less than 300 pages. What a great book.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AllieW</user>
	<review>"Shoot all the bluejays you want, if you can hit 'em, but remember it's a sin to kill a mockingbird.", p 94.Set in Maycomb, Maycomb county, Alabama during the depression, the story of this Pullitzer prize-winning classic is told from the point of view of Scout (Jean Louise) Finch, the precocious young daughter of the town lawyer, Atticus Finch. Widowed a few years previously, Atticus has been left to bring up she and her brother, Jem (Jeremy), with the help of his trusted housekeeper, Calpurnia. He is good, wise, adored by his children, and is, in many ways, the message deliverer of this stunning book.Opening just prior to Scout beginning school, the bulk of the novel's action takes place during her first few summer holidays. The character of the town is quickly established with the introduction of Boo Radley, the town scapegoat, and a man viewed with almost universal distrust and suspicion, subject of a great many rumours and much gossip. Naturally, as a result, he features highly in the children's games, to whom he is a source of curious fascination. But Boo is not the only man blamed for wrongs he did not commit - Tom Robinson, a local black man is in the same predicament. Falsely accused of raping Mayella Ewell, he is to stand trial with Atticus as his defence lawyer, and it is this event which provides the focus for the second half of the book. The trail proves to be a pivotal point in the development of the children and their attitudes, and reveals a great many things about the town and its insular inhabitants.Harper Lee delivers her spell-binding narrative at the same lazy, hazy pace as life in the town she depicts, which serves to increase the heat and tension, and is wonderfully appropriate. Within it, she delineates several important interrelated themes : moral courage, the presence good and evil and evil in the world (into which camp do people fall, and how do they deal with it?), innocence (of childhood or otherwise), dealing with difference (and the consequent need for empathy), and the process of growing up. This was a novel truly of its time - Harper Lee completed it in 1957, just two years after the famous bus incident in Birmingham, Alabama. However, the racist and prejudiced attitudes of the towns folk, and their devastating consequences present a challenge to us all. Would we, too, have been tempted to harm the innocent mockingbird?All in all, this is a novel which challenges and inspires, which warms and breaks the heart at one and the same time. School syllabus material it may be, but it is far more than that; it compels you to read by virtue of its own innate beauty. Flawless, this is one for every bookshelf in the land. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kace</user>
	<review>This for me, is everything a story should be.  I didn't love it for the message, which I happen to agree with, but for the characters, and the way that Harper Lee could spin a story.  When I first read the book, I liked to think I was a little like Scout...but that probably wasn't really accurate. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>debnance</user>
	<review>Atticus Finch is my kind of man! What an admirable character! I've read this book several times and I have never been disappointed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>joyleppin</user>
	<review>Harper Lee brings together a story about children who learn moral courage and restraint from a father who demonstrates both. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wisewoman</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird, Harper Lee's amazing Pulitzer-winning novel, is a rare and luminous novel that cannot be made trite no matter how many times it is assigned in high school. This book is quite funny in places, incredibly sad in others, and just plain real everywhere. It's our sad imperfect world seen through the eyes of a child — and thus rendered hopeful.It seems silly to summarize the plot of such a well-known work, but briefly, this is the story of two white children in Alabama circa the 1930s whose father, a respected lawyer, is appointed to defend a black man accused of raping a white woman. The subject matter sounds brutal but it never descends to the merely ugly for several reasons. One is because of the narrative voice: funny, honest, innocent, eight-year-old Scout. Another reason is that the evil is balanced — overshadowed, even — by the good people in the story, especially Atticus. But more on him later.Lee is leisurely in her pace and tells all kinds of anecdotes about Maycomb County and its inhabitants before getting down to what we might call the real story. But as I savored the anecdotes this time, I realized that they are an essential part of Lee's world-building. I felt as though I had been given a slice of 1930s Alabama, tasting as good and as bad as real life.The characters are perfectly written, always believable in their complexity and motivations. There are a lot of "good" characters who are imperfect and display prejudice at times, and some "bad" characters who turn out not to be so bad after all. There is a character who seems completely irredeemable, without a spark of virtue to spice his wickedness. And then there's Atticus.Atticus Finch is one of the greatest heroes I've ever met in literature, the kind of man you want to name sons after. I've heard Atticus called the worst kind of Southern patriarchal white supremacist, because instead of starting a revolution and demanding change, he worked within and appeared to accept the flawed system of his time. This, of course, is rubbish. There is a time and place for militant demands... and there is also a time and place for personal integrity lived out quietly and without fanfare. Atticus does what he does because it is his best chance for saving Tom Robinson. Starting a public campaign to remedy all the ills ever suffered by the black population in Alabama and America and the world would not help Tom. Leading by example is such a cliché, but a character like Atticus Finch restores meaning to it. He is the moral center of this story and yet never loses his humanity.One profound thing about To Kill a Mockingbird is that it has something to say not only about the evils of racism, but also about the honorable way to treat those who subscribe to views we would consider prejudiced. There are plenty of books out there that rail against prejudice, but very few that offer an unflinching ideal for interacting with both its victims and perpetrators. Again and again Atticus affirms that the people of Maycomb are still good people at heart, despite their ugly and illogical racism. He says that their views are worthy of respect even if he doesn't agree with them. Sometimes this seems a little unfair; letting Mrs. Henry Du Bois off the hook for her nastiness just because she is a sick woman doesn't seem right to me. But maybe this is grace in action, and Atticus almost a Christ-figure — forgiving even (and especially) when forgiveness is not deserved.Religion is a thought-provoking theme in the story. Hypocrisy and legalism receive their due by being shown for what they are. And there are some very funny caricatures of religious sentiments (J. Grimes Everett and the missionary society come to mind here). But religion is not universally condemned; Atticus is certainly sincere in his faith and sits alone in church every Sunday so as not to be distracted by his children. It's clear that his faith is intensely personal and heartfelt. Calpurnia's church is a place where the people are earnest in their beliefs and exhorted — strongly — to live out their faith by helping one another, even sacrificially. I love the part when Reverend Sykes orders that the church doors be closed until they have collected enough money to help Helen Robinson! In several places, Atticus and Miss Maudie talk about being Christian as a good thing, a standard that many fall short of. Atticus' final plea to the jury on Tom's behalf invokes the name of God.For this reread, I listened to Sissy Spacek's narration on Recorded Books audiobook. It was superb. Her gentle Southern drawl was just enough and not too much, and she really understood the characters. I could tell that she enjoyed the humorous parts, and was fearless in the heavier moments. I know there are a couple audiobooks out there for this book, but this has to be one of the better ones. Spacek is fantastic and her work perfectly complements the story.To Kill A Mockingbird is a brilliant book, the kind that stays with you forever. Powerful and compelling. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>anoceandrowning</user>
	<review>Harper Lee's story of a good man fighting a broken system was ridiculously good. It was good like a second jam-packed bowl of ice cream after a halfway full "I'll just have a taste" bowl. I finished it in two days, but would've finished it in one if my goddamned body didn't require sleep. Scout was awesome. She's a strong, smart female character. She's the kind of girl I want my daughter to read about. And Atticus...he's the dad we all wish we had. He's intelligent, fair, caring, and the best shot in the whole county. It's relieving to see how great life can be in such an unjust world.This is one of those books that makes me pissed off at myself. Why did I wait so long? Do yourself a favor. Don't. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cailin</user>
	<review>I just finished this book - I try to read it every few years. It is beautifully written and reminds me of both the sweet and innocent side of life as well as the disturbing side I still struggle to understand.” </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fufuakaspeechless</user>
	<review>Absolute must read. I LOVE this story. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>geirsan</user>
	<review>Det er ikke ofte at pensumlitteratur fra videregående skole river tak i meg. Det er heller ikke så ofte at jeg får den gode følelsen av å lese noe som  tåler tidens tann og står bomfast når andre bøker forsvinner ut over horisonten for aldri mer å dukke opp igjen. To Kill a Mockingbird er en oppvekstroman fra Sørstatene, det er en rettsakroman, og det er en bok om borgerrettigheter i rasistiske USA. En liten jente vokser opp i en småby i Alabama sammen med broren sin og faren, en godhjertet og grundig advokat. En stor del av boken bygger opp om livet i småbyen, og forteller om forskjellige videreverdigheter rundt de forskjellige personene i byen. Men den egentlige historien handler om en svart gutt som blir anklaget for voldtekt, og advokaten må tre inn som forsvarer. Det blir raskt klart at gutten er uskyldig, men man må tro på den forurettedes far som er hvit, selv om det er helt åpenbart at "voldtekten" er en konstruert historie. Histoiren er enkelt og troverdig fortalt. Det er varme og sterke personligheter som skildres, men det viktigste som kommer ut av boken er den utvetydige holdningen til faren, advokaten: Du skal ikke mene noe om et menneske før du har lånt hans sko, tatt deg på de og gått i de. En historie om empati og troen på mennesker der slike holdninger har dårlig grobunn. En fortjent klassikerstatus.Filmen samsvarer forøvrig godt med boken. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>judithrs</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird. Harper Lee. 1960. I picked this up a few weeks ago when I was putting books up in the study, read the first page and was hooked again! I don’t know how many times I have read this wonderful book, but like all classics, it is just as good as it was the first time I read it, if not better. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thiagobomfim</user>
	<review>Uma bela história sob a perspectiva de uma menina. Harper Lee toca-nos em pequenos detalhes das situações em que demonstra verdades comum a todos os homens: a maioria deles são bons, dependendo das circunstâncias. A tradução em Português (BR) da editora José Olympio é pobre em notas de tradução, e até mesmo a capa do livro exiba uma fote de uma casa que não se assemelha à nenhuma descrição da história, nem mesmo àquela de Boo Radley. Falta um prefácio que informe ao leitor desavisado a importância dessa obra. Mesmo com esses pequenos percalços da edição brasileira, a própria história não deixa nada a desejar. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mmillet</user>
	<review>The library I work at was hosting the 'Big Read' and chose this book for '08. I had read it in high school but the hubby hadn't so we decided to read it aloud to each other. I understood so much more this time around (partly because I was a pretty naive teenager) and loved every minute of it.Scout's recollections are funny, smart, heartbreaking, and endearing as only as child's can be. It was amazing to step back in time to learn about small town Southern life in the midst of a crisis. The slow yet steady building of events sucks you in until you are so entrenched in Scout's persona that you feel the same emotions. This time I was much more taken with Jem's character -- I appreciated his quest to become every much the honest gentleman that Atticus is. A pure delight! </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MMWiseheart</user>
	<review>I loved this book! I was fourteen when I read it. It's part mystery, part adventure. There are lots of lessons to be learned from it. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MMWiseheart</user>
	<review>I loved this book! I was fourteen when I read it. It's part mystery, part adventure. There are lots of lessons to be learned from it. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MrsSClass</user>
	<review>In this book it tells about a young man accused of a crime just becuase of his race. With the help of two young children he may be able to prove the court wrong! This is an eye opening and heart warming story, i highly recamend it. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dragonfairy</user>
	<review>Every time I pick this novel up, I am amazed at how well written and engaging it is. I can go years without reading it, and not pay any attention to it, and then pick it up and have dozens of truths about how the world works and thinks, and dozens of memories about my own childhood, about the first time I encountered this novel, and my own hopes and dreams that were created when reading about the trial that Atticus took on.This is one of those novels that I encourage everyone to read. Even if reading isn't your thing, or if you prefer non-fiction or whatnot. Harper Lee created a moving and magnificent story that will get to the core of anyone that reads it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>archerje</user>
	<review>Set in the small Southern town of Maycomb, Alabama, during the Depression, To Kill a Mockingbird follows three years in the life of 8-year-old Scout Finch, her brother, Jem, and their father, Atticus--three years punctuated by the arrest and eventual trial of a young black man accused of raping a white woman. Though her story explores big themes, Harper Lee chooses to tell it through the eyes of a child. The result is a tough and tender novel of race, class, justice, and the pain of growing up.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kari1016</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird won the Pulitzer in 1961 and even earned Lee the Presidential Medal of Freedom in 2007 (yes, she is still alive!). The novel takes place in the fictional town of Maycomb, Alabama, during the Great Depression (1935, or so). It's the kind of setting that defines the story and all of the people in it. The story is told from the perspective of 6-year-old Scout Finch as she lives and learns about life and reality for a couple of years. It's a coming-of-age story, just using a much younger age than usual. Scout and her brother Jem (four years her senior) are the two children of a widowed defense lawyer, Atticus. The story begins with the childhood innocence of a new summer as the Finch kids and their friend Dill try to coerce Boo Radley, the town recluse, out of his house. Over the next two years, however, Scout and Jem learn more about the real world than they expected as Atticus defends a black man against a rape charge in a racially charged Southern town.I don't know if anyone else likes to do this but when I'm reading books like this one that have such renown, I like to Wikipedia- and SparkNotes-search them so I get the full picture—the history, the context, the little-known facts. This is one of those classics that has so much behind the story that it'd seem a shame to simply read the book without Google-searching it as well.I love Scout. It is hard to fathom that what you're reading is supposed to be the voice of a six-year-old, but I don't think the language used requires a completely realistic interpretation. Lee uses a child's voice to get her point across which is this: children aren't naive just because they don't know the way of the world yet. They notice behaviors; they notice language; they notice injustice. The unique thing about Scout (and Jem) is that they each have a mind of their own. They notice things, but instead of just accepting actions and behaviors as the "way things are," they question what they see. They ask "why?" and they form their own sets of beliefs. I read another reviewer state, "[Scout] wanted to be a person first and then a girl," which is a mentality I am sure stemmed from the kids' relationship with their father. Atticus is older than most other fathers, more serious, less gloat-worthy (the Finch kids have never been able to brag about his shot or athletic ability). In the two or so years spanned in this novel, Jem and Scout learn more about their father and his rules on life than they probably ever expected. Atticus teaches by example, not by words. He feels a moral obligation to defend Tom Robinson against an unjust charge, even though race relations determined his fate before the trial even began. He teaches Scout and Jem that some things are worth fighting for because they are right, even if they may be a lost cause. He treats his children with respect and earns theirs in return.I know there are dozens of themes and motifs and symbols that one could analyze during and after reading this book, and that's part of the fun upon finishing it. If you finish the last page and put it back on the shelf, you're missing half of it. You wouldn't know how the story is partly autobiographical or that it was never expected to sell. But as you read the story, savor it, and save the analysis for the end. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>trinibaby9</user>
	<review>This is actually a good book.  I would have enjoyed it much more if I hadn't first read it as a compulsory reading and had to tear it apart.  I hate being pigeon holed into someone elses view points.  People should be able to take from a book what they will.  I would say this is definitely worth reading a second time on your own if you were forced to read it before as part of a curriculum. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stamp007</user>
	<review>This is a great book about a lawyer defending a black man accussed of raping a white girl. It deals with issues of racism in the South during the Great Depression. The lawyer's children play roles in the book dealing with racism and unfair practices..</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>EnglishGeek13</user>
	<review>A wonderful look at life in the South and the lessons we should all learn as children. It's one of my favorites. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Blazingice0608</user>
	<review>This novel was absolutly amazing, its no wonder it got the Pulitzer AND best picture the following year. The characters, setting, plot, absolutly everyone was just incredible, cant say enough good things about this book, an absolute must read for anyone out there. It really gets into a lot of deep things to do with growing up, parenting, and just life in general. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rampaginglibrarian</user>
	<review>some books you are forced to read in school and that colours your opinion of them (although there were a few i absolutely loved.) Some of these books i read over again in later life and loved them. This one i didn't love and must not have made a huge impression because i don't remember it so well. Perhaps a second glance? </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rampaginglibrarian</user>
	<review>some books you are forced to read in school and that colours your opinion of them (although there were a few i absolutely loved.) Some of these books i read over again in later life and loved them. This one i didn't love and must not have made a huge impression because i don't remember it so well. Perhaps a second glance? </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ladybug74</user>
	<review>This is one of the few required reading books that I enjoyed when I was in grade school. I listened to an audio version recently and loved this book even more as an adult. I think I was able to understand and appreciate the book more now than I did when I was younger. I was reminded why this book is a classic and would recommend it to anybody, especially if you like historical or Southern fiction. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>vgusg1rl</user>
	<review>Excellent book. I can't remember if I ever read this as part of required reading in high school, however I'm glad I took the time to re-read this book again. I really enjoyed reading this the second time around. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Stodelay</user>
	<review>This is a stellar book.  It's received tons of attention and rightly so.  I think the characters are human, heroic, and rich enough to draw our sympathy without being one-dimensional.  I think this book is a real masterpiece. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Anagarika</user>
	<review>My wife recommended this book, and it was a great read. It's too bad Harper Lee didn't write more novels. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>melydia</user>
	<review>We did this play in high school; I was called at the last minute to be an extra in the courtroom scene. I remember being struck by the quiet power of the dialogue. Now, over a decade later, I've finally read the novel on which it was based and rediscovered that feeling. I've found there are very few books that live up to so much hype - recently a group of librarians declared this to be the best book of the 20th century - but this is one of those rare exceptions. It's thought-provoking and complex while remaining very readable and entertaining. I definitely recommend this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrsdwilliams</user>
	<review>It's been years since I read this beautiful coming of age story and it was time to revisit it.  Scout is one of my favorite characters of all time.  I love how upset she gets when her teacher, horrified that Scout knows how to read at the beginning of first grade, tells her to stop reading with her father at home.  And her relief when Atticus says they will continue to read together, but they won't tell the teacher...Even though I have probably read this book about 20 times now, I discover new things to love about it with each reading.  This time, I especially appreciated the beauty of Scout's relationship with her father.  As my own father has recently resurfaced in my life (an unwelcome event, to say the least), I have been thinking a great deal just lately about the nature of fatherhood.  As Scout gets to know the local crazy man and watches her father defend a black man accused of raping a white woman, she learns about the nature of justice and the dangers of judging others only by what you think you know.This is a classic for a reason (and the movie's pretty good, too). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Featherfire</user>
	<review>I LOVED this book. Enjoyable and engaging from the first page to the last. I would read it over and over. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CFons</user>
	<review>Dans l'amérique de la crise de 29, une petite fille blanche (très courageuse) va être confrontée au racisme. C'est le livre le plus lu aux Etats Unis. C'est vraiment à lire!!! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rainpebble</user>
	<review>There have been so many good, great, and wonderfully written reviews on this book that I don't really see one more making any difference.What I will say is that this is a book that does not leave your heart nor your mind when you have finished reading it.  It is a work more brilliant than brilliant.  The characters become immediately enmeshed in your heart and you care about them so very much.  Even Mrs. Dubose and Aunt Alexandra and Dill had me wrapped around his little finger from his first appearance on the page.  "To Kill a Mockingbird" is a beautiful work of prose and I won't soon forget it.  Now I understand why my 91 year old mother reads it several times a year.  It is, simply put, a book one falls in love with. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lendroth</user>
	<review>No review necessary, is it?</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jimmaclachlan</user>
	<review>I've probably read this half a dozen times since the 70's.  I find a little more to think about each time.  Excellent read about kids growing up  facing prejudice, along with other trials of life, morals  death.  While the movie with Gregory Peck was excellent, I still prefer the book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aethercowboy</user>
	<review>During the Great Depression, we meet our protagonist, Scout Finch. Her father, Atticus, is a lawyer, and it falls upon him to defend Tom Robinson, a black man who's been accused of raping a white woman.Additionally, Scout, her brother Jem, and their newfound friend Dill, deal with the mystery of Boo Radley, the mysterious neighbor wrapped in mystery, rumor, and intrigue.This is a prime example of good Southern Gothic fiction, and is highly recommended for anybody interested in a good read. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>polo9</user>
	<review>I read this in1962,  recommended it to everyone I knew and gave away multiple copies.  It was just right for that time, but I have no plans to see how it reads today.Harper Lee may have proven that everyone has a least one good book in them. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CaRmSy</user>
	<review>Enjoyed this, a great read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jabumafu</user>
	<review>This was the first book I had to read for HS English and I wanted to kiss the teacher for introducing us to such an amazing novel. To this day, Scout, her father and his client all still live in my heart </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>justchris</user>
	<review>I reread To Kill a Mockingbird again this year. I think it's becoming an annual thing because this book is simply brilliant. It may be the only book that Harper Lee ever wrote, but it's a hell of a legacy by itself. I recently heard the author described as essentially the epitome of a Southern Democrat.I think most people are familiar with the gist of the story: Tom Robinson, a black man, is accused of raping a white girl (Mayella Ewell). Atticus Finch is the attorney appointed to defend him in this courtroom drama. But the story isn't just about the trial, which actually takes up very little of the novel. Instead, it's an incredible portrait of small-town southern life and the complex mosaic of relationships and interactions among blacks, whites, rich, poor, educated, and ignorant.Scout, the eight-year-old daughter of Atticus Finch, is the narrator, and her ignorance and innocence and preoccupation with childish things act as a very effective lens shining a light slantwise on the dark side of human nature and the ills of racism, since confronting these things directly is still so very difficult even today.Thank you Emily Dickens for your words:Tell all the Truth but tell it slant---Success in Cirrcuit liesToo bright for our infirm DelightThe Truth's superb surpriseAs Lightening to the Children easedWith explanation kindThe Truth must dazzle graduallyOr every man be blind---And so it is with this story, building gradually from the normalcy of everyday life of playtime and school, to the pretrial rumors and taunts and attempted lynching, to the crisis of the trial itself, and the aftershocks culminating in the climax and resolution that give the book its title. The way is paved with amazing characterizations and dialogue. The writing is wonderfully evocative of the era. The child's voice and perspective are perfectly portrayed. I can't think of any single flaw, though I'm certainly willing to listen if someone else disagrees. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>joyceclark</user>
	<review>This book is worth reading, and re-reading.  I find something new every time I read it.  Beautifully crafted, powerful, thought-provoking. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>readingisgood</user>
	<review>i want to read it so much</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>1dragones</user>
	<review>“...They don't eat up people's gardens, don't nest in corncribs, they don't do one thing but sing their hearts out for us." That's why it's a sin to kill a mockingbird.”This brilliantly told story of two motherless children takes place during the great depression. Some of the events depicted in the story are based on real events of the time; the town and the characters are fictional. The lessons Jean Louise (Scout) Finch and her brother Jem learn are priceless lessons on courage, prejudice, honesty, justice, and injustice and more.To Kill a Mockingbird grabbed my attention immediately. While this novel is entertaining, it is not a "fluffy" read. The story also bears deep analysis of the symbolism used by the author.  For instance, the mocking bird is symbolic of innocence.While the story is told in first person by an adult Scout reminiscing about her childhood, she recounts a child's observations with an adult vocabulary. This perspective adds a depth to the story that would not be present if the vocabulary used was that of a child. Young Scout appears to be wise beyond her years (not quite nine at the end of the story); she is also a recipient of her father Atticus's unique parenting style. He believes that the instances of disobedience, the mistakes and errors in judgement made by his children, contain valuable lessons which can help them to better understand and deal with life if they can grasp these lessons.Recommended to readers who like to read and analyze a story. There is much material for analysis here and many study guides available online and elsewhere for the reader who is so minded. Yet unlike many stories deep enough to withstand the extended analysis, I can also recommend this to readers who just want to be entertained.This review was previously published on Dragonviews </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wvlibrarydude</user>
	<review>Worth another read as an adult.I read and enjoyed the book sometime in high school (not sure when exactly), and always regarded as an excellent book.  Returning to the novel 25 years later, I am struck by the workmanship with my essentials: dialogue, character development, plot, setting and language.  The novel isn't the greatest in any of these areas, but all together it shines like a well cut diamond.  Facets bring new light and depth to the story upon reading.I have heard people regard Atticus as the perfect father figure, but I see a man that is a product of his time.  He stood up for injustice, but he was also involved in some of the injustices around him.  A much more realistic story than the one many another writer would have created.I encourage others to read To Kill a Mockingbird for the first time or as another visit.  I believe it will need another read from me in the future, to see how I respond 5 or 10 years from now. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>laudemgloriae</user>
	<review>Well, okay, who didn't love To Kill a Mockingbird? A beautiful story about truth, friendship, innocence and the dignity of the human person that endures in spite of falsehood and injustice. The characters are so... tangible and the story so captivating that I think it actually made me cry... which doesn't happen often. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fyi715</user>
	<review>excellent read, great characters, interesting storyline </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sturlington</user>
	<review>Upon my second reading of this novel, I can unequivocally state that it is the finest, most perfect novel of the 20th century, and possibly of all of literature. What more needs to be said? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sdibartola</user>
	<review>It seems a little superfluous to review a novel that is the most common book read by high school students in the United States (I read it for the first time when I was in the 9th grade), but since it’s among my top 10 favorite books of all time I can’t resist. “To Kill a Mockingbird” was published in 1960 and won the Pulitzer Prize in 1961. It is Harper Lee’s only published novel, but it has sold more than 30 million copies and been translated into 40 different languages. Starting in 1964, Ms. Lee began declining interviews and has not talked with reporters about the book since. The story is loosely based on Lee’s observations of family and neighbors in her hometown of Monroeville, Alabama in the 1930’s.The book is narrated by 8-year-old Scout, daughter of widowed lawyer Atticus Finch. It recounts Scout’s adventures with her older brother Jem and another boy named Dill who visits his aunt in the town during summers (Dill is based on Truman Capote, a close friend of Lee’s). The kids are simultaneously fascinated by and terrified of a recluse named “Boo” Radley, a grown man who never seems to leave his house for obscure reasons. During the course of the story, Atticus defends a black man named Tom Robinson, accused of raping a white woman (Mayella Ewell). Despite strong evidence of his innocence, Robinson is convicted by the jury. Near the end of the book, the mysterious “Boo” Radley steps in and saves Scout and Jem from a late night murderous attack by Bob Ewell (Mayella’s father), who is outraged that Atticus defended a black man.The book can be seen as a “coming of age” novel with respect to Scout. Some have criticized the narrative voice as being far too sophisticated for an 8-year old child. Although this criticism seems justified, others have viewed the narrative voice more as that of a grown woman reflecting on her childhood. The novel’s main themes are racial injustice, the importance of human dignity and tolerance of differences, and the loss of innocence. Children are not born prejudiced; prejudice is learned from adults. Another criticism of the book is the way African Americans are portrayed. It is instructive however to consider the setting. The book describes events in the deep South during the 1930’s. For realism, language should reflect the times. “The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn” by Mark Twain has been similarly criticized (and unjustly in my opinion).Early on in the book, Atticus emphasizes to Scout the importance of seeing things from the perspective of others: “First of all,” he said, “if you can learn a simple trick, Scout, you’ll get along a lot better with all kinds of folks. You never really understand a person until you consider things from his point of view – ““Sir?”“ – until you climb into his skin and walk around in it.”Concerned that some of townspeople will try and take the law into their own hands, Atticus sits outside of the jail one evening watching over Tom. Jem, Scout, and Dill arrive on the scene just as four cars pull up and several men get out. Scout breaks away from Jem’s grip and runs over to Atticus; she doesn’t understand what is going on. Scout notices Mr. Walter Cunningham, whose son Walter Jr is in her class at school. She strikes up an innocent conversation with him and asks after Walter. Mr. Cunningham responds:“I’ll tell him you said hey, little lady,” he said.Then he straightened up and waved a big paw. “Let’s clear out,” he called. “Let’s get going, boys.”Later, Atticus reflects on the amazing fact that a child was able to effortlessly defuse a potentially dangerous situation:“So it took an eight-year-old child to bring ‘em to their senses, didn’t it?” said Atticus. “That proves something – that a gang of wild animals can be stopped, simply because they’re still human. Hmp, maybe we need a police force of children … you children last night made Walter Cunningham stand in my shoes for a minute. That was enough.”The novel could be a manual for diversity training. Although a minor scene, one of my favorite parts of the book is when Calpurnia (the African American housekeeper for the Finches) brings Jem and Scout to church with her and the reception is decidedly cold:Lula stopped, but she said, “You ain’t got no business bringin’ white chillun here – they got their church, we got our’n. It is our church, ain’t it, Miss Cal?”Calpurnia said, “It’s the same God, ain’t it?”The scene shows that intolerance is blind to color. Not only are the white people of the town prejudiced against the blacks. The black townspeople also are not very tolerant of the whites. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>break</user>
	<review>I don't believe I can add much to analysis or criticism of Harper Lee's To Kill a Mockingbird. After all this 1964  Pulitzer Prize-winning novel is one of the most read and loved book of recent history. I, like many other readers was swept away by the simplicity of small town life, depicted in warm tones, from a young girl's point of view. The perspective didn't change throughout, even as the book sank into darker and darker subject matters. The essence of the story seems to be the trial(s and tribulations) of an African American man who was wrongfully accused of raping a white girl. Despite being clear for everybody that the crime did not happen, that he is an upright citizen, while the supposed victim came from a despicable background he receives the expected guilty verdict in 1935's Alabama. But the real essence of the book is not its plot, but the moral characters of the lawyer defending him. I cannot give justice to the whole book so I won't try.I listened to the book in Sissy Spacek's superb rendering.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jopearson56</user>
	<review>What's not to love about this book? And how many times have I read it? Three? Four? Maybe five? This time, I re-read it because it was one of two books with related themes chosen as titles for the annual Linn Area Reads project (the other was Sandra Dallas's Tallgrass). I wasn't planning to re-read it -- knew I loved it, but I also felt I knew it. Then I attended the page-to-stage presentation by a local theater group who will be performing the play outdoors this summer. The presentation was excellent and it inspiredme to check out the book again so I could re-read it before I went to the play in July. It is, of course, worth re-reading. Such a wonderful and inspiring story, told in such a compelling way. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>datrappert</user>
	<review>Have re-read this at least twice, and now as an adult, it still brings the same deep emotions. I can see of course that Atticus is almost too good to be true - but then the book shifts a little and becomes just as much a story of a daughter's love for her father as a story of a single man fighting against a terrible injustice. The town of Maycomb, Alabama is a fictionalized version of the author's home town of Monroeville, Alabama. The character of Dill is modeled on Truman Capote, a childhood friend of Harper Lee. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fiverivers</user>
	<review>I first read Harper Lee's extraordinary tale when I was 14. It had a profound affect on the way I thought. Recently I returned to the novel and wondered why I hadn't re-read it before. Elegantly written, clear yet complex characterization, a compelling story. There is a reason To Kill a Mockingbird has gone on to become a classic work of literature. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ohdani</user>
	<review>This book is just incredible. Everyone really needs to read this. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jocey79</user>
	<review>not quite finished but will finish today, but I really think in the end I will have enjoyed this book very much.  So far I have enjoyed it.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tandah</user>
	<review>An almost perfect book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TheKnittedSheep</user>
	<review>This is high on the list of favorite books that will be read over and over! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>unlikelyaristotle</user>
	<review>This is a wonderful story set in (I believe fictional) county of Maycomb, a Southern village in America during the 1930s. The narrator is a young girl, Scout Finch, and it centers around her father - Atticus Finch - who is a lawyer and appointed to defend a black man accused of raping a white girl. I like many things about this book. First of all, it speaks in the voice of a child so innocently and perfectly, I can completely imagine a young Scout Finch penning it while bored on a hot Maycomb County night. Second, I love the sense of humor, the accidental children's sense of humor, like when Scout decided she wanted to try 'cussing' and calmly recounted the incident of when she asked for someone to 'pass the damn ham' please. I actually laughed out loud in my dentists waiting room at that for a good minute! I'm still not entirely sure why...Third of all, is the simplicity. Although you could say there's maybe two or three stories going on at one time, something about the simple way a complicated story is told, makes it very poignant. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>courtb</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books of all time.  A classic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cswolff9</user>
	<review>Probably one of the few required reading books I LOVED in school. I've read it a few times since. Amazing lesson in tolerance and acceptance. Scout was quite a little rascal; I adored her character very much. Jem tried to be such a good big brother and look after her. Their relationship with their father Atticus was heartwarming. Watching all that unfolds around this family with the trial of Tom Robinson to the rescue of the kids by Boo Radley is incredibly satisfying reading. Will always be a favorite of mine. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nwhyte</user>
	<review>http://nwhyte.livejournal.com/1280291...Another classic reread for me. It is as good as I remembered; I had forgotten just how much of the book is the set-up for the trial scene, which is actually only a fairly short chapter. It is a brilliant and brutal depiction of childhood in rural Alabama in the 1930s, when your father is the town's most visible liberal, and of the murder of a black man by racism.I am bothered, though, about the complacency of the ending. Actually, Atticus Finch's morality suffers a serious defeat. Boo Radley is spared his day in court, for a crime which he committed but would certainly have been acquitted of; totally the opposite fate to Tom Robinson's. Yet I am left uncomfortably feeling that we are expected to consider this a happy ending. And what of the Ewell family, now fatherless and denied justice as they denied it to the Robinsons? Nobody wins, and I think the last chapter needed a bit more edge to be true to the rest of the book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Leiloune</user>
	<review>Dans une petite ville d’Alabama, au moment de la Grande Dépression, Atticus Finch élève seul ses deux enfants, Jem et Scout. Homme intègre et rigoureux, cet avocat est commis d’office pour défendre un Noir accusé d’avoir violé une Blanche. L'histoire très bien écrite est vue à travers les yeux de la petite Scout.A lire ! le légèreté et la gravité se côtoie dans un roman très touchant sur le racisme, l'enfance et les adultes </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kahlee2000</user>
	<review>http://thebookwormslibrary.com/?p=230... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kadutton</user>
	<review>Wonderful coming of age story as three young children confront racism, prejudice, and social injustice in their small Southern town in the 1960's </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>janiep</user>
	<review>My all time favorite book.  This book is the reason I went to law school!    The characters are rich and the story is moving.  Harper Lee's story of racism, honor and justice is one everyone should read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rpanek</user>
	<review>The children of an attorney’s lives’ change when their white father defends a black man in court.  They become aware of racism in their hometown and the divisions it causes.  The plot is conflict between characters and society.  This book has various themes which can be explored.  In Writing, students can write an essay on their feelings toward racism.  In regards to technology, students can use the internet to locate further information about the book’s themes.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KTtheWife</user>
	<review>I had never read To Kill a Mockingbird before, so when I found it at the thrift store for 25 cents I was very excited. In case you haven't read it, here is a synopsis from Amazon:    "Set in the small Southern town of Maycomb, Alabama, during the Depression, To Kill a Mockingbird follows three years in the life of 8-year-old Scout Finch, her brother, Jem, and their father, Atticus--three years punctuated by the arrest and eventual trial of a young black man accused of raping a white woman."I'm so glad I decided to read this book. It's definitely my favorite "classic" that I've read so far. Also, it's on the 1001 Books to Read Before You Die list. I was very surprised that it was in the perspective of such a young girl. I really had no idea what the book was about before I read it. I liked that Scout eventually realized that all men really are created equally by the end of the book. I think this is definitely a book that all people should read. It's very good. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thorold</user>
	<review>I somehow escaped reading this at school, and, perceiving it as "something we read at school" never bothered much about it since. After all, we all know what it's about...Now I finally have read it, I would say that I'm pleasantly surprised. Scout is an engaging and funny narrator, and the story is a lot more complex than I imagined. It's not just a simple attack on racism, but a more nuanced look at how issues of race and class might have been perceived (by white people) in a small town in the American South in the thirties. The child narrator device allows Lee to question some basic assumptions, but of course it only provides a single point of view and doesn't really allow her to represent the black characters in very much depth. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dbhutch</user>
	<review>When I was a Jr in high school this was given to us to read, I love the story.Atticus Finch is a white lawyer and he is defending a black man who is being charged with the rape of a bi racial woman.  The small town in Alabama they live in an uproar over it, and this is all seen thru the eyes of his daughter Scout. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wikiro</user>
	<review>A Favorite </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>belleek</user>
	<review>One of the few books I've read twice.  No one should be given a high school diploma without having read this book, yet somehow, I managed that.  I didn't read this book until adulthood and after seeing the movie.  It is a true American classic novel.  And one of the best. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SamuelW</user>
	<review>If there is an unwritten list of books that everyone in the developed world should read at least once, then To Kill a Mockingbird is definitely on it. Through the eyes of Scout and Jem, Harper Lee explores the seething racism of Maycomb County, and the story of one man’s inspiring struggle to dispel it. The writing is helped along by a warm, childlike humour that prevents the story from becoming too depressing. The characters are well thought out and constructed, and Lee portrays them colourfully and realistically. I don’t think I have ever admired and respected any fictional character as much as I now admire and respect Atticus Finch.The messages this book carries are thoughtful, relevant and very well conveyed. It is only from the point of view of Scout, whose reasoning skills have not yet been tainted by the town’s prejudices, that we are truly able to explore the injustice of racial intolerance. Lee calmly analyses racism on a number of different levels, each time delivering a valuable message that will stay with readers long after they finish the book.While reading To Kill a Mockingbird, I was fortunate to be able to discuss it with many of my classmates, who were also reading it for English assignments. A number of them lamented that it was one of the most boring books they had ever read. While I don’t agree with their complaints, I can definitely see where they are coming from. At times, the novel is in danger of being too slow. Lee takes far too long to get to the actual storyline, and even then, the plot is a little like butter that has been scraped across too large a piece of literary bread. Fragments of the story are interspersed through the everyday lives of Scout and Jem, and at times we are in danger of having too much everyday life and not enough story. The 309 pages that Lee has given us are wonderful, but her work could have been accomplished in 250 pages or less, and would be a better novel for it.For those patient enough to let Lee take her time, To Kill a Mockingbird is an enduring classic that will touch readers’ hearts with its sincerity and warmth. Without a doubt, this book is worth a read.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kimmclean</user>
	<review>A white attorney defends a black man accused of raping a biracial women in the south during the 1960s.  The community is ourtaged that Attiticus is defending the negro, but he feels that justice needs to be served.  A second story is a coming of age story of Scout and her brother who deal with the fallback of the trial on their lives.  There are many racial slurs, detailed sexual content and foul language.  A banned book. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>clinchamps</user>
	<review>Magnifique roman sur la justice, la différence de l'autre, l'enfance et la paternité. À lire absolument </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BookMarkMe</user>
	<review>An interesting and formative read. I'm glad to have made the literary acquaintance of Scout  Jem </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>melopher</user>
	<review>What an amazing book.  Heartwarming and heartbreaking at the same time.   The writing is exquisite, with a surprising amount of depth.  There are so many layers to this book, which makes it highly re-readable.  Also very easy to read for the amount of insight.  Oh, and a great story too! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Boo_Radley</user>
	<review>Meisterwerk. Masterpiece.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>eliseh</user>
	<review>On the surface, it is a tale of racial prejudice in the search for justice, but in fact the story goes beyond that. It is about all prejudices, about the importance of walking around in someone else's shoes in order to truly understand them. Jem and Scout are delightfully child-like, and the effect of a hindsight narrative only adds to the many layers to be found here. Atticus Finch is the man to beat all men - he is the ideal father, the ideal man. He stands for justice, for righteousness and for "fighting back", even when you know you have lost. He is the ideal against which all men should be measured. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>keithhamblen</user>
	<review>"great book";  humanistic versus Christian (yet great Christian sparkles); insights into humanity, cultural differences, children; many funny and beautiful and loveable characters; profanity </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mamzel</user>
	<review>I just wish there was a sixth star to give this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>NickSerra</user>
	<review>Lawyer Atticus Finch defends the real mockingbird of Harper Lee's classic, Puliter Prize-winning novel--a black man charged with the rape of a white woman. Through the eyes of Atticus's children, Scout and Jem Finch, Harper Lee explores with rich humor and unanswering honesty the irrationality of adult attitudes toward race and class in the Deep South of the 1930</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shmuffin</user>
	<review>I read it in high school and it was such an odd book. I had a hard time getting into it but by the end I was in love with the characters and didn't want it to end. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>anna.karim</user>
	<review>http://anna-bookshelf.blogspot.com/20... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Conner23456</user>
	<review>I liked this book. But, it did take some time to read because it is a slow reading book. But, overall I like how the book played out. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chackett</user>
	<review>If an author has one book in her, let it be this book.  From page 1, Lee draws the reader into this story with engaging characters and a compelling narrative.  This book is a powerful and relevant in 2009 as it was in 1960 when it was first published. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ahooper04</user>
	<review>The incredible story of young Scout and the events that take place in her small Alabama town during the 1930s.  This is a must read.  So much can be learned about life from Scout and Atticus. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DubaiReader</user>
	<review>I'm glad I read this.	To Kill a Mockingbird is not a book I would have picked up were it not being read by my book group. I don't generally favour books about the deep south of America, written over 50 years ago. This, however, was definitely the exception. It was not only a coming-of-age novel narrated by the young Jean Louise (Scout) but it also painted a strong picture of race relations and racism at the time. This was particularly interesting following on from my most recent read - Barak Obama's Dreams From My Father, which was set about 20 years later and showed a gradual progression from Harper Lee's America through Obama's early years to the recent earth shattering election of a black president in US.In the light of current events, this book is an even more poinant read than before and I highly recommend it. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ANovelMenagerie</user>
	<review>The Story LineThis is a book with a couple of different story lines maintained within it.  The story is narrated by Scout Finch, an observant young girl living in Maycomb, Alabama.  She lives with her older brother Jem, and her father Atticus.  Scout’s mother has passed away, so she remains tight on the shirt-tails of Jem learning the way of the world from an intellegent viewpoint beyond her years.In this small town, Atticus is a lawyer who has been appointed by the courts to defend Tom Robinson, a black man accused of raping a poor, white girl Mayella.  It becomes obvious during Tom’s trial that he was physically unable to commit this crime due to an injury to one of his arms.  In addition, during this trial, it becomes clear that Mayella’s father, Bob Ewell, was the actual perpetrator of beating up Mayella after her sexual advances towards Tom.  Despire Atticus’ convincing defense of  Tom, a jury of twelve cannot acquit him simply based on the color of his skin.  Bob seeks revenge towards Atticus for bringing to light the truths about his violence against Mayella, although he denies the truth of it.  Bob’s revenge is eventually enacted upon Scout and Jem one night on their way home from a school pageant.  Scout and Jem are saved from this attack by their neighbor with a mysterious past, Boo Radley.  Boo has lived inside his home since an incident with the law as a young man/teen.  Rumors have surfaced about Boo’s craziness leading Scout and Jem to fear the worst about him looming within his home.  In the earlier points of the story, Scout and Jem’s fascination with Boo have them attempting to draw him out of his seclusion, including leaving items for him in a tree.  Throughout the story, both Atticus and his black cook, Calpurnia, exemplify the true moral compasses to Scout and the reader. The bring light to the importance of equality for all men regardless of race, color, or creed.  They are the voice of reason in this town’s ever-present injustice.  My ReviewThis Pulitzer Prize winning book (1961), has received numerous other awards over the years.  After reading upon Harper Lee’s history, I find this book to be loosely based on her life growing up in rural Alabama.  She is a descendant of Robert E. Lee and the daughter of a lawyer, who attended law school, herself.  In 2007, she was awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom for the truth in the content of this book.  The truth I am speaking of is that no man, nor any woman, should be sentenced to a crime that he/she did not commit solely based on the color of his/her skin.  In addition, no man or group of people should be locked up and judged based on their religious beliefs (as identified by Scout’s observations of Hilter’s actions against the Jews).   For the time that this book was written, I find it brave of Harper Lee to speak such truths in a nation still filled with so much prejudice against the African-American population of our country.  This book has so many other characters and nuiances than as described in the story line above.  There are many sub-stories about the internal prejudices of this town based on the breeding and wealth of its members.  For example, Scout raises the question as to why she can’t play with a little boy just based upon who his family is.  Scout’s viewpoint, as well as Jem’s at times, represents how we should look at others and what true justice should look like.  Atticus is the most patient and loving father that any girl could ever want.  Dill, Scout’s childhood sweetheart, to me represented the innocence of love and joy and the naivety of the human’s mind.  Calpurnia just enveloped me with warmth and integrity.  The characters of this book are all key to the overall message of the story.This book is written with southern dialects and maintains much in it about what the life was like in its time period.  It maintains a high level of symbolism and leads way to study on meanings laid within the text of the book.On Sher’s “Out of Ten Scale”:This is the part of my review that I regret.  This is obviously a national literary treasure to our country.  The content is important and I believe this to be a very good choice for American Literature studies in school.  It is very well written and loved by, I’m sure, most or all.  However, I just didn’t PERSONALLY find a connection to the book as I had hoped.  Let me give an example, in I Know Why the Caged Bird Sings by Maya Angelou, I was deeply connected to the narrator and the story and I loved that book.  However, with Scout and Mockingbird, I didn’t feel that same connection.  I did appreciate, however, the message of the book and couldn’t agree more whole-heartedly.  For example, read this key passage:“… As you grow older, you’ll see white men cheat black men every day of your life, but let me tell you something and don’t you forget it - whenever a white man does that to a black man, no matter who he is, how rich he is, or how fine a family he comes from, that white man is trash.”This book is filled with truths like this one that are relevant and timeless.  For that, I appreciate this literature and respect it greatly.  (Now comes the big “However”).  However, I just didn’t really connect to this book emotionally.  I appreciate it, but I didn’t love it.  Therefore, strictly from my PERSONAL viewpoint, I am awarding this book for the genre Fiction: American History an 8 out of 10.  I must add, however, that this is a classic.  If you haven’t read it and you are interested in reading this content, I would definitely recommend it!  Reading this work only would make you a more diversified, intelligent and well-read person. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Lindarinya</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books of all time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>miss.folio</user>
	<review>Don't miss this one.Read it once and it will stay with you for a lifetime. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cal8769</user>
	<review>Wow, what a moving and thought provoking book. It shows racial issues in a small town in the 30's without being preachy. I can't believe that I waited this long to read this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bkiker</user>
	<review>I finally read this classic from cover to cover. I'm glad I waited to read it. Many people have read this book in high school or know the basic story. To refresh our memory, the story is about a young girl and her brother growing up in Alabama during the Depression. The story is divide into two parts. The first part mainly on the children's antics during the summer, and the second part is focused on the trail of a black man accused of raping a white women. The book's main focus is definitely focused on racism, but on a broader scale in touches on man's tendency to be prejudicious or unequal to many ethic and cultural groups.  I can see why it is considered a classic of southern literature, and how his stood up to the test of time. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>WWWDaryl</user>
	<review>Too bad Harper Lee did not write more. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluedream</user>
	<review>I think this is the best book I ever had to read for school, yes. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>katie33</user>
	<review>The best of the best! </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kasualkafe</user>
	<review>I don`t think I read this book in school and felt it was nigh time to consume this classic.  I enjoyed the story and with a little help from sparknotes.com was able to answer some of the questions , allusions and references the book makes that slowed down my reading process - (sparknotes - great tool)   The other reviews here summarize and analyze this book more eloquently than I can do at this time so I will not waste any more of a potential readers time. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>quoddy</user>
	<review>It is truly a beautiful book; it shows compassion towards the black man of the days when whites were supreme. It is sweet, it is revealing, and it doesn't force you into a chair and make you agree with it. It shows the corrupt court they had, and in it's own childish point-of-view, the follies and nonsense of being racist against blacks. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>timjones</user>
	<review>I first read this book at high school, and saw the film starring Gregory Peck not long after that. I had forgotten almost everything about the book except its setting and the fact that it was one of the few set books at high school that I thoroughly enjoyed.I enjoyed it just as much when reading it recently. Some things surprised me: I remembered the story as being almost entirely taken up with the accusation and then trial of Tom Robinson, whereas that whole strand of the narrative is not introduced until well into the book, and then only gradually. I also wondered whether Atticus Finch was, perhaps, just a little too perfect. But the novel is warm, engaging, and well told, and it was a pleasure to re-read it as an adult. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ChristopherTurner</user>
	<review>I loved the narrative voice, I loved how the seemingly innocent can be insightful about a hateful crime - perhaps children have not learned to hate the way adults aften have, so they are moer open to the greater truths. See my comments on A Time To Kill and The Demon Haunted World. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gardener2510</user>
	<review>a classic </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cwicker27</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird is a novel that takes place in one of the hardest times in American history, and it is told from the perspective of a young white girl named Scout. As scout grows up in the town of Maycomb, Alabama, she tells stories that teach her about the reality and the harshness of life. When her father, Atticus Finch, takes on a case to defend a black man being accused of rape, Scout and her family feel the weight of what her father has chosen to do, which they believe is the right thing to do. Also, Scout, her brother Jem and their friend Dill become interested in the mystery of the man named Boo Radley who lives in their town. As they further investigate the life of this man, Tom Robinson’s case expands to be one of the most memorable and tragic memories in Scout’s life. 	The theme of hero occurs throughout the book and appears in many characters. The different characters represent different heroes mainly to Scout because of the perspective from which the book is told. To scout, Boo Radley and her father Atticus Finch are the heroes of the book. Atticus represents the consistence presence of good in her own life, which is demonstrated not only when he chooses to defend Tom Robinson, but also in other events such as the shooting of the rabid dog. Boo Radley represents the potential for good in the world outside of her own family. Through most of the book he is a mystery to her, but as the story progresses he becomes more of a positive figure in her life, goodness represented by a total stranger. 	Having read To Kill a Mockingbird once already in eighth grade, I knew what to expect with the story. I feel like now that I am older and better at reading and generally recognizing the author’s techniques, I was able to appreciate so much more of the novel. Also, reading a novel for the second time always unfurls new ideas that you didn’t notice before. I think that this book is an amazing book that teaches an amazing lesson through the story of a young girl encountering the clashing of good and evil in her life. It is definitely worth the read both the first and the second time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>egoose1</user>
	<review>I read this book when I was in eighth grade in my English class. I so recommend, to those of you in the same position, re-reading this novel.Told from Scout's point of view, a girl looking back on her experience as a young girl, gives the reader a feeling of knowing-innocence throughout the novel. The story illustrates Scout's coming-of-age over the course of about a year -- it shows the reader her realization that good and evil must co-exist. This is a huge realization that all children come to in a different way. Atticus Finch, Scout's father, exhibits great wisdom, strength, and intelligence throughout the novel that pushes his children (Scout and brother Jem) to realize the importance of living with sympathy and understanding -- to realize "you never really understand a person until you consider things from his point of view...until you climb into his skin and walk around in it." Set during the Great Depression when racism was roaring, it is difficult for Scout and Jem to understand what all the fuss is about, especially because their father has brought them up like so with a housekeeper, Calpurnia, who had shown the children nothing but love and wisdom all their lives. One of the most famous lines from the novel, "It's a sin to kill a mockingbird,” displays the heart of this novel's meaning. One must not judge, criticize, or treat poorly someone that has done nothing wrong -- and even though human nature's evil side will inevitably shine through at certain times, it is necessary to live whole-heartedly and with an understanding that in the end, most people will probably turn out to be "real nice." To Kill a Mockingbird ties in with our theme because of the character of Atticus who is truthfully the hero of the novel. He did not believe in prejudice or racism and stood up for that. He taught his children the ultimate morals of life and watched them as they grow. He did not put all the answers to life beofre them, but rather insured that they would come to them on their own. His wisdom drove the story forward. The coming-of-age storyline kept the book on track, as Scout is reflecting on the way she matured in her childhood surrounded by racism and unfairness - her father's innocent client, Tom Robinson, being shot to death merely because of the color of his skin, and her great realization that while someone may seem "creepy," there is likely a reason for it -- like their mysterious neighbor Boo Radley who was ever present and exhibited a sense of quiet kindness and compassion. These quiet acts played a large role in Scout and Jem's maturation and realization of the ultimate goodness that is present even during times where evilness seems to prevail. I rated this novel 5 stars because Harper Lee not only wrote an incredibly well-written and fascinating novel, but she wrote with a deeper meaning that we still must focus on 60 years later -- the simplicity of acting with kindness, not judging, and realizing that good and evil must coexist but focusing more on the good in all things and people will bring a more fulfilling life. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>drlake66</user>
	<review>This book is a classic for a reason.  It is a simply story told from a child's point of view but it addresses issues that we are still dealing with every day.  Following Scout and Jem as they mature and learn more about their father and their neighbors is both sad and touching.  It allows us all to remember that moment when we realized that adults lie and are hypocrites, that things are not always as simple as black and white and that life is rarely fair.It was a wonderfully amazing book and I'm so glad I finally read it.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tundranocaps</user>
	<review>Read it during my private English class. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RicDay</user>
	<review>A must-read for anyone wanting to understand the social environment and racial tensions of the southern US in the 1950s </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MahoganyRain</user>
	<review>There probably are very few American's that have not a least heard about Harper Lee's "To Kill A Mockingbird".  I don't recall when I first heard about this book but I remember hearing about it some point in my life.  It wasn't required reading for me in high school and since I was not one to voluntarily read classics in high school this book got overlooked. I feel robbed.  My high school English teachers felt that it was more important to assign such boring books as "Ethan Frome" but left "To Kill A Mockingbird" out, shame on them.  I am not going to classify this book as a page turner, but it was almost there.  The last 100 or so pages I couldn't stop reading.The story is told in first person and the narrator is a young child by the name of Scout.   Now, there are so many directions that Lee could have taken with her creation of Scout.  But she decided that she would be highly advanced for a child (in the book she is between the ages of 6 and 8), and this is good.  Because the reader get not only to see how Scout develops but also gets a look into her thought process and how she tackles some of the complicated adult issues she has to face.  Sometimes I forgot that this story was being told through the eyes of a child.The language in the story was both simple and complex.  Every now and than Lee would through in a SAT word (at least that was what I called them in high school) but they were perfectly in context with the story and did not distract from the flow.  In fact they helped illustrated and remind the reader that Scout is a child.Now to the storyline.  Even though this book was published in the 1960's and takes place in the 1930's the subject matter is still relevant to today.  The struggle for equality in legal system, prejudice, and class.  All these issues come up in the book and Lee handles them well, maybe because she does it from the unbias eyes of a child.This book as been criticized for the use of the "N" word but I think that it is apporiate because first it is a historical fiction novel and second that was reality back in the time frame of the story.  The only time that my eyebrow raised was when I reached the following passage on page 118:    "The warm bittersweet smell of clean Negro welcomed us as we entered the churchyard..."I have no idea what that means.  Bittersweet smell and clean.... I am lost.  But otherwise a solid well written book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mostlyliterary</user>
	<review>Of course this is one of the best books ever written -- a story that stays with you for life. I saw the film as a child, before reading the book, and I found it haunting and tremendously moving. I can still visualize so many of the scenes, though I haven't watched it in years. The book was a wonderful reinforcement, though the film left indelible images in my imagination, so I continued to picture the movie stars in all of the roles. A few years ago my family listened to the audio version with Sissy Spacek, while on a road trip to the Grand Canyon. It was really well done, and we enjoyed it very much. My daughter just read this book for 8th grade, and I enjoyed talking with her about it. I'd like to re-read it again someday soon. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>reader1534</user>
	<review>This book is one of the classics of literature. Harper Lee is a master of creating a view on both society in the 1930s and its racial discrimination that clearly exists and creating characters that are strong- willed and are honest people. Atticus is the only lawyer who will defend Mr. Robinson. Atticus believes that Robinson is innocent and he is going to fight his hardest to free him. Lee also establishes Atticus' children Jem and Scout as ambitious and supportive. They are very curious and seem to find themselves in places they probably should not be. To kill a Mockingbird is a novel that should not be missed.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sarah408</user>
	<review>http://sarahbbc.wordpress.com/2009/01... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dgadkins88</user>
	<review>This story takes place in Alabama during depression times. Two children view the entire world and their outlook on it. This books allows parents to see how their children see things and what has impacts on their lives. I would highly recommend high school students to read this. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>potterfan2121</user>
	<review>good, want to own it </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ZanKnits</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird is absolutely one of my favorite pieces of fiction ever. It is an incredible book, and I re-read it as often as possible. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MartinRohrbach</user>
	<review>Classic literature. Black vs. White. Rich vs. Poor. Must read but once is enough. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sherton</user>
	<review>One of my all time favorite novels which I first read in high school.  Who could ever forget Atticus, Scout, Jem and Boo Radley? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sswartz</user>
	<review>-336/ 336 pages-This book was mainly about Scout Finch living in a boring town called Maycomb, trying to find something fun to do with her brother Jem. They soon start playing games and eventually find items in a tree trunk made for them, knowing it was from the crazy man Arthur "Boo" Radley. They try to amuse themselves by trying Boo to come out, but little did they know, they were the ones amusing Boo. Boo saves them in mystical ways and by the end of the story, he goes out of his house saves Jem and Scout from being killed. -Scout Finch changes throughout the story in many ways. One way was that sat first, she acted like a boy and beat up the kids at school, but soon  she started acting more mature and lady like. She also realized that the world isn't as nice as she thought it was. She found out that there are people out in her town judging and mistreating others, like the trial of Tom Robinson being accused of rape, when he clearly wasn't. Scout was a very intelligent girl, she knew how to read when she first started going to school and she had common sense, knowing what was right, and doing what she has to do.-I could relate to Boo Radley in a way because sometimes, because I know if I get judged about something and so many people dislike me and think I'm crazy, I wouldn't want to deal with it and I would exclude myself from them and do my own thing.-I didn't like the random things they say about their families and background. It was sort of random and didn't really have anything to do with the book and it was boring.-I would recommend this book to anyone in junior high or higher because it is a really good book and tells a lot about the Great Depression time and experiences of racism and excitement. -I would play Dakota Fanning as Scout in this movie because she shows a lot of affection in her roles and she can show how a girl would really act. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>annekiwi</user>
	<review>I first read this book for my freshman year of high school summer reading.  Or should I say I didn't read it?  I didn't read it over summer and I didn't read it the night before the test.  I read it the whole day I was at school supposed to be paying attention to other subjects.  And I regretted it.  It was such a great book, I was so moved and deeply immersed in the drama.  I reread it, naturally and got so much more out of it the second time.  I remembered it fondly over the years.  And when I joined Zooba it was one of the first books that I bought.  And I couldn't wait to reread it.  But I think my memories of it were tinged with how much I enjoyed my first year of high school.  The joy I got from leaving behind the awfulness of elementary school and becoming a new person, making new friends that didn't know my whole family.  Meeting people I hadn't known my whole life, people who had vastly different upbringing than I did.  It was still a good book, just not THE GREATEST BOOK I HAVE EVER READ which is the way I remembered it.  Please don't get me wrong, the book was a delight to read again.  It just wasn't as deeply moving as when I was 14, but I still enjoyed it.I think my favorite part of the book revolved around Jem destroying the camillas and having to read to the little old morphine addict.  That process of helping her wean her addiction and how the children both came to learn so much from the situation [even though they were unaware of it].  Or maybe it was Scout learning to be a lady with the help of her aunt and maid/nanny.  There were many good episodes and highly recommend it to anyone who hasn't read it.  Is there still anybody who hasn't read it? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>flocu</user>
	<review>"Atticus Finch is the same in his house as he is on the public streets.""Before I can live with other folks I've got to live with myself." (Atticus Finch)Imho these 2 statements sum up the most important thing there is in life. Be true to others and be true to yourself.Atticus Finch is such a strong role model, I'm even rethinking my wish to not father any children. Unfortunately Atticus is fiction and I'm not. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tomwrites</user>
	<review>Best writing about children in an American novel. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Othemts</user>
	<review>What more can one say about this book?  It is the perfect novel, rightly beloved by countless readers.  It works as a vision of the world through a child's eyes, as a treatise against racism, and as a courtroom drama.  Mostly, it's just a great book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ptzop</user>
	<review>I'm so glad I re-read this as an adult.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alivanmom</user>
	<review>This modern classic, set in the segregated South of the 1930s, is the story of two young children who learn about life and the great character of their father, Atticus Finch, as he struggles with a difficult case in which he must defend a black man wrongfully accused of raping a white woman.The story is told through the eyes of the younger child, a nine year old girl. This charming perspective, related in an authentic Southern dialect, makes for a surprisingly innocent way of tackling some rather tough topics. Catholic parents of today, who are forced to explain difficult topics such as abortion to their young children, will likely sympathize with this father and be impressed with how well he handles the situation.Atticus, an aging lawyer and widowed father of two, is a man who spends his free time reading. His children find him somewhat boring and wish he could be more like their classmates' fathers who are young and athletic. As the story develops, the children begin to learn why their father is respected by those neighbors and friends whose opinions really count.The story culminates in a court battle in which Atticus is assigned to defend an innocent black man in a hopelessly biased rape case. He is reluctant to take the case because he knows he has no chance of winning and is concerned about the emotional persecution his children will suffer in a community where racial tensions run high. Nevertheless, he knows he must do the right thing and proceeds with the case. The case itself and the man involved turn out tragically and the family goes through many difficult and even frightening things, but the book proves to be a great classic because of the great character development, the moral considerations the story addresses and the growth of the children as they suffer through the case with their father. It should provide a wealth of literary, historical and moral themes for teens or adults.I'd like to address two issues that may concern parents regarding the content of this book. First, some parents have asked me whether, in a day where sexual sin runs rampant, such books as this should simply be avoided. I would answer that I certainly think books which glorify fornication or cause the imagination to dwell on sensuality during the sensitive teen years should be avoided. In contrast however, this book, particularly with appropriate guidance, should help teens to develop the moral context without which human sexuality so often lowers itself to mere pleasure and animal instinct. I believe this book does so without danger to the imagination. The rape was fabricated, the discussions concerning it are not at all graphic, and an implication that the young woman was actually a victim of incest is so subtle that it may very well be missed. The Christian answer to teaching children to avoid sin is not to ignore sensitive topics entirely, but to prayerfully and prudently teach children right from wrong and the consequences of sin in a manner suitable to their maturity.Second, some may be concerned that the book makes some criticisms of Christians. It should be understood that the book does not villify Christians (most of the characters on both sides of the issue seem to consider themselves Christians), but highlights the hypocrisy of those who commit evil while calling themselves Christian. Clearly, the position taken by Atticus is solidly Christian. Also, understanding the hypocrisy presented in the book should be very helpful in developing a solid Christian conscience in preparation for a difficult and complex world.While the book could be studied as early as eighth grade, it would probably be understood more deeply a few years later, in mid-to-upper high school. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DFLA_CierraG</user>
	<review>To kill a mockingbird is not that good, because they use to many big words that i didn't understand. The book is also very confusing and hard to get. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bzedan</user>
	<review>This has got to be the least intimidating classic out there. I mean, yes, totally full of thinking and smarts and importance to the culture, but it doesn't hit you over the head with it. We've just got a couple of kids, existing in a little town and just living, with all the crazy brave truthfulness that kids have.I mean, dang, anything you say (and don't it dare be the word "poingant") has been said and whatever. Nothing I can add.Oh! Except this, a drawing by the wonderful Calamity Jon Morris of Scout in her ham costume that I totally pictured during the relevant scene. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>janegend</user>
	<review>I read this every few years </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Lindsaybooklist</user>
	<review>I thought the book was very good.  It  was very interesting in the trial. I thought that was the best part.                    Austin Bloom</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>staceyvinson</user>
	<review>One of the finest novels ever written;perhaps the finest to come from an American author. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jordicouturexo3</user>
	<review>To Kill A Mockingbird was a required reading for my ninth grade year. It is told by the young (8 year old), yet very intelligent, Scout Finch. Scout's father is Atticus Finch, a lawyer in Maycomb County, Alabama. They are living in the year 1935, when there were still issues over the equality of black Americans and white Americans. Atticus Finch takes on a case about a black man, who supposedly rapes a white lowlife woman. Scout tries to understand why people treat the black man worse than they treat white people. She shows her maturity, even at the age of 8, by understanding there is no difference, while people the elders in her town cannot begin to fathom such a thing. Scout's older brother Jem, is her partner in crime, Jem tries to be Scout's teacher but she doesn't want to listen. Together, with the help of a friend, Dill, they try to solve the mystery of their "ghost" neighbor Boo Radley, and make sense of the mayhem involving their father's case. To Kill A Mockingbird is my by far my favorite book that I have ever read in school, I loved it so much that I read it again, after I read it in school. I recommend this book to readers of all ages and genders. It is the transformation of Scout and Jem Finch, losing their innocence, becoming young adults, and understanding their society and themselves. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>molly4407</user>
	<review>I don't know how I never read this growing up, but now that I have I am glad I made the time for it. A truly unforgettable tale told by the young Scout Finch that will have you turning the pages until the very end without ever wanting to put it down.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nunes84</user>
	<review>One of the best on so many levels.  I can't believe I waited so long to read it.  If I had read this 22 years ago, my daughter would be nickname Scout.  She has read it and, even at 21, says she would welcome the nickname. In addition to the overall quality of writing, sense of place and time, and social responsibility of this work, Scout is one of the strongest young girl characters in fiction. She has now relegated Allegra Maude Goldman to second place. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>foof2you</user>
	<review>Unlike other books that teachers make kids read,  A Cathcher in the Rye is one, this is a really great story that comes to life as you read.  The charcters are rich, the storytelling marvelous a real joy to read.  Strongly recommend! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rose-Marie</user>
	<review>Søskenparet Småen (Jean Louise) og Jem vokser opp i en liten sørstatsby i USA i 30-årene. Moren døde da de var små, og faren Atticus, som er sakfører, gjør det han kan for å gi barna en så god oppvekst som mulig. Den dagen Atticus blir pålagt å forsvare en sort mann som er anklaget for voldtekt, starter problemene. Mens Atticus selv takler dette med stoisk ro, får barna høre mye stygt både fra voksne og barn. Under rettssaken står troverdigheten til en hardt arbeidende sort mann mot troverdigheten til en familie hvis far drikker og aldri har gjort et ærlig arbeidsslag i hele sitt liv. Har den sorte mannen i det hele tatt en sjanse? Dessverre er dette en problemstilling som er høyst aktuell mange steder i verden den dag i dag. Boka er nydelig skrevet! Atticus er en raus og varm far, og Småen - jeg-personen i boka - en herlig liten rebell av ei gutte-jente på knapt ni år. Jeg beklager sterkt at den ikke var tykkere!Boka er filmatisert:http://no.librarything.com/work/detai... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>geyejoel</user>
	<review>So much better than I remembered it. Fantastic book not only in Lee's mastery of language and metaphor, but also in her not-so-subtle critique of reason, prejudice, and morals. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wildcard_sej</user>
	<review>Young Scout Finch tells of growing up in Maycomb Alabama during the 1930s, with her older brother Jem and their friend Dill. Initially, their interest is mostly consumed with trying to entice their mysterious reclusive neighbour, "Boo" Radley, out of his house, but soon their lawyer father, Atticus, must defend a young Negro charged with raping a white girl, and their eyes are opened to the realities of racial prejudice and injustice.To Kill a Mockingbrd appears on most banned books lists, but is often also considered by librarians to be a book "every adult should read before they die".  The book is full of racial epithets and racial prejudice which may make for uncomfortable reading, but the language and attitudes were typical for the time period and may therefore be both instructive and illuminating.  I can't remember how old I was when I first read this book except that I was probably too young to realise its significance at the time, and it wasn't on any of my study-lists.  Definitely worth re-reading and thinking about properly. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KatharineDB</user>
	<review>Favorite book of all time </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Hamburgerclan</user>
	<review>Hmmm. I'm a bit intimidated in trying to write a review of this one. It's a classic after all. A wonderfully textured and layered tale of prejudice in 1930s Alabama. How can I hope to do justice with a little review? I mean, without actually making a serious effort? Perhaps I can't. Ah, well. Suffice it to say that this is the account of a rape trial as seen through the eyes of 8-year-old "Scout" Finch, the daughter of Atticus Finch, the defense attorney. A black man has been accused of raping a young white woman and the resulting trial pushes all sorts of feelings and beliefs into the daylight. Actually, when I say that this is an account of the trial, it's like saying a tree is its trunk. The trial is the main plotline around which all the other plotlines and characters and setting intertwine. It's a fascinating read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>litelady-ajh</user>
	<review>This is one of my favorite books.  I loved Scout and her relationships with the other characters; especially with her father.  Whenever someone comes into our library wanting a great book to read, I always suggest this one first. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Vampirate_queen</user>
	<review>This is an amazing book! I had to read it for school, and I can 100% guarantee that I would have loved it even more if I hadn't had to do work on it.I also saw it as a play, and that was great too, though nothing amounted to how well-written the book was.I totally recommend this book to everyone. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rebeccareid</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird by Harper Lee almost perfectly captures the main challenge of growing up: realizing human nature, both good and bad.The novel follows Scout Finch from age 6 to age 9 in the midst of the Great Depression in rural Alabama.  Scout is a tomboy in overalls but is expected to be a little lady. She sees many opposites in the people around her: not as poor versus very poor, boy versus girl, old town residents versus newcomers, drunk versus sober, kind versus mean, and, underscoring it all, black versus white.And yet, in her eight-year-old wisdom, Scout observes, "Naw, Jem, I think there’s just one kind of folks. Folks." (chapter 23)But then Scout learns by experience that people often treat each other poorly.  To Kill a Mockingbird is honest yet beautiful examination of how we all look at each other. Why do people judge and hurt those who “don’t do one thing” to harm the world around us? Why do people bring heartache on the helpless? Why are people prejudiced?Through Scout’s young eyes, I was reminded of how important it is for me to avoid judging others “until you climb into his skin and walk around in it.” She also helped me see what it means to be a neighbor.I reread this 15 years after my first read. I need to read it more often.More on my blog </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thebluestockings</user>
	<review>I love this book. I’m not alone in this adoration though. In fact, I think this book has pretty much been deemed the best book of the twentieth century.Scout, the narrator, and her older brother Jem are the children of Atticus Finch. Their mother died years ago, so they’ve been raised by Atticus and by Calpurnia, the black maid. Scout and Jem are generally carefree children living in Maycomb, Alabama during the Depression. They spend their summers adventuring with their friend Dill and trying to get Boo Radley, the neighborhood recluse, to come out of his house. Things change, though, when Atticus, an attorney, agrees to defend a black man charged with raping a white woman.There is nary a misstep in this book. The characters are unbelievably well written and fleshed out. Lee slowly creates this town full of people with, what at first seem to be, random tidbits. It all builds and comes together in several climatic scenes. As an attorney , I particularly appreciate the portrayal of Atticus and the realistic courtroom scenes. Here’s a line from his closing statement at the trial:The witnesses for the state.have presented themselves to you gentlemen, to this court, in the cynical confidence that their testimony would not be doubted, confident that you gentlemen would go along with them on the assumption-the evil assumption-that all Negroes lie, that all Negroes are basically immoral beings, that all Negro men are not to be trusted around our women, an assumption one associates with minds of their caliber. Which, gentlemen, we know is in itself a lie as black as Tom Robinson’s skin, a lie I do not have to point out to you. You know the truth, the truth is this: some Negroes lie, some Negroes are immoral, some Negro men cannot be trusted around women, black or white. But this is a truth that applies to the human race and to no particular race of men.While I read this book as a child in school like most people, I think adults should read or reread this book at regular intervals. I appreciated the writing and the themes and the characters so much more this time around, and I’ll probably appreciate them more as I get older. Such a book is truly a classic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>terricoop</user>
	<review>“To Kill A Mockingbird” is a delightful novel that has had unintended consequences and effects on society.  Intended as the tale of two children and their unending quest to lure their reclusive neighbor out of his house, the novel has become a standard and beacon of legal conduct and expertise - the very definition of legal civility.However, there is a lot more going on here.  This is one of the quintessential ‘southern’ novels where everyone is pretty well related to everyone else, but the social boundaries between ‘fine folk’ and everyone else is clearly marked by a boundary that only the participants can see.  Scout, at nine, never really does understand.  She just sees ‘folks.’  Jem, at thirteen, says he used to think that way, when he was younger.Which brings me to my next point.  This is a story of the essential nature and contrasts that are the lives of children.  On one hand Scout and Jem harbor and spin weird fantasies and plots about their neighbor, Boo Radley.  He only comes out at night to eat small animals, yet he could possibly be lured outside with a trail of lemon drops.  On the other hand, Jem and Scout help their father face down a lynch mob and sneak into a graphic rape trial.  On her first day of school, Scout explains the extreme poverty of a classmate to the new idealistic teacher, then allows Jem to roll her down the street inside an old tire.  When life was simple and choices were clear cut.The final undercurrent I will comment on is this book is also a glimpse into an insular small town during the Depression.  Times were always hard, the economic failure of a nation only made them harder.  Folks got by.  Doctors and lawyers took their fees in potatoes and stovewood.  As Scout said, ‘there was nothing to buy and nothing to buy it with.’  An interesting insight into our own economic woes.Why readers will like this book:This is character driven literature.  Even the story of the Tom Robinson trial, so beloved by lawyers, is secondary to the change and development of Scout, Jem, Atticus Finch and even Boo Radley.  At the very end as Scout has her realization of just how precious she and her brother are to Boo and his solitary life, she also exults that she got to see Boo and Jem didn’t.  Quirky to the end, the book is the essential nature of Jean Louis ‘Scout’ Finch.Why writers should read this book:This short novel, the only one written by Harper Lee, is a masterful example of the correct use of first-person point-of-view.  The story is always told from Scout’s perspective, yet it is not overburdened with a tedious litany of ‘I this’ and ‘I that’.  Any writer that wants to tell stories in first-person can take a lesson from “To Kill A Mockingbird.”  There’s definitely more, but that is the overwhelming ‘technical’ lesson to be learned from this novel. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Visrael</user>
	<review>This is a book that made me almost want to be there as a child (in the Finch home) and see these things for myself.  I wanted to know Atticus Finch.  I wanted to play with Jem and Scout for the summer.  In spite of all the happenings, it still seemed like a peaceful time.  Some of the things that went on in the book rose out of hearsay and made it more dramatic, like the history of Boo and his family.   Jem and Scout created a reality in their own minds about Boo.  This book positively represents family, community, integrity and the reality at that time. It is a reality that gives us a view of the inequality, bias and hatred of that time.  There are many different characters in this book.  This is an excellent book for a character analysis. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Violeten</user>
	<review>I loved this book, but how could you not? Its moving, truthful and raw like any good novel should be. Atticus finch is an amazing human and really inspires you to be as good as he was, its the kind of book that will give you goosebumps and make the hairs stand up on your arm. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TheTortoise</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mocking Bird is utterly brilliant, profoundly moving, sensitive and fine. A novel that is beautifully written and whose themes are compelling and relevant – a superb achievement. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gabeblaze</user>
	<review>(Plot summary includes spoilers. The - - - indicates a suggested place to stop if you've not read the text)Scout, a young girl growing up in Maycomb Alabama, lives with her brother Jem and her Father Atticus Finch. They have a cook named Calpurnia (Cal). This story spans a few years of Scout's life as she sees may events unfold. Her brother, friend Dill and she wonders about the residents of the shut-up house next door. This curiosity leads to many hi-jinks trying to get in to see Mr. "Boo Radley." She starts school, is dissatisfied with the education system and learns to fit in slowly. With many allusions, confusions and interesting turns along the way the Finch family confronts many moral grey areas for their small town when Atticus agrees to defend Tom Robinson a black man accused of raping Robert Ewell's daughter Mayella. - - -Even though the town considers the Ewells "trash" it appears to suddenly think a lot less of the finches because of Atticus' insistence to treat Tom Robinson like any other client. Atticus goes into the task knowing two things, Tom is innocent, and he's going to be found guilty. As Jem and a confused Scout follow the goings on in the trial the town climate changes drastically. After the trial Tom Robinson is shot in jail while waiting on his appeal. Many feel that this is the end of the worry about him, however; after the way that the Ewell’s were treated at the trial Robert Ewell is left feeling put-upon and vengeful. He supposedly attempts to break into the judge’s house and verbally assaults Tom’s widow. While Scout and Jem are walking home from the Halloween pageant they are assaulted and the scuffle ends in Robert Ewell’s death, Jem’s arm broken, Scout costume ruined and none other than the elusive Boo Radley carrying Jem home to his father. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RPerritt</user>
	<review>I really enjoyed this book. It took me quite a while to finish it because I have so much going on. I wish there were more people like Atticus Finch in this world. Boo Radley really came through for the kids in the end. I was glad that the bad man got what he deserved in the end. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>firebird013</user>
	<review>If you have not read this you have missed one of the greatest books of all time. Trueman Capote is the the real life exemplar of one of the children in the story - whom Harper Lee knew as a child. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jlgroves</user>
	<review>Probably one of my all time favorites.  Read it the first time in school and it started my love of reading.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>juhudo</user>
	<review>ein klassiker, der mich berührt hat: aus der perspektive eines kleinen mädchens werden themen wie ehre, toleranz, glaubwürdigkeit und mut abgehandelt. in einen abgelegenen südstaatenkleinstadt wird ein junger schwarzer beschuldigt, ein weißes mädchen der unterschicht angegriffen und vergewaltigt zu haben. atticus fink, der vater des mädchens, wird zum pflichtverteidiger bestellt und er nimmt seine aufgabe trotz des unwillens, den er sich in seiner umgebung zuzieht, sehr ernst. für den angeklagten gibt es keine rettung, aber langsam beginnt ein umdenkprozess.lineare handlung, gut gezeichnete, glaunwürdige charaktere, einfache sprache. ein einblick in einen teil amerikas der 30-iger jahre. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>maripax</user>
	<review>La estupenda película que provocó, ha eclipsado en cierta manera esta narración de una niña que cuenta lo que a veces no comprende todavía. Enternecedora sin caer en lo cursi. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TakeItOrLeaveIt</user>
	<review>a must read in elementary school. this books ethics are very old fashioned but still important as a literary accomplishment. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jen12</user>
	<review>An excellent read for all age groups</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>loriephillips</user>
	<review>Believe it or not but I first read this book when I was about 10 years old.  Of course I did not really understand some of the moral issues that are addressed in the book, they were much to subtle for a 10 year old.  I've read it several times since then and get more out of it every time.  Harper Lee was a fantastic writer who could really get into the mind of a child and also bring a bygone era back to life.  This is a wonderful book, probably my favorite book of all time.  A beautifully written and timeless story. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sjjk</user>
	<review>klassieke roman, us, racism </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tonyalex</user>
	<review>What can you say about a classic? Everyone wants Atticus as their father, and made me realized how much I missed being as innocent as Scout.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>trlchick25</user>
	<review>This book is easy reading, I was surprised with how fast I was able to read it. I loved some of the characters and their relationships. It's a good story but to me it's a one time book. I didn't get what made it so much more special than other books. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>punxsygal</user>
	<review>I absolutely loved this book!!!  With all the reviews done of it, it is very hard to find anything new to add.  If you take away anything from this book, it should be Atticus' belief in respect for all humans regardless of race or abilities.  It definitely should be required reading in all high schools. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lilyfyrestorm</user>
	<review>Finally, a classic that I enjoyed! Ms. Lee's voice resonates with truth and character. Scout is an unforgettable young lady. The phrasing, especially the southern dialect is written in such a way that it conveys the sound of the words, but is not confusing. The plot is satisfying and worth the investment.I wish I'd read it sooner. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siriaeve</user>
	<review>This was required reading for my Junior Cert, away back in the mists of time. It's a testament to the power of this book that it was just as eye-opening and relevant to me, living in Ireland, as it wasmdash;and still ismdash;for people living in the States. Lee's prose is incrediblemdash;subtle yet still forthright, with a marvellous ear for the rhythms of dialogue, the vernacular and the speech of a child. It certainly doesn't encompass all of the conversation which needs to be had on racemdash;couldn't possibly do so, not in one volume written by a white womanmdash;but as an opening salvo, as something to make you think, it more than succeeds in its aims. I don't know the current English curriculum in Irish schools, but I hope this is still being placed into the hands of second and third year students: it's a book which absolutely needs to be read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aiufjcf</user>
	<review>This is easily the best book i've read this year. I would definently recomend this one. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JenJambon</user>
	<review>This is the most amazing book ever.  I have read it several times and find something new in it every time I pick it up.  As a child, I was so scared of Boo Radley!  It seems funny now because as an adult he is such an interesting character, a hero.  Harper Lee has created a social comentary built around unforgetable characters.  Her characters do not suffer for the message that she is trying to convey, in fact, they seem more real because of it.  "Stand up child, your father is passin'.  some of the most moving words ever written.  I get chills even now! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kynaratholis</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books. Compelling, thoughtful and a fun read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>supermanlver</user>
	<review>I loved this story. I had to read it for school and the discussions that we had in class really helped me to understand it a little more. It's a novel that really informs you about the history of small southern towns around the 1930's. There are lots of racial prejudices in the story but it teaches a lesson that you have to stand up for what you believe in, even if everyone else thinks you're wrong. A wonderful story, i would recommend it for teenage readers and older.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>smitkevi</user>
	<review>Few books I read in school were more worth reading than what I would have been reading on my own. This is one of the exceptions. If I were an english teacher, this would be required reading. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jcmontgomery</user>
	<review>Initially, I was introduced to Harper Lee’s novel through the 1962 movie starring Gregory Peck. However, I had never read the book. As I wanted this reading to be as fresh as possible, I made it a point not to read anything about the book: reviews, criticisms – nothing. I wanted any impressions made, to be my own. Not until finishing did I consult other reviews and study guides.The amount of information available was absolutely overwhelming. But it was all someone else’s opinions, and this review is supposed to be about my own. Once I had divested myself of any preconceived notions and others pronouncements, I finally had a clearer idea of what my impressions really are about the novel.Miss Lee has created a story which not only projects a strong theme of ethics and morals, but also contains subtle undercurrents of courage and prejudice (of class as well as race), which she has woven brilliantly throughout the narrative. There is also the loss of childhood innocence, which is a bittersweet moment. But it must come, and Miss Lee handles it eloquently and with respect. Yes, the lesson is instilled through tragedy, but with dignity, and this is what struck me so profoundly about the novel.To Kill A Mockingbird is separated into two parts, yet they work together to illustrate the consequences of ignorance and prejudice. Strengthening the theme along the way is the character of Atticus Finch. He is the embodiment of moral rectitude; remaining constant and true, a physical reminder to his children and community that “right action and the greater good” are what makes up a person’s dignity – not their social standing, skin color, or economic status.His children Jem and Scout, as well as their friend Dill, are exposed to situations which test their own understanding of right and wrong, good and evil. Part of this learning experience is seeing how people of strong moral character (Atticus) and those with little or none (Bob Ewell) react to circumstances into which they are thrust unwillingly. Both men are faced with a choice: do the right thing knowing full well that it will possibly mean losing the respect of friends, family, and community, or take the easier path of denying your own morality at the cost of dignity. As Atticus states, “…before I can live with other folks I’ve got to live with myself. The one thing that doesn’t abide by majority rule is a person’s conscience.”In addition to this lesson about dignity, another is of courage. Sometimes the right choice is the hardest, and does not always lead to victory. Courage is being able to face the inevitable, even if you know from the beginning, it is a losing one. Here is where Miss Lee’s brilliance shines. It is not enough to have Atticus as a role model; she has each child learn this harsh truth through personal experiences. In one of the more poignant passages in the book, Atticus explains to Jem what real courage is, “I wanted you to see what real courage is, instead of getting the idea that courage is a man with a gun in his hand. It’s when you know you’re licked before you begin but you begin anyway and you see it through no matter what.” One thing that surprised me the most about this book was the amount of controversy surrounding it, even to this day. But the reader must remember that within the setting and tone of the novel, it is appropriate – and I would say absolutely necessary. How can one truly understand 1935 Alabama unless one gets into the mindset of its people and the harshness of its environment?It was not a politically correct period in American History; therefore politically correct sensibilities must be set aside when reading this book. In this novel, as in life, the goodness of men is always tempered with its opposite. The simple fact is that human nature is made up of the capacity to be ultimately kind or horrifyingly evil. But when the evil in us is faced with dignity, grace, and courage, it can be overcome.I give this book 5 stars with the simple advisement that one take into consideration the language and subject matter and rise above it, for its message is much more important than the words used to convey it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>arouse77</user>
	<review>reading this made me understand why we call certain books "classic"written in a lively prose, this story is about the expansion of awareness possible only at a very particular time in life.  though this book has been turned into a movie where the legal drama takes the main focus, i felt the real story here was in how the family of Scout, Jem, and Atticus grow together and apart in the face of the harsh realities that dwell on the periphery of their insular southern town.as Scout's understanding of her world and the people who populate it becomes more sophisticated and nuanced, she sacrifices some of her shining innocence for the weightier gift of compassion. this story illustrates with sensitivity and sense this quintessential process of maturation. highly recommended. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>reading_fox</user>
	<review>Charming and delightful, and at times heartwrenching. Set in 1935 but written in 1960 it features a couple of years in the life of 8yr old Jean Louise Finch, called inexplicably Scout. She lives with her brother Jem in a small town, Maycomb in Alabama. Her father is a lawyer, and one day is appointed to defend a Negro who is accused of raping a white trash family's oldest daughter. The story is potently told from the view of the 8yr old Scout, small town events set the scene in the year before the trial. Large as life characters play out the small dramas that fill any minor town; Scout starts school and various neighburs are introduced and predudices confrimed. People of Colour are either Negros or niggers depending on a person's background. The looming war in Europe merits two paragraphs, but the plight of the jews is interestingly compared to that of the blacks. the trial which is what the book is 'about' features surprisingly little in the life of Scout, and it's only on the actual day that she goes to the court to see what's happening. Scout's life is dominated by a passing friend called Dill - Jim Baker Harris, and attempts to see her reclusive and terriffying neighbour Boo (Arthur) Radley. Perhaps the actual point of the book is focus on the consequences of people's outlook and attempts by an 8 yr old with very occasional older commentry to understand why people behave as they do. The older commentary is rare but the switch in tense is occasionally annoying, and the only very minor downside of the entire story. The prose is delicate but can be very moving, and captures the innocense and intensity of childhood very well. The story is quite short for a work of this magnitude. The title is one of the many many pithy sayings the various characters say to Scout as part of her education in becoming a lady "It's a sin to kill a mockingbird because all they do all day is sing for plesaure". A massive shame that this is the only work by Harper Lee, there has to be some suspician that it is at least in part biographical. A wonderful tale, full of insight into what life was really like in 1930s southern america. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>asummerwasting08</user>
	<review>LOVED the characters so very much--the childhood innocence mixed in with the mature narration was compelling, and I want to be Atticus when I grow up. Though the storyline of Alabama sleepy-town adventures got rather tedious after awhile, the scene of Robinson's trial was amazing, and the end of the novel wrapped everything up quite nicely. Well-written, well-realized, and well-loved for a reason. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>debs4jc</user>
	<review>Excellent, a standard by which other books should be measured. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>karenraebennett</user>
	<review>You are drawn into this tale by the great writing and can almost feel yourself aside Scout and Jem in their adventures.  The mystery unfolds slowly at just the right pace to go with a good old southern experience, and then knocks you off your feet.  This is a must read for advanced middle school and all high school students. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TadAD</user>
	<review>Great movie.  Greater book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jxnhole</user>
	<review>My absolute most favorite book ever! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sorsha</user>
	<review>http://olvasonaplo.freeblog.hu/archiv... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>booksfallapart</user>
	<review>Wow! I have NEVER had this kind of experience coming back to a book after ten or eleven or whatever it's been years and remembering so, so much, like vales of childhood and shit. Not the plot - I got Boo Radley completely mixed up with Tom Robinson in my head, and if you remember the book you'll know how hard that would be - but the dialogue: "Simply because we were licked a hundred years before we started is no reason for us not to try to win" and "Ain't no snot-nosed slut of a schoolteacher ever born c'n make me do nuthin'!" and "Old Adolf Hitler has been prosecutin' the Jews" and Jee crawlin' hovas and an entailment is a condition of having your tail in a crack aaand a whole bushel of others. The dialogue is Platonic in its pleasance, and that is just one of the foremost of this book's delights. It is the cornbread-that's-just-greasy-enough-but-not-too-greasy of world fiction, and Atticus Finch is one of our literature's great noble lions. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thmazing</user>
	<review>http://thmazing.blogspot.com/2007/11/...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ElizabethPisani</user>
	<review>What to say? This one will survive the early-onset Alzheimer's, I'm sure. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sweetos</user>
	<review>one of the best books that tackles society and racial discrimination.i liked how the story was told through the eyes of a child - gave it a different kind of wit and liveliness to it.atticus is one of the best heroes in literature of all time, a perfect fit with probably the best book of the 20th century . </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>EssFair</user>
	<review>I read this book when I was in high school and wanted to read it again to see if being older and more experienced changed my perception of the book. It hasn’t; it is still a great book. The fact that the narrator was a child helped my juvenile understanding grow as the narrator’s. Now that I’m older, I can catch some of the nuances added by Scout’s adult self who has been able to reflect on the events of her childhood. That keeps the novel interesting to an adult. I had forgotten about some of the characters like Atticus’s sister and Dill’s aunt. Amazingly, it has not dated. Many older books can be unconsciously anti-feminist. This one is not, in part because Scout is a tomboy so her perspective about how a girl should behave is different from the typical 1930’s, Southern woman. This book remains a good examination of how prejudice about different ethnic groups, women, the mentally ill, or anybody that is just different can be insidious and damaging.I recommend this book to anyone. If you have only seen the movie—read it. If you read it years ago—read it again. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>perlle</user>
	<review>A lot is made of the racism in this book. But Lee does a good job of juxtaposing the race issues with class issues and I wonder why that is not discussed more. If leaves one wondering if class and race issues can ever be separated. Overall, I liked the message at the end of the book about 'most people being nice when you really see them.' If the author had taken a more pessimistic bent this work would not be nearly as powerful. It's nice when optimism wins out over cynicism. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CarrieLynn</user>
	<review>First read this book as a teen. Recently reread it. Just as powerful now as it was then. Shares the top of my favorites with A Tree Grows in Brooklyn. Also thought the movie was absolutely fantastic. (Gregory Peck, YUM!) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>readergirliz</user>
	<review>I didn't truly appreciate this book until after I finished it.  While I was reading it, it seemed a little slow, but when Tom Robinson's trial began, I began to fall in love with it.   It is an extremely worthwhile read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kchris</user>
	<review>Life-changing in its quality writing and story.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tryion</user>
	<review>One of the first "big" books I read as a kid. Loved every minute of it and still do. Even the courtroom scenes were exciting to me. Perhaps because it is told through the eyes of a child. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>onHudson</user>
	<review>Without question, the best book I've ever been assigned to read (it was for middle school English class), and overall one of the best books I've read in my life. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>virtualdummy27</user>
	<review>A true classic can be appreciated despite the generation that it's being read in. Prejudice may still be an issue today but not enough to truly allow me to feel for the characters and their situations. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SunnieB</user>
	<review>I first read this book waayyy back when I was in elementary or Jr.High school and before I had seen the movie.  I remember it being one of, if not THE first book we had a real discussion about.  I loved it!  Soon after that, when I saw the movie on TV and put definate faces to Scout, Jem and Atticus... it was even better.  I recently re-read it for about the 3rd time and enjoyed it like the first.   I recommend this to everyone. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wyvernfriend</user>
	<review>An interesting story of a southern lawyer and a case of a black man being accused of rape of a white young woman.   It's told from the viewpoint of his daughter who is quite young at this time, almost too young for some of the viewpoints.It's involved and you can see the fracture lines in the society that were building at the time.  Some of the ideas stated by the characters gives quite a good insight into the life and times.  You could see where some of the issues really annoyed Harper Lee and where she was forcing a point.  Sometimes the points were a little forced but other times it kept me wondering and reading. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>eme</user>
	<review>PREJUICIOS NEGROSHARPER LEE                      Título original: To kill a mockingbirdTraducción de Baldomero PortaEdiciones B. Barcelona, 2006410 páginas, 8’50 euros“Creo que empiezo a comprender por qué Boo Radley ha estado encerrado en su casa todo este tiempo… Ha sido porque quiere estará allí dentro”. El mundo ya no es el lugar maravilloso que Jem Finch creía. Después de años devanándose los sesos ha entendido, de pronto, que existen razones lo bastante poderosas como para que alguien decida recluirse, de perpetuidad, en su casa. Y así se lo hace saber a Scout, su hermana. La percepción que ambos tenían de la vida, del mundo y de los que lo pueblan se ha transformado para siempre.Tom Robinson es un hombre acusado falsamente de violación. Bastaría decir que es un hombre, pero en el marco hondamente racista del Sur de los Estados Unidos durante la Gran Depresión resulta necesario aludir a su condición de negro, pues ésta es, al fin y al cabo, la que determina el fallo del jurado. Atticus Finch, ecuánime y respetado por todos, se hace cargo de la defensa de Robinson, pero el color de éste y los prejuicios incrustados en el corazón y en la mente de casi toda la comunidad de Maycomb pesan más que la inocencia.  Matar un ruiseñor, obra inspirada en la infancia de la autora, es un alegato por la igualdad y la justicia, una denuncia con valor universal contra el racismo y la desconfianza, ganadora del premio Pulitzer en 1961. Al año siguiente Robert Mulligan la llevó a la gran pantalla en una inolvidable película que obtuvo dos Oscar: al mejor guión y al mejor intérprete masculino (Gregory Peck). El reconocimiento y el éxito sorprendieron y abrumaron tanto a Harper Lee tanto que, dicen, no llegó a reponerse. Al igual que le ocurrió a T. J. Salinguer con el célebre El guardián entre el centeno, Lee no escribió más novelas. Con su ópera prima se consagró y ya no pudo o no supo seguir. O quizás, sencillamente, no quiso. No hay forma de saberlo, sin embargo, porque Lee jamás concedió entrevistas. Todo cuanto pueda decirse raya la especulación. Lo que sí es cierto es que el mundo se perdió a una gran escritora. Si con su primera novela llegó a tanta gente, ¿qué no habría logrado con las siguientes? Azorín decía que escribir es muy fácil: “basta con poner una palabra tras otra”. Para Harper Lee, sin duda, así era. Por medio de Scout, una niña de ocho años, imprime en cada página una de las 410 páginas la ingenuidad, la ternura y, al mismo tiempo, la lucidez característica de la infancia. Engatusa al lector, y aunque no dota al relato de la crudeza propia de las novelas que abordan el tema del racismo y la desigualdad, como por ejemplo Luz de agosto, el lector no puede limitarse a seguir los hechos y esperar. No, el lector se indigna, se rebela, siente desprecio y, finalmente, desolación. Como Jem Finch, comprende que el mundo no es ese locus amoenus del que nos hablaban. No lo fue en tiempos de Harper Lee y sigue sin serlo, ahora, en tiempos de los derechos humanos. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>oh2read</user>
	<review>This book is a classic that I somehow missed reading while in high school.  Being a southerner, I don't know why one or more teachers of mine did not require it along the way.The story is told by Scout Finch, the young daughter of Atticus Finch.  She and her brother, Jem, come to learn the realities of Depression-era culture in the South very quickly through the two-year span of the book.  Scout and Jem soon realize that the world isn't as simple as they would have it be, but they also learn that they don't have to conform to the accepted behaviors in their town. From their father, Atticus, they learn that all men (and women) are created equal, and have equal standing under the law.  It is only the fabricated barriers of class and race that  stand between people.The book centers on the Finches, their neighbors, the elusive Radleys, and Tom Robinson, a young black man who goes on trial for rape.  As the book opens, Scout, Jem, and their friend Dill are almost obsessed with making their neighbor, Boo Radley, come out of his house.  A recluse for years, the town barely remembers he is there. But with his reclusiveness, his mythic stature grows for the kids, making their torture of Boo almost a "quest".  As Scout and Jem are finishing their school year, Atticus is assigned a case defending the black man, Tom Robinson, who has been accused of raping a white woman.  This causes much heartache for the children with their peers.Then as the trial draws nearer, they learn lessons they'll never forget, about race barriers, social barriers, and about themselves and the meaning of friendship in all its forms.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LhLibrarian</user>
	<review>What a moving story! It took me till after graduate school to finally read it, but I am so glad that I did. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>powell.442</user>
	<review>This book is very well written and provides an excellent story line.  The characters are very original and the book captures the playful viewpoint of children perfectly.  I really like how in all of the childrens "adventures" there was some small instance of foreshadowing or allusion to an important issue in the story.  Also, the high tension events, such was walking by Boo Radley's house and the attack in the dark are described perfectly and really envelopes the reader </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thekoolaidmom</user>
	<review>This is an amazing novel that speaks to every culture and every age.  In any culture there are the group of people who are on the bottom rung of society; be it the Jews in Nazi Germany, the Dalits of India or the blacks of the South.  In addition to the valuation of a person based on the color of their skin and not the content of their character (the Ewells being higher on the social ladder than Calpurnia or Tom,)  Harper Lee also blows up the prejudices people can have of the mentally ill (Boo Radley,) or of those they do not really know (Mrs. Dubose.)It is a multi-layered epic that a reader will pull new things from everytime it is read.  Through Dill, Jem and Scout learn that not everyone has parents who love and care for them.  Through Miss Caroline, Scout learns that change is on the horizon and she is seeing the end of an era.I would definately put this book on a list of books you must read before you die. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>moonsoar</user>
	<review>http://books.moonsoar.com/archives/20... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>becky_quilts</user>
	<review>This is the enlightening story of "Scout" Finch, growing up in Maycomb, Alabama. It starts out at a leisurely pace, describing the summer antics of Scout, her older brother Jem, and a neighbor boy Dill, as they imagine the mysterious Boo Radley in the creepy, rundown Radley Place down the street. We become familiar with Scout's precocious ways and her propensity to find trouble. As the intrigue of Boo wears off, a new interest takes it's place: the trial of Tom Robinson. Scout, and the reader, learn a lot about the mindset of Maycomb County in general, and Atticus Finch specifically, in regards to humanity, honor, and right and wrong.Scout is easy to sympathise with. Jem's character is being influenced strongly by his experiences and his growing respect for his father. It is truly a beautifully written story. I love how a vast and rich vocabulary is combined with the local undeveloped dialect of the south. And I especially love the ending. I would highly recommend this title to anyone.http://educatingpetunia.blogspot.com/... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brunhilde</user>
	<review>My second copy of this essential book, a joy from beginning to end, full of basic truths about life, loyalty, fairness and honour. And with amazing characters you wish were living in your town. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>canarylampshade</user>
	<review>Without a doubt, my favorite novel.   Great pieces of who I am and how I think and feel have their roots in this piece of fiction. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>don77</user>
	<review>3</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SanctiSpiritus</user>
	<review>To think this is the only book Harper Lee has produced. But, as they say, it's greatest to go out on top. One word eloquently equals the sum of this book: earnest. The book is not politically correct (nor should any book be). Accordingly, I am sure the book outrages every type of person to whom Harper's message was written. The book tells of the injustices black people did, and have endured. The time period is late 1930's. The story line feeds the reader a view of endurance, moral right, truth, honesty, and that one must stand up for what is morally right in the face of many detractors. Verily, a book every person should read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>samantha464</user>
	<review>My first introduction to this book was my mother reading it out loud to me on a very long car ride through the south.  Since then, I've read it myself probably twenty times.  The story is full of mystery, partly for its perspective of being narrated through the eyes of a seven year old.  She manages to, quite simply and honestly, without affect, point to the issues that can tear a small town apart. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tezz</user>
	<review>Nice book, Boo Radley greatest name of a character ever.  Reading this novel is like taking a trip back into childhood.  Very cool. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rockym87</user>
	<review>A hot southern summer, a brother/sister adventure, mystery, fear and friends. Somewhat of a dull read but a moving and exciting story none the less. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bibliobbe</user>
	<review>This is another of those books that everyone should read, at least once in their lives.  I first read it when I was 13, and I wished my life was like Scout’s.  It’s a fantastically lyrical story of racism in the deep South and one man’s stand against ignorance, seen through the eyes of a ten year old girl.  It remains as powerful today as it was when Harper Lee first wrote it.  Why is it so good?  Mostly because the characterisation is spot-on, the story is first rate and the dialogue starts at a cracking pace from the first page and never lets up until you close the book.  If you haven’t read this yet, you’d better do it soon.  And give yourself plenty of time to read it, because you won’t want to put it down. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>educ318</user>
	<review>A wonderful story of symbolism in the work "mockingbird."  How courage, strong values and beliefs can send such powerful life long learning lessons for the children in this book by their father Atticus.  I remember enjoying this book very much and was happy to re- read it for a college course. - Karla, Spring 2008I can't believe that it took me this long to read this book. Once I started it, it was hard to put down. This would be a wonderful book to use as a teaching tool in a history class. I read this book for the Spring 08 semester. (Laurie)Also read by:Shelley, Spring 2008Jennifer, Fall 2009Great book and should continue to be allowed in schools. (Sherry, Fall 2009)</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>notmyrealname</user>
	<review>A reread, my Aunty bought me this book for Christmas, telling me I couldn't be a good lawyer without reading this every few years. I think the first time I read it, I was too young to appreciate it, but now I see the full picture of innocence, tolerance, conscience and the inviolable principles of justice which should be every society's goal. Scout's naivety is done brilliantly and Atticus is, of course, a hero to every lawyer. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cecrow</user>
	<review>I didn't get to study this in highschool, and it took me a long time to get around to it on my own initiative.  I'm grateful I did; it's absolutely fantastic.  Now I understand why the father character is often referred to as the epitome of good.  Excellent, excellent, in story and message. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KylieL</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird is perfect. It's beautifully written and the story is engaging, funny and touching. Scout is a charming young girl and her father, Atticus, is a paragon of virtue. One to be read and re-read endlessly. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>katiebl</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird is a terrific and ppowerful book written in the eyes of an 8 year old whose father is a lawyer defending a black man accused to rape a white girl. This story shows the struggles of an 8 year old who must stay loyal to her daddy. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>oregonobsessionz</user>
	<review>Not much I can say about this book that others haven't already covered.  I grew up in a rural area that was pretty much white.  Reading this book as a young teenager was overwhelming.  It was the first time I had any awareness at all of race issues.  I have reread it more times than I can count. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Henk</user>
	<review>http://chef-doeuvre.blogspot.com/2007... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ReadingPenguin</user>
	<review>I had to read this book for school and I have to say that it fancinated me! It is a very well-written book that made me think. It really is the best peice of American Literature that I've read. It is about two kids, Scout and Jem, who live in the South in the 1930's and whose father is a lawyer. He has to defend a black man for a rape case. Meanwhile, the kids are trying to get a mysterous man, Boo Radley out of his house so that they can see him. In the end, both plots are tyed together in a fasinating way. This book gives you a window into seeing what life was like in the South in the 1930's. It is a sad book at some points, because innocent people ("mockingbirds" as the title says") are often fasly accused because of something that makes them different from other people (skin, thoughts, lifestyle). If you didn't read this book in school, pick it up and read it as soon as possible, because it is an amazing, not to be missed peice of  American Literature. Enjoy! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mramos</user>
	<review>Pulitzer Prize Winner. In this classic we read about Scout Finch who is an outspoken, literate six-year-old tomboy when she begins to tell of growing up in a small Alabama town with her brother and her attorney father Atticus. The children's curiosity about a reclusive neighbor is eclipsed by Atticus's attempt to defend a black man against charges of raping a white woman. I would recommend this book for anyone in high school and older readers. This is a must read book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>annegabrielle</user>
	<review>Génial, vraiment génial. J'ai acheté ce livre complètement par hasard et il m'a enchanté. Et pourtant, sur cette édition de poche, horreur, il manquait 30 pages et je me trouvais en Allemagne sans possibilité de l'échanger.Drôle et grave en même temps.Racheté ce livre 2 fois pour l'offrir </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aimless22</user>
	<review>A magically written book with wonderfully defined characters. Atticus Finch is possible the most pure, righteous and human-loving character ever created. Loved the book twenty times more than the movie which I also loved - how can one not? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cdagdagan</user>
	<review>(79/323 pages read; I've read this book before, but I decided to read it again.)Jem and Scout Finch have been curious as to why their conservative neighbor, Boo Radley, is so afraid to come out into the neighborhood. Atticus Finch, their father, has tried to prevent his two intuitive children from getting into business that they shouldn't be getting into. Jem and Scout, because of their ambition to investigate deeply, get into a lot of head-scratcher situations.Description: Atticus Finch is the father of Scout and Jem Finch. He's a very caring father who looks out for his children, even when he trusts them to stay out of trouble. He is a lawyer who deals with A LOT of clients in and out. Coming from the book (not exactly), "Atticus isn't the same as he is inside the house than he is during court". Atticus stays the caring father and stern lawyer throughout the book.The only two things I was able to relate to was the curiosity level that Jem and Scout had and the relationship that they had together. My older brother and I were always so curious about things we'd get ourselves into trouble. Jem and Scout seem to have a pretty tight-knit, brother-sister love, kind of a relationship and that's the kind I have with my brothers.As I said above, I have read this book before, but I decided to read it again. I really loved this book the first time I read it. It was so perfectly written. VERY hard to interpert, but it's interesting when you do. I recommend this to people of all ages.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chilirlw</user>
	<review>Somehow I never read this book until mid-adulthood--even though I had seen and liked the movie, I had just never had the motivation to pick it up.  As a recent transplant to Alabama, though, I thought I should read it, if only for some insight into Southern character.  Well.  A lot of fuss is made about the fact that this is Harper Lee's only book; to tell the truth, she gave us such a gift here, it seems churlish to ask for more.  This is one of those works of art that make a person proud to be a part of the human race, whose members can create such wonders. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>qofd</user>
	<review>A classic. Sorry I saw the movie first. Only decided to read it after watching "Capote" so kind of a three degrees of seperation thing. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>NiteScout</user>
	<review>One of America's finest works of literature. Lee's themes and characters are as strong and vital today as they ever have been. Scout Finch is a marvel and for me she remains a seminal literary hero. This novel stretches from a simple tale of a young girl spreading her wings and finding her voice to a powerful indictment on race relations and justice in our courts, our country and our hearts. A credo that offers difference not as something to be feared but instead to be embraced. It is truly a masterwork and continues to inspire new  generations of readers who get the lucky joy of meeting Atticus, Tom Robinson, Boo, Dill, Jem and the wonderful Scout Finch for the very first time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brunhilde</user>
	<review>I allowed myself 10 pages a day when I first read it, because I loved it so much, was desperate to know what happened (especially if they got to see Boo) but never wanted it to end. Masterpiece. Totally believable kids and saintly but non-irritating dad (who else but Greg Peck?) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>valkylee</user>
	<review>This is one of those great books of childhood.  I first read it in eighth grade for class and it was just fantastic.  The characters are so real, yet somehow above and beyond we average folk.  Atticus Finch is a good man, and a noble man, that he seems almost superhuman Superdad.  Yet at the same time he's just a normal, everyday father.  Bob Ewell is just so, so evil and disgusting, but he's a person too, and unfortunately a sort of man you still meet far too often.This is one of those books I just read over and over again.  I can't get enough of it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jeyra</user>
	<review>Appropriate for all readers. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>l3wilso</user>
	<review>Wow!  I love this book.  I read it about every 6 months.  It helps to keep me on track with the wiles of mankind. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Yoshikawa</user>
	<review>This book was pretty funny, but it seemed very...dull. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Just1MoreBook</user>
	<review>"Macomb was an old town but it was a tired old town when I first knew it."  If I could write like this I wouldn't ever write another book either! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>3M3m</user>
	<review>Wow! What a fantastic book. I don't know why I've never read this before. I really thought I already knew what it was about--a girl's father defending a black man for r*ping a white woman. It is about so much more than that, although of course that plays an important part.Scout and her family live in Maycomb, Alabama. In the beginning of the book, Scout is going into the 1st grade and her brother Jem is going into 5th. Her father is an attorney, her mother died when she was 2, and her caregiver is a sweet, smart black woman named Calpurnia. The family relationship among all members is strong--very strong. Scout and Jem play together at home (but not in school--Jem insists). Scout and her father always read together in the evenings. This is a point of contention with Scout's teacher Miss Caroline. Some of my favorite passages come from this section and they are hilarious to me as a former teacher who now homeschools.The teacher asks if anyone knows what the alphabet is, and then. . .    ...as I read the alphabet a faint line appeared between her eyebrows, and after making me read most of My First Reader and the stock-market quotations from the Mobile Register aloud, she discovered that I was literate and looked at me with more than faint distaste. Miss Caroline told me to tell my father not to teach me any more, it would interfere with my reading. [...] "Now you tell your father not to teach you any more. It's best to begin reading with a fresh mind. You tell him I'll take over from here and try to undo the damage--"    The Dewey Decimal System consisted, in part, of Miss Caroline waving cards at us on which were printed "the," "cat," "rat," "man," and "you." No comment seemed to be expected of us, and the class received these impressionistic revelations in silence. I was bored, so I began a letter to Dill. Miss Caroline caught me writing and told me to tell my father to stop teaching me. "Besides, she said. "We don't write in the first grade, we print. You won't learn to write until you're in the third grade."    ...as I inched sluggishly along the treadmill of the Maycomb County school system, I could not help receiving the impression that I was being cheated out of something. Out of what I knew not, yet I did not believe that twelve years of unrelieved boredom was exactly what the state had in mind for me.I don't want to give away too much of the story, so from here I'll be brief. Scout, Jem, and their friend Dill (said to have been inspired by Lee's childhood friend Truman Capote) spend a lot of time together in the summer trying to see Boo Radley, a neighbor who is a recluse. In fact, they are obsessed with this endeavor. Atticus Finch, Scout's father, takes on the r*pe case. The fallout from the case is felt by the Finches from the community as well as from their extended family. The book ends well, though, with a very satisfying conclusion.To Kill a Mockingbird won the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction in 1961 and was made into an Academy Award winning film starring Gregory Peck. It is the only novel Harper Lee ever published.I listened to parts of this book on Audio CD read by Sissy Spacek. Highly recommended.Caution: There are a few curse words and adult themes in the book. I would recommend this book for high school level and up. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LynneVS</user>
	<review>This is my favorite book of all time.  Atticus Finch shows us the kind of person we should all be.  I love Atticus, Scout, Jem, Miss Maudie, Dill, Cal and even Aunt Alexandra by the end. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bigsmileu1</user>
	<review>Best book I have ever read! </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Inver</user>
	<review>This is one of those books everyone should get around to reading. One of the classics. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>andyray</user>
	<review>this is one of the special stories of English literature, defining time and place. Scout is a fully developed character and so is Maycomb, Alabama.This is an autobiographical novel. Scout's cousin is fashioned after Truman Capote, Lee's cousin, and if you checked on the neighbor's around Lee's house growing up, I'm sure there would be an extremely withdrawn man-boy living in a broken-down house, and several women of Lee's description in the book living about her there. All in all, it was a purging of Lee's soul, took countless editings and revisions,and was a one-of from the word "go." Hemingway did the same thing as Lee and I do -- drew fromwhat he knew. It's just that he and I have had more life experience to write about. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>doowatt34</user>
	<review>This is the ultimate in southern smackdown novels...it is a microcosm of what happens on a world wide scale and therefore noriega, saddam, and others should have read it before they got pissy with the us....I had to read this in high school and  felt empathy for old Atticus and his children.  It is not easy defending a black sheep in front of hostile forces that you gotta live with...The book is a classic in literature though, and the lessons brought forth in it are still very relevent today.... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Shanra</user>
	<review>Basic Reason for Beginning: I always had the impression I've seen part of a movie version of this story. Now that I've read it, I doubt it was about this book. Same theme, though. It's one of those books that's always been in the back of my mind as things I wanted to read and never got around to it for no reason at all until now.Basic Reason for Finishing: Wow. Just wow.Full review hereTo Kill a Mockingbird has been a painful eyeopener to the kind of society we live in, not just America just before the Second War World, but modern day life as well. It's an utterly beatifully wrought story (see my lack of whining about how Scout speaks!) that simply blew me away. I have read a very decent amount of books in my time and I have a very high standard.I may just have to up this standard further because I have never felt a book this powerful before. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cockburnj</user>
	<review>beautiful, evocative, wonderful father/daughter/brother relationship</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chickadeegirl</user>
	<review>lots of racial info...very exciting and captivating </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>julw</user>
	<review>love Jem, love Atticus, love Boo, love the film, more inhumanity but triumph too </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>silverkim69</user>
	<review>AThis is my all time favorite book. I have read it over ten times and each time I find something new in it.  It is our loss that Harper Lee never wrote another book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ankabemo</user>
	<review>Classic </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Osbaldistone</user>
	<review>The recollections of a young girl in a small southern town during the depression.  Harper Lee adopts a near pitch-perfect voice of 'Scout' Finch as a narrator thinking back over the events and able to summon the 8-year old Scout to help tell them.Though often subtle, Lee keeps her eye on the subject of bigotry - bigotry of race, sex, class, education, family - and, through Scout's eyes, shines a spotlight on its cruelty and shows how the seeds are being planted for tidal changes that are on the way.It's hard to imagine a better storyteller. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Scaryguy</user>
	<review>Harper Lee's greatest book . . . of course her only book, but a great read! </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lacenaire</user>
	<review>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harper_L...http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/To_Kill_...http://www.kirjasto.sci.fi/harperle.h... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bookem</user>
	<review>Many might question Harper Lee's talent, calling her a "one hit wonder", but when your one hit is an American classic, it's hard to argue that you lack talent. This book seems to never go out of fashion and is a delight to read time and time again. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AleAleta</user>
	<review>A classic! The narrative, the story, the literary devices, and the significance of a first novel make it what it is today. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>john257hopper</user>
	<review>There's little I can add to what has been said many times before: this is a true human, not just American, classic which puts across its anti-racism message in a way that is simple and effective, without hectoring or lecturing the reader.  It starts off slowly and quietly, which makes it all the more effective.  I must admit I may never have read this unless I had seen the film first, but everyone in every country should both read the book and see the film if they can. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>twothumbsdown</user>
	<review>I read this book for school twice - once in the eighth grade and once my freshman year. It's my favorite book that I was required to read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dickcraig</user>
	<review>I read this book while on a trip to St. Martin.  I just loved it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jasongibbs</user>
	<review>This is a modern classic. If you didn't read it in high school, do yourself a favor and do so now.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bonehead-ut</user>
	<review>Best read when reading is not required.  If you read it because it was an assignment, read it again because you want to.   *  * </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jerine</user>
	<review>The author introduced the setting of a sleepy village, a place where two siblings grew up and it serves as their playground. So much like Five Quarters of the Orange by Joanne Harris.When Scout, the younger sibling, old enough to enter school, she finds that lesson was tedious. Whatever is taught in the classroom already known to her knowledge. Other children’s intellectual standard cannot compare to her ability to read and write. So much like Matilda by Roald Dahl.The plot progresses till Jem, Scout’s brother, was assigned to read for Mrs. Dubose. She’s an ailing old lady, harsh in her vocabulary. She lives with the help of morphine for years and died on her bed. And she reminds me of Amande in the story of Chocolat by Jonnne Harris.The way Atticus advises his children, the two siblings, it is so much like Rudyard Kipling's style from the poem If. He’s always reasonable, calm and wise. A perfect father figure.Atticus hires a black woman, Calpurnia, as a domestic helper. Her activity in church and the whole Christian community is so much like portrayed in the Friendship Cake by Lynne Hinton.In conclusion, every part of the story is a jigsaw piece from other fiction. Well, since this is a timeless classic (that’s what they call it), I reckon other author had took pieces from this book to form their own composition. A good read.http://reading-now.blogspot.com/2007/... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sertab</user>
	<review>got this book from a good friend of mine. always nice to see what books friends choose for me</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>williamcostiganjr</user>
	<review>Harper Lee does a magnificent job evoking a sleepy Southern town in this novel--perhaps too good a job, as I found myself dozing off after a while.It starts off quite well, but after a hundred pages or so of character and setting development I was ready for the trial to begin. The trial scenes are excellent, and I was turning the pages quickly at that point.Some of the characters are too one-dimensional in terms of good and evil. Additionally the anti-racism is a bit heavy-handed. A couple of times I felt like I was listening to that teacher on South Park say "Racism is bad, mmmkay." However it never crosses the line into full-blown melodrama. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrsmauck</user>
	<review>This is one of my all-time favorite books. I could see so much of myself in Scout when I first read this book, and I still do. White people's hatred and discrimination toward blacks breaks my heart every time, for its damage both toward black people, and for young children like Scout who lose their innocense because of it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kaitlynmarie</user>
	<review>The Great American Novel. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Chenga</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird won the Pulitzer prize in 1960 and was voted “Best Novel of the Century” in a poll conducted by the Library Journal (USA). It deals with adult topics but is very livery described from the point of view of a child. It's a book about racism and the struggle for equal rights, life in Alabama and growing up. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BrianDewey</user>
	<review>Lee, Harper. To Kill a Mockingbird. Warner Books, New York, 1988. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rhinoa</user>
	<review>Rating : 4.5/5 Reason for reading : Something About Me Challenge, Book Awards Reading ChallengeTells the story of the Finch family (father Atticus, son Jem and daughter Scout) living in Maycombe in America. It is set back when black people were seen as inferior citizens and were mostly employed by white people in the kitchen or picking cotton. The story starts with the children telling ghost stories about the reclusive neightbour next door who they nickname "Boo" Radley. This keeps them and their friend Dill entertained for most of the summer.The small town is rocked when negro Tom Robinson (a family man with a wife and children) is accused of raping white Mayella Ewell. The Ewell's are not the most respected of families, being poor with an alcholic father and too many children to feed on their benefit money, and are deemed "trash" by some of the other white folks. Despite this, at the time the book is set (around the 1930/40's), white people do not loose court cases if the defendent is black. Atticus is given the case to defend Tom, which he does to the best of his ability despite knowing his loss is nearly inevitable and the town folk call his all kinds of names.It was a really touching book that covers a range of topics. Foremost if the racial discrimination that went on at the time and how people were starting to change their attitudes and realise that all people are equal and that the colour of their skin is of no importance. It also discusses the class system at the time, with Atticus telling his children that no matter how rich the person, if they mistreat someone on grounds of race they are trash. The hypocrasy of the townsfolk was interesting as well. There is one incidence of a Jewish teacher who teaches Scout's class about discrimination as Hitler is starting to round up the Jews in Germany. She was however overheard at the trial of Tom making derogetary remarks about black people.The parts covering childhood and family values stopped the book from being too serious. The children are very intelligent and really grow up in the few short years the book covers. I really liked all the central characters, especially Atticus. I grew to like their neighbour Miss Maudie and their overbearing Aunt Alexandra. It also had a lovely sense of humour running through the novel. I can see why people love it so much. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Book_Junkie</user>
	<review>I doubt that there is anything I can say about this book that hasn't already been said.Simply put, this is a stunning book, and surely on many peoples' list of favourites.  The book is narrated by Scount Finch, a young girl who lives with her brother Jem, her father Atticus (surely one of the greatest literary heroes).  Atticus is a lawyer, who accepts the job of defending a black man accused of raping a white woman.  This is the deep south of the USA in the 1930s, and racism is running high.  Many townsfolk resent Atticus' decision to represent Tom Robinson (a beautifully drawn, sympathetic character), and the case causes repercussions for the whole community.All of the characters in this book are entirely believeable, and it is quite simply one of my favourite pieces of writing.  This book made me laugh, cry and count my blessings.  Truly deserving of the must-read tag. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shrubbery</user>
	<review>Yeah, great. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>atlaswinks</user>
	<review>This is one of my personal favorites and has been so since I was Scout's age. I was raised in a small southern town and the pace and voice of this book is dead on accurate. My only regret is that we don't have more reading material penned by Harper Lee. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stpnwlf</user>
	<review>Classic southern novel of racial injustice.  Another classic novel invaded by Gregory Peck's onscreen image that makes it impossible to imagine the main character as anyone else. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rayski</user>
	<review>One of my all time favorite movies and it was good to see that the movie had followed the book closely.  It was hard reading the book without seeing Gregory Peck as Atticus. Is the book about growing up?  Prejudice? Or how some people are best to be left to their own means?  Or maybe all of these? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tjsjohanna</user>
	<review>I've read the book multiple times, seen the movie, read stuff about the story.  There's so much here - motherless children, southern life, racism, parental love and example, coming-of-age ... it's a wonderful book with lots of layers and a great story.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gkeyes</user>
	<review>* </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Maxy</user>
	<review>A book worthy of being a classic. We had to read this in English and I just thought it was brilliant. You cannot read it without loving Atticus Finch. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>buckeyeaholic</user>
	<review>Totally classic.  Absolutely awesome.  I actually had to be talked into reading this book about 10 years ago.  Now I read it about once every 2 years  watch the movie whenever it's on.WARNING!!!  If listening to the audio version, be carefull where you listen if others can hear also (I recommend an iPod).  The use of the "N" word is frequent at times  while relevant to the story  time of the book, I the wrong person walks in at the wrong time you may have some explaining to do. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>GentryWoman</user>
	<review>Southern literature, racism, lawyers, childhood </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>IrinaLutz</user>
	<review>liked the metaphor </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TheTwoDs</user>
	<review>Part legal thriller, part racial injustice expose, part young girl's coming of age story, To Kill a Mockingbird just might be the "Great American Novel."  From the incredibly detailed characterizations, not just of Southern folk, but of the types of neighbors - nosy, proud, green thumbs - we all have, to the way Atticus imparts moral lessons and tries to explain the ambiguous shades of gray that exist in life, this novel touches on just about every topic and theory one could possibly expect in its 320 pages.  The story and characters will live on with the reader long after the book ends. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jenpbarr</user>
	<review>Everyone needs to read this book. I don't care if you have a busy life. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Demosthenes</user>
	<review>Just look at that face. Read in school.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bean1082</user>
	<review>My favorite book of all time!! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>iamagirldork</user>
	<review>An excellent book!http://bookcrossing.com/journal/45640...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jhowell</user>
	<review>I imagine I was the only literate adult left on this Earth that hadn't read this book up until today.  I certainly can see why so many people love it. Simple, sad, beautiful, hopeful.  Too bad racial injustice and predjudice still exists -- the story is wrapped up in such a ribbon one feels ready to believe that after reading it the young adults of the time would change the world. I don't know, maybe they did.A great, if kitchy, book. The thing that blew me away was how convincing and sincere Scout's narration was. I'd "like to" believe she was just going to jump off'n the page into my living room, she was so well drawn. And the Southern vernacular, and the small town touches like the family doctor pulling splinters, the telephone operator who knew everyone's voice; even the inbreeding was somehow charming. I truly felt as if I was in the upper balcony of that court house: even with how well known this book is -- I had no idea what was going to happen.  And I still cannot get the image of that dang ham costume out of my mind.  "Po-ork!" Bravo! A great read. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JosieGeller</user>
	<review>It's obvious why this quickly became a classic. In it's day, it faced some very serious, but real issues. The characters keep you engaged and the mystery of Boo Radley keeps you coming back until the end. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lindsacl</user>
	<review>http://laura0218.livejournal.com/1514... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AleAleta</user>
	<review>A classic! The narrative, the story, the literary devices, and the significance of a first novel make it what it is today. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>meyben</user>
	<review>One of my favorites.  Great story. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>daland</user>
	<review>A true classic.  Simply perfect. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kalobo</user>
	<review>A rich, but gentle read. I loved the purity of purpose in all the main characters. I can see why it's a classic. Nice leisurely build-up. Writer's don't often do this anymore, take time to develop the story, setting, plot and themes. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>HelloSunshine</user>
	<review>This book has such well-developed characters. The narration is done wittily and maturely, but in correlation with Scout's age. Atticus' advice is geniously relatable to real life, and the recurring themes of education, prejudice, and justice get you thinking abouut so many things that you can't believe it's only fiction. It's a good idea for younger people to read this in school, since a lot of symbolism might be missed otherwise, and that would be a shame. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hero120499</user>
	<review>http://bryansbookblog.blogspot.com/20...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>latinobookgeek</user>
	<review>I can't recall if I read this book in elementary or high school, but I do recall that I completely fell in love with the writing and the characters.  I always knew that racism was bad; my parents taught me that people were different and that all should be respected.  This story is still timely as we look at today's headlines and the prosecution of innocent people. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MerryMary</user>
	<review>A genuine classic.  Required reading in our school, and deservedly so. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jensview</user>
	<review>Has there ever been a more compassionate book than Harper Lee's To Kill a Mockingbird? I can't think of any other book that gives me such assurance that everything is going to be ok. No matter how freakish and misunderstood a person is, things will all be right in the end as long as we have love in our hearts and don't give hatred a home.I believe everyone knows the story either from the book or the movie but in case you need a refresher, Harper's story is of a little girl named Scout and how she grew out of her childhood in fictional Maycomb, Alabama in the 1930s. Scout and her brother Jem and neighbor Dill spend the first half of the book obsessed with the neighbor recluse Boo Radley. The second half of the book deals with racial prejudice of the deep south during the Great Depression.Scout Finch never knew her mother but she has a loving caregiver in Calpurnia the family maid. In the book Harper Lee provides other strong female characters in the children's lives, namely their Aunt Alexander and neighbor Miss Maudie. Combined these three women serve as substitute mothers for Jem and Scout alternating unconditional love and compassion with strong instruction and discipline. Atticus Finch is a very moral man and one of the most conscientious fathers any kid has ever had.Reading this book is like taking a day off to play hooky. The Finch children are mischievous and Harper has a knack for capturing the humor in their ways. The day it snows and the children make a "snow man" is probably my favorite chapter. Growing up in the deep south I did not see snow until I was a teen so I know just how exciting it can be to see those white flakes fall. And the one "snow man" I made in my youth looked much like the one described by Ms Lee. there was lots of grass and dirt in my snow man's torso! (If I could change one thing about the movie I would add that scene.) Another favorite chapter of mine is when Scout gets in a fight at school and ends up bringing Walter Cunningham (the boy she beat up) home for dinner.  I laugh every time I  read or watch that scene in the movie of Walter pouring syrup on his roast and mashed potatoes and Scout blurts out, "What in the sam hell or you doing?"In addition to the humor Ms Lee weaves timeless lessons for all ages in her artistic novel. In the words of Atticus Finch, "Why reasonable people go stark raving mad when anything involving a Negro comes up, is something I don't pretend to understand....The one thing that doesn't abide by majority rule is a person's conscience". To Kill a Mockingbird was published in 1960, Martin Luther King, Jr gave his "I Have a Dream" speech in 1963 and Congress passed the Civil Rights Act in 1964. Racial prejudice and Civil Rights were much talked about through the 1960s all across America. I remember "cross burnings"  by The Klan in the small town in which I grew up so I know it is true and not "made up" history. The persecution of someone for the color of their skin or any other difference (religion and/or sexual orientation included) is abhorant and should never be tolerated by a so-called "civilized" nation. If we don't continue to teach this history to our children, telling them the stories of the progress that has been made in the evolution of humankind, I fear we will repeat past mistakes (Darfur, Matthew Shepard,...).Parallel to the lesson on racial prejudice is one of tolerance. Boo Radley is rumored to be a violent monster lurking in the shadows of his darkened house, stabbing and eating raw chickens. The children dare each other to touch the house and go up on the porch. Boo is an aberration and someone to fear in the children's minds. But over the course of the novel he leaves them little gifts, precious gifts of a watch and knife and gum and he even carves their likenesses in soap and leaves it all in the hollow of the tree by the road. In the end Boo saves Jem's life. He is a loving and kind friend. "Atticus said to Jem one day, 'I'd rather you shot at the tin cans in the back yard, but I know you'll go after birds. Shoot all the bluejays you want, if you can hit 'em but remember it's a sin to kill a mockingbird.'That was the only time I ever heard Atticus say it was a sin to do something, and I asked Miss Maudie about it.'Your father's right,' she said. 'Mockingbirds don't do one thing but make music for us to enjoy. They don't eat up people's gardens, don't nest in corncribs, they don't do one thing but sing their hearts out for us. That's why it's a sin to kill a mockingbird.'" </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>carissa8402</user>
	<review>This is my ALL TIME FAVORITE!!! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Nikkles</user>
	<review>This is a fantastic book that kids everywhere should read.  Not only does it have good ethical discussions in it, but it has great characters and a good plot.  Its the type of book that makes you think and thats why everyone should read it when they are young.  The movie is good too, but one should really read the book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cestovatela</user>
	<review>A beautiful, character driven story of race relations and coming of age in the South. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>literature-geek</user>
	<review>‘The one thing that doesn’t abide by majority rule is a person’s conscience.’ These words are the imperative in Harper Lee’s ‘To Kill A Mockingbird.’ This novel is an emotive account of the battle for justice and racial egalitarianism in the early nineteen hundreds. The narrative follows one man’s exertion to forestall and eradicate unjust condemnation in a predominately white and racially prejudiced society. It would be plausible to say that this novel emanates from a solitary yet wholehearted attempt to protect the one value that becomes cracked and broken when exposed to heartless inequity – innocence.	Primarily, one may challenge why Lee would entitle her novel with what appears to be a rather trivial excerpt. However, if we look beyond the literal meaning we can uncover the true symbolism behind her virtuous unease. “Shoot all the blue jays you want, if you can hit ‘em, but remember it’s a sin to kill a mockingbird.” This interpretation carries strategic significance as it reflects the integrated importance of racism and innocence in the novel. Lee accentuates the fact that ‘white men cheat black men every day’ by incorporating the roles of Tom Robinson and Boo Radley who, doubtless, are two mockingbirds of Lee’s literary masterpiece. Fundamentally, it is essential to concede that mockingbirds only sing other bird’s songs. The evidence would readily suggest that black people do not have their own song; white people sing their songs on their behalf - based upon their own inherently prejudicial instincts. The author makes it clear that the inferior, voiceless personas of innocent characters are exemplified and twisted by the viewpoints and predisposition of the surrounding white community. For instance, when Miss Stephanie tells the children about the incident when Boo supposedly ‘drove the scissors into his parent’s leg, pulled them out, wiped them on his pants, and resumed his activities.’ After hearing inciting untruths of this kind, the children felt obligated to regard Boo Radley as a man of an evil mindset, when in reality he was the complete antithesis. In essence, this example of inventive symbolism is the needle and thread of the novel that stitches the prerequisites of morality, education and equality together.	Lee interlaces her writing with many gothic components.  Nevertheless, it is evident that the white-covered ‘nigger snowman’ employs the most illustrative influence. The snowman is a literal effigy of miscegenation. However, the snowman is reduced to ‘a thin layer of ice’ after an unforeseen fire rages through Maycomb. The most important facet when considering the symbolism of the blaze is that fire is a stronger element than snow, in the same way that discrimination overwhelms humanitarian ethics – inevitably, it prevails. The fire personifies the contemptible hate that relentlessly flickers around the outskirts of this novel. Lee’s clever use of the disintegration of snow portrays that mixed black and white cannot last. This is further intensified by the fact that societies, both black and white, were vociferously against the act of miscegenation. As a result, those who did not abide by traditional decree were alienated and marginalized from society. For example, the fear of communal exclusion led Mayella Ewell to lie in court when confronted about the incident with Tom Robinson. It is clear that miscegenation forced Mayella Ewell to kill a mockingbird. Bob Ewell could not accept that his daughter was making advances on a black man and he punished her severely for that. This could also have been the incentive for her father to beat Mayella savagely ‘almost exclusively with his left.’ Nonetheless, it is evident that Dolphus Raymond’s children who were ‘half white, half coloured’ were unmistakably divided from the general social order. Jem brands the grim circumstance as ‘sad’ for the reason that ‘they don’t belong anywhere. Coloured folks won’t have’em because they’re half white; white folks won’t have’em because they’re coloured, so they’re just in betweens, don’t belong anywhere.’ Conversely, the act of constructing the muddy snowman proves that mixed people would have a place in society if it were not as malicious and racially opinionated.		Lee approaches writing with a deliberately figurative method. The author pursues various effectual themes like ignorance versus knowledge, cowardice versus heroism, children versus adults and blacks versus whites. Conclusively, as the novel progresses and moral understanding begins to grow, conflict and prejudicial mannerisms are contradicted by the innocent philosophy of one little girl ‘I think there’s just one kind of folks. Folks.’ This evidence is substantial as it is indicative of Scouts deepening understanding of racism and condemnation. Valuable lessons are learned on the evil that blights the naïve, on the true nature of courage, and on the dangers of judging others before ‘climbing into their skin and walking around in it.’ This book is about accepting others and reaching for that level of understanding that is just within our grasp. Innocence is lost as knowledge is gained. Naivety dissolves as maturity solidifies. Men are vilified as others are credited. Adults are murdered as children are saved. A mockingbird was shot as songbirds were slaughtered – and that is truly a sin.Copyright. 2007</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Baetrice</user>
	<review>One of my all-time favorite books. It only gets better with re-reading.  This book is both powerful and subtle.  You can 'feel' the South. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MrsLee</user>
	<review>This has to be on my list of top ten books. It explores childhood and controversial events through the eyes of children, yet doesn't trivialize anything or come up with pat answers. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>karieh</user>
	<review>In my humble opinion - the greatest book ever written.  It should be required reading of every human being on this planet. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>babaluo</user>
	<review>One of the all time greats. Fantastic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ilovethebooks</user>
	<review>An absolute classic, need I say more? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>writestuff</user>
	<review>"Mockingbirds don't do one thing but make music for us to enjoy. They don't eat up people's gardens, don't nest in corncribs, they don't do one thing but sing their hearts out for us. That's why it's a sin to kill a mockingbird." - From To Kill A Mockingbird, page 103 -What can I say about To Kill A Mockingbird that hasn't already been said a million times? Harper Lee's beautiful novel set in the sleepy county of Macomb, Alabama in the 1930s defines the adage 'still waters run deep.' Scout Finch, a vibrant, curious tomboy narrates the story which spans a period of nearly three years beginning when she is six years old. The cast of characters is vast and enjoyable. From Atticus Finch (Scout's father who is a man of decency and honesty), to Jem Fitch (Scout's brother, striving to follow his father's example), to Dill (Jem and Scout's summertime companion who embodies a sense of adventure and mischief), to Tom Robinson (the black man falsely accused of rape), to Miss Maudie (Scout's next door neighbor with a heart of gold and the best cake in the country), and finally to Boo Radley (the mysterious next door neighbor who hasn't been seen in twenty-five years), Lee weaves a tale that latches onto the reader and never lets go.Lee doesn't restrict herself to merely telling a story. She includes astounding insight into the roots of racism and the idea that one man's courage to stand up against inequality may be all that's needed to begin to shatter the beliefs that sustain hatred.Perhaps what is so inviting about this novel is that its narrator is only a child. Scout Finch brings to the book an innocence and perception which only children share. Her reflections, void of the internal restraints that inhibit adults, bring a truthfulness to the novel that resonates with the reader.This is a book I will read again…and again. It is a timeless classic, beautifully written and one I highly recommend. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tanzanite</user>
	<review>http://shelfandstuff.blogspot.com/200... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>eslee</user>
	<review>Such an important, beautiful, heartbreaking work. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Greatrakes</user>
	<review>I loved this book. It's books like this that make me glad I never took English Literature at school. I ended up hating almost every book I was ever made to study at school. I'm not surprised that this is Harper Lee's only novel, it doesn't really read like a novel, more like a fictionalised autobiography. Although the novel is, famously, about deep-seated racism in the Deep South, it is really about growing up (in my untrained opinion). The characters are, in the main, decent, old fashioned, community minded and inherently racist. What makes the book fascinating is its perfect demonstration of what subtle concepts good and evil are.By using children as her protagonists, Lee is able to show how complex human relations are. To the young children, the world around them is populated by good folk and bad folk, the bad ones are fabulous creations, Boo Radley and dying Mrs Dubose. As the children grow up and, especially as the drama of the trial unfolds, truths that seemed immutable crumble away, good men form a lynch mob, monsters become frightened and reluctant heroes and the world of childhood starts to dissipate.The book is also an evocative description of time and place, I felt as though I was there. Reading this book, I realised where Donna Tartt got her inspiration for The Little Friend, another favourite read of mine, the same sense of place, a similar pace, and even the same heroine type, a young girl, believing her world to be full of monsters.Atticus Finch is often held up as the epitome of a good man and a good father, a moral rock. That he may be, but I thought he was too good to be true, too perfect, hero worship by the author. I wouldn't want a parent like Atticus, a perfect parent is too much to live up to! I'd be proud if my daughter grew up to be Scout Finch, though.A wonderful book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>whitneysetser</user>
	<review>Of course one of the most poignat novels of the last 100 years. A must read classic of importance to all who believe in justice and truth. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ashishg</user>
	<review>A poignant and nostalgic story, of childhood innocence and ideal parenthood, of silent beneficiary and subtle fight for justice, of relationships with and understanding people. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lenasouslefiguier</user>
	<review>Magique! Si en chaque homme sommeillait un peu d'Atticus Finch, le monde serait bien meilleur!C'est drôle, émouvant, on est très vite captivé par l'histoire ces deux enfants et de leur père, racontée par sa fille de six ans, confrontée à l'intolérance, au racisme, à l'étroitesse d'esprit. Vraiment très mûre, incroyablement clairvoyante, cette petite Scout Jean Louise Finch... Atmosphère Deep South.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Don1</user>
	<review>I read this book in high school in the early '60s and it changed my life.  Just excellent! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Doondeck</user>
	<review>Masterpiece. Audio Bood is wonderful. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrscastavet</user>
	<review>I surprised myself in the amount of joy I took from reading this - it is not the sort of book I would usually be drawn to reading; certainly the subject matter isn't something I would normally find compelling but it is a complete testament to the joy of Harper Lee's writing and story telling. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>momeara</user>
	<review>Fantastic book!  Simple, powerful, beautiful.  A must read.  A study of courage in the face hopeless situations.  An unflattering portrait of the deep south and how racism and discrimination is perpetuated by some and countered by others. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>anne.brewster</user>
	<review>A moving story told through a child's eyes.Court room drama with strong message which still holds true today. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AstridG</user>
	<review>raised issues of racial bigotry, fairness and family. Good depiction of small town southern life. Very enjoyable </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Harper Lee dissects racism in a small town, in general using the viewpoint of a young girl.The girl's father is a lawyer that defends a black man unjustly accused of rape of a white girl, and through this event the politics and attitudes of some of America of the time is analysed. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>briconcella</user>
	<review>Je ne comprends pas pourquoi ce livre n'est pas plus connu en France. C'est une lecture obligée pour tous les écoliers américains, puisque c'est l'histoire du racisme dans une petite ville du sud des Etats Unis dans les années 30, vu par une petite fille. Harper Lee était la grande amie de Truman Capote, et on y retrouve le meme "talent du sud". </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CrystaB</user>
	<review>I absoolutely love this book!  It is a favorite of mine that I have read over and over and never bore of!!!</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sarahmarcus</user>
	<review>This is the book I read when I'm feeling low, or when I'm sick.  I try to read it once a year or so, to restore my belief in humanity.  I would like to believe that there is a little bit of Atticus left in the world.  And, besides the great characters of Atticus and Scout, and the tremendously powerful story of Tom Robinson, and the incredible scenes and environment Lee creates, the last section always makes me cry.  The way she crafted that last section, from the third person, and recapping the entire novel is the best part of the book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tcarter</user>
	<review>Rich, enveloping, and moving.  Draws you in to this community with all its subtle dynamics and secrets.  Exposes the roots of prejudice and discrimination of all kinds.  Encourages uprightness, honour and steadfast justice in the face of popular disapproval.  A call to arms. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raven_in_the_woods</user>
	<review>Wonderful </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ablueidol</user>
	<review>Read and studied this for GCSE in the mid 1970's when I began to get myself educated in my late 20's. I enjoyed the read then and the device of seeing this through the child's viewpoint. Politically it reflected that a strand of liberal white opinion was willing to challenge racism and and support Afro-Americans in the civil right struggles. Yet never been able to read it since! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>antimuzak</user>
	<review>To Kill a Mockingbird is a coming-of-age story of Scout Finch and her brother, Jem, in 1930's Alabama. Through their locality meanderings and the example of their father, they grow to understand that the world is not always fair and that prejudice is a very real aspect of their world no matter how subtle it seems. One central theme of this book is that valuable lessons are learned in confronting those who are unlike ourselves and unlike those we know best. In the story, the children must grow up, learn civilising truths, and rise above the narrowness of the place and time in which private codes and even some legal practices contradict the idealistic principles that the community professes: "Equal rights for all, special privileges for none," as Scout says. During the course of the novel, the children pass from innocence to knowledge. They begin to realise their own connection with the community's outsiders, and they observe one man's heroism in the face of community prejudice. One overarching theme of the novel is that the mark of virtue, not to mention maturity and civilisation, involves having the insight and courage to value human differences: people unlike ourselves and people we might label as outsiders. In developing this understanding these children move from the world of childhood into a mature adolescence in which they begin to appreciate the structure of society and human relationships and to develop an understanding of human beings from the inside as motivated and feeling beings.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>petulant_seraph</user>
	<review>I remember trying to read this as a teenager and found it dull. What a tedious teenager I was. This is a beautifully told and engaging tale of prejudice </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>reb_raleigh</user>
	<review>This is my favorite book of all time! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>blocked</user>
	<review>This is easily one of my favorite books. I read it again recently just to remind myself what great writing is like. It’s such a powerful story told in as charming a way as anyone could manage. You have to love that. Even the apparently small-minded characters have a certain depth to them. And the children are polite. What a strange notion. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>amancine</user>
	<review>I love everything about this book. Harper Lee perfectly captured a precocious child's view of her world. How I envied Scout her father and Calpurnia and the neighbor lady across the street, and how carefully and lovingly they all cared for her and Jem. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JessikaCarney</user>
	<review>to me this book was a pivotal, crucial novel growing up. This book was written in an era which is completely foreign to me, yet i can still relate to the race issues within the novel as they apply to the modern world. This novel is very thought provoking and powerful, i reccomend that everyone read this novel. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>burnit99</user>
	<review>This is the one book I would take to a desert island if that were presented to me. An American classic I truly love, respect and admire.I have read it many times since high school, and am still moved to tears by many passages, especially at the end. A courageous book for the time, it tells of a southern lawyer (Atticus Finch, one of the most admirable characters in literature) who defends a black man wrongly accused of raping a white girl, and the impact it has on his children and town. It is also one of those rare fine novels to become a fine movie, one of my favorites and a worthy adaptation of a great novel. This book is a reproduction of the first edition. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>NativeRoses</user>
	<review>Very poignant tale told from a child's point of view.  Harper Lee is a master at encouraging us to see the world with the innocence of a child and from the point of view of very different segments of society -- 'crazy' outcast; working class black people; poor white angry racists; wealthy leading citizens; elderly white people; and children.  The book deals with evil as a part of life, but, as Atticus, Finch's father tells her, you cannot judge a man until you have walked in his shoes. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sallyanny</user>
	<review>One of the best books I've ever read and I have read it several times throughout my life. A true classic of American literature. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alexezell</user>
	<review>I used to teach this to my high-school freshmen every year. It never fails to open their eyes to the power that novels can have. It is a clear and present warning about our past and our future. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>herebedragons</user>
	<review>An excellent book, thought-provoking and touching. And it certainly hasn't lost its relevance, in spite of being written in and about a different social era. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gbanville</user>
	<review>Ten times better than most of the other literature they require you to read in school. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tejas</user>
	<review>Definately worth all the praise it's got. Harper tells the story of the racial injustice in the small town of Maycomb in Alabama through the eyes of the 8-year old Scout Finch. Atticus Finch standing up for what he knows is right has to defend a black man accused of raping a white girl. Scout and her brother Jem soon come to the painful realization that justice does not always follow the truth. A classic not to be missed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>miss_scarlet</user>
	<review>This classic American novel is quite interesting, containing slight elements of humor and suspense. Naturally, it is a must-read. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bsanner</user>
	<review>Simply a classic </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>snozzberry</user>
	<review>I know some people are put off by "classics", but don't be put off by this one. It sucks you in right away. You'll love it. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>moia</user>
	<review>Alltså, jag gillade inte den här boken. Det tog evigheter innan jag kom in i den och bokens höjdpunkt, rättegången, var så enkel och inte så komplicerad som jag är van vid från typ Grishams böcker. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dylanwolf</user>
	<review>Everyone's favourite classic American tale and with good reason. To Kill a Mockingbird is tightly-plotted, evenly-delivered, redolent of place and time and astonishingly accessible. It's popularity has been further maintained through the excellent 1962 film; so that a great many of us see Gregory Peck when we think of Atticus Finch. A question though - is this book most popular amongst the white middle-class because it offers absolution from guilt from those who would think of themselves as too intelligent or sophisticated to harbour racial prejudice? After all, the maligned Ewells are not the driving force that maintained a political system that subjugated the blacks. Southern white trash are only one of the "victims" in Dylan's "Only a Pawn in their Game". What is the modern black take on this novel? I would love to hear what, for instance, Toni Morrison, has to say about it. This novel is a classic because it is so simple yet raises deep, dark issues without proselytizing but, in the end, is it too cosy and gentle on its white protagonists? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cookiecat</user>
	<review>I was very disappointed in this book.  It's touted as one of the best books of all time, so I expected so much more. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Boktips.net</user>
	<review>http://www.boktips.net/index.php?p=8...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tjeffress</user>
	<review>Clearly, the Pulitzer committee thought enough of Harper Lee's book to give it top honors in 1961, but I think some of the social issues from the 1960s that pushed Mockingbird to the top of the list don't have as much relevance today.Full review: http://www.i-reports.info/b/B200635.h... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fodroy</user>
	<review>I don't remember much about this one. I had to read it as a freshman in high school, but I didn't. Then I failed a paper or test about or something. So my mom found it and forced me to read it and write a paper about it. Turns out it's pretty good. Heh. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TerrapinJetta</user>
	<review>Exceptional of course, but reading it at school put me off it somewhat because of the methods used. I hated it being read out loud so slowly when I wanted to devour it. And of course, when I went home and read it all that night and had to endure a month worth of classes of it being read out loud... Made me dislike it slightly. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>grunin</user>
	<review>The audiobook, read by Sissy Spacek, is incredible. She delineates class and character brilliantly. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>skw</user>
	<review>This was my second or third reading. What I caught that I didn't on previous readings was how the sheriff went out of his way to keep Radley out of jail but didn't even get any medical evidence regarding the accusation against Robinson.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>iammbb</user>
	<review>I first read this book when I was twelve for recreation, not school, and really enjoyed it simply as a story of a young girl and her adventures, especially favoring the relationship between the children and Boo Radley.  I first reread this book when I was fifteen, again for recreation, and was amazed to find there was a whole other, deeper story that I had missed the first time through. I have since read it more times than I can keep track of and yes, it is one of my most favorite books, if not my most favorite.  It is also a favorite of my teenage daughter who read it multiple times before first being assigned to read it in 8th grade.  If at all possible, please first become acquainted with this book before it's an assignment. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>murraymint11</user>
	<review>The only book I've given 5 stars to so far.Wonderful, wonderful book. I was immersed in it. My reading slowed down the further I got - didn't want it to finish! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>samfsmith</user>
	<review>http://forreststokes.com/wordpress/?p... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>texlexread</user>
	<review>Wow. Can't believe I've waited this long to read it. It's helped me through many workouts. I'm not done w/it yet, but loved Scout's accounts of school and reading. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>billyfantles</user>
	<review>Wikipedia:  To Kill a Mockingbird is a 1960 novel by Harper Lee, which won the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction in 1961. A coming-of-age story, it is told from the point of view of Jean Louise "Scout" Finch, the young daughter of Atticus Finch, an educated lawyer in Maycomb, Alabama, a fictional small town in the Deep South of the United States. She is accompanied by her brother Jem and their mutual friend Dill.Plot summary:Scout Finch lives with her brother, Jem, and their widowed father, Atticus, in the sleepy Alabama county of Maycomb. Maycomb is suffering through the Great Depression, but Atticus is a prominent lawyer and the Finch family is reasonably well off in comparison to the rest of society. One summer, Jem and Scout befriend a boy named Dill, who has come to live in their neighborhood for the summer, and the trio acts out stories together. Eventually, Dill becomes fascinated with the spooky house on their street called the Radley Place. The house is owned by Mr. Nathan Radley, whose brother, Arthur (nicknamed Boo), has lived there for years without venturing outside in daylight.Scout goes to school for the first time that fall and detests it. She and Jem find gifts apparently left for them in a knothole of a tree on the Radley property. Dill returns the following summer, and he, Scout, and Jem begin to act out the story of Boo Radley. Atticus puts a stop to their antics, urging the children to try to see life from another person’s perspective before making judgments. But, on Dill’s last night in Maycomb for the summer, the three sneak onto the Radley property, where Nathan Radley shoots at them. Jem loses his pants in the ensuing escape. When he returns for them, he finds them mended and hung over the fence. The next winter, Jem and Scout find more presents in the tree, presumably left by the mysterious Boo. Nathan Radley eventually plugs the knothole with cement. Shortly thereafter, a fire breaks out in another neighbor’s house, and during the fire someone slips a blanket on Scout’s shoulders as she watches the blaze. Convinced that Boo did it, Jem tells Atticus about the mended pants and the presents.To the consternation of Maycomb’s racist white community, Atticus agrees to defend a black man named Tom Robinson, who has been accused of raping Mayella Ewell. Because of Atticus’s decision, Jem and Scout are subjected to abuse from other children, even when they celebrate Christmas at the family compound on Finch’s Landing. Calpurnia, the Finches’ black cook, takes them to the local black church, where the warm and close-knit community largely embraces the children.Atticus’s sister, Alexandra, comes to live with the Finches the next summer. Dill, who is supposed to live with his “new father” in another town, runs away and comes to Maycomb. Tom Robinson’s trial begins, and when the accused man is placed in the local jail, a mob gathers to lynch him. Atticus faces the mob down the night before the trial. Jem and Scout, who sneaked out of the house, soon join him. Scout recognizes one of the men, and her polite questioning about his son shames him into dispersing the mob.At the trial itself, the children sit in the “colored balcony” with the town’s black citizens. Atticus provides clear evidence that the accusers, Mayella Ewell and her father, Bob, are lying: in fact, Mayella propositioned Tom Robinson, was caught by her father, and then accused Tom of rape to cover her shame and guilt. Atticus provides impressive evidence that the marks on Mayella’s face are from wounds that her father inflicted; upon discovering her with Tom, he called her a whore and beat her. Yet, despite the significant evidence pointing to Tom’s innocence, the all-white jury convicts him. The innocent Tom later tries to escape from prison and is shot to death. In the aftermath of the trial, Jem’s faith in justice is badly shaken, and he lapses into despondency and doubt.Despite the verdict, Bob Ewell feels that Atticus and the judge have made a fool out of him, and he vows revenge. He menaces Tom Robinson’s widow, tries to break into the judge’s house, and finally attacks Jem and Scout as they walk home from a halloween pageant at their school. Boo Radley intervenes, however, saving the children. Atticus at first believes that Jem fatally stabbed Mr. Ewell in the struggle. Boo carries the wounded Jem back to Atticus’s house, where the sheriff, in order to protect Boo (who probably did stab Mr. Ewell), insists that Ewell tripped over a tree root and fell on his own knife. After sitting with Scout for a while, Boo is walked to his home by Scout. While standing on the Radley porch Scout feels sorry for Boo because she and Jem never gave him a chance, and never repaid him for the gifts that he gave them.Later, Scout feels as though she can finally imagine what life is like for Boo. He has become a human being to her at last. With this realization, Scout embraces her father’s advice to practice sympathy and understanding and demonstrates that her experiences with hatred and prejudice will not sully her faith in human goodness.This review has been flagged by multiple users as abuse of the terms of service
						 and is no longer displayed (show).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pulchritudinous</user>
	<review>the narrater, a young girl, reminded me of myself...wierd.  But also a really great book </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>HeatherLee</user>
	<review>To Kill A Mockingbird is the great American novel. Its characters are solid and believable, moving fluidly through a finely honed tale of love and sorrow. I remember the first time I read "To Kill A Mockingbird". Flying through it in order to get my English paper done, I missed a lot. One summer later I found myself reading it again out of boredom. That boredom didn't last. In the years since I have reread the story three or four times; once even staying up all night. The power of the story lies in the words for me. The simple descriptions of complicated actions from the perspective of a small girl have incredible power. The final line of the novel regarding the fact that Atticus would be there when Jem "waked in the morning" exemplifies this by simply showing the love this man has for his son with out relying on overt emotionalism. In its' simplicity it avoids sensationalism and therefore comes across stronger and clearer. Yet in my rereading, I have always found a new level of understanding for the words and actions, growing to love the novel more each time. To Kill A Mockingbird is a sensational book to read for yourself and pass to others. Atticus Finch is a wonderful role model for all ages. He stands up for what he believes in without giving into pressures placed upon him during the story. Jean-louise Finch, also known as Scout to most people who know her, is a wonderful role model for all young and old children. She is placed in situations that many of us at one point are. She learned many lessons through out the book along with Dill Harris and her Brother Jeremy Atticus Finch. The children had their own goals set for themselves. They were "after" Arthur "Boo" Radly, and the story behind him. Harper Lee's love for people swells from the pages of this book. Her characters are exquisitely drawn, their story is believable and thrilling. Read this book and see the movie! It's too bad she went into seclusion after she wrote this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tygerlilli</user>
	<review>My all time favorite book. Ever."Atticus was right. One time he said you never really know a man until you stand in his shoes and walk around in them. Just standing on the Radley porch was enough."</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Alhana</user>
	<review>This is absoulutely my favourite book! And I discovered it (well, really discovered it, as in actually read it) just this year. It's got one of the best ensamble of literature characters out there. I can't get Scout, Jem, Atticus, and Boo out of my mind. I just love them so much.Five stars without a question. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FieryNight</user>
	<review>A homey little classic with it's own suspense, made a classic for it's moral. I liked it immensely.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mitchco</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books, certainly, but for much more than Lee's discussion of race in the American south, which at times tends toward the overly-simplified. What I find more personally resonant is the subtext dealing with identity and sexuality: Scout and Dill's attempts at hetero-normative play, which nearly always fail or are subverted by their defiant gender performances; Uncle Jack's subtle and unsubtle flamboyances; and most of all Miss Maudie’s role of gently guiding and protecting Scout through the treacherous and delicate task of carving out her own space for gender divergence.The only happy and enduring heterosexual couple in the book is arguably Tom and Helen Robinson (the oversimplification of race rearing its head again, perhaps), and even that ends badly. The Finches are an admirable early example of an alternative family situation, with Atticus and Calpurnia (aided by Miss Maudie) nurturing Jem, Scout, and Dill with now legendary warmth and dignity (later joined by Aunt Alexandria, who interrupts by reinforcing contemporaneous notions of “proper” race relations and gender behavior).I absolutely love Lee for so tenderly and sensitively addressing this facet of identity. Ultimately, though, I think the relative fluidity of gender that she presents serves to underscore the ugly centrality of race in the lives of early 20th American southerners: the characters may largely be able to work around gender constrictions, but the violation of racial barriers is life-or-death. It’s Lee’s more three-dimensional approach in addressing Scout’s developing awareness of her identity (and specifically how it operates in the American South) that really makes this a hallmark of American literature for me.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mmh166</user>
	<review>This book is a true American classic.  I enjoyed every element of this book.  It's as good on its fifth read as it is on its first.  Highly recommended. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stargirl</user>
	<review>English GCSE. I've been scarred for life by a simply awful Atticus impression. Otherwise enjoyable! </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Thalia</user>
	<review>This was the only American piece of literature we had to read in English class. It was too hard for me to read at the time so I also bought the German translation and misplaced the English version.Anyway, I haven't read a lot of books about racism in the USA, but of the ones I read this is without a doubt the best one. It grips you and doesn't let you go until you've finished the last page. It should be recommended reading for everybody. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DanDanRevolution</user>
	<review>Who doesn't love a precocious protagonist whose social observations are both endearingly ingenuous and poignant? Lee's writing is fully captivating, occasionally hysterical, and always charming. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bohemianphilosophy</user>
	<review>Read it  love it. I can see why it's a best-seller.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>overthemoon</user>
	<review>a book that gets even better every time I read it </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>laydiefa</user>
	<review>One word, masterpiece! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MissLizzy</user>
	<review>The movie that is based on this book is my mother's favorite, but I didn't actually read the novel until I was forced to, sophomore year of high school. I believe I was one of the few in my class who liked it. Atticus Finch is such a good man and father, the leader of the few kind, honest, and prejudice-free people in Maycomb. Many people have criticized Lee's narration syle, saying that as a six year-old, Scout simply would not have been as adult-sounding--but I have found that children are usually more observant, less prejudiced, and generally much less jaded than the adults around them. This is one of my favorite books. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rubberbandeffect</user>
	<review>This is one of the best books I've ever read.  I had a discussion with someone over if the story truly belongs to Scout or Atticus.  I'm still undecided, but love the perspective of both characters. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lilithcat</user>
	<review>A young girl's narrative of growing up in a small Alabama town during the depression, with her brother and widowed father, a lawyer who is appointed to represent a black man falsely accused of raping a white woman. It's about love and hate, loneliness and friendship, family and community. Facing facts for the first time, finding that truth is not always what you think.This is a book I read over and over again. Atticus Finch is my hero. (Loved the movie, too, but there is so much more to the book.)</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kimbee</user>
	<review>I found this book to drag on. I don't see why it's so popular. I twasn't a bad read but I just couldn't get into it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kattepusen</user>
	<review>***1/2I would recommend this book mostly for its sumptious descriptions of the American South in the 1930s. Through Scout's tomboy eyes, we get a glimpse of societal customs, children's games, weather superstitions and a privileged's child's race observations all emulsified in the tastes and smells of the Deep South. The rich descriptions of the world around the narrator is in my view the novel's main strenght. That said, I must admit I was quite surprised at how one-dimensional and predictable the main characters were, and the main race issue is largely a mixture of the tiresome "Uncle Tom" phenomenon and white liberal smugness. I was quite dismayed that the black folks were portrayed as little more than good-natured simpletons with just the right amount of "colored wisdom", while the enlightened white minority (who, if you are a white reader, you are to identify yourself with) are the good and noble characters in an evil and prejudiced world. Furthermore, for good measure, the rednecks are given all the convenient charcteristics of being the truly evil representation of the white race, closely followed by the stereotypical white gossiping Ladies who "sip their tea and eat their dainties" and busy themselves with charity work while reiterating every cliched racial hypocracy imaginable. In my view, if Harper Lee had dared to infuse her characters with more realistic humanity and depth beyond Good and Evil, this would have been a more compelling and honest story about race relations. As the story stands, the white reader gets his white guilt assuaged by being able to identify himself with the saint, while the black reader gets little more than the charitable handout to feel good about himself simply because he belongs to a repressed group of good people. I am not quite sure which race should feel more insulted... That said, I still enjoyed other parts of the book. The children's fascination and impatient curiosity with the mysterious neighbor is delightful reading (even though this very person predictably ends up a hero). The narrator's notions of first love also feels genuine and compelling as does the close realtionship between the narrator and her older protective brother. All in all, I would recommended the book as a look into the adolescent culture of the rural South; however, I would stick to the history books when it comes to learning about the true nature of the extreme racism that polluted the area during this time period. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Summersoldier</user>
	<review>My memory is foggy on this book because I read it in  7th grade. I do remember though, how entranced I was by it and how many times I read it (now reachind 7 or 8). A classic. Need I say more? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>angelovesposito</user>
	<review>Read in 2005 as part of the "Read Jacksonville" campaign. Definetly a must read but only a good book in my opinion. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>llm822</user>
	<review>This is, without a doubt, my favorite book of all time.  'Nuff said. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>drinkingtea</user>
	<review>A classmate who had been an exchange student and had returned to her home country where I was an exchange student had an accent that rendered this book as 'The Killer Mockingbird,' which is how I will forever think of this book.This book has been analyzed to death.  Unless you've lived under a rock for the past few decades, you already know the criticisms of this book and the praises.  It's still a good read, even if you don't give a hoot about deeper meanings or the lack thereof. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chelleching</user>
	<review>A very very good read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>coricouture</user>
	<review>Okay, it only took me 'til I was 40 to finally read this modern masterpiece, but better late than never! What fantastic, tight, beautiful, evocative writing. Just gorgeous. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Xaris</user>
	<review>My favorite American novel.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JoyE</user>
	<review>I love books that make me cry. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jbrush</user>
	<review>http://coyotemercury.com/blog1/2006/0... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>John</user>
	<review>To Kill A Mockingbird is, of course, one of the classics of American literature.  I may have read it in school at some point, though I don't remember, so I thought I would read it now.  It is a story that fits like a glove, it feels comfortable perhaps the result of the movie images of Gregory Peck running through the mind when reading.  Nevertheless, this is strong, sensitive story about coming-of-age in a poor southern town in the 1930s where relations between the whites and the blacks and everyone's rank in society is firmly fixed with every nuance known and tracked by everyone else.  It is the story of a strong father raising two children with an openness and honesty that would be refreshing in any setting and any time, but is astounding in the town of Maycomb which seems, in its structures and prejudices, to be frozen in amber.  The story is moving and funny.  The characters, aside from the narrator, Scout, her brother, Jem, and Atticus, are pretty much figures that fulfill their roles in the story, but they are drawn well.  Lee eschews a happy ending for Tom Robinson, the falsely accused black man, and the injustice of his conviction is compounded by his death during an escape attempt, but it is good that she does so, because life can be unfair, even unto death.  The lessons absorbed by Scout and Jem are many, through their father and through his actions, and one cannot but believe that they will grow up to be honest and unprejudiced people sensitive even to the nuances of prejudice that can so often masquerade as "that's just the way things are".  (Mar/06)</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gfriedman</user>
	<review>Amazon: Set in the small Southern town of Maycomb, Alabama, during the Depression, To Kill a Mockingbird follows three years in the life of 8-year-old Scout Finch, her brother, Jem, and their father, Atticus--three years punctuated by the arrest and eventual trial of a young black man accused of raping a white woman. Though her story explores big themes, Harper Lee chooses to tell it through the eyes of a child. The result is a tough and tender novel of race, class, justice, and the pain of growing up. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Sykil</user>
	<review>The English department planned for us to read this in eighth grade; however, our teacher decided not to follow that plan. I'm not sure how I feel about that. On one hand, I'm not sure I could appreciate the story at that age, but on the other hand, it's the best book I've ever read. My absolute favorite.I remember when my dad used to play chess with me when I was younger. It reminds me so much of Atticus, but that didn't last long, as he soon became encumbered with his work.I think the story's simplicity makes it appeal to everyone, and it's complexity makes it a classic. It's simple because there's no obscure, pretentious prose (as with,say, The Scarlet Letter), but it's still complex because of the allegorical nature of the characters, though I suppose they're very simple allegories in the broad spectrum of things.Overall, I think this is Literature at it's best, and it's as good as American literature gets---possibly as good as literature itself gets. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sehatter</user>
	<review>I read this book once back in sophomore year of high school.  It's stuck with me ever since. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jimodo</user>
	<review>I don't know how many times I've read this, but I do know I went through two different paperback copies before I bit the bullet and bought a hardback.  Easily the best book I've ever read, and read, and read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heidilove</user>
	<review>I read this in the fourth grade. I liked it then, and have liked it since. I should have known then that I was going to be a little odd. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>antimuzak</user>
	<review>"When he was nearly thirteen, my brother Jem got his arm badly broken at the elbow.... When enough years had gone by to enable us to look back on them, we sometimes discussed the events leading to his accident. I maintain that the Ewells started it all, but Jem, who was four years my senior, said it started long before that. He said it began the summer Dill came to us, when Dill first gave us the idea of making Boo Radley come out."Set in the small Southern town of Maycomb, Alabama, during the Depression, To Kill a Mockingbird follows three years in the life of 8-year-old Scout Finch, her brother, Jem, and their father, Atticus--three years punctuated by the arrest and eventual trial of a young black man accused of raping a white woman. Though her story explores big themes, Harper Lee chooses to tell it through the eyes of a child. The result is a tough and tender novel of race, class, justice, and the pain of growing up. Like the slow-moving occupants of her fictional town, Lee takes her time getting to the heart of her tale; we first meet the Finches the summer before Scout's first year at school. She, her brother, and Dill Harris, a boy who spends the summers with his aunt in Maycomb, while away the hours reenacting scenes from Dracula and plotting ways to get a peek at the town bogeyman, Boo Radley. At first the circumstances surrounding the alleged rape of Mayella Ewell, the daughter of a drunk and violent white farmer, barely penetrate the children's consciousness. Then Atticus is called on to defend the accused, Tom Robinson, and soon Scout and Jem find themselves caught up in events beyond their understanding. During the trial, the town exhibits its ugly side, but Lee offers plenty of counterbalance as well--in the struggle of an elderly woman to overcome her morphine habit before she dies; in the heroism of Atticus Finch, standing up for what he knows is right; and finally in Scout's hard-won understanding that most people are essentially kind "when you really see them." By turns funny, wise, and heartbreaking, To Kill a Mockingbird is one classic that continues to speak to new generations, and deserves to be reread often.Lee's Pulitzer Prize-winning first (and last) novel of racial injustice in a small Southern town ranks highly.Courage and cowardice in a 1930s Alabama town. The title, Harper Lee's To Kill a Mockingbird, part of Chelsea House Publishers' Modern Critical Interpretations series, presents the most important 20th-century criticism on Harper Lee's To Kill a Mockingbird through extracts of critical essays by well-known literary critics. This collection of criticism also features a short biography on Harper Lee, a chronology of the author's life, and an introductory essay written by Harold Bloom, Sterling Professor of the Humanities, Yale University.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rmckeown</user>
	<review>One of my all-time favorites.  Scout is one of my favorite characters of all time.  This book reminded me of my own childhood, growing up in a small town in the South.  Recently reread and rewatched the film.  It's a classic!  --RJM 10/10/05</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>flexnib</user>
	<review>One of my all-time favourites. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060935464</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>katesp</user>
	<review>A most memorable novel. The irony lies in the gap between Scout's view of the world and that of the adults around her. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>