<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jhowell</user>
	<review>This is a rare re-read for me.  In my 20's I felt as if this was the best book I had ever read and I still list it as one of my favorites . . . but can you continue to say that if you never re-read books?  So, after at least ~ 15 years I have given it another go.  Now, I am sad.  Do I leave it rated as a 5 star masterpiece with the magical eyes of nostalgia or do I rate it with my somewhat cynical and jaded current eyes of realism?So, unfortunately this time through I felt as if this odyssey of the cursed Buendia family bordered on the nonsensical.  I failed to grasp the 'realism' in this, this bible of magical realism.  There are somethings that are haunting - the yellow butterflies, the Sanskrit parchments, the little golden fishes, the cloc-cloc of the bones.  And I did appreciate some of the allegory, or the themes of history reapeating itself; the sins of the fathers; the power of nostalgia.I cannot deny the spell and influence this book had on me when I was young and the world was wide open to me.  It does have merit and beauty and inspires an almost - I don't know - a morbid fascination in the reader.  But for the life of me, I could not fully enjoy it this time.  The characters just behaved in inexplicable, outlandish, unpredicatable ways -- can you really tell a cogent story when there are no rules?Overall, this leaves me fearful to re-read some other of my favorites from the past.  Disillusioned, I will leave it with my updated 3 1/2 star recommendation.  I am not sure if it is the fault of Marquez or my withered heart and imagination.  Perhaps I'll go hole myself up in a dark room with my books and not speak or wash for the rest of my life . . . </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>philosojerk</user>
	<review>What a fantastic read.  Gabriel Garcia Marquez's sweeping tale of the rise and fall of the Buendia family was completely different from anything I've read before.  The use of magical realism, rather than turning me off as it often has done in the past, complemented perfectly the stunning characters that Marquez painted.  I can't wait to read more of his stuff.  Highly recommended, even if this is outside of your usual comfort zone/genre. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cyss</user>
	<review>I have started this book three times and cannot get past page 55.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nicholassunley</user>
	<review>Fantastic, dreamy prose. Marquez at his best. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>umkaaaa</user>
	<review>A crazy wonderful story set in a crazy wonderful world by a crazy wonderful author. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jacki</user>
	<review>One of the best ever </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>coolpinkone</user>
	<review>Bring your imagination and your senses when you check into read this sensual, tingly book.   It is really the most difficult to explain book.  It is like reading in a foggy dream like state. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TiffGabler</user>
	<review>No one DESCRIBES like Marquez.  If you like RICH text, Marquez is the guy for you. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lacaraba</user>
	<review>Extraordinaria, su lectura despierta el interés por los libros y te introduce, si ya no lo estabas, en el maravilloso mundo de la literatura. García Márquez inaugura el estilo denominado "Realismo Mágico" en el que el tiempo y el espacio son circulares. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ninecopetti</user>
	<review>Uma responsabilidade muito grande ler um livro como esse, com prêmios tão importantes da Literatura. Comprei por indicação de amigos, li compulsivamente, até acabar, porque a cada linha, a vontade é de que chegue logo o fim, para saber o desfecho de toda confusão que se lê - confusão muito bem armada, tramada, diga-se de passagem, por Garcia Marquez. Vale cada centavo investido, e é um livro para ser guardado para se ler novamente no futuro. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sinistersister</user>
	<review>This book really pissed me off.  After hearing such great things about it from EVERYONE, and being a huge magical realism fan, I sat down eager to enjoy this.  Stone me if you must, but I found it unbearable.  The only reason I finished it was because I was reading it for a class.  I know everyone says the repetitive nature of the male characters is what makes it so genius, but after two generations of Joses and Aurelianos, I was over it.  The only character I cared at all about was Ursula, but she wasn't enough to save this book.  Not for me, anyway.  I'll stick with Isabella Allende for my Latin American magical realism. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>yoursources</user>
	<review>'[The author]’s hypnotic history of his Buendias family, founders of Macondo, a remote South American settlement, is a charged chronicle of fantasy and realism…Farce and laughter vien his world…[the author] is a poet nearly, a seer, an alchemist…A tour de force, enchanting, convoluted and barbarous’ – The Times Educational Supplement'Reality and fantasy are indistinguishable: a Spanish galleon beached in the jungle, a flying carpet, a cloud of yellow flowers, an iguana in a woman’s womb, are more real than guerrilla coups, banana company massacres, and the coming of the steam-engine…As an experience it is enormously, kaleidoscopically, mysteriously alive’ – Guardian'You emerge from this marvelous novel as if from a dream, the mind on fire: with a single bound [the author] leaps on to the stage with Gunter Grass and Vladimir Nabokov, his appetites as enormous as his imagination, his fatalism greater than either.  Dazzling’ – The New York Times'One of a glittering constellation of contemporary Latin American novelists…He is the author of a classic on the grandest scale…the most obvious comparison is with Homer’s Odyssey…[The author] is a spellbinder’ - SpectatorThis review has been flagged by multiple users as abuse of the terms of service
						 and is no longer displayed (show).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>humeyra</user>
	<review>Okudum begendim</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>miriamparker</user>
	<review>What can you say about pure genius? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Centrismo</user>
	<review>La historia de la estirpe Buendía y su ciudad Macondo a traves de los anos</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rventura</user>
	<review>Back when I was in college and somewhat more impressionable, I picked up this book in the used bookstore for something like $1.25. I got it mostly for the cover, I think, and the title, which back then sounded profound.  I remember debating whether to get this one or Autumn of the Patriarch, which was next to it on the shelf and had a more Dali-esque surrealistic type cover with an old man and a cow in a palace in the cover.  Looking back now, and knowing my taste in art, I'm kinda surprised that i picked this one.  But i did.Like thousands of others, this book changed my life.  It's hard to say exactly how.  But I think that it was then that i began to realize that every sentence could contain a story and glory of its own and that density in a narrative tapestry could make you drunk.  Of course, I have no idea what that last sentence that I wrote means, but this is sort of the point too.  To let the book and story flow and push through so quickly and richly that you can't count every single molecule of water and air that surrounds you made me realize that life too is pretty magical and scary and sometimes has very tiny type.I read this once on the trip back to Ithaca from NYC and because I was still a fairly decent looking person back then, this grad student with plastic rimmed glasses sat next to me (as opposed to all the other creepier looking people on the bus).  We didn't talk much, but halfway through he turned to me and said, "Are you enjoying that Marquez book?"  Of course I was.  He had read it a while ago, he said.  We said nothing afterwards and i never saw him again.  But I liked the fact that the book could somehow connect with that strange guy who I would otherwise have nothing to do with.  I remember giving this book as a birthday present to my housemate a couple of years after that, who i didn't really like.  I told her it changed my life.  I don't think she understood it (the book), but still, it was once again an attempt to connect to someone I never could have, would have, through this book.  I really have no idea if she even finished the book.  But on my next birthday, she got me a Kurt Vonnegut book, which I did enjoy.  (God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater).  So, in some ways, i suppose it did it's job.  It made me almost forgive her for being such a crab and going into my room once to look for condoms she could use when she and her boyfriend (or whatever he was) didn't have any.I love magic-realism.  I try to find it everywhere I look now.  In many ways, it is more real than life itself.  Read this book and connect with me in a weird, obscure, unconnective way. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>liveanne</user>
	<review>lecture de jeunesse écriturequi comme le jeunesse est excessive débordante enthousisamante, j'avais adoré </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jonathon.hodge</user>
	<review>Awesome!  "Death rolled through her, like a river of ashes."  And that's in translation, no less. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Nichi</user>
	<review>One of my favourite books ever. This is a story spanning decades and featuring people who all have the same name (well.... many of them), but it still kept me on the edge of my seat. It incorporates mystic elements with geographical descriptions and historical facts (and fiction) to a picture that is staggering. A must read (in my book). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thejohnsmith</user>
	<review>One of my all time favourite reads. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RicDay</user>
	<review>Wonderful, classic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Wattsian</user>
	<review>In my adulthood, only two books have been as magical spells, taking me into a strange irrational world that is more real than my own. Mervyn Peake's "Gormenghast" is the first. This is the second. One gets the sense that there is more truth in powerful, unreal relief of sadness and joy in these two works than is in our life. That they reach toward a Platonic ideal of reality that is NOT Heaven and is NOT Hell, yet exists above them, like our own world, a mixture of good and bad, pain and pleasure, and that makes some sense. But not quite so much sense. We yearn for life to have meaning. Perhaps life is planned in a way, but not FOR something. It is planned because it is. It happens because it does. There is RHYME and REASON to it, but not often the rhyme and reason that speaks to us and curbs our hunger and clears our head. Just a rhyme and a reason. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>onebluesynapse</user>
	<review>Perhaps the best book I've ever read... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hansel714</user>
	<review>http://hansel25.livejournal.com/27398... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>macorig</user>
	<review>Lo lessi al secondo tentativo tutto di un fiato in una settimana, praticamente non facevo altro, un libro che sa rapirti, con le sue storie surreali ma cosi "vive". Da avere e da leggere tutto in una volta altrimenti con tutti quei personaggi si rischia di perdere il filo! :-) </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>julianapwk</user>
	<review>ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF SOLITUDE by Gabriel Garcia Marquez is an amazing and wonderful book. It displays magical realism at its best and weaves through the lives of the Buendia family and the town of Macondo which they have founded.One single sentence can give you the shivers and the wording and phrasing of this book is amazing! So deep and profound with such intense language then you end up loving and obsessing this book and lamenting that you can't write like Marquez.I would recommend this book to anyone who likes magical realism, Latin American literature, reading classics, or just being inspired and touched in a raw and unusual way. It's one of those books that you could read over and over again for the rest of your life and you would still be discovering something new and different each and every time.SUMMARY:Probably Garcia Marquez's finest and most famous work, ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF SOLITUDE tells the story of the rise and fall, birth and death of the mythical town of Macondo through the history of the Buendia family. Inventive, amusing, magnetic, sad, alive with unforgettable men adn women, and with a truth and understanding that strike the soul. ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF SOLITUDE is a masterpiece of the art of fiction.RANDOM INFORMATION:Marquez won the Nobel Price for this, so I would also recommend you read his acceptance speech which you can find on the internet (but DO NOT read it until AFTER having read the book)(Written April 11, 2003 on Amazon.com) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>julianapwk</user>
	<review>ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF SOLITUDE by Gabriel Garcia Marquez is an amazing and wonderful book. It displays magical realism at its best and weaves through the lives of the Buendia family and the town of Macondo which they have founded.One single sentence can give you the shivers and the wording and phrasing of this book is amazing! So deep and profound with such intense language then you end up loving and obsessing this book and lamenting that you can't write like Marquez.I would recommend this book to anyone who likes magical realism, Latin American literature, reading classics, or just being inspired and touched in a raw and unusual way. It's one of those books that you could read over and over again for the rest of your life and you would still be discovering something new and different each and every time.SUMMARY:Probably Garcia Marquez's finest and most famous work, ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF SOLITUDE tells the story of the rise and fall, birth and death of the mythical town of Macondo through the history of the Buendia family. Inventive, amusing, magnetic, sad, alive with unforgettable men adn women, and with a truth and understanding that strike the soul. ONE HUNDRED YEARS OF SOLITUDE is a masterpiece of the art of fiction.RANDOM INFORMATION:Marquez won the Nobel Price for this, so I would also recommend you read his acceptance speech which you can find on the internet (but DO NOT read it until AFTER having read the book)(Written April 11, 2003 on Amazon.com) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>missporkchop</user>
	<review>I've read other reviews of this book and it seems that people either love it or hate it. I'm in the love camp. The writing is beautiful. Sure, the people and events aren't always realistic, but sometimes you need to loosen up on reality to get the bigger picture, and this book does that. My one beef is that all the characters (and there are lots) have the same or similar names and it's next to impossible to remember who you're reading about at specific periods. My copy included a family tree in the front that I made frequent use of, but even it wasn't detailed enough. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>leandrop</user>
	<review>Cien Años de Soledad es un trabajo perfecto. Gabriel escribió un libro que habla del hombre en sí; con sus fortunas y desaciertos; sus alegrías y tristezas; sus corduras y sus locuras. Una obra maestra escrita con una narrativa simple, como si estuviera siendo contado por una abuela, pero lleno de pasajes increíblemente geniales. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>arukiyomi</user>
	<review>Pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants, pants…To read the rest of the review, head over to Arukiyomi... </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>meguiguerchu</user>
	<review>not that good in my opinion.. a bit boring from the middle </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Vorobyey</user>
	<review>In places I found the English translation a bit "clunky". </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siriaeve</user>
	<review>I loved this book: García Marquez is very like Faulkner in his subject matter, yet he manages not to drive me crazy. His wonderful writing style is aided by a very smooth translation, and the story he tells is fantastic in the original sense of the word. It's an elliptical, oblique foundation myth for all of Latin America, while at the same time being an engrossing, confusing, absorbing tale of a family over the course of a century. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jimmytomatoes</user>
	<review>For my taste it was very long and slow at times.  However I was pleased with the ending </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>soylentgreen23</user>
	<review>Wow. What a book! I can hardly believe that a single volume of words printed on paper could be this powerful, and yet, here I am, weeks after having turned the last page, and I am still lost in thought because of it. Wow. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rferrer</user>
	<review>Es maravilloso, la primera línea que lees se te queda enganchada en el alma para siempre. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>read_lola_read</user>
	<review>Fantastic ending.  An enchanting story that is definitely not a 'light' read.  If you can make it to the end it is so worthwhile.  Marquez is indeed an amazing storyteller. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sarah_rubyred</user>
	<review>I love real people, especially when they are slightly magical like this. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>frizero</user>
	<review>Garcia Márquez é um mestre da ficção latinoamericana, autor de livros memoráveis e histórias que, em alguns anos, poderão facilmente confundir-se com uma mitologia do continente.  Mas bastaria para o autor ter escrito este "Cem Anos de Solidão" para entrar no rol dos grandes escritores mundiais.  Uma narrativa envolvente que leva o leitor por gerações e gerações dos Buendía sem dar a ele chance alguma de largar o livro... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Replay</user>
	<review>I got it from the first pages of the book. No need to go any further along this boring and tortuous way. I didn't like it. I didn't like his writing and the name thing is utterly annoying. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TakeItOrLeaveIt</user>
	<review>didn't dig it as much as everyone else did. the name thing bothered me. i see his point but I don't like his writing style and didn't relate with this book. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>silversurfer</user>
	<review>One of the greatest pieces of works ever writen...One of my all time favoirte books. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Schmerguls</user>
	<review>2028 One Hundred Years of Solitude, by Gabriel Garcia Marquez  translated from the Spanish by Gregory Rabassa  (read 6 Nov 1986) Since the author won the Nobel Prize in 1982 I thought I should read something by him.  This was an awfully boring book--all about stupid impossible people in a Latin American town in a country never identified.  It was so stupid--all about the Buendia family.  I hated the whole book. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Papiniano</user>
	<review>Cien años de soledad es una de las principales novelas de la literatura en lengua española y uno de los mejores exponentes del realismo mágico. García Márquez narra la historia de varias generaciones de la familia Buendía, desde la fundación de Macondo, el pueblo en el que viven. Fundamentalmente, es destacable el estilo, muy peculiar, del autor, lo novedoso del relato y la incorporación de elementos mágicos o irreales al relato con toda naturalidad. Asimismo, el tono del narrador está muy bien escogido: el narrador cuenta la historia como si la hubiera vivido en primera persona, como quien narra un cuento, deteniéndose en los aspectos más importantes o que a él le merecen mayor atención.Por último, no puede dejar de mencionarse el gran dominio de García Márquez demuestra de la lengua española, sobre todo de su léxico. La novela merece la fama que tiene y además es muy entretenida y divertida. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gwendydd</user>
	<review>I should reread this in a class or something, because I felt like i just wasn't getting something.  None of the characters were likeable, and although the writing is lovely, I just didn't enjoy the book. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Fluffyblue</user>
	<review>I found this book hard to read at times, easy at others.  It seemed like there was a lot in it - there was little by way of paragraphs and natural breaks in terms of reading a few pages and then stopping - some of it was endless!  For a story about one family, over a period of one hundred years (or more - some of the characters proclaimed they were well over a hundred!) in one town in South America it was, I suppose, interesting.  If you think about it that way, the book did very well to keep me reading it, although at times I felt like giving up.The story was light hearted, I would not say comedic, it was more tragic than that.  I didn't see the magic other than the obvious levitational experiences etc, but on the whole I did enjoy it.One thing I did find very hard was determining who the book was talking about.  A lot of the characters shared the same name over the generations - some from the same generation too.  I found I was often referring to the family chart at the beginning of the book, and having to re-read parts to find out who was doing what.On the whole though, it was a good read. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sweetos</user>
	<review>Brilliantly written. Amazing characters. Funny. Depressing. This book haunts me till this day. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>revolutionary_marcia</user>
	<review>Uno de esos grandes imprescindibles, enormes obras maestras más allá de las épocas y los contextos espaciales. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Lu87</user>
	<review>Un'atmosfera magica, emozionante; e sotto la supeficie della favola, tante verità su cui riflettere.Che dire? Tutto quello che cercavo in un libro, qui l'ho trovato. Da leggere e rileggere. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KRAAL</user>
	<review>Hay libros que merecen leerse. Hay libros que merecen una relectura. Sin ninguna duda Cien años de Soledad es un gran libro. Imprescindible. Necesario leerlo y disfrutarlo en castellano. Es vasto, mágico, embaucador... el autor te va dirigiendo en continuas maniobras. Esta edición me parece impresionante, por las notas a pie de página que dan la información necesaria y precisa. Ralentice la lectura para no acabar el libro... deseoso que fuera como el libro de arena de Borges. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>passionforthepage</user>
	<review>Not my cup of tea. Synopsis: One Hundred Years of Solitude tells the story of the rise and fall, birth and death of the mythical town of Macondo through the one hundred year history of the Buendía family.Random Thoughts: In turns confusing and brilliant, I don’t think I’ve ever read a more odd but engaging book. I didn’t hate One Hundred Years of Solitude and I’m not sorry I read it, but I’m also glad that it’s over. I doubt I’ll do it again. I know a lot of people love Marquez’s writing in general and One Hundred Years of Solitude in particular, but this is not destined to become one of my favorite books. I prefer books with more plot and less meandering. In fact, the meandering sort of drove me crazy and by the time I got close to the end of the book, I was desperately counting how many pages I still had left to read. Full review: http://passionforthepage.blogspot.com... </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Budz888</user>
	<review>Nobel Prize Colombia Magical</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>curbyourentropy</user>
	<review>Magic realism does have its weak points. For example, I didn't really care about the characters in a meaningful way--they seemed empty, unaware, like pawns in Garcia's genre. I found myself only caring about them inasmuch as they provided me with a sense of familiarity with the story. I grieved for the passing of the characters from generation to generation, but only because I missed the connection I did have with those characters and their lives, and I didn't want that familiarity to disappear. That being said, I guess that's the genius of the novel. It takes you from one generation to another, creating and destroying and recreating your sense of comfort and familiarity and connectedness with each generation... Taking you in and out of the solitude that the story itself is about. Or something. I don't know. It really is an enjoyable read, though, and very well written. And the ending is fantastic. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TunstallSummerReads</user>
	<review>One Hundred Years of Solitude tells the story of the rise and fall, birth and death of themythical town of Macondo through the history of the Buendía family. Inventive, amusing,magnetic, sad, and alive with unforgettable men and women -- brimming with truth,compassion, and a lyrical magic that strikes the soul -- this novel is a masterpiece in the art offiction. --from Amazon.comThis review has been flagged by multiple users as abuse of the terms of service
						 and is no longer displayed (show).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>crsiaac</user>
	<review>Fascinante. Un universo. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lisisky</user>
	<review>En un pueblo llamado Macondo, el cuál fue fundado por José Arcadio Buendía debido a que éste se marchó de Riohacha junto a su esposa, Úrsula Iguarán, por haber matado de duelo a un hombre. Ellos se habían casado a pesar de ser primos, un precedente indicaba que de un matrimonio en el cual hubieran vínculos familiares podía nacer un hijo con cola de cerdo, pero por suerte eso no ocurrió. Tuvieron tres hijos, y así empieza la historia de la familia Buendía, que es la primera generación que comienza por describir Márquez. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mireille4m</user>
	<review>Prachtig Zuid Amerikaans epos </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CarlosMcRey</user>
	<review>I've never been a huge fan of "magical realism."  In fact, I've kind of disliked the label, often thinking of it as shorthand for "fantasy written by non-anglos."  I am, however, willing to admit when I'm wrong.   And this is certainly one of those cases, as this work goes far beyond the conventions of fantasy.  Marquez sets up a unique narrative, the story of a family and a town, in which miraculous and strange events are treated as everyday occurrences, and names seem to be reused in each generation.  The effect of all this isn't one of confusion or arbitrariness.  Instead, the novel reads like a very complex fable or myth.Yet Marquez incorporates into this myth very real events, such as a bloody and pointless civil war, the reign of the fruit companies, and the murder of striking workers.  In doing so, he's creating what could be taken as the foundation myth for Colombia (and by extension Latin America).  That's certainly a tall order, but Marquez is up to the task.  His prose, which with its twists in time and space are reminiscent of a more lyrical Faulkner, is integral to the fabulous sense of the tale.  It's probably fair to say that this is one of the great Latin American novels of the 20th century.  It innovated many elements that would be borrowed later by other writers.  Yet these elements, which make up magic realism, are so well integrated into the novel that one doesn't get that sense of cliche that often happens with reading influentual works. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stveggy</user>
	<review>I didn't get on with this book at all  - too many characters </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Carnophile</user>
	<review>I’m about two fifths of the way through it now and so far find it good but over-rated. It’s not the best thing since the taming of fire, as some would have you believe. On the other hand, maybe it just seems over-rated because it spawned so many imitators that its originality is no longer apparent: Everyone and his brother writes magical realism now.Miscellany:Why oh why give everyone the same name? There are, at my present count, 132 Aurelianos and 634 Arcadios. This generates terrible confusion for the reader; it kept pulling me out of the story as I paused to try to remember who the current paragraph was about. Even if this naming pattern is the norm in South American cultures, there’s no need to stick with it in fiction. Especially this kind of fiction: If we can have flying carpets, rivulets of blood that flow uphill, and rains of flowers, I think we can depart from nomenclature conventions.People kept almost having incestuous sex, but veering off at the last instant. But even though they veer off, Yuck! Please, Marquez, just don’t go there at all, not even close to there.The whole thing seems like a dream because of the lucid depiction of magical events. I can’t get out of my head the idea that the last line will be “And then he woke up.”LATER: I've finished it and it gets worse - the pacing seems to slip out of his control as each generation is given more cursory treatment than the previous one - but then the ending, meaning the last paragraph, is brilliant. It's so good it saves the book from being consigned to 3-star status. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Daumas</user>
	<review>gosto muito, mas me cansa um pouco o tal realismo fantastico, me confundo com esta confusão de nomes iguais. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LaiaCastellvell</user>
	<review>Sorprenent </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JoseArcadio</user>
	<review>I have read Gabriel Garcia Marquez's "Cronica de una Muerte Anunciada" and this english translation of Marquez's masterpiece perfectly captures his style. Famous for his magical realism or "realismo magico" Marquez creates a modern epic acounting for the history of Macondo and several generations of the Buendia family.Marquez's magical realism creates vivid familiar scenes that are often infused by supernatural occurences. However, these occurence are described so matter of factly that they become as familiar as normal daily events. This is an excellent and recommended read for all those who wish to read a modern classic. Dynamic in tone, One Hundred Years of Solitude is a rollercoaster of emotion, often depressing at one moment and lighthearted the next. It is a must read for all. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Heathcliff</user>
	<review>Magical. I just absolutley loved it. Confused the hell out of me but the fact that I still loved it only shows how strong a book it is. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SanctiSpiritus</user>
	<review>Most likely the greatest epic I have ever read. The story grips you, pulls you in, and commands 100% of your concentration. Marquez deserves two Nobel Prizes for this tale. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gary237</user>
	<review>There has been renewed interest in the work of the Nobel Prize winning Columbian novelist Gabriel Garcia Marquez.  The keystone of his work is "One Hundred Years of Solitude" originally published in 1967.  A reissue edition of the novel published in 2003 by Harper Collins and translated by Gregory Rabassa tells the story of several generations of residents of the fictional town “Macondo.”  Like the South American macondo tree, the people of the town have roots both in and above the earth.  In simple declarative sentences, a style he learned from his mother’s oral histories of her family, Marquez describes every aspect of the lives of the people from birth to death and beyond.  Macondo lies in solitude between the mountains and the sea, and the several generations of characters mirror that solitude in their personal understanding of the world.  Idiosyncracy and passion are common denominators in the diverse characters who are all full of life but respectful of death.  The reader quickly enters the story by learning to abandon the traditional sense of time, space, and social structure.  Then Marquez takes the believer on a marvelous conscious and unconscious journey through the human condition. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MbuTseTseFly</user>
	<review>De loin un favori. Superbe, magique et terrible. Un très bon commencement pour découvrir la littérature sud-américaine </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>whitewavedarling</user>
	<review>I'd be the first to admit that this book is a bit daunting, as much for the number of characters as anything, but once you're involved in the story it's a fairly quick and certainly fascinating read.  Marquez is famous for magical realism, and here it's at its best.  The scenes and characters will stick with you long after the story's over, and you'll find yourself laughing out loud with or without the characters.  If you like novels that span generations, or you're up for a book that will draw you in and make you look at things rather differently, pick this one up with an open mind. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wvlibrarydude</user>
	<review>Read in college close to 20 years ago.  The book blew me away then.  Probably should re-read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>clong</user>
	<review>Obviously, I'm in the minority on this one, but I just didn't find that much to get excited about. I'm glad I read it, but it was slow going, and it is far far from the top of my list of great novels of the 20th century.  The narrative style is distinctive, but few of the characters are sympathetic (the only ones I could really say I cared much about were the matriarch Ursula and the last of the Aurelianos). The opening and closing are both well done, but for me this only pulled it up to a 7/10. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>c4nn1b4l</user>
	<review>Nem olvastam még regényt, amely ennyire jól reprezentálta volna az emberek viselkedését - tébolyban, szerelemben, háborúban.Mesésen realista. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fsofield</user>
	<review>My all time favorite book. Magical realism at it's best. A must read!</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Choccy</user>
	<review>One Hundred Years of Solitude, why there's nobody makin' a film based on this book?It was just a mesmerizing read. One will feel enchanted when imagining the lives of the Buendia family in their land, Macondo. At least there were five generations of Buendias in the story. One will wonder, due to all the events occurred - which were totally bizarre yet magical - has this family's fate already been decided before?This is a madhouse, said Ursula Buendia, the wife of Jose Arcadio Buendia, the man who started the whole thing, our famous patient zero.Was it the family itself? Was it the place? Why all the members of Buendia family exhibited their own version of solitary lives? Whether he/she was a military rebel, a gypsy, an alchemist, a simple trader, all of them lived in "solitary" world.Conclusion is, you just can't put down this book. I spent one whole Saturday because it had glue on it. Unputdownable. I kid you not. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>majolica</user>
	<review>fantastic and an adventure </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gatopinto</user>
	<review>http://gaudi.ua.es/uhtbin/cgisirsi/0/...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>www.snigel.nu</user>
	<review>Link to a review on my personal website  (might be in Swedish). </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dugmel</user>
	<review>This book is written in one of the most unique styles I have ever read. The author's prose is dense and beautiful and he can change the direction of the story in a few words...and often does. The basic story is well-discussed here, but suffice it to say it is a fascinating read where the theme of history repeating itself over the generations of a family is at the core of the book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>librarianarpita</user>
	<review>Best book ever! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>daniela1965</user>
	<review>E' la storia centenaria della famiglia Buendia e della città di Macondo. In un intreccio di vicende favolose, secondo il disegno premonitorio tracciato nelle pergamene di un indovino, Melquiades, si compie il destino della città dal momento della sua fondazione alla sua momentanea e disordinata fortuna, quando i nordamericani vi impiantarono una piantagione di banane, fino alla sua rovina e definitiva decadenza. La parabola della famiglia segue la parabola di solitudine e di sconfitta che sta scritta nel destino di Macondo, facendo perno sulle 23 guerre civili promosse e tutte perdute dal colonnello Aureliano, padre di 17 figli illeggittimi e descrivendo in una successione paradossale le vicende e le morti dei vari Buendia. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JMBLibrary</user>
	<review>This book surprised me and is one of my top favorites. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>martinmccarvill</user>
	<review>I've always been uneasy with how all the positive superlatives imply disbelief. "Not credible! So unlikely it amazes me! Like something out of a fantasy! You just, you just wonder how it could possibly be!"This book is not incredible, amazing, fantastic or wonderful. What it is is so inventive, surprising, and heartachingly good. I called Calvino's "Baron in the Trees" "magic idealism" once and thought I was making a tentative redefinition, but reading this I realize the difference between magic realism and Calvino's idealism - in a way not meant to limit his immensity but merely to pay tribute, Garcia Marquez is like Calvino with the dirt mixed in.There were two moments when he got smug about his own magisterialness and I fronted to myself like they were going to be enough for me to give this book a 4.5 (not that I usually think about the rating while I'm reading, and not that I had it in for this book or anything, but I expected so much to enjoy it that I guess I was just being ornery).  When that man fell from the roof and instead of gore from his broken head out leaked the perfumed oil of true love, I was vanquished.You quiver with the fear of the magic fading, because my god, the 20th century is coming! And banana companies and later coke and FARC I guess! But no. It doesn't sag, it swells. It swells. And then the whole mythology disappears in kudzu and whirlwind.Fuck it. This book is incredible, amazing, fantastic and wonderful. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Floddertje</user>
	<review>Wel mooi, toch niet uitgelezen.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cursonivel</user>
	<review>cien años de soledad es la voluntad de referir aquéllas lecturas que supusieron para los distintos colaboradores un viaje sin retorno, una ruptura, un hito en nuestra educación y condición de lectores. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>antimuzak</user>
	<review>A band of adventurers find a town in the heart of the South American jungle. Their leader is Jose Arcadio Buendia, the town is called Macondo. The occasion marks the beginning: of the world, of a great family, and of a century of extraordinary events.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bigdc</user>
	<review>One Hundred Years of Solitude by Gabriel Garcia Marquez is a tremendous piece of literature.  It's not an easy read.  You're not going to turn its pages like you would the latest John Grisham novel, or The DaVinci Code.  You have to read each page, soaking up every word, immersing yourself in the imagery.  Mr. Marquez says that he tells the story as his grandmother used to tell stories to him: with a brick face.  That's useful to remember while reading, because that is certainly the tone the book takes.  If you can get through the first 50 pages, you will enjoy it.  But those 50 are a doozy.  It's hard to keep track of the characters, at times (mainly because they are all named Jose Arcadio or Aureliano), but a family tree at the beginning of my edition was helpful.  The book follows the Buendia family, from the founding of fictional Macondo to a fitting and fulfilling conclusion.  The family goes through wars, marriages, many births and deaths, as well as several technological advances and invasions by gypsies and banana companies (trust me, the banana company is important).  You begin to realize, as matriarch Ursula does, that as time passes, time does not really pass for this family, but turns in a circle.  And as the circle closes on Macondo and the Buendias, you realize that Mr. Marquez has taken you on a remarkable journey in his literature.  Recommended, but be prepared for a hard read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BrianDewey</user>
	<review>Garc?a Marquez, Gabriel. One Hundred Years of Solitude. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wordygirl39</user>
	<review>Someday I might make it past page 100 of this book. I know, I know--I'm supposed to love it. And as an English teacher, I understand how egregious it is for me not to love this novel. It isn't that I don't like Magical Realism (I love Borges and Kafka), it's that I feel manipulated by this story every time I try to read it. Ah well...maybe someday I'll "get it" about the novel. Until then, I'll keep trying to read it every few years. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ferebend</user>
	<review>There's a lot going on in this novel at any given time. In a nutshell, the plot goes like this: A lot of really shitty things happen to a lot of really shitty people (who are all related and all have the same name) over a long period of time... oh, and there's magic.Seriously, that about covers it. There isn't much of a plot, per se. Basically, the story chronicles the lives of the Buendia family who, along with some other, nameless, disenfranchised individuals, decide to head deep into unsettled territory, build their own town and live out their lives free of others' influence.No less then six generations of the family are covered. As is common in Hispanic cultures (I think?), there's a lot of name recycling going on. Coupled with the fact that the characters tend to be incredibly long-lived, promiscious and (sometimes) incestuous, it gets really confusing. At one point, there are approximately 22 characters named 'Aureliano.' Not far into the book, I decided to abandon all hope of keeping track of exactly what's happening to whom and consign myself to reading through in a semi-aware fog.What is obvious about practically everyone in the family, though, is that they are extremely fucked up. To the point where they can't really be taken seriously. No one has normal relationships and no one exhibits normal feelings. It's a wonder the family even survived until the sixth generation, until you consider the aforementioned promiscuity.Anyway, the original Buendia's efforts to isolate themselves ultimately fail, as the world slugs on into more modern times and makes inroads everywhere. The first to come are the gypsies. The gypsies are magic. No, really. They have flying carpets. Flying carpets which actually fly. The town grows significantly over the years as various peoples barge in to claim their own stake in the (surprising) prosperity, with lots of really terrible consequences for the original habitants. Not that it really matters, because they're horrible people anyway, but I digress.Can you tell I didn't really like this book? Reading it was somewhat akin to listening to the ramblings of an old, senile man. Disjointed, exaggerated, superstitious, etc. The only thing that held the story together was the continued existence of the original matriarch, Ursula, who lived to be astonishingly old. But even she couldn't last forever. (That wasn't a spoiler. There's a shitload of death in this book and it doesn't exactly come as a surprise.)Oh, and there's magic... </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bek.randersbib</user>
	<review>Sydamerikansk roman fra en isoleret landsby, omgivet af sumpe og urskove og beboet af fantaster, som dog både tillader fantasiens frihed og hverdagens realisme</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stpnwlf</user>
	<review>See Love in the Time of Cholera for discussion of Marquez' writing style. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>opinion8dsngr</user>
	<review>This novel is written like a coherent, feverish dream.  Full of gritty details and fanciful assumptions, Marquez makes the reader see average events- touching ice, seeing ants crawl by, seem mystical  and amazing.     The plot line itself follows the town of Mocando through the anything but linear family line of one of the town's first settling couples.  From this beginning comes political intrigue, murder, sexual romance, and cycles of deep understanding all told in an off-hand, flitting sort of way.     The book is a heavy read, and sometime it slows down and seems pointless.  It definitely requires a suspension of belief.  In the end, however, the novel does eventually pay off quite richly. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>karima29</user>
	<review>It's almost impossible for me to write a review on this book. It seems like the reading of it went by in flash, and by the last page I wasn't ready for it to end. It's easy to read this book and be overwhelmed, be scared that you're missing something, because just about everybody makes a big deal about this book. So I found myself reading it and being very conscious of every single word. That's probably why I noticed that the word 'solitude' is used alot, almost on every page or second page. The novel explores themes of magical realism, fate, solitude, and time. In a period of one hundred years it tells the story of the rise and fall of the Buendias family, a fictional family but told against the backdrop of the history of Columbia during that time. What may be worth nothing is that it's a tale told about and 'by' the 'losers. It's often said that History is written by the winners. This story is different in that way. The author gave a voice to people who may not otherwise have ever been heard.That's the best I can do here. Try to make sense of it. But I would definately recommend it. It's the kind of book that's perfect for a bookclub though, so that it can be discussed. It was in my bookclub about two years ago, but this is the first time I'm getting to it. Now I wish I had read it then, so that I could have heard what the others had to say on it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>abirdman</user>
	<review>Magical. Perfect. Must be read by anyone who wants to consider themselves cultured. This book is probably reason enough to learn Spanish, though the translation is excellent and transparent. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>proxoper1</user>
	<review>Family </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>curso04</user>
	<review>libro que cuenta la historia de una familia en macondo y sus generaciones </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Soshial</user>
	<review>http://soshial.blogspot.com/2007/04/b... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>micurso</user>
	<review>Cien años de soledad es una novela del escritor colombiano Gabriel García Márquez, quien obtuvo el Premio Nobel de Literatura en 1982, y es considerada una obra maestra de la literatura hispanoamericana y universal. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>coffeezombie</user>
	<review>The height of Central/South American magical realism (that I've readanyway) and wonderful piece of storytelling. Following a family througha century of strange occurances and political turmoil, it seems like anoutlet for every strange idea Marquez has ever had. From the year ofsolid rain, to the strange outbreak of insomnia that causes thefamily's village to slowly lose their memory, the novel lives in aworld of its own creation tied to our own by the subtle dream logicrunning through it. Necessary reading.(This review originally appeared on zombieunderground.net) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MorHavok</user>
	<review>Magic realism, I think that may be my main issue with this book. No matter how hard I tried I was not able to finish it. The writing style just did not appeal to me in the slightest. I also felt the story was somewhat weak. I hate to totally bash this book because I dont feel it was as bad as I personally thought, yet I wouldnt be recommending it to anyone. </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>antimuzak</user>
	<review>The novel tells the story of the rise and fall of the mythical town of Macondo through the history of the Buendía family. It is a rich and brilliant chronicle of life and death, and the tragicomedy of humankind. In the noble, ridiculous, beautiful, and tawdry story of the Buendía family, one sees all of humanity, just as in the history, myths, growth, and decay of Macondo, one sees all of Latin America.Love and lust, war and revolution, riches and poverty, youth and senility -- the variety of life, the endlessness of death, the search for peace and truth -- these universal themes dominate the novel. Whether he is describing an affair of passion or the voracity of capitalism and the corruption of government, Gabriel García Márquez always writes with the simplicity, ease, and purity that are the mark of a master.Alternately reverential and comical, One Hundred Years of Solitude weaves the political, personal, and spiritual to bring a new consciousness to storytelling. Translated into dozens of languages, this stunning work is no less than an accounting of the history of the human race.Paul West - Bookworld: The fecund, savage, irresistable...you have the sense of living, along with the Buendias (and the rest), in them, through them and in spite of them, and all their loves, madnesses and wars, their alliances, compromises, dreams and deaths...the characters rear up large and rippling with life against the green texture of nature itself.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Julia.McG</user>
	<review>I really enjoyed reading this book, but have trouble giving it a higher rating just because I read it over such a long period of time. Many of the characters have the same names, and it's a little bit confusing if you haven't picked it up for a month or so. Aside from that, it's beautiful and entertaining, and I'd definitely recommend it to others. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>joiescire</user>
	<review>A wonderful story, very detailed and very involved. It took me a little while to truely get into this book, but I really enjoyed it once I did. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>subuus</user>
	<review>http://www.litteratursiden.dk/sw42857... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bennui</user>
	<review>This book will always have a place in my heart for the time it spent with me in my back pocket as I sauntered the streets of Amsterdam in the summer of 2003. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cnivel1</user>
	<review>una de las mejores obras colombianas, nominada a premio nobel. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cursonivel1</user>
	<review>La novela tiene una declaración asustante que se desarrolla y explica en manera lógica, que ninguna otra conclusión puede ser posible. La manipulación del tiempo y creación de un sistema total no permite la medida de tiempo en una concepción lineal. La acción no es cronológica, pero tiene la funcción de evocar el fin de un ciclo vital desde el principio. Así, pues, el presente se ve de la perspectiva del pasado y es proyección al futuro. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cursonivel1</user>
	<review>macondo descripcion del lugar maravilloso creado por su escritor </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cursonivel1</user>
	<review>"Muchos años después, frente al pelotón de fusilamiento, el coronel Aureliano Buendía había de recordar aquella tarde remota en que su padre lo llevó a conocer el hielo. Macondo era entonces una aldea de 20 casas de barro y cañabrava construidas a la orilla de un río de aguas diáfanas que se precipitaban por un lecho de piedras pulidas, blancas y enormes como huevos prehistóricos </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jaylabelle</user>
	<review>An epic story of 6 generations of the Buendia family and their enchanting town. Written in the style of magical realism. Not always easy to get through, but a treasure just the same! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rhinoa</user>
	<review>This book tells the story of a family who founded a town called Mocando in South America. It spans over one hundred years with visits from gypsies with scientific inventions, alchemy, a plague of insomnia, civil war and rain that lasted over two years. When mysterious gypsy Melquiades (friend of Jose Arcadio) dies for the second timehe leaaves behind papers with the family that will take one hundred years to decipher by one of Jose Arcadio's descendents.It took me such a long time to get into this book as I found it so dull. It's such a classic and so many people have recommended it to me that I felt guilty for not enjoying it more so I perservered... The last one hundred pages or so redeemed it slightly by grabbing my attention more. The other thing I found hard going was keeping track of who was who as the family shared a few key names (Aureliano, Jose, Arcadio, Amaranta and Remedios). Luckily at the front of the book was a family tree which helped me to keep up with which generation I was reading about by frequently checking back to it.My favourite characters were Ursula Iguaran who was the matriach of the family married to the original Jose Arcadio and Pilar Ternera who was outside of the main family and the mother of two sons by different brothers in the family. Pilar Ternera was a prostitute and a madam who read playing cards and lived well over a hundred years. Ursula kept her family in check and despite turning blind she was the most insightful and knowledgable of the family.Overall though I will have to give it **1/2 out of 5 sadly. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ex_ottoyuhr</user>
	<review>I'll finish this eventually, and I'll get back to you if I figure out what's going on. That's a pretty big 'if.'</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dgussak</user>
	<review>This is no ordinary novel. Dip into the reviews since One Hundred Years of Solitude was first published in 1967, and you will find acclaim more appropriate to a sacred text than to a work of fiction. 'The greatest revelation in the Spanish language since the Don Quixote of Cervantes' (Pablo Neruda); 'the first piece of literature since the Book of Genesis that should be required reading for the entire human race' (New York Times Book Review). Gabriel García Márquez's masterpiece - the first Latin American novel to gain admiration from the Western literary establishment - has entranced and touched the souls of millions.It is a weird and wonderful odyssey, an intoxicating kaleidoscope of unforgettable characters and phantasmagorical events. From the very first page, when the travelling gypsy Melquíades arrives in the village of Macondo, the reader is swept breathlessly up into the passions, triumphs and disasters of seven generations of the Buendía family. The pace is relentless, the imagination dazzling, the thrills immediate. Here you will find love, desire, war, insanity, magic and revolution, comedy and tragedy. Here you will find ghostly Spanish galleons moored in the middle of forests, suicides that defy the laws of physics, an orphan girl who eats earth and spreads a plague of insomnia. Blending myth, allegory and folklore with powerful storytelling, One Hundred Years of Solitude is indisputably one of the greatest books of the 20th century, by 'one of the greatest living storytellers' (Time).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mariejelis</user>
	<review>Story plot is twisted and purposely confusing (down to the characters' names!) and while I could appreciate the originality and creativity , I personnaly had a hard time not letting the confusion take away at my enjoyment... Perhaps I will give it another try one day. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nb1</user>
	<review>amazing </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cestovatela</user>
	<review>A literary classic I couldn't quite connect with.  Marquez conveys some powerful truths about the forces of time and poverty, but the characters feel more like literary constructs moving through a vast forest of symbolism.  To fully appreciate this book, I would've needed characters I could connect with. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>minkeyx</user>
	<review>I like magic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lindsacl</user>
	<review>http://laura0218.livejournal.com/8485... </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Griff</user>
	<review>One Hundred Years of Solitude by Gabriel Garcia Marquez. Family history? Social history? Political history? Dream? Reality? All of that rolled into one. I can't say I understood it all (whatever that means), but it was well worth the investment of time and effort. Likely even better upon rereading in a few years.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chrisadami</user>
	<review>Opening:Many years later, as he faced the firing squad, Colonel Aureliano de Buendía was to remember that distant afternoon when his father took him to discover ice. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Arctic-Stranger</user>
	<review>I read this book on a beach in Mexico, and from the first sentence I knew I had run into an author who had command of language and story. One of the few books that had me in tears...more than once.Dont let the OPRAH on the cover put you off. This is the story of the Buendías family and their lives in Macondo, a village in the middle of nowhere. The family is full of characters in the broadest sense of the term. Some are lusty and full of life, others are very prim and proper. There is family squabbles, political unrest, and MAGIC in the air. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>briconcella</user>
	<review>Les fantomes parlent, les bananiers font de l'ombre aux dames sur les bords de l'Orénoque, et il n'y a rien à faire, sauf se caler au fond du fauteuil pour visiter un monde truculent et épicé, dont on aimerait qu'il existe vraiment. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nobodysfool</user>
	<review>It took years, but I finally finished One Hundred Years of Solitude, and I'm so glad I did. This book is a masterpiece, spanning generations and the rise and fall of a town. Garcia Marquez entwines mystical stories and dozens of colorful and crazy characters into a twisted and tangled family history. Gorgeous and fun to read (though you have to pay close attention to the names!). </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wirkman</user>
	<review>From the intoxicating first sentence to that final judgment in the very last (and long) sentence, this great work entices, bedazzles, entrances, ensorcles, enchants. It is the great work of Latin American Magic Realism. There are many other fine works in this movement, but this is the work at the pinnacle . . . or, at least I've discovered none better. Which is why I kept the original paperback that I read way back in high schoolWhat an amazing book. It is time to read this again. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>calvin_xa</user>
	<review>I would like to like marquez. my spanish-speaking friends love his stuff. This for me was one long, confusing genealogy project in novel form. Full of really random stuff like the kid with the oversized genitals and the massacre. It was so sparsely connected and completely illogical that it felt like one of my own dreams. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lorelorn_2007</user>
	<review>This is the story of the town of Macondo in South America, from its founding to its eventual destruction.This book is both a family drama, and a metaphor for South America itself. We see the town grow from self-reliance based on a pioneer spirit, through to needless and wasteful civil war, followed by the dominance of foreign-owned multinationals.Through all of this the Buendia family, like the town they founded, prosper, falter and finally fail. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jscobie</user>
	<review>Many years later as you face your mortality you will remember that distant afternoon when time, space and human history were contained within the pages of a Columbian novel like the crystalline wonder of your most marvellous childhood memory. What consolation could there be for not reading 100 Years of Solitude before you die? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>michaeldwebb</user>
	<review>For some reason I didn't really thing I would enyoy this, but how wrong was I? This was of those books that I read very, very slowly because I didn't want it to end (do other people do that?).It tells the story of the the rise and fall of an isolated South American town, centering on the lives a single family over many generations.It's a really densely written story - the wonderfully evocative prose packs a huge amount into every page, packing the book feel incredibly epic, yet really personal at the same time. The setting is obviously very alien (at least it me), and at times, especially in the early parts, it's made even more special by small reference to fantastical items (science or magic?) such as flying carpets, almost like a wonky memory of distant times. The bulk of the book is however, firmly founded in reality, personalities and politics (family and beyond - all very colourful!).So, this is a book that I really, really enjoyed, and would says it's one of those books that everyone should at least take a look at. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Trotsky731</user>
	<review>Great storytelling with a wealth of information. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lindayakle</user>
	<review>When my car broke down a couple of summers ago, I was stranded in a small town with no book to read, so I went to the local Wal-Mart where the most readable book on the shelves was the new printing of the Marquez novel in the wake of Oprah's Book Selection press.  I had read it year's ago but couldn't believe how much richer it seemed to me this reading. It was probably the reading - and rereading - highlight of my year. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Stbalbach</user>
	<review>Marquez, born 1927, published Solitude when he was about 40 in 1967, the same year I was born, and I was about 40 when I first read it in 2007, "in medias res". It is from this perspective of being in the "middle of things" that it is possible to understand the novel. Themes of inter-generational similarities and solitude becomes very much a part of life when sandwiched between the twin responsibilities of caring for both the younger and elder generations.  For me, the novel became increasingly tedious towards the end as old characters died and new characters appear, all with the same names, it becomes difficult to even care anymore, creating a sense of despair and pessimistic pre-determinism that I did not find enjoyable. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nicoyu</user>
	<review>A story of Buendia family. Mixed up with magic world, such as gypsy magicians, and real world, including plague, war, and civilization.The way that Marquez described life and death is very poetic, and attracts me most. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chatfielda</user>
	<review>Here's the thing about this book. I'm not going to try and give a detailed review of someone as incredible and praise worthy as Garcia Marquez because there's nothing in his work to critique. As the masterwork of his Nobel Prize winning career, One Hundred Years of Solitude is one of the greatest novels of the past century, and maybe beyond.Repetitions and cycles manifest themselves in One Hundred Years of Solitude so rampantly that each action taken assumes the visage of an action already taken. Echoes of past events repeatedly occur and each time it happens it forces me to recall the circumstances of the same action in a previous chapter. Beyond the attempt to create parallels between characters that share names, I find myself tracking the events that occur at certain ages for these characters, the development of Macondo in relation, the circumstances of deaths, and more. There are any number of reasons I could prattle on about how incredible his storytelling is, the Borgesian charm he infuses his cast with in detailing the cyclical recurrence of tragedy in the family to end all families. Jose Arcadia Buendia in any incarnation is a character to fall in love with, mourn, and rail against in all the same breath, and so each one, as he is born and grown, and ultimately destroyed is as heartbreaking as the first. As each generation dilutes the strength of the original, the family disintegrates further from its source, becoming almost abominable at certain stages, but the real tragedy is in the beauty and clarity of Garcia Marquez's prose, so perfect in its encapsulation of such stark imagery. He writes as only a master could of a world with not one.One Hundred Years of Solitude is one of those rare books that regardless of the Oprah Book Club Label (and yes, I tend to be annoyed by it) is prominently displayed in my collection alongside masters such as Kafka, Borges, and Joyce, men who deserved the award as much as Marquez if only in that they taught him everything he knows. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pickwick817</user>
	<review>I read this book a long time ago.  I remember enjoying it, but thinking it was "way out there".  I guess my expectations were slanted toward realism, but I was surprised to get a healthy dose of fantasy. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>phunction</user>
	<review>as i began reading this, i was surprised by the writing style. it is written in heavy prose, with very little dialogue. it looks daunting then, when you open up the book to any page and you see full paragraphs, as if it were one massive essay. i suppose it makes sense, considering that roughly one hundred years is being covered in less than 500 pages. its as if everything is written as a story being told. it is in fact a story of recollection, one that unfolds magically through the words of marquez in the city of macondo and the buendia family. the writing is mystical and poetic, with some of the most beautiful language, particularly in the last 30 pages or so. i had a difficult time finding my way into the story, but now that i'm done, i'm so glad i read it. one of the quotes on the back of the book stuck with me throughout the reading: "Mr. Garcia Marquez has done nothing less than to create in the reader a sense of all that is profound, meaningful, and meaningless in life." ~William Kennedy, New York Timesi don't think it could be put any better.this was by far the best choice for my first book of the year and this time in my life. covering every facet of both the complexity and simplicity of love and solitude, i found myself reading and re-reading certain parts, finding the weight of the words in my own context. it was perfect. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Chandra</user>
	<review>The second half isn't as enchanting as the first. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stipe168</user>
	<review>stunning. passion overflow. I can flip to any page in this massive book and scan down to any line, and something spectacular or heartbreaking is happening. And it’d be beautifully executed and just a little strange, a little off-kilter. Takes about a hundred years to read. save room for cholera! There is too much going on in this book, but that's OK, just keep reading. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kelyana</user>
	<review>My favorite book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Thalia</user>
	<review>A beautiful book and so different from what I usually read. It took some time to get into it, but once I did and also had a family tree (printed out from the internet as there isn't one in my copy), I got totally lost in Macondo.And the end... oh, the end. Somehow predictable, somehow I still had hope, but when it came it was the only logical conclusion to a great magical tale. But it still killed me.And at all times, I really believed Macondo and the Buendias existed. The fantasy and magical elements weren't too frequent to make it unbelievable. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dylanwolf</user>
	<review>The world's greatest opening sentence - Many years later, as he faced the firing squad, Colonel Aureliano Buendia, was to remember that distant afternoon when his father took him to discover ice - is followed by possible the world's greatest novel. Set in the fictional village of Macondo in Colombia One Hundred Years of Solitude is the saga of the Buendia family. A novel of failing memory and repeated mistakes this book rewards the reader with a rich and satisfying tale incorporating Marquez's famous magical realism. For ice in hot climes elsewhere and a totally different book try Paul Theroux's Mosquito Coast. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>southpaw</user>
	<review>I really wanted to like this book, particularly as I'd heard such rave reviews about it. I tried really hard. Unfortunately, I just found it hard work. The text was dense, with endless sentences encased into page long (or more) paragraphs; the family tree confusing, particularly as the pace of the introduction of characters seemed rushed; and not least, the relentless pace of the prose, which combined with the above, made it for me, quite an unrewarding read. I found myself having to review my reading the next day to remember the numerous character additions in one short piece of reading, and ultimately, looking forward desperately to finishing it.A worthy work, I'm sure, but just not for me. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lzorzella</user>
	<review>One of my all time favourites.It is: a borderline fantastic reality tale of a family in an isolated city. Overall: Despite the title, the book is not depressing. It is actually fun. The main characters (Jose Arcadio and Aureliano Buendia) permeate a frentic sequence of events, while continuing their compulsion to repetition (which is passed along to their descendency) in order to resolve their original sin. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>boekenwijs</user>
	<review>http://boekenwijs.blogspot.com/2006/0... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Clurb</user>
	<review>This was a fantastic tragi-comic family history full of big characters and unreal adventures. There's a very fine line between fantasy and reality with this book yet it remains throughout utterly believeable.Make sure your copy has a picture of the family tree. There were two or three times where I got totally confused and had to fall back on it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>judieharren</user>
	<review>Magical fiction set in South America.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aewilson20</user>
	<review>I know that many people LOVE this book, but I struggled through it.  I found the plot lines and character names convoluted and confusing. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>billyfantles</user>
	<review>Wikipedia:  One Hundred Years of Solitude (Spanish: Cien años de soledad) is a novel by Gabriel García Márquez which was first published in Spanish in 1967 (Buenos Aires: Sudamericana), with an English translation by Gregory Rabassa released in 1970 (New York: Harper and Row). The book is considered García Márquez's masterpiece, metaphorically encompassing the history of Colombia. The novel chronicles a family's struggle, and the history of their fictional town, Macondo, for one hundred years. García Márquez acknowledges in his autobiography Living to Tell the Tale that Macondo was based on the towns where he spent his childhood.Plot summary: All of the events of One Hundred Years of Solitude take place in the fictional Colombian village of Macondo. The town is founded by José Arcadio Buendía, a strong-willed and impulsive leader who becomes deeply interested in the mysteries of the universe when a band of Gypsies visits Macondo, led by the recurring Melquíades. As the town grows, the fledgling government of the country takes an interest in Macondo's affairs, but they are held back by José Arcadio Buendía.Civil war breaks out in the land, and Macondo soon takes a role in the war, sending a militia led by Colonel Aureliano Buendía, José Arcadio Buendía's son, to fight against the conservative regime. While the colonel is gone, Arcadio, his nephew, takes leadership of the town but soon becomes a brutal dictator. The Conservatives capture the town, and Arcadio is shot by a firing squad.The wars continue, with Colonel Aureliano narrowly avoiding death multiple times, until, weary of the meaningless fighting, he arranges a peace treaty that will last until the end of the novel. After the treaty is signed, Aureliano shoots himself in the chest, but survives. The town develops into a sprawling center of activity as foreigners arrive by the thousands. The foreigners begin a banana plantation near Macondo. The town prospers until a strike arises at the banana plantation. The national army is called in, and the protesting workers are gunned down and thrown into the ocean. At this time, Úrsula, the impossibly ancient widow of José Arcadio Buendía, remarks that "it was as if time was going in a circle".After the banana worker massacre, the town is saturated by heavy rains that last for almost five years. Úrsula says that she is waiting for the rains to stop so that she can die at last. The last member of the Buendía line, named Aureliano Babilonia (originally referred to as Aureliano Buendía, before he discovers through Melquíades' parchments that Babilonia is his paternal surname), is born at this time. When the rains stop, Úrsula dies at last, and Macondo is left desolated.Aureliano Babilonia is finally left in solitude at the crumbling Buendía house, where he studies the parchments of Melquíades, who has appeared as a ghost to him. He gives up on this task to have a love affair with his aunt, though he is unsure whether they are related. When she dies in childbirth and his son (who is born with a pig's tail) is eaten by ants, Aureliano is finally able to decipher the parchments. The house, and the town, disintegrate into a whirlwind as he translates the parchments, on which is contained the entire history of the Buendía family, as predicted by Melquíades. As he finishes translating, the entire town is obliterated from the world. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ycc2106</user>
	<review>This is the first book I read completely in Spanish, beautiful images of a long saga that goes on for more than one century. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LTW</user>
	<review>It was one of the first books to be written in a style that is called "magic-realism". That means that the book doesn't have to make sense. This is not an easy to read book; if you are looking for light reading, this is not it. Also, this is not a book to read quickly; it takes a lot of reflection to try to grasp the meaning (and often times you don't) of the wonderous stories.Having said that, this is a wonderful book. Garcia Marquez tells the story of a family and a town, Macondo. The things that happen there are surreal; strange murders, sleeping disorders, scientists, soldiers, all revolve around the mansion of the Buendia family in Macondo. The tales introduce the reader to 20th century Latin American literature, with tales of love, sadness, desperation, hurt, and loss. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tiha</user>
	<review>http://www.linux-girl.be/e107_plugins...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sramos</user>
	<review>over enthusiastic use of adjectives </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mockers</user>
	<review>Supposed to be his masterwork, but you know I think I prefer Of Love and Other Demons. You can lose yourself for days on end in this one though. Marvelous and full of marvels. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>eslee</user>
	<review>One of my most favorite books of all time. It boasts both my favorite opening line ("Many years later, as he faced the firing squad, Colonel Aureliano Buendía was to remember that distant afternoon when his father took him to discover ice.") and possibly my favorite ending of a novel of all time, with utter brilliance in between. This novel is absolutely gorgeous. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>indrekparli</user>
	<review>Kolumbia kirjanik Gabriel Garcia Marquez (s. 1928) saavutas maailmakuulsuse romaaniga «Sada aastat üksildust» (1967), millest kujunes ühtlasi Ladina-Ameerika maagilise realismi tähtteos. Romaan esitab Buendiade suguvõsa loo. Ja Macondo küla või väikelinna tekkimise ning hävimise loo. Geograafiliselt kaardilt puuduv, kirjanikufantaasias loodud Macondo mahutab endasse kogu Kolumbia, -- aga võib-olla kogu Ladina-Ameerika -- tema müüdid, eksootika ja ebausu, üle kõige aga üksilduse, mille juured asuvad vägivallas ja vihkamises, eneseuhkes isemeelsuses, võimuihas ning enesearmastuses. Sellest vabanemise võimalusi näeb kirjanik ülluses ning armastuses.1982. a. omistati kirjanikule Nobeli kirjanduspreemia eeskätt just nimetatud üldinimlike joonte kujundajana.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tiggergrrl</user>
	<review>Garcia Marquez can draw you into a world of his creation like no one else.  beautiful work about the human condition </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kattepusen</user>
	<review>Yes, this is a seriously engaging book, and as far as the style of "magical realism" goes - this one has it ALL. However, even though I enjoyed reading it and could not leave it alone for any long periods of time, I was still a bit disappointed by this family-saga classic, and I must admit I am much more fond of Marquez' "Love in the Time of Cholera". I found it a pretty easy read, and that might actually be part of the problem - I feel it is actually too easy...Most aspects of the story, including the people and all their thoughts and feelings, are almost "over-explained", which does not leave the characters with any mysteries. I almost felt cheated out of my desire to ponder their personalities, thoughts and actions - perhaps with the exception of Remedios the Beauty, where the author resists the urge to dissect her interior emotions. As a sidenote, I kept referring to the family chart in the beginning of the book quite often. Some readers have complained that the book is hard to follow due to all the similar names in the family tree that appear with regular intervals in the different generations. When I state that the story is too "easy" I am mainly referring to the portrayals of the charcters and not Marquez' elaborate construction of generational relationships. Overall, I liked the descriptions of the town, landscapes and scenery the best since Marquez left me something for my own imagination. In conclusion, I liked the book, but I did not love it </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BCCJillster</user>
	<review>One of the must reads.  It's a total experience and you just have to submerge yourself and go with the flow.  Don't try to "understand" it--just be in the moment with Marquez.  Give yourself over to this world for a while. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raphaelmatto</user>
	<review>Perfect. I haven't found any other book as magically real. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rajendran</user>
	<review>"Only a few novels change people's lives. This is one of them. As W.L.Webb wrote in the Guardian it 'continues to inspire in readers throughout the world a devotion-like conversion to some benign new religion'.A band of adventurers establish a town in the heart of the South American jungle. The occasion marks the beginning: of the world, of a great family, of a century of extraordinary events, and of a quite extraordinary novel."</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bjartur</user>
	<review>Most Overrated Book Ever </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>drvenkman</user>
	<review>One of my top 5 favorites of all time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jentifer</user>
	<review>I can't believe I managed to live so long without reading this novel. Full of "magic realism" before it was given any sort of name, this story spans the lifetimes of many extraordinary characters. It's heartbreaking and enthralling. As you read, it feels as if you are being reminded of stories you already know and had forgotten. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>overthemoon</user>
	<review>one of my favourite books of all time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>youzin</user>
	<review>it's just amazing,masterpiece </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cecilturtle</user>
	<review>Classique de cet auteur sur-doué - une saga familiale qui n'est jamais lassante </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kellibee</user>
	<review>I couldn't get past the similarly named characters. I loved the story, but it just got too confusing. I quit over half way through. I hope to finish it up one day.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Megami</user>
	<review>This fantastical tale is based around the life of the Buendia family and the village that they founded, Macondo. While epic in its scale (one hundred years) it does not read like an epic. Rather, it is like listening to an old relative recount past ancestors, with a decidedly magical-realism spin. This book is beautifully written (and translated, by Gregory Rabassa) with some of the most evocative and lyrical prose you are likely to come across. Yet it is still a very sturdy story - while you could read it for the craftsmanship of the words alone, you would miss a very good tale. Marquez has the interesting technique of referring to events in his stories before they happen, so you joyfully look out for events coming up.A word of warning - make sure that the edition that you buy/borrow/steal has a copy of the family tree in the beginning - with so many characters having the same name, and the branches of the family being so entwined, you will find yourself referring to it time and again. And don't be put off by the number of pages - even though it has over 400, it never bogs down. Once you have read this wonderful tale of a village and family gone full circle, from a beginning to an end, you will realise why it was awarded the Nobel Prize. Treat yourself. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gfriedman</user>
	<review>New York Times Book Review. "One Hundred Years of Solitude is the first piece of literature since the Book of Genesis that should be required reading for the entire human race. The novel tells the story of the rise and fall of the mythical town of Macondo through the history of the Buendía family. It is a rich and brilliant chronicle of life and death, and the tragicomedy of humankind. In the noble, ridiculous, beautiful, and tawdry story of the Buendía family, one sees all of humanity, just as in the history, myths, growth, and decay of Macondo, one sees all of Latin America. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mattviews</user>
	<review>One Hundred Years of Solitude tells the story of the rise and fall, birth and death, and vicissitudes of the town of Macondo through the history of the Buendia family. Detached and matter-of-fact, the narrative serenely unveils the happenings around the Buendia house and its prolific generations, filled with unforgettable characters. For some readers the novel might flow somewhat uneventfully and convey a breath of aridness - don't give up because after about a hundred pages or so Garcia Marquez has delineated a clairvoyant tapestry of human emotions, all types of solitude, love, and bitterness that accentuate struggles of townspeople and members of the Buendia family to the fullest actuality.Reading the book, it seems, at times, as if I'm travelling through still photographs. Life of the Macondians, as well as the Buendias, one after another generation, as it always was, fixed in its frame, just there at just that time. In a big picture, Macondo had been a prosperous place and well on its way until it was disordered, corrupted, and suppressed by the banana company, whose engineers brought on the deluge as a pretext to avoid promises made to the local workers. At the core of the novel are those who were caught up in the upheaval that unfortunately turned into a massacre killing 3000 people. The novel is beautifully written, with the author's attending to the minutest details and nuances. A recurring theme is that solitude had made (in many of the characters, men and women) a selection of their memory and had burned the dimming piles of nostalgic waste that life had accumulated in their heart, and thus had purified, magnified, and eternalized the others. People relapsed into intransigent solitude though they all live within a huge family under the same roof. As family members advanced in their years, they made detailed recapitulation (or brought to realization) of life in the house and completely changed the opinion they had held of their descendants and siblings. One Hundred Years of Solitude is a complicated analysis of human emotions and struggles through the decadence of a mythical town and its pillar family. The book evokes such clairvoyance as it scrupulously examines the most insignificant happenings and truths in a family that members of which did not see. The novel exposes to the full human flaws: incapability of love, gall of bitterness, invincible cowardice, irrational fear, and sinful pride (which led to the fall of one of the major characters, Colonel Aureliano Buendia).Final words of advice: have a notebook and genealogy chart of the Buendia family ready and do not hesitate to backtrek when names of the characters become confusing. Savor and ruminate the dreamy narrative that plunges deeper and sidles closer to core of human emotions. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stacyinthecity2006</user>
	<review>This was a really great book. I read it because it seems like a book everyone should read (several friends and Oprah telling me I should read it) so I finally got around to it. The book started out hard to read, and for me, that can be frustrating. Even though the book was harder to read (required more thought, longer time to go over the pages, understand the characters) I could tell that I was going to love it.By halfway through, I wasn't having the same trouble reading it, and I could tell that it was going to pay off in the end.The ending gave me a lot to think about. It really "wowed" me, and I had to ponder it for a while. I thought about the family in the book, the line of family. The women in the family. I thought about the things that happened, and the reality vs the story. There are a lot of very interesting and powerful themes throughout this book.In short, I'm now one of those people that will recommend this book to everyone they know. I will make my children read it. It is really amazing, and I hope everyone else will enjoy it as much as I did. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Sarahsponda</user>
	<review>This book started well for me, even entered into my dreams, but I lost steam about halfway through. The characters' names are confusing and the chapters are not linear. I kept going and it was worth the work. The end is perfect. I think the story and characters will stay with me for a long while.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dreamingtereza</user>
	<review>Garcia Marquez is simply magical!  One Hundred Years of Solitude boasts the most memorable novel ending I've encountered to date. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fleacircus</user>
	<review>http://www2.folha.uol.com.br/bibliote...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Crowyhead</user>
	<review>Probably one of my favorite books of all time, definitely one of my favorite books that was assigned reading. Incidents from this book resurface in my memory at odd times, like half-remembered dreams, strange and beautiful, or terrible and strange. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>librarychick</user>
	<review>All of the events of One Hundred Years of Solitude take place in the fictional Colombian village of Macondo.García Márquez writes in the style of magical realism, a style of writing that is analogous to surrealism in pictorial and plastic work. In magical realism, events that seem impossible – such as levitation – are commonplace, and things are not as they first seem. The theme illustrated in this style is that reality is subjective and is dependent upon the individual.In One Hundred Years of Solitude, time is almost impossible to keep track of. This is exemplified in the rapid switches in time in the narrative, the impossibly long lifespans of some characters, and the motif that "Time is moving in a circle". The characters in the novel often make the same errors as their ancestors, not learning from previous mistakes. A recurring motif is that of memory, which is often absent in Macondo.http://www.answers.comThis review has been flagged by multiple users as abuse of the terms of service
						 and is no longer displayed (show).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dawnpen</user>
	<review>...And about the hammocks that swing to an offbeat clock and the ants counting on rotten food, the kind of mouth you have to have to say it. How unfair, you might say; that its blueprint was written by a ghost, a third party, not even someone you can count on. That "home" is like that, across all that time and land, and they're expected to live with this? And they are. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>julsitos2</user>
	<review>Superbly written. It's full of magical surprises which you might find disturbing, actually it is disturbing in a morbid way that will never let you go. You need to finish the book just to find out what happened to the Buendias. The only thing negative in his novel is the depressing you-know-everyone's-gonna-die feeling that leaves a bad aftertaste when you finish the book. But a masterpiece nonetheless! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jp6v</user>
	<review>http://journal.ryoohki.net/articles/2...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ursula</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books of all time. Indescribably beautiful and tragic and full of life. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hippietrail</user>
	<review>My all time favourite. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brendak</user>
	<review>Follows the story of one family for a hundred years. Interesting book, but hard to follow because they keep naming the various generations the same thing. Covers major Colombian events like the Banana Massacre and revolutionary attempts. It's a really long book, so you have to be committed to it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0060883286</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ana05</user>
	<review>Leído </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>