<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Keola Donaghy</user>
	<review>

Weaving The Web is a wonderful blending of three distinct subjects: the history of the World Wide Web, an astute analysis of the web's "current" state, that is, where it stands in the middle of 1999, and where it's  founder believes and thinks it is headed. It is difficult to believe the  accuracy of Berners-Lee's vision of what the web could be in the time that  the web was just a dream, and how he worked to achieve it. He also dispels  the common belief that he either disdains the accumulation of wealth that  could have been his had he chosen a different path, or that he envies those  individuals who have made millions (or billions) by building on the web's  humble beginnings. He also does not begrudge the commercialization over the  web, as many academics did at the time when the web was viewed primarily as  a medium for the free sharing of ideas and information.Berners-Lee talks  in depth about the social implications of technology, and indeed the World  Wide Web is a social beast as much as it is a technological one. He does  separate, however, the duties of bodies like the W3C whose sole purpose is  to facilitate and strengthen the standards and protocols that are providing  new richness and robustness to the web. This is clearly highlighted in his  discussion of PICS, which allows for creation of rules that can facilitate  filtering of objectionable material on the web. Berners-Lee makes the clear  distinction between those who create the PICS technology, and those who  decide how it will be implemented.It is evident from this book that  Berners-Lee is far from finished in his duties. While not as radical as the  initial concept of the World-Wide Web must have been in its time, his  discussion of security, privacy, and collaboration and how they can and  should be implemented on the web should be read by anyone who wants to be a  player in Cyberspace. Berners-Lee does not hold a monopoly on great ideas  for the web, but he clearly has a grasp on the balance and understanding of  both the technology as well as its place in society that others would be  well served to strive for.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Pete Nelson</user>
	<review>

I have heard so many stories of the beginnings of the web, but for the  first time, here is how it really happened.  Tim Berners-Lee, the man who  developed the 'World Wide Web' now tells the tale of how all this  hypertext-hoopla began.Berners-Lee writes in plain english, allowing  non-programmers to share in his vision and goals for a universal (or should  that be uniform?) way to share information across the internet.  Especially  interesting is the history of the browser market itself, without all the  'browser-war' hype.Best of all, this book does not read like a technical  specification -- but is full of warmth and humor as we see Berners-Lee  bring his brainchild to light.I read equot;Where Wizards Stay Up Late:  the Origins of the Internetequot; by Katie Hafner and Matthew Lyon, and  desperately wished someone would do similar justice to the history of the  web.  Not only has someone now done just that, but that someone happens to  be the inventor of the web!  What more could you ask for?
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

This is an amazing account of how the Web came to be by the man who pulled together the ideas of many others to create it. Considering how much his invention has changed the world, he is incredibly humble in telling his  story. Very easy and fast read. Also provides a good background knowledge  of the technical side for those interested in creating for the Web. Which,  as he states over and over again, was one of the main reasons he created  it; so people from anywhere, no matter who they were, could reach other  people and share information. I found the technical information very easily  absorbed and easy to understand. But I want to point out this is NOT a  techy, how-to manual, full of jargon. Merely one man's story and an  overview of the technology and ideas surrounding him. Highly recommend to  anyone.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ann M Navarro</user>
	<review>

When I first ventured out onto the Web in 1994, little did I know that just a few years later I'd have the opportunity to meet and work with the man who's ideas put this new virtual world into motion. But there I was, at a W3C Advisory Committee meeting in San Jose, CA (Jan. 1998), sitting elbow to elbow with Berners-Lee at lunch, very much star-struck. Today, nearly three years later, I've had the pleasure to know a little bit more about Tim Berners-Lee the man, and to see him in action at various W3C meetings and conferences. Reserved, self-effacing, and even shy, you're still able to look into his eyes and see the gears turning exponentially faster than the ideas can possibly come out of his mouth, though he does try -- often being reminded to slow down so that his comments can be digested by the rest of us. Though we disagree occasionally (primarily about the universal application and suitability of namespaces), I very much respect his guidance and vision. Reading Weaving the Web was enlightening in several aspects: it filled in the holes in my knowledge obtained by talking with Tim, reading other historical works, and speaking with those who also helped make the Web what it is today. The most valuable aspect is the realization that if one truly believes in something and  perseveres in their that a good idea can become more than that, it can become something that changes the lives of us all.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>K. E. Gill</user>
	<review>

I've been online since 94, build sites, and teach web-related classes. This book is a wonderful testament to the *philosophy* of universal access -- freedom from hardware and software handcuffs that continue to plague general computing today.We (USA) don't stand for a lack of  interoperability in other infrastructure products (phone, fax, gasoline,  railroads, electricity, TV signals, etc). Why should we with computing  systems?TBL says we don't have to. And thanks to him today, on the WWW, we don't.So it lacks background on  TCP/IP. So what? This isn't a equot;technicalequot; book. It's a history  book; a philosophical treatise. One man's vision of technology as a  community building tool.Where are we going? Where *should* we be going  with this technology? How private is private - and why should you care? The  second half of the book should be mandatory reading for all regulators and  elected officials.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>David M. Chess</user>
	<review>

equot;Weaving the Webequot; gives the overwhelming impression that Tim Berners-Lee is basically a Regular Guy who was in exactly the right place at the right time.  He comes across as a relentlessly enlightened person,  beneficent toward all, earnest to the point of humorlessness.The book  tells the story of the past and present of the Web, and Berners-Lee's ideas  about the future, at a very high level.  It's not a Techie's History of the  Web; there are a few annoying technical gaffes, and not much about the bits  and bytes.  I was surprised to read some non-technical reviewers opine that  it was *too* technical.  No pleasing everyone, I guess!I'm not convinced  by Berners-Lee's idea that, if only we hook everything together well  enough, we will then be able to make computers that understand, that  reason, that figure stuff out for us.  I think the hooking-together is the  easy part, and we'll still be far from real understanding.  On the other  hand, maybe I would have been a skeptic back in 1989, too, when he was  telling people about this crazy thing called the World Wide Web...   *8)
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

Berners-Lee has created something so universal that 50 years from now  we won't even remember it had an inventor. Who can remember the inventor of television or radio? The goodness of the man shines through. He wants to  make the world a better place and he has already. He has a pespective on it  all, placing the birth of his first child above his amazing technical  achievement. This book is a good read, for those of us who used Mosaic and  those who never heard of Windows 3.1. I would compare Berners-Lee to  Gandhi, who achieved more through forceful ideas than by brute  intimidation. The greatest idea is the openness of HTML. Read and learn why  this works where other new ideas have failed.Brian Black
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>"shigs"</user>
	<review>

Written in a conversational style, Weaving the Web provides a first hand account of the people and personalities behind the creation of the WWW. In addition to Berners-Lee's account of how the web was created, he provides his thought-provoking vision of the equot;web of the future.equot; The book provides an interesting insight into Berners-Lee, himself. It is interesting to understand his motivations in creating the WWW and how he and others interacted during the emergence of this new medium - such as those at the University of Illinois (Marc Andreesen etc..). Another reason why this book so relevant is the fact that the events described are in the equot;so-recentequot; past that many of us can think clearly back when the WWW was not such a pervasive influence in our lives. From a equot;non-technical perspective,equot; I enjoyed learning about Berners-Lee positions on such controversial issues as the Microsoft Anti-trust case, Censorship on the Web, the commercialization of the web and many other issues. This book provides and excellent opportunity for the founder of the web to address many issues that touch our every day lives. From a technological perspective, Berners-Lee challenges technologists to think about the implications of the technologies that they create and the work that they do. He challenges us to take more a equot;macroequot; perspective and about the web and it's potential. He provides ideas for many new technologies that could benefit the web well into the future. He provides arguments in support of the equot;open-sourceequot; movement as well as critiques of the current patent system. The book uses technical terms but the author provides a Glossary that makes the book accessible to technicians and non-technicians alike. This is thoughtful on the author's part and should encourage anyone to pick up this book. In sum, the book can best be described as an easy to read historical account that is both thought-provoking and accessible to a general audience.
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Newt Gingrich</user>
	<review>

This is a fascinating book on several levels.  It is first a great social  history of improbable invention.  Take an English computer specialist  working at CERN (the European Nuclear Research Consortium in Switzerland)  who comes up with an idea for a worldwide system of easy communications  that merely means he has to invent the concept of the URI and URL system of  universal identifiers on a web of interconnected computers so that users  can find specific sites.  Then create a single protocol for www that  everyone on the planet will get used to including http as a protocol for  transferring information across a variety of systems, and do all of this on  a voluntary basis subsidized by a nuclear research facility that was  focused on vastly different questions.This is the story of that stunning  achievement but would be worth reading for only its own insights into  technology and how societies evolve and how a determined creative and  patient individual can impact on that evolution.  However, this book is  much more.  It is second an introduction to a way of thinking about the web  as a truly interactive system that allows people on a worldwide basis to  work together.  Berners-Lee notes that his vision of the web is not merely  passive reading and passive accessing but the creation of a truly universal  ability for people to work together and create a mutually better and more  productive society by bringing people together as individuals on a  worldwide basis.  I found myself thinking much more about truly interactive  participatory ideas with the web and how would you manage that level of  creativity and group participation.  This is a very worthwhile and easy to  read story.
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>006251587X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Budi Putra</user>
	<review>

THIRTY years ago, this smart network was not existed, but now, nearly 1 billion people has already accessed into it. Indeed, no one can imagine that a project which was initially came from a secret military project in United States in the middle-1960's could be a great business now, almost three dacade ahead. And Tim Berners-Lee's invention, web browser, in the beginning of 1990's, has been a catalyst in accelerating the progress of Internet, when a smart network can be used more than just sending and receiving electronic mail. The invention of web browser has been a quantum leap for business world to get beneficiaries and profit from it: then e-business was born.Tim is a genius who brought us WWW and HTTP reveals how he invented the web, reflects on its impact to dawn of new century. Named one of the 100 greatest midns of the 20th century by Time magazine, Tim Berners-Lee is responsible for one of that century's most important achievement: the world wide web.Written in monologue model, Weaving the Web offers insights into the true nature of the Web, showing readers how to use it into its fullest advantage. This is a behind the news story which will make you should say thanks because it's impossible to imagine our life without Internet now, and of course, for the coming years.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>