<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0151660387</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

Conspirisy therories aside, Orwell's prolific masterpiece '1984' tells of the struggle to remain human when faced with insurmountable odds. Orwell's unique vison, formed in the desperation of post-war Europe in 1947, descibes a future in which a totalitarism government controls all. The main character, Winston, is not set up to be a likeable, hopeful, hero-type protagonist, but rather, is created in the image of all men. He loses hope, attempts to fight the system with  small rebellion of his own, and fails miserably, as anyone would under the circumstances. His affair with a woman is the subject of censure in many reviews of this book, but again, it was not set up to portray a loving, human relationship, but to serve as irony in it's most bitter form. When love, honor, compassion, and other words of that calibure are erased from the human vocabulary, you have 1984. And Orwell's vision may serve as the correct one. People today lose their humanity with alarming swiftness, and we are faced with the simple choice Winston must make: fight or flee. Fight Big Brother and the government, or flee the mind and become another faceless drone like other characters in the story. While depressing, this novel also raises some interesting questions. I recommend this book to anyone who has ever questioned the fate of the human race. In short, everyone should read this book.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0151660387</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

The scariest, deepest, most intesting, and undoubtedly the best book I've ever read.  When I started it, I couldn't put it down.  When I finished it, I couldn't pick it up for fear of paranoia.  Even now, after I've finnaly somewhat gotten over it, there are still some nights I can't sleep thinking about this unbelievably incredible book.  It's ten times scarier than any Stephen King novel, and it's at least as deep, if not deeper, than anything written by Poe or Shakespeare.  This book should undoubtedly be a requirement for anyone in the entire world living under any form of government.  The story takes place in 1984, but it could be set in 2084 and not much would change.  There is absolutely nothing I've ever read which even comes close to projecting the kind of heavy, depressing, absolute fear which uterly consumes the reader and stays with them forever.  Of course I would recommend this book, but I must warn that it can't be treated lightly.  It will send you to the edge of paranoia, and throw you into a smothering kind of depression.  This is not a book you will soon forget, and it's not a book you can read without questioning everything you think and believe.  You'll never hear the phrase equot;Big Brother is watching youequot; again, without chills going down you're spine, and fear filling every corner of your being
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0151660387</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>B. D. Pruett "Thunderworm"</user>
	<review>

The classic original.  The reason we use the term: "Orwellian".  This is the book which predicted "The Lives of Others" The Lives of Others.  Much of Orwell's work is now part of our lexicon: "Big Brother".  This should be mandatory reading in High Schools.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0151660387</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

Orwell's 1984 is the best reason for people to read.  It demonstrates clearly and horrifically what can happen to an uneducated society that allows itself to be controlled due to it's own fear of initiative.  Anyone who asks me why I read is automatically referred to this book, which is as important now as it was when it was written.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>