<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0156260557</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cmpinto</user>
	<review>4th Quarter book. 290 pagesDifficult Loves By Italo Calvino is a Novel that contains a variety of stories.  I read the all of the stories. Calvino has unique way in grabbing his readers attention and having them be able to connect to his stories. His usage of words always had me confused and I would find myself having to re-read what I had just read. The one story that I liked the most was "The Adventure of a SOldier." Reading this story reminded me of the BAQ of How do we connect with others? We all sometimes have the need for physical touch in order for us to connect with one another, some kind of intimacy. A lot of times we come to judging eachother by our physical appearance. When Tomagra saw the widow sit next to him, he automatically started to judge how she dressed and made assumptions."She didnt move; he thought: maybe she wants this. But he also thought: Another moment and it will be too late. Or maybe she's sitting there studying me, preparing to make a scene." (190) I loved how calvino decribed his train of thoughts and how he described his actions. Many of us can relate to Tomagra, moments where you are over thinking your actions and you end up not doing what you are supposed to do, later regretting your decision. I thought it was interesting how the two characters were a soldier and a widow, where love can/is lacked in their lives. So, it made sense that maybe a stranger's touch is exactly what eachother needed in their lives for the moment. I wondered why the widow didnt say anything to him? why they didnt just talk? Maybe because calvino is trying to say that "actions speak louder than words", that physical touch is stronger than just trying to "touch" a person through verbal actions.Through out the story Tomagra is very tempted to touch this widow but he finds himself trying so hard to come up with ways to get her attention but it doesnt worlk. Finally at the end. He jumps and reaches out to her and touches her and doesnt really do anything about it. I found that really weird.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156260557</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dar1234</user>
	<review>Um livro nos mesmos moldes de O Castelo dos Destinos Cruzados - que o antecedeu em vários anos -, do mesmo autor, no qual uma série de histórias diferentes nos são contadas assim como uma série mágica de idas e vindas por lugares e situações bem diversas umas das outras. Personagens comuns, muito diferentes e, às vezes,  muito semelhantes entre si, compondo as histórias.E assim é que já na primeira história encontramos um soldado indo gozar uma licença durante a Páscoa, e que se vê às voltas com uma viúva, mais velha do que ele, num compartimento do trem em que viajavam; história na qual é possível o riso, é patente (sem trocadilho) a ansiedade de quem quer perpetrar algo ao mesmo tempo cerimonioso e devasso; e assim você vai vendo o sacrifício dele (e o seu, nalguma altura de sua vida) em conseguir, ou não, controlar a mão nas pernas, nos seios da viúva.São mesmo histórias factíveis, assombrosas, capazes de nos encontrar por aí, a qualquer hora do dia e da noite. Ítalo Calvino é um autor muito bom de se ler, bate na Sociedade, sem ser maçante nem moralista (e olha que estou falando de italiano). </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156260557</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ifjuly</user>
	<review>my favorite calvino so far, even trumps if on a winter's night a traveler... but i haven't read cosmicomics yet! </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156260557</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>piefuchs</user>
	<review>A story from this book was read at our wedding. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>