<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BiblioBollenstreek</user>
	<review>Betoverend en meeslepend over het leven van Jezus, zo zou het gegaan kunnen zijn. Grote rol en eerherstel voor Maria Magdalena. (OLD)</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Atomicmutant</user>
	<review>The Gospel According to Jesus Christ is a distinctly non-traditional novelin both style and substance.  I am intrigued by religious books by non-religious people.  (Well, non-traditionallyreligious, and non-fundamentalist, certainly).  It’s a human attempt by a thoughtful and creative soulto cut through the centuries of accumulated baggage and try to drag some relevant human truthout of the biblical stories.  I was intrigued by his treatment of Joseph, and amirror image of atonement that Jesus presents for his earthly father’s sins, Iwas mesmerized by a misty encounter on a boat between Jesus, God, and theDevil, and I was stunned by the last sentence of the book.  I really enjoyed therealistic portrayal of these well-known characters, especially the “Marys”, who cameoff as real women and not as story props.  Well done.I would be careful about who to recommend the book to, though.  Religious folkwill be put off, I’m sure and there are certainly doctrinal problems here, not the leastof which is an abortive reimagining of Jesus’ raising of Lazarus--a wonderfullymordant existentialist take on that whole affair.Non-religious folk will have to have the determination to sit through “that old storyagain”.    Of course, I found the novel to be most compelling in the areas betweenthe familiar story, where Saramago has the broader canvas upon which to paint.  Someparts felt like just going down the laundry list of events and miracles, but I suppose theyneeded to be there. I really enjoyed the writing style, I have read that it is a barrier to some readers of Saramago, but I was swept away by it.    He tends towards run on sentences, andmissing punctuation, to poetic effect.Give this one a try if you're poetically inclined and philosophically curious aboutthe Christian tradition. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bmesec</user>
	<review>Je treba vedeti, da je Jose Saramago, portugalski nobelovec, komunist. In nič kaj naklonjen našemu Gospodu Jezusu Kristusu in njegovi Cerkvi. Je pa pravi pisatelj (njegov Esej o slepoti je treba brati) in če se tak loti tako pomembne teme, kot je literarna interpretacija evangelija, lahko pričakujemo zanimive uvide. Knjiga se bere, vendar sem bil nemalo razočaran. Ne zato, ker si Saramago, po mojem precej po nepotrebnem in samo zato, da bi socialistično doktrinarsko povečal težo Jožefa, delavca, izmisli celoten Jožefov življenjepis z njegovim grehom, ki je v tem, da ni preprečil pokola betlehemskih otročičev, vred. Ne zato, ker združi Jezusa in Magdaleno v pravi meseni boemski ljubezni – nad tem naj se zgražajo cerkvenjaki, meni so se zdeli opisi te ljubezni lepi in prepričljivi. Na določenem mestu se Saramagova intuicija približa tistemu, kar se tudi meni zdi bistveno, namreč zapovedi, naj se človeka ne žrtvuje višjim ciljem, pa vse skupaj zvodeni v povsem neumestni alegoriji meglenih pogajanj med Bogom in Satanom. V zajetnem »romanu« je preveč površnega posmeha in premalo resnega poskusa razumeti Jezusovo pot in sporočilo.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>uvejota</user>
	<review>Para mi, la mejor novela de Saramago </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrlady</user>
	<review>The same way Lolita is a little more beautiful because it doesn't exactly translate into perfect English, this book is spell-binding in its story of the life of Christ, through his eyes.  It's blof and brave in the most glorious off-the-cuff, sarcastic way.  If this were the Bible, I think a lot more people would have read it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>geobyte</user>
	<review>"O filho de José e de Maria nasceu como todos os filhos dos homens, sujo de sangue de sua mãe, viscoso das suas mucosidades e sofrendo em silêncio. Chorou porque o fizeram chorar, e chorará por esse mesmo e único motivo." Todos conhecem a história do filho de José e Maria, mas nesta narrativa ela ganha tanta beleza e tanta pungência que é como se estivesse sendo contada pela primeira vez. Nas palavras de José Paulo Paes: "Interessado menos na onipotência do divino que na frágil mas tenaz resistência do humano, a arte magistral de Saramago exc ... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AleAleta</user>
	<review>I really liked the whole content of the story; it is something different and interesting. The only downside I find is that, it being a Saramago, the writing is a little complex at certain points making it tedious to read. In overall I do recommend it, but just take your time to read it. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lis</user>
	<review>Saramago nos muestra una visión humana de la vida de Jesús de Nazaret. Esta novela causó una gran polémica en Portugal, que terminó con la decisión del escritor de abandonar su país para instalarse en Lanzarote. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Hillerm</user>
	<review>http://www.hillerleiturgia.com/sarama...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mattviews</user>
	<review>Saramago deftly embraces historical facts, myth and reality and juggles them in this extraordinarily fictitious account of Jesus Christ. The novel is an in-depth psychological portrait of a savior who possesses a touch of humanity so much more substantial than the Bible claims. Jesus who is at once the Son of God, the beginning and the end, men's destiny, and a young man of the earth is an interweaving of letters, irony, spirituality, irreverence, humanity, and foible.The novel hinges on the fact that Jesus' father, Joseph of Nazareth, out of cowardice and selfishness of the heart, failed to alert the parents that King Herod had issued a decree to kill boys under the age of 3. He could have spared the lives of 27 children had he spoken up. Joseph felt the scruple of running off to save his own son but had forfeited the lives of others. The guilt he felt was exactly guilt a man may feel without having sinned or committed the actual crime himself. It was the sin of omission.To assuage his remorse that incessantly plagued him, Joseph, as he truly believed he was acting out of his own accord and obeying God's will, made strenuous effort to beget more and more children to compensate for the 27 lives. When Jesus learned about Joseph's crime, Jesus felt poignant for his father but asserted that his father was to blame for the deaths of innocent children. Joseph's sin was illustrated to full actuality as Jesus envisaged infants dying in perfect innocence and parents who had done nothing wrong. Jesus was embittered and broken at the fact that never was a man more guilty than his own father, who had sinned to save his life.Joseph's death, which was rather dramatic and undeserving, bore the scruple of his own conscience and arose the question of what awaited him after death. Would it be possible than everything ended with death? What would happen to the life's sorrow and sufferings, especially the sufferings right before the last breath? What about the memory if time is such an undulating surface than can only be accessed by memory, would memory of such suffering linger at least for a short period of time? Saramago has repeatedly made claims to explore the notion of after-death and its correlation to human existence throughout the novel.Jesus under Saramago's pen is not as perfect, impure, and righteous as the Bible portraits him to be. One sees that the savior succumbs to temptation, to not receiving the cup of death, to choose to remain on earth and not to be crowned with glory. The most provocative and controversial aspect of the book is when Jesus intervened the stoning of an adulteress, which brought him to awareness that he was living in sin with Mary Magdalene, and thus living in defiance to God's will. The sin of adultery (sexual immorality as the Bible claims) brought Jesus into open conflict with the observed law. The book is not deprived of interesting dialogues in spite of the serious overtones of theology. My favorite is the conversation in which the Devil pleaded with God to admit him into the kingdom. God curtly denied the request asserting than the good God represented would cease to exist without the evil Devil represented. In regard to the meaning of human existence and the pursuit of holiness, Saramago does leave us with an enlightening thought (with such sober dignity) that the soul, in order to be able to boast of a clean and blameless body, has burdened itself with sadness, envy and impurity. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0156001411</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cowpeace</user>
	<review>Blurp: Het evangelie volgens Jezus Christus veroorzaakte bij verschijning in Portugal veel opschudding. Toen het boek door ministerieel ingrijpen werd geschrapt van de kandidatenlijst voor de Europese Literatuurprijs, kwam het tot een forse politieke rel. 'Het bevat scènes, beweringen, uitroepen, gedachten, die een schrijver enkele eeuwen geleden op de brandstapel hadden gebracht, zonder recht op een begrafenis,' aldus een Portugese krant. José Saramago, winnaar van de Nobelprijs voor de Literatuur 1998, geeft in deze roman zijn eigen versie van het Nieuwe Testament. Voor hem is Jezus Christus een volledig menselijk wezen, derhalve ook begiftigd met seksualiteit. Zijn partner is Maria Magdalena, die in het boek uitgroeit tot een uiterst vitale vrouw, vol kracht en wijsheid. Ook de verhouding tussen God en Duivel komt bij Saramago op verrassende wijze in een nieuw licht te staan. Zijn evangelie, het evangelie van een atheïst, geeft een zeer persoonlijke en tegendraadse interpretatie van de aloude tradities. - Heel in de verte is de lach van God te horen, om ons eraan te herinneren dat de waarheid niet eenduidig is en de mens altijd ontgaat. - Publico. - Het evangelie volgens Jezus Christus zal de immpact krijgen van een torpedo en ontploffen in het hart van de katholieke dogma's. - O Ribatejo. - De schurk van dit evangelie is God zelf. - O Ribatejo. - Over De stad der blinden: - Lees deze roman en huiver. - PZC. - De tijdloze meerwaarde van De stad der blinden bevestigt de oprechte keuze van Saramago als winnaar van de prestigieuze Nobelprijs voor Literatuur. - Trouw.Samenv.: Levensbeschrĳving van Christus vanuit niet-gelovige visie.Samenv.: De R.K.-kerk heeft geen Inquisitie meer anders was het slecht afgelopen met Saramago, de Portugese schrijver van dit eigentijdse anti-evangelie. Hij verslaat het leven van Jezus Christus als dat van een zoon die rebelleert tegen een verwaten en willekeurige God de Vader. Maar al is Saramago niet in de positie van een Rushdie, Portugal stond niettemin op z'n kop toen dit boek uitkwam. Schokkend is behalve de persoonlijke, niet door geloof gestuurde, sarcastische interpretatie van het Nieuwe Testament vooral de vermenselijking van hoofdpersonen als genoemde Jezus, zijn vriendin Maria Magdalena, Jozef, Maria, met hun eigenaardigheden en behoeften die besmuikt maken omdat wij hen altijd in een sfeer van heiligheid hebben gewaand. Aardig is dat door de schrijver bij sommige delen uit het Testament verrassend kort, bij andere - de kindermoord - juist lang wordt stilgestaan. Zijn realisme is doorspekt met veel wondermooie zinsneden die hun kracht ook ontlenen aan de verrassende positie van de romanstof ten opzichte van voor iedereen overbekend, gewijd cultuurgoed. Het nederlands van de vertaling is zeer overtuigend en bruist.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>