<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Wintceas</user>
	<review>Absolutely wonderful! I only think the book is too structured, and because of that I have a feeling of artificiality.  I understand Eco is not an artist though, but a great scientist and erudite. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Doktor_Stein</user>
	<review>Es gibt Bücher, die sich nicht lesen lassen. Es gibt Bücher, die nicht zu verstehen sind. Und es gibt Bücher, die man sich nicht vorlesen lassen kann. Dazu gehört – leider, leider, leider – „Der Name der Rose“ von Umberto Eco. Natürlich – das Buch selbst ist großartig, aber seien wir ehrlich: Manche Passagen haben wir doch beim Lesen großzügig überlesen, manche haben wir geflissentlich ignoriert. Was nun beim Buch machbar ist, erweist sich beim Hörbuch als nahezu unmöglich. Gert Heidenreich ist dabei keinerlei Vorwurf zu machen. Er liest grandios. Aber spätenstens bei den ellenlangen Passagen auf Latein oder den diversen Visionen wird es haarig. Das Hörbuch umfasst 20 CDs und erschien im Hörverlag. Das Beiheft hätte ruhig etwas umfänglicher sein dürfen – beim immerhin stolzen Preis von 49 Euro für dieses Hörbuch. Aber bei den Beiheften sparen die Verlage ja gerne. Alles in allen eine schwierige Entscheidung: Einerseits ein Klassiker – anderseits extrem anstrengend zu hören. Wahrscheinlich ist man besser beraten, sich mit den gedruckten Werk zurückzuziehen und den Schlußfolgerungen William von Baskervilles zu folgen. Und billiger ist es dazu. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cmawardle</user>
	<review>A marvelous whodunit and window to the past.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>samfsmith</user>
	<review>I read this ages ago, and decided to read it again to examine more closely how it is written. This edition has a postscript by the author explaining many things about the writing of the novel.Interesting that he describes the first hundred pages as a penance or initiation for reading the novel. I found myself skimming much of the historical facts about the sects and heretics. Is all that detail really necessary? Isn’t it enough to know the facts without so much detail? I would certainly cut a lot.And it seems that the author added the extra levels of narrator (a modern translator at least twice removed from the young novice narrator) as a salve to his own ego. Odd.But at it’s core, there is the traditional detective novel, much like a story of Sherlock Holmes narrated by Doctor Watson. William of Baskerville is the “detective” and everything is narrated by the novice Adso.Much of the extra material valued so highly by Eco was, of course, removed for the movie.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KSG-Bib</user>
	<review>sehr schönes Buch, in dem es auch um Bibliotheken geht ;-) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>webreader</user>
	<review>I read this book several years ago and for a good long while, it had returned to my thoughts. Reading it again, I found timely a timely political theme.This is the story of two delegations called to a neutral setting to debate their religious positions as they relate to the influence of the Church on government. The erudite English monk, William, instructs his young acolyte on the separate paths of spirituality and government as the arguments--punctuated by a series of mysterious deaths--rage unseemly among men of holy calling.As scenes portray illicitly charged prisoners interrogated by an inquisitor who presumes guilt unless innocence is proven, and accepts the threat and practice of torture as a normal tool of investigation; the monumental pride of  principals convinced of the superiority of their rule and the inferiority of the ruled; the intolerance of opposing factions; and the disastrous consequences of secrecy--I understand why this book, first read as a finely crafted mystery, began to speak to me again during the administration of George W. Bush. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stkates09</user>
	<review>This is one of my favorite books.  The setting of an old monastery filled with old scriptoriums and libraries provides such a sense of escapism for me in terms of reading.  The plot revolves around a murder mystery that is solved with a clever sense of awareness by the semiotician main character.  Will suggest to others. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>joyfulgirl</user>
	<review>I am not sure what I think or feel about this book. It took me a long time to read, compared with most books. I found it tedious and wordy, but still enjoyable.The fact that there are many phrases in latin, and other european languages, made it difficult to read, due to my monolingualism.I am the sort of person who reads a book for enjoyment, not to pick it to pieces and analyse to find "deeper meanings." Therefore I probably missed most of the semiotics Eco intended. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bk04011</user>
	<review>The Name of the Rose by Umberto Eco is, at the most simple level, the story of a medieval Franciscan Sherlock and his Dominican Watson setting out to solve a series of murders at an Italian monastery.  These murders center on a mysterious library and a missing book.  Eco makes use of an incredible vocabulary; I kept thinking that finding the necessary English words must have been an extended treasure hunt for his translator.  Eco also uses language to create strong, complex, overwhelming visual effects, conveying powerfully the art and architecture of the place and the intense impact they had on his assistant.   The actual, so to speak “factual” ending of the story made me angry.  Anyone who knows the ending can imagine why I would be upset.   I was also angry because I felt I had been “had”.  Eco had completely tricked me regarding the storyline he actually intended.  Now that I have recovered my aplomb, I am amused and still shaking my head at Eco’s cleverness and at the extent to which the book I read had been my own creation.  The material was there but the focus was my own.  It will be interesting to go back and read TNOTR again sometime, knowing what I now know about it. I think it would be hard to read this book just for the mystery story, as there is just too much else going on.  Having read it, I am strongly tempted to tackle his others, but cautiously. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>P_S_Patrick</user>
	<review>I've read three books by this author before, and would rank two of them among my favourite novels, perhaps along with this one, I have not yet decided. This being his most well know title, I was perhaps unreasonably expecting it to be his best; I don't think it is, though it comes close. The plot is pretty good, and anyone interested in medieval life and books should be fascinated, or at least moderately interested, while fans of (murder) mysteries have plenty here to enjoy too; I cannot think of a better example of how these genres should be done than here. Readers not accustomed to Eco's style may find it a bit hard going, though fans of his who have read Foucault's pendulum should find it comparatively easy. As with his other stories there is a focus on theology, philosophy, and general scholarly things, which may not be to everyone's taste, but which many like me enjoy. It would be easy to become confused with some of this if you were not already familiar with it, especially where some of the dialogue is composed of a mixture of languages, (I'm sure he did this one or two of his other stories too), which is unintelligible those who do not know at least a bit of the languages, which can include French, German, Spanish, and Latin, if I remember correctly, though most of the non-English bits are in Latin, potential readers should not be put off by this as the book as a whole is quite intelligible if none of these languages are known. For all this though, it can be a page turner at times, and in places is quite exciting, even if some passages proceed at a slower pace. I wouldn't hesitate to recommend this book to those interested in the genre, but I think that the Island of The Day Before would perhaps feel more accessible to those not too interested in the subject matter of this book, who wanted to try a novel by Eco. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>vvstokkom</user>
	<review>Een ware nachtmerrie voor iedere bibliothecaris, maar moet men ooit van je leven gelezen hebben </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>HannahKiwi</user>
	<review>As a murder mystery, it fulfills its function perfectly: it makes us search through for clues, drops red herrings constantly, delays significantly enough to display fully our epistemophilia, 'strip-teases' the answer, and proffers enough allusions to make us feel remarkably intelligent at its conclusion.  However, where it stretches beyond the confines of genre, seeking too much to enter the realms of sexuality or religious history, it fails to maintain interest of tone or reader.  It relegates itself to a mediocrity between genres. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>andejons</user>
	<review>Det sägs att verkligt stora berättelser bjuder på en uppsjö av sätt att tolka dem; oberoende av vem, var eller när de läses kommer läsaren kunna knyta an till något i dem. I så fall har Umberto Ecos Rosens namn onekligen goda förutsättningar för att stå pall för tidens ryck. Historien är på ytan tämligen lätt att återge: någon gång på 1320-talet kommer två munkar, William av Baskerville, en åldrig franciskanerbroder, och novisen Adso av Melk, till ett italienskt kloster, känt för sitt enorma bibliotek. Den forne inkvisitorn Villhelm får av abboten i uppdrag att utreda ett dödsfall, men snart dör fler och fler av munkarna. Samtidigt är två beskickningar på väg mot klostret, som skall bli skådeplats för en förpostfäktning mellan företrädare för påven i Avignon och den tysk-romerske kejsarens legater. På ytan är det således en till högmedeltiden förlagd klassisk pusseldeckare, men som verket är fyllt med filosofiska utläggningar om än det ena, än det andra, kan man även läsa boken som en varning för blind fanatism, en betraktelse över huruvida kunskap bör släpas fri eller förbehållas de som skolats att nyttja den, som ett försök att förklara skrattets kraft, eller en introduktion till semiotiken.Den som inte är beredd att läsa långa utläggningar över olika ämnen bör inte bemödiga sig att öppna boken; den är knappast ännu en bagatell i genren historiska romaner eller ens ett rent försök att i klostermiljö försöka sga något om vår egen tid. Ofta kommer därför även långa stycken där någon viss medeltida företeelse beskrivs i närmast plågsam detalj. Samtidigt är bilden av medeltiden knappast helt riktigt: det bibliotek som klostret förfogar över och som handlingen kretsar kring sägs förvisso vara kristenhetens största, med böcker som skulle gjort greven av Fortsas grön av avund, men det marginalen till tvåan är så enorm att det blir löjligt. Samtidigt förekommer i en av skurkrollerna en fanatisk inkvisitor, som inte nöjer sig med att jaga kättare utan även är före sin tid och bränner häxor på bål – ett barbari som inkvisitionen inte skulle bli inblandad i  förrän ett helt sekel senare.Nåväl, hur är då läsvärdet? Högt, för den som kan acceptera eller välkomna det hårda tuggmotståndet. Mordgåtan är kompetent hanterad, det filosofiska materialet är tankeväckande, även om det ibland förefaller som Eco slår knut på sig själv för att kunna få sina hjältar att hysa »moderna« åsikter om till exempel kvinnans roll i samhället, även om William troligen är långt mindre anakronistisk än man kan tro. Om man är det minsta intresserad av att sätta sig  in i annorlunda sätt att tänka bör man definitivt ge Rosens namn ett försök. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>the_awesome_opossum</user>
	<review>The Name of the Rose is a fascinating, complex book that begins as a murder mystery/thriller and ends as a treatise on history and theology and literature...and still remains a thriller. It is narrated by Adso, a novice in a monastery who has accompanied his master William to investigate a suspicious death of a monk. But monks continue to drop dead, at about the rate of one a day, as William struggles to uncover both the murderer and the motives.The writing is characteristically complex, full of Latin and obscure literary allusions. Don't get bogged down in it; it sets the mood for a monastery full of monks copying out their obscure Latin texts. But the plot is amazingly constructed; the vivid characters are placed exactly how they need to be, the plot twists and turns in the right places, and Adso, an innocent youth, is a good guide for the reader through the action. I had so much fun reading this book; I thought it was incredibly engaging and satisfying </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tuckerresearch</user>
	<review>A brilliant novel, taking a theological Sherlock Holmes to 1327.  The narrator, Adso of Melk, appeals because he does what any thinking man does, he is furiously engaged in a battle between his heart and his head.  The mystery is intriguing, and the characters are drawn well, once you begin remembering which esoteric medieval name goes with which person.  The book does have long historical and theological passages, which serve to make the book better if you are of a scholarly bent (compare to Moby-Dick), though it might harass readers more used to "action-packed" novels.  There is a lot of Latin, with a smattering of other languages, so I recommend buying The Key to The Name of the Rose as a help. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tegmiles</user>
	<review>Bhè, che dire: l'opera più bella che abbia mai scritto Eco. Lo consiglio vivamente! </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>arukiyomi</user>
	<review>An amazing book that, for a first novel, is a great feat of literature. There’s so much going on that it’s very hard to review it concisely.What did I love, well, i loved the whole murder mystery that the book is based around. That’s a great device. But what I loved especially here was the setting, a 14th century abbey where it is the monks who are victims, suspects and detectives.Using that setting, Eco is able to have a free hand to introduce...What did he introduce? Read the rest of the review and comment at Arukiyomi... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>faulknerd_2000</user>
	<review>One of my favorite novels of all time.  It alternately literate, thrilling, and sensual.  Despite being vividly set in the Middle Ages, it also speaks to our turbulent times with debates about religion and science. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>krishmp</user>
	<review>One of the worst books i ever read. i can't understand why i didn't drop it after i had struggled through the first few pages, but it was just probably me not knowing how to cut my losses. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hermit_9</user>
	<review>I read this too long ago for much in the way of detail here. I just love Eco. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>koalamom</user>
	<review>I found this book interesting in parts and tedious in others.  I often got lost in the rhetoric, felt the author said everything about a certain topic that could ever be said. I scanned a lot to get past a lot of words that seemed to have little to do with the plot or even contribute to it.  It wasn't a bad book, just too many words.  I picked it up at a sale because I had seen the title for years in the daily crossword - Eco is a nice name to use in crosswords. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wisewoman</user>
	<review>I just finished this novel, and I feel a sort of pride in the accomplishment, but it is mixed with uncertainty. Pride because I finally made myself read this book that was intimidating me, and uncertainty because I know I missed half the allusions in this book, trudging heavyfooted through halls of glass. I'm not really sure what the title has to do with the story. I probably missed an allusion to roses in my haste to get to the action. I read very quickly. Or perhaps it is an allusion to Shakespeare's rose, which would be as sweet by any other name. Maybe?The story is this: William of Baskerville is like a medieval Sherlock Holmes who has renounced his former position as an inquisitor to devote himself to less troubling work. The story is told from the perspective of Adso, a young novice who is drawn with William into the dangerous intrigue of a rich abbey in Italy. The abbot has requested William's help in unraveling the mysterious death of one of the abbey's illuminators, Adelmo. But Adelmo's death is just the beginning of a series of deaths, that seem to mimic the portents of the Seven Seals of Revelation. So this is just a murder mystery, right? No. The narrative is heavily padded with long philosophical and religious discussions. The Church is in tumult over politics and popes, and is concentrating on hunting down heretics to find an outlet for its unrest. Dissident groups that teach that Christ lived in poverty and owned nothing are targeted in particular by the wealthy Church. There are also long debates on the value, function, and proper place of laughter... which is somewhat ironic, as the book really wasn't funny at all. The only slightly humorous parts were the chapter synopses that appeared at the head of each chapter and delineated what was to come in each chapter. Maybe it was just me, but some of the descriptions were very wry. There's just so much here, so much density. So many ideas, so many unanswered questions... Should knowledge be free to all, or is its worth increased when it is hoarded and protected from the unworthy? Are human events guided by chance or destiny? Are books really so dangerous as the book that kills every monk who touches it? And is religion the labyrinth where men die suffocated, where we meet the Devil laughing?I guess I will take refuge in my lack of knowledge and pass this off as a review for readers like me, who don't know Latin and haven't a clue about the political situation in medieval Italy. I read this book because I have always been intrigued by the title, though I was intimidated by the vast learning and sprawling philosophy of its author. I finally screwed up my courage to tackle it and found that it wasn't so terrifying as I thought. It's heavy, yes, but even if you don't get all the philosophy, there is a decent story underneath. Overall, I enjoyed this book and I'd like to think I wasn't completely buried under all the heavy philosophy. Don't be intimidated if you're not a scholar; if you can manage the long digressions, there is much to enjoy here. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jmcilree</user>
	<review>Typical Eco: convoluted and fun. But it did drag on.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zuzi</user>
	<review>Obwohl es schon ein altes Buch ist, kann man es weiterempfehlen. Auch die Verfilmung des Buches sollte man sehen.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ysol</user>
	<review>Detta är en av mina favoriter bland Ecos många romaner. Utspelar sig under medeltiden och man förstår tidigt hur insatt Eco är i den medeltida tanketraditionen och filosofin. I denna thriller blandas medeltida kristen kultur, religion och historia på ett för läsaren övertygande sätt. Den är spännande och medryckande i sin berättarstil. När jag lägger ifrån mig boken kännerjag mig övertygad om att det måste ha varit såhär den medeltida människan levt och tänkt i sina kloster. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TimONeill</user>
	<review>If I had to spend a year on a desert island and was only allowed to take one book, this would be it.At the time of its publication, one reviewer described `The Name of the Rose' as "a book about everything". At first glance, it may seem to be a book largely about obscure Fourteenth Century religious controversies, heresies and sects, with a murder mystery mixed in. But this is a book that rewards repeat readings (I've just finished it for the seventh time), and the heart of the novel is in its exposition of semiotics - the world as a blizzard of signs and life and thought as their constant interpretation. Just as Brother William of Baskerville guides the naïve Adso through the world of the monastery and the wider world of knowledge and reason, so Eco guides the reader through a story where few things are what they seem and everything can be read several ways.Even the `obscure Fourteenth Century sects', which many readers find either bewildering, dull or both, represent far more than they seem at first glance. The long controversy over the poverty of Christ and its application in the medieval Church forms the focus for a wide-ranging analysis of how ideals can motivate and inspire different people in different ways. In this novel we find skeptics (like William), mystical non-conformists (like Umbertino de Casale), terrorists and revolutionaries (like the Dolcinite heretics) and fundamentalists (like Jorge and Bernard Gui). At the time of its first publication, the parallels between the book's religious politics and modern manifestations of the same ways of thinking, including Cold War political expediency and terrorists like the Red Brigades, would have been obvious to Italian readers. These days, in the wake of 9/11 and the Iraq War, Eco's analysis has not lost any of its resonance.Some warnings for new readers - if you think (the truly appalling) `The Da Vinci Code' was "masterful writing", you probably want to save yourself time and effort and read something else. It's not as daunting as many make out, but "Rose" is far from a light read. Eco also deliberately made the first 100 pages a difficult read, but stick with it. All those obscure politics and odd names do make some sense after a while.Secondly, many reviewers have complained about the untranslated Latin passages. Despite what some of them have said, these are rarely more than a line or two and usually short lines at that. Medievalists will recognise most of them anyway (they are quotes from the Vulgate, Occam and Aquinas and so on, and usually famous ones), but non-specialists will usually get the essence of them from their contexts. In almost all cases they are roughly translated or paraphrased in the dialogue that precedes or follows them anyway, so they aren't actually `untranslated' at all - they just look that way.Thirdly, people who approach this novel merely as a medieval whodunit a la the Brother Caedfel mysteries are likely to find `Rose' a strain. While the mystery story forms the basis of the plot, there is a lot more to this novel than plot. Some have said they found the mystery clichéd and derivative of other mysteries. Ummm ... yes - Eco is a postmodernist. It's *meant* to be derivative.The real joy of this novel is its layers of meaning, which is why it's one that can be read and re-read with new discoveries every time. It's a delight to read and great exercise for the mind and spirit, as well as a counter to those who think the Middle Ages was simply a period of superstition and ignorance. Far from being an anachronism or a prefigurement of more `enlightened' times, William of Baskerville represents the medieval voices of reason, innovation and logic that are ignored by most popular representations of this badly misunderstood period.A must read - but with your brain well and truly in high gear. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gottadance</user>
	<review>A well crafted mystery -- spell binding from beginning to end. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TadAD</user>
	<review>I found it unreadable. </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Schmerguls</user>
	<review>1928 The Name of the Rose, by Umberto Eco  translated from the Italian by William Weaver  (read 19 May 1985) This has the guise of a detective story but is laid in 1327 in a monastery in Italy, and is filled with philosophy and medieval learning.  I did not enjoy the book. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CarlosMcRey</user>
	<review>An unidentified scholar discovers a manuscript narrating William of Baskerville's mission to arrange a meeting between religious and political factions in 14th Century Europe and a series of murders in the unnamed monastery which place that meeting in jeopardy. This is the story not of the unidentified scholar, but of William, himself a scholar, and Adso of Melk, the narrator and author of the manuscript, as they seek to uncover the pattern at work behind the murders. Eco's scholarship shines through in his description of monastery life and the way he ties the theology into the social and political tensions of the era. While the murder mystery drives the narrative, the story really deals with the power of ideas and the value of open inquiry. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>inekegroters</user>
	<review>Spannend boek, historisch boek, literair boek. Heel veelzijdig, om helemaal in te duiken. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gwendydd</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books of all time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mdshrk1</user>
	<review>William of Baskerville, an ex-Inquisitor, goes to an Italian monastery, finds murder, heresy, and one of the best libraries of its time. I like this book more for the insights it gives into Catholicism, than for the mystery, though the mystery is excellent. Eco's philosophical insights into religion, books, and words make this a compelling read.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jimworm</user>
	<review>Eco is brilliant. Great characters, intriguing setting, compelling plot, amazing prose. Here and there it's tough-going, maybe a little dry, but totally worth the effort. A wonderful, captivating story, beautifully told. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Patentnonsense</user>
	<review>Eco builds his medieval world so knowledgeably and carefully that its destruction is painful.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gabry_enzo</user>
	<review>è strano ma questo è l'unico libro che ho iniziato a leggere credo una ventina di volte per poi arrivarew a pagina 15 e non riuscire ad andare avanti.. non so il motivo...ma ho come una sorta di rifiuto cche inizia sempre dallo stesso punto....</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jssdrlnd</user>
	<review>I've wanted to read this book for a long time, and now finally I'm getting the chance to do it. While the double frame story was a little off-putting — causing me to skip ahead a bit until I got the meat of the book — I'm fully engrossed by what looks like a murder mystery turned on its head. All the theology is fascinating as well.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hunkydory</user>
	<review>Upon being forced into reading this book for a University essay as the book I wanted to complete the essay upon was all booked out at the library, I managed to find my favourite author and favourite book in a massive stroke of luck. The Name of the Rose by Umberto Eco weaves philosophy, religion, history and mystery into a complex, intriguing and deep story with fantastic characters, awesome plot concepts and arguments that ensured I would go on to research various religious and philosophical factors and concepts, greatly increasing my general knowledge and interest for various fields of study.The mystery, however, is not sidelined to make way for pure philosophy, as Eco manages to interlock the two aspects of the novel with great vision and intelligent writing. A novel that I have read numerous times and hope to re-read many times in the future, a mystery for the ages and for the intelligent, and those who at least want to become a bit more intelligent! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MrsLee</user>
	<review>Set in the 1300s in an Italian monastery, The Name of the Rose is a mystery revolving around missing manuscripts, convoluted relationships and theological debates. William of Baskerville sets out to find the culprit who seems to be killing a monk for every judgment day listed in the Apocalypse. His helper, the novice Adso, narrates this tale from memory. Adso is a young man, just forming his theological ideas and beliefs, and finding them being stretched and challenged by the events happening around him.I enjoyed this book, the mystery was keen, the theology interesting, and the history revealing. I must say though, that while I enjoyed much of the talk between William and Adso, some of the other characters did go on a bit. It is a very long, slow paced book, and I found myself skimming some of the long lists of details and arguments near the end. I became impatient to get on with the mystery. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jhack</user>
	<review>Sicuramente da leggere, anche (e soprattutto) se si è visto il film. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>morganc5</user>
	<review>A fantastic text!  I could not stop reading until I came to the end. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Carolus</user>
	<review>Critique habituelle et lassante du Moyen Âge et de l'Église, doublée d'une insupportable pédanterie. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mry</user>
	<review>My all-time favourite book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>EloE</user>
	<review>In einer norditalienischen Benediktinerabtei geschehen mysteriöse Todesfälle. Die Gäste Bruder William und sein Schüler Adson werden mit der Untersuchung beauftragt und stoßen auf eine Verschwörung, die sich um die weltberühmte Bibliothek der Abtei dreht.Um diese furiose Kriminalgeschichte herum erzählt Eco von Inquisition und Investiturstreit, den Problemen des Zölibat, zeichnet ein hochdetailliertes Bild der Glaubenskämpfe innerhalb der Kirche und nimmt die Unterschiede zwischen Benediktinern und Franziskanern unter die Lupe. Wohl nicht zu Unrecht wird Der Name der Rose oft als Professorenbuch tituliert, aber gerade die Tiefe und Komplexheit machen den Reiz aus. Ich habe selten so viel gelernt beim Lesen eines Romans, und langweilig ist es nur äußerst selten geworden. Klasse!Die immer wieder eingestreuten lateinischen Passagen tragen sehr zur Atmosphäre bei, dass sie nur teilweise im Anhang übersetzt sind, ist aber frech. Zum Glück sind einige meiner total eingeschlafenen Lateinkenntnisse bei der Lektüre wieder aufgewacht. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bkoopman</user>
	<review>Set in Italy during the Inquisition, conflicts abound.  Good versus evil becomes high intrigue when institutions must build layers of secrecy to protect their power, and the power grows to become more important than the sanctity of life.  Solving the mystery of murders eventually ends in the destruction of the Abby and its beautiful buildings.  But in the end, nothing is more important than the human beings which we are to serve, and when that perspective is lost, evil is given a foothold.  I enjoyed this story very much, and might need to re-read it in order to fully comprehend the nuances, the layers and the Latin. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SanctiSpiritus</user>
	<review>The learned  scholarly author, Umberto Eco has heaped mystery upon mystery in this epic tale.  This book may be considered esoteric, as it does take more of an effort to read.  However, the reader shall be rewarded!  The reader will learn the depravities of 14th century.  He will also become apprised of examples of how the Catholic church warped the message of Jesus Christ.  The book is a venerable deposit of knowledge that gives the mind a justified work-out. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fyrefly98</user>
	<review>Summary: Adso of Melk, our narrator, is a young Benedictine monk traveling with William of Baskerville, a Franciscan and ex-inquisitor, in the year 1327.  William has been summoned to an abbey in Italy to investigate the mysterious death of one of the brothers.  The abbey is home of one of the greatest - and strangest and most secretive - libraries of its time.  After Adso and William arrive at the abbey, more murders occur... murders bound up with the secrets of the library, the nighttime activities of the abbey, and a dire prediction of the coming of the apocalypse.Review: I'm going to start my review at the end, with the author's postscript.  In this, he says that the first 100 incredibly dense, difficult pages are intentionally dense and difficult, to serve as a "penance" or "initiation" for the reader, to make sure he is "worthy" of reading the rest of the novel.  I rather wish I'd read the post-script first, and saved myself the journey, because: what an incredibly arrogant way of going about writing a book!  I don't think of myself as particularly unintelligent, impatient, or incapable of dealing with books with complex themes or a lot of historical detail, but apparently I'm not intelligent, patient, or capable enough to be a "worthy" reader of Eco's writing.  Five hundred and fifty pages of which at least 400 are Catholic history and debates about obscure points of theology and untranslated bits of Latin, padded around a mystery that was good and mysterious, but generally overlooked in favor of more ramblings about heresy and poverty and whether or not Christ laughed... I'm sure it's a symptom of my unworthiness, but that's not what I want in a novel.  In general, apart from being dense and difficult, which it surely was, I also found the tone to be arrogant and demeaning - as though the whole point of the book was to demonstrate how much smarter (excuse me, "more erudite") than you the author is, and if you didn't get it or didn't like it, it's because you're too dumb or low or common to understand true Art, but certainly it wasn't through any fault of the work itself.  Which: I call shenanigans.  The mystery was good, and bits of the writing were very evocative, but in general I found this book to be a huge struggle: dry, boring, and willfully obtuse.  Eco can keep his worthy readers, I'm going to stick to books that are actually enjoyable. 1.5 out of 5 stars.Recommendation: If I want some (read: 400 pages of) ecclesiastical debate mixed in with my historical mystery, I'll ask for it, thanks.  Otherwise, you can keep your erudite babbling to yourself.  I'm clearly in the minority here, but I don't think it's worth your bother unless you've got a masochistic streak to your reading habits. </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>a.holger</user>
	<review>Das erste Buch von Eco, das ich gelesen habe und immer noch das Beste. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jjmachshev</user>
	<review>If you liked "The DaVinci Code", then you should definately pick up this book. It has monks, demons, murder, etc all wrapped up in a fascinating mystery from the Middle Ages. Delicious... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jasonpettus</user>
	<review>(Reprinted from the Chicago Center for Literature and Photography [cclapcenter.com]. I am the original author of this essay, as well as the owner of CCLaP; it is not being reprinted here illegally.)The CCLaP 100: In which I read a hundred so-called "classics" and then write reports on whether or not I think they deserve the labelBook #7: The Name of the Rose, by Umberto EcoThe story in a nutshell:In one of the more fascinating stories of how a novelist was first drawn to his profession, scholar Umberto Eco was actually an Italian history professor and Medieval expert for years before ever turning to creative writing; according to legend, it was his thrilling and exacting retelling of actual Dark Age stories that inspired his friends to keep urging him to write a novel based in those times, which he finally did in the late 1970s. As such, then, The Name of the Rose is a bizarre amalgam that you scarcely ever find in contemporary literature -- a genre actioner (murder mystery) with a lot of melodramatic elements at its core, but at the same time a detailed historical look at actual 1300s Europe, with a big part of the reason to read this book being so that one can be exposed to the meticulous detail of Eco's prose on the subject, from the period's clothing and architecture to its religious structures and philosophies. But on top of this, turns out that Eco is a postmodernist and accomplished semiotics expert as well, turning the book not just into a potboiler mystery and historical novel but indeed an entire thesis on the nature of language itself, on the meaning behind symbols, and on why human behavior repeats itself so often no matter which age you study, and no matter what the rationale behind such behavior during any given age.Plotwise it's the story of a Franciscan monk named William of Baskerville, which is just the start of the sly references to Sherlock Holmes Eco deliberately inserts; turns out that William is also British, a champion of logic and deductive reasoning, and even has a clueless teenage assistant named Adso who stands in symbolically for the equally clueless audience. William is in Italy, helping a fellow monk investigate a mysterious death in the fortified abbey where the man leads; turns out, in fact, that this is one of the largest and most renowned of all the Christian Dark-Age monastery libraries, attracting an international team of egghead monks and a scholarly atmosphere more akin to modern universities. Both the novel and the investigation take place over seven days at this fortress/abbey, where William and Adso spend their time gathering clues, pontificating on all kinds of subjects that intellectuals in the 1300s pontificated on, and examining in detail such historical details as the church's then-ongoing debate over whether it's better to be rich or poor, as well as why the Benedictine monks and the Franciscan ones hated each other so intensely back then in the first place. This being a murder mystery, of course, the actual plot is something best left for the reader to discover on their own, although I'll warn you that the actual "whodunit" part isn't very suspenseful; as mentioned above, the real point of this being a murder mystery is for Eco to show just how similarly humans behaved back then as we do now, even as the times themselves inspire completely different motivations and excuses. (So in other words, a lot less "I love my baby's mamma" in the 1300s, a lot more "The devil made me do it.")The argument for it being a classic:Fans of this novel (and there are a whole lot of them; it's hard to dislike this book, frankly) argue that this book deserves the "classic" label more quickly than a lot of other contemporary novels do (after all, the book's only 27 years old at this point), precisely because it deals with issues from an age of classics; so in other words, because it's set in Medieval times, is written in Dark Age vernacular and includes historical details worthily accurate of the respected academe Eco is, fans claim that of course The Name of the Rose will eventually be a classic, such a foregone conclusion that we might as well declare it one now. Ah, but there's also a much stronger argument for this being considered a classic right now; as mentioned, many of those who study the esoteric academic field of semiotics claim that the novel is a perfect example of what they do, explained in layman's terms so that non-academes can finally get it. As such, then, these people claim that The Name of the Rose is not just an exciting DaVinci-Code-style historical thriller, but also a densely layered examination of stories about stories about stories, of symbols about symbols about symbols, of the meaning behind meaning behind meaning. Yeah, see what they mean when they say that semiotics is a hard thing to explain to the general public?The argument against:The main argument against this being a classic seems to be one brought up a lot with well-written yet contemporary books ("contemporary" in this case being any less than half a century old) -- that the book is simply too new to be able to reasonably judge whether it should rightly be called a timeless classic, one of those fabled "books you should read before you die." For just one example, when The Name of the Rose first came out in 1980, it was the first time anyone had ever tried setting a rational Holmesian-style mystery story within a Medieval monastery; in the years since, we've had all kinds of projects on the subject, including a popular weekly BBC/Masterpiece series. It's a great book, even its critics are quick to point out, even if somewhat on the dry side at points (ugh, all those debates about papal decrees); but who's to say if anyone's going to even remember this novel a hundred years from now, or the notoriously spotty career Eco has since had as a novelist. (Don't forget, Eco is mostly a scholar and historian; although considered a rockstar in the academic world, his reputation as a writer of fiction is much more contentious.)My verdict:So let's make it clear right off the bat -- that from a pure entertainment standpoint, The Name of the Rose is one of the most delightful novels I've read in years, years. It's funny, it's smart, it's insightful, it's thrilling, it's nerdy; Cheese And Rice, it's everything a lover of books could possibly ever want from a well-done one. But is it a classic? Well, unfortunately, I think I'm going to have to agree with the critics on this one; that although it could very well become a classic one day, one of those Catcher in the Rye style "one-hit wonders" that populate so many lists, I think it's simply too early to make such a call either in a positive or negative way, especially considering Eco's otherwise spotty career as a novelist. That's part of the point of "classics" lists existing, after all, and why those who care about such lists take them so seriously; because ultimately such a designation should reflect not only how good a book itself is, but how well it's stood the test of time, of how relevant it's continued to be to generation after generation, of how timeless the author's style and word-choice. One always has to be careful when adding newish books to such lists, especially novels less than 30 years old, because we have no idea at this point how such books are going to stand the test of time; load up your classics list with such titles, and your list suddenly becomes worthless fluff, as relevant and important as a whole evening of handing out freakin' Quill Awards. It's for this reason that I'm excluding The Name of the Rose from my own personal Canon, although still highly encourage all of you to actually read it, just from the standpoint of pure enjoyment.Is it a classic? Not yet </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Monastic murder mystery.An atmospheric story of a monk investigator and his naive but affable sidekick as they try and discover the truth behind a series of murders in what is basically an academic setting for the time.The pair have to walk a fine line between getting in trouble with the inquisition, doing the right thing, and working out what is going on with the various strange secret organisations in and around the place.Very entertaining.http://notfreesf.blogspot.com/2008/03... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>briandarvell</user>
	<review>Begun: 12.12.2007Finished: 26.02.2008Rating: 4/5The first wonderful scene is near to the beginning of the story when Adso is enraptured by the grand display above the entrance to the church. Many great and frightening things lead him to stand and stare at it for a long time, taking in every detail. This was an interesting scene and will likely have important meaning later in the story.The scene when William and Adso enter the scriptorium for the first time is a wonderful experience too. The light majestically lightens the entire hall due to the great number of windows present. There are many monks in the vicinity, bent over their work of copying or illuminating, and they eventually look at the fabulous and highly imaginative work which was being completed by the now murdered monk: Adelmo.The part of the story just before midpoint where William and Adso sneak into the labyrinthine library through the ossuary beneath the church is a terrific exercise in true subterfuge fiction writing. This has been one of my most favorite parts of the story and I read through this in a devouring pace. The chase scene and the time where they are lost through the various polyhedrical rooms which have Latin scrolls above their doors and Adso becomes intoxicated by a rare fume or scares himself silly due to coming across his own reflection in the mirror. All is truly majestically written.Not much has happened for the many pages surrounding the two-thirds portion of the novel. It has become a little slow and much of the ’story’ seems just a historical recounting of the political subterfuge surrounding the Pope John and his stay at Avignon. Additionally, much of the story around here is also dealing with the various religious factions that sprouted during this time such as Fra Dolcino and the Minorites.After finally finishing the story I am happy to have read it. The ending was strong and wrapped up the story in its entirety well. It was hard for me to follow much of the very religious-based material that the author wrote about. This caused many longer passages throughout the story to be a bit lost on me. I would happily read another Umberto Eco novel again -although not in the near future for its depth and the required commitment can be a little daunting.From: http://briandarvell.wordpress.com/200... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jhowell</user>
	<review>I wanted to like this book more than I did -- I love the mystery novel that is also literature -- however . . . this novel had ever so slightly more tedious parts that it did enjoyable parts.The crime solving and the mysteries of the labyrinthine library were intringuing and well-done. But the droning, rather dense and mystic religious passages did me in -- while admirable in terms of evocative imagery, on the whole too numerous.  (Not to mention all the untranslated Latin which quickly grew tiresome.)Overall, although I was able to appreciate this novel on its many levels -- a 'whodunnit,'  an ideological allegory, and book about books -- I did not love it, as it was hard work without enough reward.  I do have a feeling, though, that it will have made a lasting impression on me. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Anne51</user>
	<review>Een moord op een monnik die plaatsvindt in de bibliotheek van een klooster en een wijze monnik die met zijn hulpje de moord oplost: een zoektocht naar waarheid. Beter kan het niet worden. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SLHobbs</user>
	<review>Sometimes this was rough going, and the author could have pulled a good 100-200 pages out of the novel without hurting it at all...it would have only decreased the drag.  While I love the story, the premise, and the characters, the writing itself was...overly involved.  In both the movie and in the book, my heart hurt and bled when the library went up in flames.  I cried for the books. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>edergoncalves</user>
	<review>Lendo a descrição do pano de fundo de "O nome da rosa", um leitor desinformado, não conhecedor da obra de Umberto Eco, correria um grande risco de classificar este livro como entediante. Afinal, toda a história desenrola-se em uma Abadia e, principalmente, nos meandres de sua biblioteca. Entretanto, a astúcia e o talento de Umberto Eco tornam "O nome da rosa" além de uma fascinante obra de ficção, um dossiê sobre o cotidiano daqueles que dedicam sua vida à religião. "O nome da rosa" em nada fica a dever aos grandes clássicos da literatura investigativa. O autor cria uma intricada e belíssima história a respeito dos segredos que a biblioteca de uma abadia guarda. Mas mais do que isso, o autor desnuda a intimidade da vida monástica, especialmente em um tempo de extrema repressão moral. As conseqüências inevitáveis deste modo vida são retratados com a sutileza requintada que é característica de Umberto Eco. Sem dúvida nenhuma, uma excelente leitura.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MbuTseTseFly</user>
	<review>Fabuleux </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>openset</user>
	<review>This is the third Eco book I've read, after Baudolino and Foucault's Pendulum, and I'm beginning to notice a pattern.  Those works are complex, heavy on the symbolism, brilliant, but have weaker or difficult to accept climaxes and endings.  Name of the Rose follows--or should I say establishes--this pattern.  There are long passages of symbolic exposition by the narrator that slow the pace too much, but at the same time add a richness to the story that a direct murder mystery would lack.  The final paragraphs sway off unexpectedly as though the narrator fought off senility up to that point and could no longer contain himself.  A more purposeful ending would have been better.  The climactic revelation made me step away from the story and ask myself: "Is both the motive and the philosophical justification behind it really plausible?"  I'm still not entirely convinced it is, but then the scholastic setting and characters of the story cause me to doubt myself.Despite those possible weaknesses, the mastery of Eco is evident.  He knows how to write history and how to drive his symbols and themes to great effect.  I'll be reading this one again with pleasure to pick up the subtler points.  The various untranslated Latin phrases and titles are not required to be understood to enjoy the story, and the most plot-wise important portions are actually translated for the reader.  The rest are minor rewards for the dedicated classicist and antiquarian. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>scarletslippers</user>
	<review>"Books are not made to be believed, but to be subjected to enquiry."Big book, big ideas.The murder-mystery element is easy enough to follow, but the religious stuff - though interesting - is much harder, and I'm not really sure I've understood the politico-religious machinations going on. However, I do find some of the intellectual ideas thrown up quite fascinating. William of Baskerville is a sympathetic character - intelligent, questioning, logical, a compassionate ex-Inquisitor: "I lacked the courage to investigate the weaknesses of the wicked, because I discovered they are the same as the weaknesses of the saintly." Is it always possible to distinguish between good and evil? The distinction isn't always clear, and changes over time.I find intriguing the idea of the library which no one but the librarian and his assistant may enter - 'This place of forbidden knowledge is guarded by many and most cunning devices. Knowledge is used to conceal, rather than to enlighten.' My rational mind believes knowledge-is-good, but I suppose there's also the harking back to the Tree of Knowledge - knowledge wrongly applied ('a little learning is a dangerous thing') - but who has the right to tell us the knowledge we may have access to and that which we may not? What constitutes 'good' and 'bad' knowledge seems to me as spurious as some of the definitions of heresy described in the novel. "What I meant is that there is little difference between the ardour of the seraphim and the ardour of Lucifer, because they are always born from an extreme igniting of the will." Knowledge might be dangerous but ignorance, I think, is more so.I like the political parallels in some of the religious questions. William tells his pupil, Adso, that 'The faith a movement proclaims doesn't count: what counts is the hope it offers'. He makes the point that heretical movements have found favour among the 'simple' people because hope is what heresy seems to offer (rather like the hope offered by New Labour!!) and that 'The people of God cannot be changed until the outcasts are restored to its body' (in the same way, perhaps, that a good government must take into account the views and problems of the poor and disaffected, not just those of the rich and powerful).William understands the power of love, that love can be destructive as well as enriching: "There is nothing in the world...that I hold as suspect as love, for it penetrates the soul more than any other thing. Nothing exists that so fills and binds the heart as love does." When love turns sour, it can be the most dangerous thing in the world.Adso's one sexual experience, an almost mystical encounter with a girl he finds in the kitchen and whose name he never knows, is described using material from the Song of Songs (which is erotic, no matter which way you slice it - I know it's symbolic, and isn't meant to refer to human sexual love, but I would find it impossible not to read those beautiful, sensual phrases in any other way). Adso knows that he sinned, but he sees the experience in positive terms - he thinks of the girl with love, the encounter 'right and good and holy'. The girl is a poor peasant girl who sells her sexual favours in exchange for much-needed food, but Adso's love for her is ennobling, even though it's a completely doomed love.This is very much a book about books, however. The key to the mystery of the monks' deaths seems to lie in the secret room of the library. The monks seem to have died because they read a particular book. Adso thinks of the library as 'the place of a long, centuries-old murmuring, an imperceptible dialogue between one parchment and another, a living thing...a treasure of secrets emanated by many minds, surviving the death of those who had produced them...'The suppressed book, which proves to have been the murder weapon, was poisoned by Jorge, who refuses to admit that laughter can be 'a force for good'. His argument is that laughter is a means to distract people from fear - from fear of the Devil. 'And from this book there could be born the new destructive aim to destroy death through redemption from fear.' He refuses to think of himself as a murderer - 'Each died according to his sins. I was only an instrument'. Splitting hairs. He is surely morally responsible.In the end, the library is burned to the ground, along with the church and the rest of the abbey. A poisoned mind, a poisoned book; a blind man who sees only what he wants to see. [July 2004] </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hyperpat</user>
	<review>http://www.amazon.com/review/R38MC6W6... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Choccy</user>
	<review>What a mesmerizing (yet sometimes confusing) book. Five hundred pages, not including the introduction and post-script.It is basically consisted of two main plots. First was the mysterious murders of monks in an Italian Franciscan abbey on the 14th century, in which a former Inquisitor named William of Baskerville and his novice turned detectives to solve the murders. Second was the so-called historic meeting between Franciscan leaders (favored by the Roman Emperor) and their archenemy, representatives of the Pope John who resided then in Avignon. Organizing the meeting was actually the main duty of William.I have to admit that my interest lies deeper in the first plot. It's just more simple. The murders were somewhat arranged in certain fashions, mimicking the prophesied events during the sounding of seven trumpets in the Apocalypse. Plus, the Abbey itself, with all its rich legacies and precious relics, holds many secrets and intrigues; with the center of attention was its amazing library that no one can enter except the librarian. The library was said to be the most complete library in Europe, contained not only teachings on the Scriptures but also those of heretics, magicians, alchemists, etc.William of Baskerville, our monk-detective, presented a unique character with his use of logic and modern tools. His novice, Adso of Melk, well, he's your typical boyscout, but suffering from a number of delusions and inner battles (the curse of youth, perhaps). They both embarked on a fascinating adventure in the abbey, trying to solve the mystery of the library and its almost innumerable labyrinths, deciphering symbols, facing bizarre monks ranging from hostile, mysterious, frightened, excessively curious and most of all, they all have motives for killing. Most of the victims were connected to the library. Suffice to say, the murders is caused by something in the library, which should not be seen by others.The second plot? Well, couldn't say I really understand the narratives and dialogues, since they mostly involved theological debates whether monks were allowed to be poor. The Pope said the Franciscans were heretics while the accused said the Pope was corrupt. My brain is just not strong enough for that kind of thing. I love the quarreling part though, when the monks lost their temper, because it's so damn funny.Despite some desperate efforts from my parts to skip some pages of this book due to my lack of understanding, I still say this book has its own grandeur. Perhaps because if there's an existing library as magnificent as the one in the abbey, I shall be very interested to have to a visit there. Seduction does not always come from human flesh or splendid treasures, but also in knowledge. And sometimes it's even more dangerous.Will I read other Eco's works? Yeah sure, why not. Next would be the Foucault's Pendulum. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ireed110</user>
	<review>Murders by monks. Politics meet religion. Priests are people too. Books shouldn't be kept secret.I tried so hard to get into this book. I really did. Every now and then it would get interesting, but it never grabbed me for more than a few pages at a time. I could have skipped whole sections and it wouldn't have made a difference. Maybe someday I'll try again and see what all the hype is about, but there's plenty of books I'd rather read instead first. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gary237</user>
	<review>In "The Name of the Rose," Umberto Eco describes monks' attempts in medieval monasteries to obtain and preserve knowledge in writing and signs. Knowledge was limited and those who hoarded it had power. The murder mystery develops around the possession of this precious commodity shattering the religious brotherhood. Knowledge became more available over time, and valuable old books and signs were lost. Eco takes the reader on a wonderful tour of a violent and mystical era, leaving arcane signposts for guidance. It is enjoyable and necessary to decipher all of the signs in order to experience the times and the character interaction. An erotic scene occurs in the story leading to a long-lasting priestly memory. It is a memory of regret for the priest, but not due to the sexual event. It is the regret of not knowing the name of the momentary beloved. And, though the rose grows, blooms, and ultimately withers to dust, it is the name of the rose that remains forever. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>roblong</user>
	<review>Further evidence that Catholics (lapsed or otherwise) write the best novels.  As well as a compelling mystery this is as fine an evocation of another world (medieval Europe is much further removed from us now than any science-fiction fantasy) as I have ever read.  For much of the time the novel feels like the monastery in which it takes place: a supposed oasis of calm and studied learning, infested and eventually overwhelmed by a lunatic and chaotic world of millennial cults, inquisitions and internecine accusations of heresy.  When the mystery was resolved I feared the ending might fall flat but not at all, this is fascinating and challenging to the last. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fanakapan</user>
	<review>What's not to like? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stillbeing</user>
	<review>I *finally* staggered through this one. An interesting read, but terribly, terribly dense and the monk-speak, although in character, does grate after a while. There was just enough mystery, intruige and wisdom in there to keep me from giving up, but I felt some of the plot devices were too convenient or just unnecessary and the characters diverged into philosophising too often, which broke the flow of action too much. That said, there was some fantastic imagery in there and it prompted me to have a really twisted dream after reading too late into the night, so that was fun. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Caramellunacy</user>
	<review>This is another of those frame story upon frame story novels. 'The author' writes that he found and translated a book that claimed to be an accurate reproduction of the original manuscript of a medieval monk Adso of Melk. The manuscript itself was written in the monk's old age but detailed his experiences with sin, heresy, and murder in a certain monastery in his youth. As a young novice, Adso accompanied Franciscan William of Baskerville, renowned for his deductive and reasoning powers, to this monastery to help prepare for a meeting between the Pope and one of the more radical proponents of the poverty of Christ - a monumental occasion with important political overtones. During their time at the monastery, however, William (and Adso) are drawn into the investigation of mysterious deaths and other occurrences around the abbey. This book was slow going. While Eco captures the feeling and flow of medieval texts admirably, I found much of the novel too obscure for my liking. The passages in Latin were frustrating and difficult to comprehend in context, as were several of the long historical passages as they referred to situations, political developments, and people I was unfamiliar with. I read part of this novel in a class in Italy in which the professor explained a great deal of the history, but I no longer remember most of it. Some sort of gloss or annotated edition would have served me better. This was a highly interesting book to study and I actually learned a great deal about medieval life and political strains - as well as different concepts of heresies. But as a pleasure read, the vehicle of the mystery simply wasn't worked out satisfactorily for me. I wanted a few more hints dropped or some indication so that I could puzzle along with the 'detectives' (I'm quite certain that 'Baskerville' was a blatant Sherlock Holmes reference). I also found the postscript by the author extraordinarily uninteresting. To me it seemed rather self-congratulatory at times and at others so full of 'process' that it read remarkably like the explanations of the sonnets that Dante included in his 'Vita Nuova'. Simply uninteresting. I would skip that part if rereading. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>drivingsideways</user>
	<review>For the initial 200 pages Eco tries deliberately to make you throw the book at the wall, by being dense to the point of annoying. Be patient, and uh..keep a Latin-English translator handy. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>parelle</user>
	<review>I really do love this book, with its envocation of the departed medieval world and characters within.  I probably reread it once a year, though I mean to take a latin dictionary with me my next bout to understand all of the text. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kell_Smurthwaite</user>
	<review>This was my first experience of Eco's writing and I have to say that I was quite impressed! Yes, I'd already seen the film of the same name years ago (and loved it), but now I was seeing it afresh and picturing some of the characters much differently than they had been portrayed. There is a fair amount of Latin used throughout the narrative, but as it's all used within context, the majority of it is easily understood, and those phrases not immediately clear are translated within the following dialogue, so one doesn't feel at all confused by the use of language.The language used is very descriptive and the plot is quite complex; add to this the sheer length of the novel and you have quite a heavy-going book, but it is one that is well-worth reading as it is an enjoyable journey from start to finish and I, for one, loved Eco's cleverness, both with plotting and characterisation, throughout. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cursonivel</user>
	<review>el nombre de la rosa es un libro donde podemos encontar verdades de la iglesia como el que en los tiempos de la inquisicion eran unos salvajes y escondian los libros de bromas o chaistes porque era pecado. leanlo </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>slkrbru</user>
	<review>Thank goodness I am done.  I kept reading because it was on Rory's list AND 1,000 Books to Read Before You Die AND I purchased it.  I wanted to enjoy this book but for several reasons which could be summed up with this:  a 500 page novel that could have been enjoyable minus 300 pages.  My 1 star rating is also a reflection on me as a reader.  I WISH I could understand and appreciate works of this type but I do not.  I keep trying though! </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kloafman</user>
	<review>Exellent, but I never felt the need to read it again. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BrianDewey</user>
	<review>Eco, Umberto. The Name of the Rose. Harvest, New York, 1980. I first read this book in New Hampshire; I must have been in the 8th grade. I was way too young to fully understand what was going on -- even today, a dozen years later, I miss most of the allusions -- but I still remember how I was captivated by Eco's creation of place. I wanted to live in a medieval monastery and live my life chasing ideas as if they were tangible things. On the second reading, my understanding of some of the philosophy  history is a little deeper, mostly due to having read Russell's A History of Western Philosophy. However, what still inspires me the most about this book, and the reason why I will probably re-read it several times in my life, is this is story reminds you that ideas  aesthetics matter. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stpnwlf</user>
	<review>A well-written and beautifully paced mystery novel set in a totally unique setting - a monastery in the middle ages. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>scrip79</user>
	<review>http://www.ilpotereelagloria.com/libr... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ct.bergeron</user>
	<review>Rien ne va plus dans la chrétienté. Rebelle à toute autorité, des bandes d'hérétiques sillonnent les royaumes servent a leur insu le jeu impitoyable des pouvoirs. En arrivant dans le havre de sérénité et de neutralité qu'est l'abbaye situé entre Provence et Ligurie, en l'an de grâce et de disgrâce 1327, l'ex-inquisiteur Guillaume de Baskerville, accompagnée de son secrétaire, se voit prié par l'abbé de découvrir qui a poussé  un des moines à se fracasser les os au pied de vénérable murailles. Crimes, vice, hérésie tout va alors advenir en l'espace de 7 jours. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>curso04</user>
	<review>El nombre de la rosa es, originalmente, una novela de Umberto Eco publicada en 1980. Posteriormente, en 1986, fue llevada al cine por el director Jean Jacques Annaud. El personaje principal fue interpretado por Sean Connery. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nutcase</user>
	<review>Mooi boek, moeilijk begin eerste 100 pagina's maar daarna kan je niet meer stoppen. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Stbalbach</user>
	<review>This will be a difficult novel for anyone that does not have an academic background in the Middle Ages. Luckily, I have spent the past 3 years preparing with excellent surveys such as Norman Cantor (The Civilization of the Middle Ages), Joseph Strayer (The Middle Ages, 395-1500) and Morris Bishop (The Middle Ages). There is hardly a sentence that does not connect with a scholarly topic on the Middle Ages, which should come as no surprise as Eco was foremost a medieval scholar before he wrote this his first novel. The first 100 pages of the novel are like reading a medieval manuscript, trying to piece together what is known of Medieval history and figuring out what Eco is talking about, not unlike what happens with the characters in the novel. With that said, the novel can still be enjoyed by anyone without a medieval history background because of the excellent plot and Gothic atmosphere. The novel needs extensive annotations to fully appreciate (such as The Key to The Name of the Rose, although I found it lacking in many ways).'Rose' works on many layers and can be approached from many perspectives. It's impossible to cover all the permutations in a single reading, indeed I have read it only once primarily a "reading for the plot" to understand the sequence of events. The movie helps in this regard, although it has some substantial "Hollywood" changes at the end and is much less subtle and interesting - recommend reading the novel first.Most valuable for me was Eco brought to life the Guelphs vs Ghibellines dispute in color, shape and form that only fiction can achieve. It's the difference between intellectually understanding history versus emotionally experiencing, and for this alone the novel is priceless, the best of what historical fiction can achieve. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siliconeye</user>
	<review>lius.fi/esko/studia/Nameoftherose_cmap.html</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siliconeye</user>
	<review>http://lius.fi/esko/studia/Nameofther...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siliconeye</user>
	<review>http://lius.fi/esko/studia/Nameofther...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DaveFragments</user>
	<review>perhaps the best book I have ever read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wirkman</user>
	<review>One of my favorite novels, and the one I have most often recommended to family . . . and received enthuasiastic report.The movie of the book was a few flickers of shadow from the book's full effect, and may not even be worth watching, in comparison. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chrisadami</user>
	<review>Opening:http://www.dllab.caltech.edu/~adami/b... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Arctic-Stranger</user>
	<review>You can read this as a fascinating medieval dectective story, but eventually it hits you that this is about the life we live. After a series of deaths in a monastary, the monks try to make sense of things by deducing a pattern from the book of Revelation. These deaths are not random events, they are a precursor to God's coming judgment. Well, it turns out they were NOT random events, but they had little to do with the Book of Revelation either. The moral of the story: Be careful what stories you tell, because that is what you will believe, whether it is true or not. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>littlebookworm</user>
	<review>Intelligent and absorbing.  This book required thought, speculation, and truly did cause me to question life and assumptions I've made, which is the mark of a great, great work.  I would say that the religious discussion was distracting and prolonged in some sections though.  Regardless, highly recommended, and I'll be looking for more of Eco's work. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TheTwoDs</user>
	<review>A magical combination of mystery, theology, philosophy and historical novel.  I first read it in my teenage years and at that time I appreciated the mystery, but the historic references and philosophical and theological debates went over my head.  Now, having re-read it 17 years later, the incredible depth Eco created has been revealed to me.  No two readers will get the same thing out of this book, which is the mark of a great novel.  I highly recommend it, as you will feel you are living in the Middle Ages at the abbey, trying to solve the mystery and learn about the origins and purposes of some of the religious orders. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>miketroll</user>
	<review>Intricate mediaeval whodunit. So much better than the feeble movie adaptation, which boils the plot down to almost nothing. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stephenmurphy</user>
	<review>So much more than just a whodunnit. A whoarewe? A whydowe?</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Humbert_Humbert</user>
	<review>Incredible.  That is the only word I can use to describe this book.  Any book love definately needs this in their collection.  With murder, deceit, and an ancient library you couldn't ask for more. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tole_lege</user>
	<review>Fascinating... You can spend the time to decipher the bits that have been left in Latin, or variants thereof, and other languages along the way - but there's no need to do so, to understand the story.My one caveat is that this is a NOVEL and was never meant to be anything else.  I've seen it cited as a historical document once too often....</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heidilove</user>
	<review>wow. just wow. i love this work. it is not only suspenseful, but funny and illuminates the time period quite well. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raven_in_the_woods</user>
	<review>Wonderful </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brose72</user>
	<review>Medieval detective story set in the mysterious labyrinth of an unnamed Italian Abbey. A complex, twisting story that integrates many topics and subjects on a search to uncover the cause and reason for a series of murders. A slow moving story and a bit heavy on the use of Latin phrases (even for a former Latin prayer spewing altar boy)but still a good story if you are not in a hurry to uncover the truth. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>placo75</user>
	<review>A very good novel. Easier than Foucault's Pendulum, but still challenging. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Levitron</user>
	<review>one of my favourite all time books - probably Eco's most accessible, whilst still retaining that difficult air that all his books carry (i.e. they're not beach books!) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lewispike</user>
	<review>Frankly I prefered the film. That might be heresy here, but although the stories are very similar I find pages and pages of rapture about Christian statury hard to read.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jontseng</user>
	<review>A powerful evocation of the scholastic milieu. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kestrell</user>
	<review>My favorite book, I reread it every couple of years. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shoreline</user>
	<review>This book is heavy on the history, but the conclusion, which stunned me, was well worth the demanding read.But because I read it a touch impatiently the first time round, I feel compelled to read it a second time.Highly recommended. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Lisuebie</user>
	<review>Eco's writing stems from the head and less from keen observation or love of words.So, this mystery is full of information, puzzles, surprises, ideas.  It is an intellectual pleasure to read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ragwaine</user>
	<review>Cool but more about religion than mystery.  Some parts could have been cut.  Too much latin. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aubreyfs</user>
	<review>This is a very dark (well, it is medieval) story hanging on 1) a clash of factions regarding a single assumption on the wealth of Jesus, and 2) a series of murders in a monastery that holds the clue to a cryptic labyrinthian library.  Very harsh at times:  "Kill them all.  God will recognize his own."  "What terrifies you most in purity?  - Haste."  This book needs to be read SLOWLY in order to understand all of the obtuse arguments.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>coffeezombie</user>
	<review>So books this intelligent were once best sellers? Eco's name-making work takes place in an Italian abbey during the 14th century, as an English monk and his German apprentice and scribe try to solve a bizarre series of murders by using logical deduction and a wide knowledge of biblical history. Eco is adept at creating a complete world within the walls of the abbey and surrounding it with the political and philosophical debates of the past. Finding a perfect balance between the scholarly and the entertaining, Eco here creates one of the finest works of popular fiction of the past 50 years. As much a book for bibliophiles and history buffs as it is for mystery lovers. (This review originally appeared on zombieunderground.net) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>piefuchs</user>
	<review>A true great of the historical fiction genre.  The detailed descriptions of the fractioning of the church is wonderful.  The accompanying mystery story is enjoyable as well. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Clurb</user>
	<review>Foul-mouthed monks, deep spiritual contemplation, bloody murders, guile, acumen, sex and intrigue. This book had everything. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>beezle176</user>
	<review>gives you the creeps - fantastic and spell binding </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pmorris</user>
	<review>I enjoyed this book very much. I initially had a hard tiome getting started, some visulaization problems, I think, but pressed on and was drawn in. Very dark, but quite fascinating. Well written and translated. I've also read two of his other books but enjoyed them less. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TerrapinJetta</user>
	<review>This was a very enjoyable read, a sort of italian monk Sherlock Holmes/Dr Watson sort of thing, with interesting bits about italian history. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jaemark</user>
	<review>http://theproseportal.wordpress.com/2... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>udo</user>
	<review>I read this book shortly before finishing my a levels and it somehow really seems to have sparked my interest in medieval history. I read another novel by Eco but this is in my opinion his best one. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nimatee</user>
	<review>Intelligent plot, diffcult words, demands a lot of patience..</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nillacat</user>
	<review>I read this in college, when I aspired to be a well-read intellectual of the sort I thought they bred in England, able to quote Shakespeare and Cicero, Caesar and Chaucer, Aristotle and Aeschylus. Of course I'm not that sort (I imagine I'd have already become one by 18 if I were really so inclined.) Name of the Rose is a medieval detective story, a story of murder and of literary clues, and is, ultimately, about people who care more for books than for lives or the world they live in. Which I was when I read it. Which I am no longer, which is why I am not likely to reread it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>altivo</user>
	<review>Superbly drawn mystery, bildungsroman, and a finely drawn medieval setting contribute to a delightful tale especially for those with a scholarly bent or a love of things medieval and monastic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tiffehr</user>
	<review>The definitive Eco -- 5 pages detailing a medieval doorway and Salvatore the Heretic (wonderfully done by Ron Perlman in the Sean Connery movie version).  I need to re-read it to give a credible review. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rakerman</user>
	<review>Slow to get started (apparently deliberately).  Lots of interesting history.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heathweaver</user>
	<review>Eco is an amazing author. I highly recommend this book as an enjoyable read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MisterJJones</user>
	<review>http://blogs.warwick.ac.uk/jjones/ent... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bookwitch</user>
	<review>Like a creature from a medieval bestiary, Umberto Eco’s great novel is a fabulous monster of a book, conforming to neither the rules of nature nor of contemporary fiction. Summoned by the abbot of an Italian monastery to solve the mysterious death of a young monk, William of Baskerville, together with his assistant Adso, a novice, find themselves caught up in a series of bizarre deaths that seem to centre on the vast labyrinthine library and its precious, secret and avidly-guarded contents. This is a difficult book in places, slow to start and loaded with knowledge and intellect. Fluency in English will give one a sense of the meaning of some of the untranslated Latin that runs throughout the book, but I’d loved to have understood completely. Parts read like lessons in political history, and the intricacies of power struggles between popes and princes, scattered liberally with the names of lesser and  more widely known figures, are gone into in some depth. Lists of fantastic creatures, medicinal herbs or the contents of a dream can dominate whole pages. Yet Eco has drawn William and Adso with a delicate and tender brush – each is recognisably human, each is flawed and easy to empathise with. The scene between Adso and the girl is beautifully described, and the writing throughout the 400 plus pages faultless. If at times I found the author’s intellect and knowledge daunting, even to the point of feeling unworthy to be reading, there were sections where I simply couldn’t put the book down, and I felt on turning the final page that without those passages mentioned above both the novel and its readers would be the poorer. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bcquinnsmom</user>
	<review>People are dying left and right in the Abbey. Why? What "secret" is being guarded and why? This book is a true work of genius and you'll see why at the end. I really can't say anything because the story is too good to spoil. One of my top 100 books. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JohnK</user>
	<review>Als ik nu toch één boek mocht nomineren voor ‘beste boek van de eeuw’ dan zou dat De naam van de roos zijn. Natuurlijk is dit een heel persoonlijke keuze en als recensent mag je niet té persoonlijk worden. Maar velen met mij die het boek kochten en lazen zijn het eens dat het moeilijk zal zijn een werk te vinden waarin literatuur, geschiedenis, cultuur, religie en spanning met elkaar zo’n ongelooflijk mooi, intelligent en spannend boek vormen.Het element ‘spanning’, waardoor dit boek ook zo geliefd is bij lezers van Crimezone, wordt gevormd door het feit dat de hoofdpersoon William van Baskerville (in de film een prachtig gezicht gegeven door Sean Connery) geconfronteerd wordt met brute moorden in de abdij. De abdij waar William van Baskerville en zijn beschermeling Adson van Melk samen aankomen. William met een deels geheime missie en Adson als argeloze jongeling.Het element ‘religie’ is de ruggengraat van het boek. In een korte inleiding beschrijft Umberto Eco hoe hij op het spoor kwam – bij toeval, om mee te beginnen – van de originele manuscripten die hem er toe hebben aangezet dit boek te schrijven. Alles draait om een van de vele ruzies die er in de loop der eeuwen zijn geweest tussen de wereldlijke en de geestelijke stand. In dit geval de ruzie tussen keizer Lodewijk en paus Johannes. Wij leven dan tegenwoordig wel in een land waar een strikte scheiding is tussen kerk en staat, in vroeger eeuwen was die scheiding er niet. En dus hadden koningen, keizers en pausen vaak ruzie over wie nu de macht had over wie. En vooral ook: over wat, want in die tijd waren pausen rijke en machtige mannen. William van Baskerville is gevraagd om als ‘mediator’ op te treden in een van de vele conflicten tussen de paus en degenen die echt van hun geloof willen getuigen: franciscaner monniken.Het element geschiedenis, het element cultuur en het element literatuur volgen hier uit. Het verhaal speelt zich honderden jaren geleden af, de achtergrond is vaak voor ons niet (meer) te begrijpen en Umberto Eco heeft het geheel vervat in prachtige taal zonder gekunsteld of gezwollen over te komen. De naam van de roos is geen boek om ‘even’ te lezen als je in de trein naar je werk zit, of op een zonnig strand. De naam van de roos is het soort boek dat je moet savoureren: je moet je geestelijk en lichamelijk goed voorbereiden. Neem plaats in je lievelingsstoel of op je lievelingsbank of voor mijn part in bed. Zet deurbel en telefoon uit. Zet eventueel ook huisgenoten uit… Verzeker je van genoeg eten en drinken voor een uur of twee. En begin. Daarna moet je even pauze nemen; dit is hard nodig om alle informatie die Eco verstrekt goed tot je te laten doordringen. Maak eventueel aantekeningen om op het Internet of in de bibliotheek zaken na te kijken (die neiging krijg je echt). Doe de volgende dag hetzelfde. Kortom: verlies je in dit boek. En mocht je het toch een beetje lastig lezen vinden – het is tenslotte nogal veel wat je ineens op je bord krijgt – kijk dan eerst eens naar de film. Ik ken weinig boeken die zo mooi verfilmd zijn, met zoveel aandacht voor detail! Het boek zal voor mij in elk geval altijd het belangrijkste blijven, maar de film geeft je op een bepaalde manier de essentie zonder afbreuk te doen aan de rest.Hoe ‘het afloopt’ is eigenlijk niet belangrijk… Eco geeft de lezer enige honderden pagina’s een kijkje in en op een fascinerend tijdperk, met fascinerende mensen en gebeurtenissen.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>argyriou</user>
	<review>Aside from being a fun read (it's a medieval murder mystery), I liked "The Name Of The Rose" because it showed clearly the distinction between the medieval mindset and the modern mindset, at a time when the modern mindset was struggling to come into existence. None of the characters are truly modern men, but the two protagonists are the closest.  Their antagonists embody the medieval mindset quite thoroughly and unappealingly.  This book ruined the romantic fantasy of the middle ages for me, and gave me an appreciation for modernity in its widest sense. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kelberts</user>
	<review>tedious </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mjiko</user>
	<review>Kind of like a mediaeval Sherlock Holmes, Brother William goes about investigating a series of monk murders with an implacable rationality and wit. Fantastic. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mattviews</user>
	<review>In 1327, Franciscans in a wealthy Italian abbey are suspected of heresy. Brother William of England and his scribe, who is a Benedictine novice and the narrator of the book, arrive to investigate. The timely arrival of the perspicacious brother coincides with seven bizarre deaths at the abbey. The spree of deaths from surreptitious cause claims the life of an illustrator Adelmo, a Greek scholar Venantius and other monks at the abbey.The first fifty or so pages of the book brief the vicissitudes of churches and the emergence of heresies and diabolical practices. My first impression of the novel is some circuitous unraveling of heretics and power struggles between the Pope and the emperor. After trudging through these historical backgrounds and religious overtones, the book becomes nothing but an intriguing thriller in probing and unraveling the mystery behind all the deaths.As Brother William traces to the bone of the mystery that seamlessly entangles the relationships and the paths overlapped the victims, it becomes perspicuous that the possession and theft of a banned book from the abbey library has led to deaths of scholars and monks in vein. The library, its promise, prestige, and prohibitions, incurs a strong hold on the monks and scholars who have sinfully coveted and hoped one day to violate all its secrets and gain access to the books.While the abbot sternly tightens the grip of library access and so to thwart falsehood and infidel knowledge from befalling into wrong hands, barred from such knowledge only inevitably creates in everyone an insatiable lust for such materials. The very knowledge that the abbey has accumulated is used as barter goods, cause for pride, and motive for boasting and prestige. It has been adumbrated that a monk, stirred by unquenchable desires for intellect, will even comply with carnal desire in order to satisfy the pursuit of intellect.The probe for truth sheds light as Brother William and our narrator indomitably ventures into the library, collects evidence, deciphers secret zodiac symbols and manuscripts, notes the library's subjects and arrangements, and thus cracks the labyrinth. Evolution of the librarian appointments at the abbey indubitably gives away the identity of the ultimate devil.The Name of the Rose deftly evokes the paradox of truth. As William's investigation takes an unexpected turn and sheds light on the truth, the very unbearable truth that the abbot refuses to recognize and confronts out of fear of besmirching the abbey's prestige, Eco obfuscates readers with the ghastly consequence and the toll of the obsession with truth. Does truth really set one free as the Bible claims, or does it come with a price?The Name of the Rose is a tale of a master's journey in unraveling a complicated knot at a sacred institution. Under the veneer of scholastic and immaculate surface is prurient desire for knowledge, covet for power, and scruple for sin against chastity. The interminable discourse on church history and heresy will be elucidated throughout the novel (so don't be discouraged by the difficult prose), as relevant personalities will recount their involvement with heretics. It's an ingenious, fine piece of literature that challenges bright minds. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jbd1</user>
	<review>One of the first, and best, of the current crop of literary thrillers out there. Tough to get into at first, but keep going, it'll grab you. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Smiley</user>
	<review>Anyone using Librarything knows this book.  There are less celebrated books, rightly so, called Gospel by Wilton Barnhart.  Like Moby Dick, the canvas is broad and the plot in pursuit of the translation of a lost Gospel provides a spin through much of church history. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dreamer98</user>
	<review>A good mystery but lengthy and although the religious discourse my interest some, it just bored me. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Crowyhead</user>
	<review>I greatly enjoyed this. Be forwarned that while it's a mystery novel, it's really about church history, and heresy, and dangerous knowledge... And also, if you're a librarian, it might make you cry.If you haven't read any Eco, I think this is a good place to start, because it's got a great plot and gets you used to Eco's wordy, erudite style. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wenestvedt</user>
	<review>This mystery set in a medieval monastery is a great story, though I prefer to think of the actor who does the Brother Cadfael shows instead of Sean Connery in the lead, and Christian Slater just, you know, off-screen. (I didn't see the movie, obviously.)More background than you may want: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Name... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tole_lege</user>
	<review>Not the edition I have but still interesting, I suppose.I've seen too many bits of this quoted as history, however....</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hippietrail</user>
	<review>This was my favourite book for years (until I read García Márquez's One Hundred Years of Solitude). Now it's a book I collect in all the languages I can find it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Eric_the_Hamster</user>
	<review>As well as being a great piece of historical fiction, this is also a classic "whodunnit". Some pretty harrowing descriptions of the sort of persecution perpetrated by the Medieval European church. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MaraJade88</user>
	<review>http://cnytr.blogspot.com/2005/07/lau...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>incap</user>
	<review>UMBERTO ECO NACIO EN ALESANDRIA (PIAMONTE),  AÑO1932,HA DADO CURSOS EN LAS UNIVERSIDADES TURIN, FLORENCIA, Y MILAN Y EN ALGUNAS DE LATINOAMERICA.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>reket007</user>
	<review>http://www.ozon.ru/context/detail/id/...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>