<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>William E. Liberatore "edcctf"</user>
	<review>

"That is the nature of the presidency.  Perceptions are shaped by the clarity of hindsight.  In the moment of decision, you don't have that advantage."  -G. BushIn a lot of ways this statement just about sums up the book.  The President of the United States, maybe more so than any other person on the face of the Earth, has his/her every decision microscopically analyzed by just about everyone... after the fact, when the results are known and more information is available.  I thought this to be a very interesting premise for a presidential memoir.  It doesn't come across as an apology nor does it come across as an excuse.  President Bush gives you the situation as he saw it and lets you make your own decision.I am not a huge fan of President Bush, but I don't think he is the utter failure as President that some consider him.  I come away with some empathy (though short of being President, I don't think anyone could truly grasp the reality) for President Bush.  Could things have been done better... more than likely.  Could they have been worse... almost certainly... but how many of us couldn't apply those phrases to our own lives?  If you are a Bush fan, I'd almost guarantee you'll like the book.  If you aren't a fan.... you'll probably find some more ammunition to bash him.  For myself, I don't at all regret the time spent reading the book and that is usually the measure that I put on literary material.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Richard Stoyeck "StocksAtBottom.com"</user>
	<review>

The book is written thematically, not chronologically. This is important because it gives the book a much different flavor than one that is written month by month, and year by year. This book was not ghost written. This is his hand and his words, and it comes through on every page - all 512 of them. I had no expectations when I opened the cover other than to enjoy the book. I found it was written with a wonderful light hand, Bush being a story teller, no question about it. And he pulls no punches, he tells you the real deal and he does not filter it. Other people will write pro and con on this book depending upon their political filters. There will be none of that here. I am only interested in enjoying a book and telling you that you will also or maybe not. I am going to give you a flavoring of the book and you will know immediately if this is for you:*	In the Presidency there are no do-over's*	Quitting drinking was one of the toughest decisions he ever made*	It wouldn't be the last time the student George Bush slept through a Yale lecture*	He says he had the same personality as his mother. He would needle people to show affection and to make a point. He flares up rapidly. He and his mother both can be real blunt, a trait that gets them into trouble from time to time*	Bush was enormously influenced by a history teacher on crutches at his prep school which was Andover Phillips Academy in Mass. His name was Tom Lyons (crippled by polio), and he nurtured, he hectored, he praised, and demanded a lot. He instilled in George Bush a love of history that remained with him throughout a lifetime. *	Reverend William Sloan Coffin was a contemporary of the president's father, George HW Bush while both were at Yale. When George W. was a student at Yale, his father had just lost his bid to become a Senator from Texas. George W. asked the Reverend to perhaps write a letter to console his father, and the Reverend's former classmate. The Reverend responded, "Your father was beaten by a better man." I don't think the future President ever recovered from the remark. *	Having spent considerable time in Texas over the last couple of decades I thoroughly enjoyed Texas wisdom which the President captures brilliantly in one statement. He refers to some people as "Book smart and sidewalk stupid". *	He sums up his education by telling us that he went to Andover by tradition, Yale by expectation, and Harvard by choice. *	The funniest story in the book is when he is sitting at a dinner party in Kennebunkport with his parents during his heavy alcohol stage, and he says to a contemporary of his parents, so what is sex like after 50. Everyone was aghast at the statement. The future President receives a note after he is elected. The note says, "Well George how is it?"*	What you are looking at here is an absolutely honest, self examination.*	When the President becomes introspective and talks about personnel, his philosophy is that the people who surround you will determine the quality of advice you receive and the way your goals are implemented. *	He mentions meeting with Margaret Thatcher who told him that she usually makes up her mind about a man in 10 seconds, and very rarely changes it. You cannot write 500 plus pages of biography without revealing yourself. You simply cannot hide it for that long. I do not believe that this President has a bad bone in his body. Did he make mistakes, yes lots of them, and everyone else does too. It's all so easy in hindsight, and so difficult to call them accurately before the event. He takes responsibility, and welcomes history's future judgment of him. This is a man who sleeps at night. It's all here in 14 chapters, from stem cells, September 11th, Afghanistan, Iraq, Katrina, the Surge, his freedom agenda, and finishing with the financial crisis. You will wind up reading the whole thing, and looking for more. You will be critical, and at the same time consoling, for this was and is, a good man. They may have been errors of judgment, but not of the heart. From the hiring's to the firings, read this book and you will better understand a part of history we all lived through. He holds no punches and tells you what he thinks of the players who were part of his Administration.And then there's the family, his love of father and mother. Their loving imprint on him, and the child they produced. George Bush is the perfect example of the apple not falling very far from the tree. He is the product of a totally enveloping family where he was not pushed, but gently supported to find his own way. There were stumbles along the way including the decade long battle with alcoholism. I thoroughly enjoyed this book and ask you my fellow reader to come to it with an open mind, with a fresh eye, and try to see if you can capture some fresh thoughts on this very interesting man who has led a very interesting life. In the end it seemed to me that if George Bush was your friend, you didn't need many more friends - you were covered. Thank you for reading this review. Richard C. Stoyeck 
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>David S. Davies</user>
	<review>

Most of the reviews here are not of the book but of the President, so typically the reviews are falling along party lines (similar to way too many things these days). It should be possible to review the book as an autobiography and not a political commentary. That said, the book is an interesting reflection by President Bush on his perception of his life and actions. It is not a work of master prose. The President writes like he speaks. The thoughts are straight forward and often simple, but they are his. It is not insightful but it is revealing. If you are looking for insight into the workings of Washington or an assessment of policy, this book is not for you. If you want to read about how President Bush views his life and presidency, the book does a pretty good job of that. It often leaves the reader with questions and certainly does not contain deep reflection (that will take many more years to develop), but it is the George W Bush talking about George W Bush as he sees himself and his presidency today.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>R. Young "el Roberto"</user>
	<review>

So first off I'm pretty left. I didn't buy this book with the intention of hating President Bush. In fact despite the policy problems and the damage to the economy under his administration I don't "hate" him or anyone. So with that being said I found it nice to gain a personal perspective with a person who is challenged daily with decisions the average person couldn't fathom. What makes this man and his mind work? Why did he make choices that made me so angry? Why did the press constantly berate him regardless of what he did? These things I wanted answers on and I got them in this book.There are many things that none of us ever hear about and those things were better clarified here. I can understand the challenges the man faced and from a historical perspective I actually feel I've learned a lot about the way the upper ranks of US Government act in the present day. I've seen some comments on here about not telling the truth and whatnot but feel those are from left wing fanatics that just cant open their mind to the truth that a president is a human.The writing at times is somewhat childish but I'm also happy it's not over the wall in a "Rhodes Scholar" kind of way. It's in a basic story telling format with dips and dives into major events that we all know about by now if we've bothered to buy this book. I'm happy that it's not a bang on the drums Republican story that tries to shove ideals down my throat. In fact it's simply this man sharing what he feels and why he did what he did. I was particularly drawn to the Stem Cell chapter because I followed that closely when it happened and always felt the president was lambasted for the press, the Democratic party, and the bloggers benefit. This tells me a lot of what I already know about the current political climate and the way people are so polarized. It clears up many lies from the media that I knew were lies as they graced the TV on various channels. It also clarifies the truths that I knew and the reason I didn't vote for him.Either way it's good to crawl inside the mind of a president for a few hours and understand what makes them tick.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>David In South Carolina</user>
	<review>

I have never been a fan of Bush. In fact I really thought he was the worst president in history. I could not put this book down. He had an extraordinarily hard job, and when he tells of his mindset when making the decisions he made I have to admire him. I truly think that he did what he thought was the rite thing to do on each and every one of his decisions. I can honestly say that I now think that he did a good job.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JJ</user>
	<review>

I voted for Bush the first time. I didn't vote for him the second time. I rarely read political books or memoirs, but the way Bush has carried himself after leaving office had me intrigued and gave me a new respect for the man. I started this book and, at times, got very bogged down with details that this mostly fiction reader doesn't like, but still, I appreciated it and didn't skip anything (as I usually will). It was a fascinating look into politics, what really goes on behind the scenes, and how truly difficult (as I imagined, but never really new)dealing with a national tragedy was.Humorous and smart, what I liked about the book was that, after I was done reading it, I felt that President Bush was an ordinary guy who managed to do an extraordinary job with class. Not perfect, not by a long shot, but that he admits his errors and does so, I believe, sincerely. A truly fascinating book.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kevin Afghani</user>
	<review>

Here's what I took out of reading this book.  First, I got a great overview of world events that occurred during Bush's eight years in office.  Regardless of whether you agreed with Bush, your memory will at least be refreshed on the important events of the Bush years, including 9/11, the stem cell controversy, Iraq, Afghanistan, and the financial meltdown.  With hindsight being 20/40, it's easy to forget how we felt during some of those events, and this book does a good job of bringing us back to those uncertain times.  Second, it made me sympathize with Bush for some of the decisions he made, including those I disagreed with.  I was struck at how influenced he was by the people around him.  For example, his advisors basically put him in a state of constant fear of a potential terrorist strike on him personally, and I was left wondering whether this was the cause of some of his war mentality.  Another example is the doomsday scenario he was given during the financial crisis.  These "worst case scenarios" always seemed to be the guiding light of his decisions.  Also, while I disagreed with his stem cell policy, that chapter at least helped me understand his thinking.  Third, I was reminded of some of the reasons why I was ready for Bush to leave office when he did.  The chapter that most reminded me of this was the one called "Freedom Agenda"; this chapter contains his overly-simplistic, black-and-white view of the world that I did not like during his presidency.So whether you agree with Bush or not, I think this was a worth-while read.  The most boring chapter was the one about the African malaria/AIDS initiative.  Other than that, it kept my attention.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Michael P. Gallagher</user>
	<review>

I read this one right after the release, and being one of the many who was tired of W and ready for him to leave office, I have a new perspective on the man - no matter if you are a Democrat, Republican, or whatever political party affiliation you may lean I believe if you read this book with an open mind you will have a new perspective on W, too: he is a man, certainly not perfect, and every decision made with the facts and circumstances at hand is subject to second guessing.  After all, hindsight is 20-20.I thought the reflections on alcohol and religion were refreshing in a politician - when do you hear of a politician having truly candid conversations on those two subjects?  The realities of not finding WMD in Iraq, the repercussions of Hurricane Katrina, Scooter Libby, and the honesty come out in this book.  Love him or hate him, I think this is an honest reflection, albeit with a few cards still held close to the vest - being President of the USA has to be one of the most difficult jobs ever, and wears on you.  You try to make the best decisions at the time - sometimes they work out, and unfortunately sometimes they don't and you have to live with it.  That is life.If you are looking for a good read on W's perspective, I recommend you pick this one up.  If you can't get over the negative - or even highly enthusiastic - celebration of W's presidency, this one is probably not for you.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tim</user>
	<review>

This book provided an interesting, thematic look at the major issues in the presidency of America's forty-third president. Even if you do not share the policy leanings of GWB, you will most likely come away at least understanding hit rationale for the major decisions he made and be convinced that he placed serious thought and judgment into making them. I came away very surprised and gained a great deal of respect and empathy for his management style and processes, even in instances where the decisions may not have been ones I would have made in his place. A must for anyone interested in American politics. I found that many insights and pieces of information I did not get during his time in office.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307590615</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gen. JC Christian, patriot</user>
	<review>

The presidential memoir serves an important function in our society. It provides a former president with an opportunity to shape how we will be viewed by history. They aren't easy books to write. Facts create roadblocks that the ex-president must overcome. Most attempt to do so by twisting and tearing at the facts until an acceptable truth emerges. My president, Our Glorious Leader George W. Bush, boldly took another approach. He tortured the facts until they confessed to their treachery. Then, He summarily executed them with a Hellfire-C missile launched from a Predator drone.And the results are breathtaking. I stood up and cheered when I read His claim that waterboarding isn't torture because He paid His lawyers to say it isn't. That's chutzpah, my friends. It's a zen kind of chutzpah, one that is only achieved when self delusion and a supreme lack of self-awareness come into perfect balance. I was also very moved by His recounting of His childhood encounter with the Bush family fetus jar. It was very vividly written. I can almost see Barbara Bush standing there in her blue gown, arms outstretched as she presents the fetus jar to young W. "Hold him, W," she screeches, her pearls rattling angrily, "kiss your little dead fetus brother; kiss him now, you little mistake!"Now that's parenthood. It's no wonder He became what He is today.It does not matter if the story is true or not. No one cares that it's more likely that Barbara caught young George drinking from the family fetus jar. The story works either way, because it's about respect for life or the alcohol that preserves the traces of it. And that's the key to understanding President Bush. He respects life so much, He eagerly takes it from those he deems undeserving.But this book isn't perfect. Glorious Leader Bush's experiments with firecrackers and frogs--experiments that shaped His thoughts on justice--goes unreported. Same goes for his triumph over alcoholism and his later studies on the beneficial health effects derived by drinking huge quantities of Vicks NyQuil Multi-Symptom Cold/Flu Relief- Original Flavor. None of that appears in this memoir. That's why I can't give "Decision Points" five stars.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>