<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Patrick Devenny</user>
	<review>

Remember when your parents and teachers would try to get you to read?  The favored line is that reading equot;can take you anywhere in the worldequot;.  Well, that sounds nice, but it never really rang true, especially as books offer only a short term separation from the problems of real life.  Well, Umberto Eco's epic novel The Name of the Rose might be one of those few novels that really approaches the suggested transportation powers books can possess.  It is such a equot;thickequot; novel.  Intellectually, it is staggering in its complexity and fluidity.  The reader can simply marvel at the range of ideas and logical conversation that Eco includes in this novel.  As other reviewers have pointed out, you really do feel smarter upon finishing it.  That is the first theme of the book that strikes you, but many more are out there for you to explore.The actual story of The Name of the Rose (sometimes the story gets lost in the novel) is a classic murder mystery, set in a 14th century Italian abbey.  Because of recent political and religious strife in the surrounding areas, the competing powers of the Holy Roman Emperor and the Papal authorities both see importance in this area.  Rumors of heresy within the walls abound, a mark the Franciscan friars try their best to avoid.  Our main character is the former inquisitor William of Baskerville, an extremely intelligent and learned official, under the employment of the Emperor.  With him is his faithful assistant Adso, who is our narrator.  Their assignment is to make sense of the conflicting stories people tell about what is in the monastery.  Just as they start their investigation, monks start getting killed, in brutal but symbolic ways.  William and Adso are forced to use all their powers of logic and deduction to begin to piece together the clues.The clues point to a dark secret inside the heralded library of the abbey.  There, monks toil day after day, reproducing the classics and more modern works.  This is where civilization was being saved at the time, in small monasteries which kept alive science and ancient literature.  However, somethings that are hidden away in the library are not meant to be seen, and a strangely rigid library control apparatus shields certain works from William.  As the murders and the obstinacy of the librarians continue, William becomes more suspicious of the abbey's leadership at large.  A conspiracy begins to emerge, one dedicated to the many scriptural and architectural secrets possessed by the Italian abbey.  It quickly becomes apparent to William and the reader that what is involved here is much more important than the political issues of the day.The pure historical swath of The Name of the Rose is hard to even summarize, as it is just immeasurably grand.  The reader learns of the medieval church and of a Europe torn apart by theological argument.  Messiahs and prophets tour the land, with inquisitors and church officials constantly at work stamping them out.  Battle between the secular and divine worlds begin to emerge, as the Popes become more and more involved in the everyday politics of Europe.  Eco shows the reader how important ideas were at this time, as theological speculation was by far the most critical arena of thought in that violent era.  Ideas concerning the divinity of Christ, the power of the Popes, and the importance of older, equot;paganequot; philosophies were constantly fought over.  William is a wonderful guide, as his mind is the window into the age.  He is the embodiment of learned divinity, torn between the complex humanism of the ancients and the compelling reality of the present.  He is a man of his time, a valuable tool for readers so much removed.  The writing itself is absolutely magnificent, as every scene, every setting, every character is rendered in eminently readable caricatures.  It's just a novel you shake your head when you put it down, knowing you never will fully understand the brilliance of this book.  Go get it, now!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>J. Mullin</user>
	<review>

One reviewer here on Amazon was right on the money when he said that reading a novel by Umberto Eco instantly raises your IQ by a couple of points.  The Name of the Rose has been my first encounter with Eco's work,  and I was for the most part very impressed with his skillful murder mystery  set in a 14th century Italian monastery.The novel works on many levels.   It is a compelling murder mystery, as young narrator Adso of Elk  accompanies the wise William of Baskerville as he uses logic and semiotics  to not only solve a murder mystery, but to decipher labrynths and hidden  secrets of the vast monastery library.  Interwoven with the murder mystery  is a virtual course on philosophy and late Middle Ages religion, as Eco  provides detailed accounts of the histories of various sects, includes  scholarly debate on topics such as the poverty of Christ, and a history of  the Catholic Church leading to the establishment of a papacy in Avignon,  France.One is reminded of Sherlock Holmes and Dr. Watson as William and  Adso use logic and determination to piece together numerous bizarre deaths  and occurences at the Abbey, while encountering obstacles and outright  hostility by the Abbot and his librarian, to name a couple.  The setting of  the novel, and the glimpse into a culture that few of us can even imagine,  is reason enough to read The Name of the Rose.The book is not without  its faults however. I think the book should stand alone, (ie you should not  have to buy a separate equot;reader's guideequot;) and I was very  frustrated at the numerous Latin phrases that are included throughout the  novel with no translation.  Perhaps this is more the fault of the  translator than Eco himself, but it makes for a difficult reading  experience. One does not need to know the meaning of every word in the book  to follow the plot, but it is aggravating to stumble across paragraph-long  passages or insciptions that are completely foreign to most readers,  without so much as a footnote. There are also fairly long digressions  involving topics of religious debate or history of minor sects that, in my  opinion, were extraneous and contributed little overall to the success of  the novel. However, overall, I thought the novel was rewarding, both  informative and suspenseful.
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

I'd like to add to the many reviews of this book only a few comments about the meaning of the famous Latin sentence equot;Stat rosa pristina nomine, nomina nuda tenemusequot;. Literaly it can be translated as equot;The  ancient rose subsists thanks to its name, we have only bare namesequot;. It  is an ancient sentence often quoted by s.c. nominalist philosophers of  Middle Ages who thought that our mind isn't able to discover the true  essence of things and so it isn't able a fortiori to have the minimum idea  of God. In fact in medieval philosophy God was often compared to the figure  of a rose; the nominalists wanted to say with the sentence that even God,  the supreme being, persists only through its name, i.e. persists upon an  extremely frail thing. Names were seen as simple equot;flatus vocisequot;,  equot;emission of voiceequot; without value. The nominalist philosophers  who declared that even God was a flatus vocis were condemned as heretics (a  theme that recurs often in the novel). But here the sentence isn't quoted  only for its historical value, but also because it can be applied also to  the love of the young monk Adso; he meets in the monastry a young woman and  perhaps falls in love with her. In his mind she is just the  equot;roseequot;, i.e. God, of whom he doesn't know the name (the woman and  Adso speak different languages). It is then a very pitiful and sad thing  that of the woman he doesn't know the name, because, if nominalist theories  were true, he won't be able to keep with him, in his heart and mind, in his  future life and old age, the remembrances of that encounter and of those  days which changed his life and mind forever (cf. the pages of the novel  where the old Adso comments on those evets).
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

I loved this book when I first read it 6 years ago so much that it was one of the few things I took with me when I came to US. Reading NR is a many-fold experience, so many reviews are right about it. However I was  deeply disappointed with the way Eco is published in English. You see, my  Russian edition has about 70 pages of comments ranging from historical to  theological ones. Who in this modern world remembers Dolcino or a  difference between katars and minorites ?? It is nice when a reader is well  versed in both Latin, medieval Deutch and some Italian but at least my  Russian translator and editors went to great pains to help me, a reader,  along the way. You can see so many comments (read those about  equot;Pendulumequot;, for example) that blame Eco for being a pompous  intellectual while it is really the result of modern day education that  does not prepare an average reader to deal with such a multi-layered work.  Otherwise we would not have people asking about the meaning of last words  in novel.Stat rosa pristina nomine, nomina nuda tenemus.With the past  name of rose, names are shed (naked) in future.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

It is November, 1327.  Adso of Melk, the narrator, has accompanied William of Baskerville to a remote, wealthy Franciscan abbey in the mountains of northern Italy.  Upon arriving, William discovers that a murder has taken  place and the body of the monk, Adelmo, has been discovered outside the  abbey walls.  The abbot, Abo, is very concerned and charges William with  solving the murders.  For, not only is the safety of the monks in jeopardy,  a papal delegation from Pope John XXII in Avignon could well use the  murders as an excuse for investigating the abbey, something Abo definitely  wants to avoid.  By the time the papal delegation, led by two inquisitors  arrives, the situation at the abbey has worsened.  Two more monks are dead  and two more die soon afterward.  The abbot's worst fears are realized when  the papal inquisitors learn he has been sheltering monks who were once  followers of the condemed heretic, Fra Dolcino.  Although the abott  dismisses Willliam, he remains and a few hours later, the mystery is  solved, two more monks have died and the monastery has been consumed by  fire.  The Name of the Rose is first and foremost a mystery of the highest  order, and it is possible to enjoy it on that level alone.  But it is also  a charming roman a clef, something I think many readers have missed.  We  don't have to look far to realize Sherlock Holmes in the guise of William  of Baskerville or Adso as Dr. Watson.  The blind Spaniard, Jorge of Burgos  is easily recognized as the Argentinian writer Jorge Luis Borges.  Eco also  challenges us by thinly disguising figures from postwar Italian politics as  various other members of the abbey.  The figures in the book thus  correspond to other figures in different books or in real life.  Each  figure also represents a metaphysical concept:  William, reason; Adso,  mysticism; Jorge, evil, and then, in true medieval fashion, characters are  thus pitted one against the other as opposing forces.  I hate to see  comparisons of this marvelous work of literature to Iain Pears's, An  Instance of the Fingerpost.  The books are as unlike as night is to day.   While An Instance of the Fingerpost goes to great lengths to point out that  ultimate truth does exist and can, indeed, be realized, The Name of the  Rose is, at its heart, a book about uncertainty, especially the uncertainty  of truth.  In An Instance of the Fingerpost, the reader is asked to  interpret a collection of signs and symbols, which, when interpreted in the  one correct manner, will inevitably lead to the identity and motive of the  criminal, i.e., the truth.  In The Name of the Rose, the search for  ultimate truth is far more ambiguous.  Near the end of the book, William  tells Adso that many hypotheses, false though they may be, can still lead  one to a correct solution.  And, while certainty is what's pursued in An  Instance of the Fingerpost, certainty remains an impossibility in The Name  of the Rose.  As William says to Adso, equot;The only truth lies in  learning to free ourselves from the insane passion for the truth.equot;   Umberto Eco's strength lies in his plotting and his layering.  His books  are like a collection of boxes, each one opening to reveal yet another and  another.  I found no such layering in An Instance of the Fingerpost.  And,  finally, while An Instance of the Fingerpost was certainly a phenomenon,  The Name of the Rose is definitely much more.  This book is literature, a  timeless classic to be enjoyed by many generations yet to come.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Debbie Lee Wesselmann</user>
	<review>

Forget the movie version of THE NAME OF THE ROSE.  This brilliant book by Umberto Eco is meant to be read, absorbed, considered, held close to your chest before you reluctantly put it down. Filled with complexities - philosophy, historical details, superb characterizations - it does not make for easy reading.  I'm a seasoned reader of classics and literary fiction, and yet I struggled through the first pages.  What a mistake it would have been to give up!  Once I reached page 50 or so, I couldn't put it down.By now, the plot is well known:  a monk and his young assistant (the narrator) arrive at a monastery to investigate heresy at the height of the Inquisition.  No sooner do they arrive when their focus is shifted to a series of mysterious murders.  Who is behind the atrocious acts, and why?  Is there greater meaning to the deaths than first appears?  While the suspenseful plot keeps the story moving forward at surprising speed (surprising, given the language and wealth of historical details), the philosophy of the era is the soul of the novel, lending credulity to the characters and their situations as well as having implications for those living in the 21st century.  Issues of censorship, free thought, the power of the written word, and the need for rational thought in chaotic times all come into play. THE NAME OF THE ROSE is a magnificent example of fiction destined to last.  I highly recommend it for serious readers of all tastes.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Chris</user>
	<review>

This is not a proper review, more a couple of comments about things which the first few reviewers missed (I didn't read all 157 reviews). One of Umberto Eco's perennial themes, expressed elsewhere in essays, is what he sees as the the similarity between the society of the equot;dark agesequot; and that of today. For instance he draws explicit parallels between the heretics and utopian communities of the past and contemporary cults such as Jim Jones, the SLA, the Red Brigades and so forth. This book needs to be read in the light of that; it's not just a historical novel about monks. There are also obvious references to the work of Borges in this novel, as well as to Sherlock Holmes (William of Baskerville?). And of course the theme of rationalism versus superstition (not to mention religious war) has  been brought into considerably sharper focus by world events since the book was written.Overall, I can't see why people regard this as a hard book to read. Although there is a lot of historical background, (accurate rather than as some have suggested pseudo-philosophical or invented) it's presented in a vivid and entertaining way, the story keeps you turning the pages, and it's surely the only serious novel to include a recipe for fried cheese.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>S. Park</user>
	<review>

Before I say anything about the book - I think the Editorial Review and the first Synopsis that appears above should be deleted.  The Editorial gives the plot and the villain away and the Synopsis is just plain wrong -  it's not the Franciscans suspected of heresy that William is after!  Also,  he initially arrives to the Benedictine abbey on a diplomatic mission, and  gets involved only later in the investigation, and this of the murders, and  not the stray Franciscans!  Anyway, I first read The Name of the Rose in  college, in a well-annotated Korean edition, and at that time I thought it  was a great mystery but the historical/argumentative parts bogged it down a  bit.  Now I am reading it again in English, with a lot more appreciation  and interest in Middle Age civilization and politics, and I am savoring  every detail.  It helps to have The Key to the Name of the Rose at hand,  since the English edition doesn't offer any explanations on the Latin or  the numerous historical figures mentioned (but The Key isn't perfect either  - sometimes the glossary doesn't seem to offer enough pertinent  information).  I find myself laughing out loud at William's wickedly done  impersonations of Sherlock Holmes.  As Eco himself says, this is a story of  and for people who love books, with all the usual possessiveness, curiosity  and jealousy, and it is a really great read.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>M. J. JACKSON</user>
	<review>

OK there isn't much I can add to the already large volume of reviews devoted to this book.Personally I think its one of the best books I've read - I first read it because I had to read something for a school English dissertation and I chose this on a recommendation.  It did a pretty good job in providing me with lots to say then and helping me get into university so I've always been grateful to Umberto Eco ever since and I've reread it several times over the last decade and a half since then each time getting a little more out of it which is surely one of the hallmarks of a great book.  Many people have said that this works on a number of levels - detective story, historical novel set in a lost world of great religious and political turmoil, on a more abstract level as a philosophical novel tackling problems relating to our knowledge of the world, of faith versus reason etc.  This what to me is so great about it - if it was just a detective novel with a clever plot I've had read it once for my long forgotten English essay and not returned to it since.  Instead every time I've read it I've come away with some new thoughts having noticed some new detail or made sense of something that was previously obscure.  I don't agree with some of the other points made - first of all my latin is pretty much non-existent but I didn't have a problem with the latin - there isn't THAT much in there and much of it is more or less guessable from the surrounding dialogue.  Ditto the odd piece of French, Middle High German and the scraps of what I think might be Provencal.  I don't understand every word but it gives a good impression of a multilingual abbey full of latin speaking monks and adds to the background.  Also you don't need to be a philosophy expert or a historian - almost everything I know about religious debates in that period I got from this book.  I'm sure an expert in these fields would get even more out of this erudite tome but as it is you get plenty out of it anyhow and it all adds to the realistic quality of the setting.Some people find the religious debates unnecessary.  I think they are very necessary indeed - the book tackles themes of religious faith versus intellectual enquiry, the problems of knowledge, of how a totalitarian state controls the knowledge and freedoms of its subjects etc.  These are not just dry intellectual topics they are matters with consequences for the world we live in these "digressions" into religion and history show us these consequences - in William of Baskervilles' world we see how the poor and oppressed flock to the likes of Fra Dolcino and become terrorists and oppressors themselves, we see problems of what happens when religious leaders and ideologues seek too much temporal power, how totalitarian states control and distort reality through the control of information and how they crack down on freedom of thought.  Who can honestly say given the last 100 years these aren't relevant today? I could go on for pages more about this book but I've got to stop somewhere.  Clearly from other reviews not everyone will like this but I'd certainly recommend as many folk as possible to give it a go.  At times sure it takes an effort but ultimately its worth it.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Christian Thoma</user>
	<review>

Umberto Eco is the most complicated and most interesting authors in the world today (if you don't believe me, read Foucault's Pendulum).  To call it a equot;mysteryequot; is vastly oversimplifying things.  The book is  about discovery, and those who do not want things to be discovered.   Shrouded in a cloak of historical reality (the poverty debate between the  Papacy at Avignon and the ascendant Franciscan order), clever in even its  most mundane details (the labyrinth of the library), the Name of the Rose  is easily one of my top ten books of all time.  Be forewarned: this book is  not to be approached lightly; it is intellectual in every sense of the  word, and despite its labelling as a mystery, it does not resemble  contemporary mysteries at all. A word of advice (for any Eco book): if  you don't understand something, keep going.  Either it will be explained or  it will never come up again, in which case it need not be worried about.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>