<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jikoaite</user>
	<review>As usual, much better than the film!</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CarolC</user>
	<review>I met the author once. All I could say to him was "I love your book" repeatedly. He was so charming and gentlemanly. sadly, I forgot to ask his autograph.</review>
	<rating>0</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Daniel Peachey</user>
	<review>Eco is very obviously intelligent and knowledgeable. The research for this book must have taken months, let alone writing it.A simple premise to start with, as there is a murder in an abbey just as a new monk arrives, who is known for his great detective skills. As he attempts to solve the murder, there are more deaths, a massive amount of theological discussion, a background setting of religious turmoil across Europe, and even the abbey itself is a complex mystery laden with secrets.Even though you may find yourself at various points trying to understand the copious amounts of information regarding the scenario, or the scattered foreign (and untranslated) phrases, the story keeps moving at a nice pace, allowing you the time to think and follow the story as it is re-enacted by Adso many years in the future. It does however, suffer very slightly from the slow pace. William, the detective monk doesn't seem to spend much time detecting, and the murders can seem like sidenotes in the story of the religious background. It's almost as if Eco wanted to explore the theological aspects of the time rather than tell a story, but a story was the best way of going about getting people to read it.Nevertheless, this is only a small point, as the story (and thankfully) the religious discussions are interesting and well worth reading. It could be that the book suffered in my eyes as my reading pace slowed to a crawl during this book. It should be noted that this was my fault, and not the novel's.Overall, the novel is fascinating, well-written, well thought out, and ultimately very satisfying. The library in the Aedificium is probably one the best rooms ever created in literature, and the conclusion of the mystery is satisfying, even if the overall ending seems a tad over-dramatic, which is out of keeping with the rest of the book.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Your Sources</user>
	<review>'The late medieval world, teetering on the edge of discoveries and ideas that will hurl it into [a world] more recognisably like ours...evoked with a force and a wit that are breathtaking' – Financial Times...A spectacular popular and critical success, [the book] is not only a narrative of a murder investigation but an astonishing chronicles of the Middle Ages.</review>
	<rating>0</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>咕嚕 &amp; KK</user>
	<review>不知道發了什麼瘋，跑去買他的英文版小說... 查字典查到手軟啊。</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SU</user>
	<review>比中文版好多了雖然閱讀進度頗慢......</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0307264890</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Lou</user>
	<review>http://blog.360.yahoo.com/blog-nEP52Yc9dLOrgx_U...</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
</result>