<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bookworm in WI</user>
	<review>

Well, after deciding I needed to expand my repertoire of authors that I read, I happened to see Ms. Blackstock on a talk show--and she discussed briefly this new book.  I had heard of her previous pseudonyms, used in the secular market, but never read her--they were romance.  This book sounded perfect, and I was not disappointed!  The characters are well developed, the storyline moves at a good pace, and as the reader approaches the end...you can't wait to find out...whodunnit?  And what a twist!  I read this over the span of 24 hours--I had to sleep and take care of my little ones, you know--and boy, was it satisfying!  And I see it's Book 1 of a new series!  Well, now I need to go back and read her Newpointe 911 series, as I wait for the next installment of Cape Refuge!  If you like suspense, mystery and a "clean" read, you won't be disappointed with this one!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mystery Series Fan</user>
	<review>

When I find out about a good series, I try to read them in order but it's time consuming to find the order in which they're written.  So, I'm going to provide that for anyone else who's interested.  Read the Cape Refuge Series in this order:Cape RefugeSouthern StormRivers EdgeBreaker's ReefThis is an excellent series of stories following characters you'll soon realize you care deeply about.  Truly an enjoyable experience.  
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mariann Graczyk "marigr"</user>
	<review>

For anyone who is a mystery buff, this book is painful. The book begins with the murder of a  beloved couple on Cape Refuge. Their distraught daughters are determined to learn the truth about their parents' lives  and brutal deaths. Intriguing!  But then author looses focus and starts  putting her characters in jail so she won't have to weave them into the plot. One of the  protagonists spends the whole book behind bars, and he never even consults an attorney. Unbelieveable!  A good portion of the story is devoted to the characters' relationship to God, which may please some readers, but in reality, it acts like a filler so the author can keep the readers busy, and hope that they won't notice the glaring lack of a substantive story. I downloaded this authors second book, before I read this one, but will be sending it to kindle heaven unread.
      </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Shane Hendrickson</user>
	<review>

I first became hooked on Terri Blackstock when I read the "Newpointe 911" series. After that, I read her previous series, "SunCoast Chronicles". They were all great (Newpointe being far better), and this new series will have no problem living up to her name.I found the characters in Cape Refuge to be quite engaging. Unlike some previous books, this one didn't throw you at the bad guy right away. Some major plot twists keep you guessing for a while. (You may think it's this person, but then this person, but wait that person is lying...maybe...)A very awesome read and highly recommended.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Beverly J. Scott "Author and avid reader"</user>
	<review>

Author Terri Blackstock once again displayes her supurb talent with this well written fast-paced suspenseful narrative. Her down-to-earth realistic characters capture your heart as they struggle with the unexpected and brutal murder of Thelma and Wayne Owens. The drama and dialogue in "Cape Refuge" will keep you reading long after midnight. This hard-to-put-down Christian novel will turn you into a Blackstock fan. "Cape Refuge" a memorable novel.Beverly J Scott author of Righteous Revenge
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Michelle Connor</user>
	<review>

i was looking for mystery.  what i found was boring and preachy.  not a book for anyone who is not a rabid christian.
      </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Carrie S. Cloud "indycarrie"</user>
	<review>

Well, I've been reading Terri Blackstock's books for several years now, first the Sun Coast series then the Newpointe 911 series. After reading Cape Refuge, I think I may have to bump Sue Grafton from the top of my favorite contemporary authors list. Blackstock is a consistent winner. The characters in this book are all well developed, even the minor ones. The pacing is great. It doesn't suffer from that "plod along for 200+ pages then hurry up and solve the crime" problem that many modern mysteries do. I really can't recommend this book, and Blackstock, highly enough. If you like Christian mysteries, start reading this woman's work!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Dr. Jarvis L. Doyle "Traindoc"</user>
	<review>

I got to chapter 6.  Johnathon is arrested by Cade.  On no evidence except a  missing spear gun and he the only known owner of such a gun.  For MURDER !  What baloney !  I am a retired dentist and I could have defended this case. This author knows NOTHNG about police procedure, evidence, or jurisprudence at ALL!
      </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Deborah A. Wedick "gnarfle23"</user>
	<review>

not worth the price paid for this book. reads like a romance novel with extremely preachy overtone. cardboard characters. now i have to read the section about how to delete from my kindle. i am relieved that no trees died for this book in the king dle version
      </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0310235928</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>T. Poole "Faith and Fiction Fan"</user>
	<review>

I guess I am very spoiled. After reading her other projects, I have grown accustomed to in depth characters, solid plots, and great pacing. In this one, the characters were lovable, but somewhat shallow. The plot was decent, but definitely not her best creation. The pacing was rather slow. If you have never read one of her other books, then you should enjoy this one. However, if you have read the Newpoint 911 or SunCoast Chronicles series, don't expect that kind of excellence. This book didn't read as fast as her others.This was an average book. Pick it up at the library.
      </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
</result>