<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zashibis</user>
	<review>

Negative reviews get no love on Amazon, but, having been thoroughly taken in by the glowing reviews in the NYT, Time, the Economist, etc., I feel compelled to add a voice of dissent and caution.I read and enjoyed The Corrections, so was looking forward to seeing what Franzen had been up to for the past 10 years. What he's been up to is, essentially, rewriting The Corrections, but extracting all the humor that leavened the misanthropic bleakness of his vision in the earlier work. Once again we're presented with an outwardly "perfect" nuclear Midwestern family that secretly consists of neurotic hysterics with low self-esteem who ultimately find themselves mired in infidelity and morally dubious business dealings. Once again the focus is on generational conflict, and the "sins of the fathers" revisited in the lives of the children.Besides the lack of originality, the problem, in essence, is this time out I don't believe a single, solitary word of it. I don't believe in liberal middle-class parents who'd let their teenage son move in with their obnoxious Republican neighbors. I don't believe in a talented college athlete who'd let herself be hoodwinked for years by a ditzy, obsessive fan. I don't believe in a committed environmentalist who'd sign off on strip mining vast tracts of virgin forest in the name of reclaiming those tracts many years afterwards for a single-species preserve. I don't believe in a 19-year-old arms dealer making procurement purchases in Paraguay. I don't believe in a couple who remain married, but utterly incommunicado, for 6 years. I don't believe in a 47-year-old man with no religious convictions who is trying beer for the very first time, and is prone to bursting into tears on the least provocation. And that's just for starters.Worse, the dialogue this time out is actually painful to read in its patent artificiality. I defy anyone to point to a passage in this book and seriously maintain that this is how parents, children or lovers actually talk to one another, in 2010 or ever. It's as stilted and laden with portentousness as soap opera dialogue. In a plot-driven page-turner in the Grisham mode, this wouldn't be a fatal flaw, but Freedom, with its political and social preoccupations, is a novel that wants to be taken be seriously, and that's simply not possible when the characters speak in an uninterrupted steam of cliche.The very worst bit, however, is Patty's 200-page "autobiography" which purports to be her life story told in her own voice, but is, in fact, completely indistinguishable from the authorial voice used in the rest of the novel. That this "autobiography" is later part of significant -- and, again, wholly unbelievable -- plot twist compounds this reader's dismay.A last problem is the characterization in the novel. One-dimensional caricatures abound, from Patty's Hippie-dippy sister Abigail to Walter's starry-eyed, buxom assistant Lalith to Joey's shallow, glamour-puss love-interest Jenna to the shrill Fundamentalist kook who plays a significant role in the final section of the novel. The main characters -- Walter, Patty, Richard, and Joey -- are more developed, but scarcely more believable. Walter's character, for instance, does a 180 -- starting as a preternaturally patient, kind, dutiful son and husband, and becoming an erratic, impatient, unhinged hothead. The problem is not so much the change in personality -- people do change over time -- but the fact that the reader isn't privy to what drives or motivates the change. We see the college-age milquetoast and the middle-aged fanatic, but no steps in between.It gives me no particular pleasure to trash this novel. Franzen is to be commended for attempting something ambitious in a Tolstoyan mode (Tolstoy is, in fact, referenced directly and indirectly throughout the novel) -- to give an American picture of "how we live now." But, for me, unfortunately, his effort here falls completely flat, and I can't possibly recommend it to anyone.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BrianB</user>
	<review>

I will avoid the plot review, because so many others seem compelled to summarize, and the repetition becomes tiresome. I enjoyed this novel, and I think you will too. I gave it four stars because it is not perfect, but it is better than most current fiction. Franzen may be a "serious" writer, but he is also highly readable, with an interesting story that can be enjoyed for itself alone, absent any considerations of literary aspirations.This is a big, rambling tale of modern Americans in their modern lives, people who reminded me of real people, a plot which kept me turning the pages of this compulsively readable, mostly entertaining novel. The tone is slightly condescending, as the quote above my review would suggest, mostly cynical, and ultimately hopeful by the end of the story, when his battered, bruised and bruising characters emerge from the wreckage of their lives, and bravely carry on.In many ways this novel is similar to his previous work, The Corrections. I remember enjoying that novel a few years back, although I could not understand why the critics raved about it. Franzen proves yet again that he is a very good writer, building a complicated but workable plot, creating characters who are real, complex and often disappointing, showing us his American self-portrait in 2010. He reaches for a big theme, as the title implies, but he doesn't quite achieve his goal of demontrating the illusory nature of our freedom (or alternatively that all this freedom is killing us). Like Sophocles, Franzen seems to take a dim view of freedom. I probably should not compare Franzen to Sophocles, or other great writers, past or present. He has a genuine voice, a straightforward style, but he does not possess lyrical abilities, nor great thematic breadth. His writing style is similar to Paul Murray's, serving up a cast of mostly unremarkable people who screw up their lives by means of their character defects, giving you a funny and sad slice of everyday life, saying something profound in the process.Amazon reviewers were much less enamored with The Corrections than the professional reviewers: they gave only three stars on average, with almost as many one star reviews as five star. Franzen's self portraits are closer to the world of the publishing industry than the world of amazon readers. His characters are based in the Midwest, at least in the beginning of the novel, but they are not the American everyman or woman. They are highly educated, well read, socially evolved and spiritually lost in the manner of the wealthy white specimen liberalis americanus. This writing feels too focused upon their world to allow for universal appeal.  Nevertheless, Freedom is a very well and carefully written novel. Only time itself will reveal if this is the work of the moment, or a work for all time.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cary B. Barad</user>
	<review>

Excellent writing when dealing with the painfully intimate and intricate details of adolescence, marriage, childrearing, infidelity and romantic yearnings.  In fact, it approaches the true-to-life fictional style used so successfully by Tom Wolfe in the "Bonfire of the Vanities," and "A Man in Full."Yet, this saga ominously hits a brick wall when it becomes enmeshed with any number of environomental, social and political issues (incluing mining and overpopulation) that seem to go on for far too long and which consume an excessive amount of time and space.  Very "preachy", didactic and repetitive if you will.As a result, we are confronted with a lengthy novel that is only partially rewarding.  It is constucted on cycles of excitement and tedium which make for an erratic reading experience.  You really have to invest a good deal of time and effort searching for the literary nuggets that make the effort worthwhile in the end.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jesse Kornbluth "Head Butler"</user>
	<review>

Barack Obama went to Martha's Vineyard and there obtained, a week before its release, a copy of Jonathan Franzen's novel. That same week, my family was heading to the Bahamas, and because we'd be isolated on a island three miles long and half a mile wide, with spotty internet access and even more problematic electricity, I was able to convince the publisher to give me an embargoed copy of the book.I doubt that the President has made his way through all 562 pages of "Freedom." My wife and I have made it to the end. It required no effort of will, just a little negotiation ("I'll take the kid to the beach if you'll use the time to read"). That is how, on our final morning overlooking the pink sands where Corona makes its wish-you-were-there beer commercials, I staggered to the end, sobbing as I read the last ten pages. My wife finished the book while we waited for our baggage in New York, and then couldn't speak for most of the cab ride home. What's the big deal? The people. Not the characters. The people. Men and women we come to know and care about, not because they're so admirable but because they're so real. Like Patty Berglund, a former college basketball star, now a stay-at-home mom. In her slowly gentrifying neighborhood in St. Paul, Minnesota, she was, Franzen writes, "already fully the thing that was just starting to happen to the rest of the street." That is: "a morning of baby-encumbered errands, an afternoon of public radio, the Silver Palate Cookbook, cloth diapers, drywall compound and latex paint, and then Goodnight Moon, then zinfandel." The questions that plagued her: "Where to recycle batteries? ... How elaborate did a kitchen water filter need to be? ...Could coffee beans be ground the night before you used them, or did this have to be done in the morning?"  Like Walter Berglund, her husband. Son of a man who owned a small motel in Hibbing --- yes, that Hibbing, where Bob Zimmerman grew up and dreamed himself into Bob Dylan --- he was the very nice guy you never really knew in college because he was studying so hard and working his way through school. He'd met Patty there and knew she was The One, and waited for her to know it. And when she said yes, and shared that her dream was motherhood, he shelved every exalted ambition to get a job in Corporate Communications at 3M. When we meet him, he's the executive director of Minnesota's Nature Conservancy, having trouble with his teen-aged son, about to move to Washington for a new job --- he'll sell his St. Paul house "near the bottom of the post-9/11 slump." One more character drives this novel, Walter's college roommate and unlikely best friend. Richard Katz is the leader of nihilistic rock bands, and he's made for the part: talk, dark and arrogant, deadly attractive to women and eager to exploit that attraction. You don't want the truth served up with nasty spin? Keep away from Richard. Patty keeps away. Not because she dislikes Richard --- she craves him. But she's made her choice: a man who will do anything to create a home with her. Hot sex? It passes. It has to. Except that.... This is Fiction 101: Building Characters, and if you're surprised how hard it grabs you, it's because today's most acclaimed fiction is too "literary" to care more about people than language or structure or the next definition of fiction. Franzen, like Balzac and Dickens, is a journalist at heart --- what he's created in "Freedom" is this generation's "Bonfire of the Vanities." The mark of this kind of novel is not only that it feels true but that it becomes true. There's a sequence here about American profiteering during the early days of the Iraq War that's excruciating in its account of American officials who didn't give a damn. Now, as the war "ends, recent articles remind us of billions lost and unaccounted for. These crimes, for the government, are consigned to a memory hole. But there's no lack of accountability here. Not on Franzen's watch. Look anywhere in this novel, and you'll see how it defines our time. Like that bird on the cover. It's not decorative. It's going to have its own preserve in West Virginia, courtesy of a billionaire who will, in exchange for a few protected acres, get to blow up mountains and harvest coal. And just as we're reading this, here is Jane Mayer's revelatory New Yorker profile of David and Charles Koch, the billionaires whose companies pollute and despoil while David gives hundreds of millions to Lincoln Center, the American Museum of Natural History, and the Metropolitan Museum of Art. Let's consider the title. Franzen's characters are not like the Koch brothers or the coal magnate or the Iraq fraudsters. They are their victims, living in an America where we make our biggest choices as shoppers. It's a dreary, ugly culture. Even Walter --- staid Walter --- comes to make a surprising indictment: "As long as you've got your six-foot-wide-plasma TV and the electricity to run it, you don't have to think about any of the ugly consequences. You can watch 'Survivor: Indonesia' till there's no more Indonesia!" The personal quarrels? Just as lacerating. I can't imagine having a fight with my wife as ugly as the ones in these pages. But they're not set-pieces. They're the intimate moments of people whose conflicts, though maybe not ours, are recognizable to us. And when those fights end, sometimes there is clarity, even beauty: "She cried then, torrentially, and he lay down with her. Fighting had become their portal to sex, almost the only way it ever happened anymore. While the rain lashed and the sky flashed, he tried to fill her with self-worth and desire, tried to convey how much he needed her to be the person he could bury his cares in. It never quite worked, and yet, when they were done, there came a stretch of minutes in which they lay in the quiet majesty of long marriage, forgot themselves in shared sadness and forgiveness for everything they'd inflicted on each other, and rested." "The quiet majesty of long marriage" --- that phrase stopped me cold and led me back to the ultimate subject of this book, which is, I think, the challenge of building a functional romantic partnership when you're carrying the legacy of your flawed family and your country's dishonest and exploitative culture. Again, I suspect this challenge isn't unique to Patty and Walter Berglund. It's mine, for sure. And, just maybe, yours. And that is why the end is so devastating. It's richly symbolic --- and, for once, the symbol works. It sets our fond hopes against our hard realities. It reminds us of the limits of our personal power. It redefines what "freedom" is for people like us, in a time like this. And it suggests, after our big dreams have been crushed, that we may still make smaller dreams come true. I wish I could be more specific, but that would spoil your experience of "Freedom." Let me just say that the end is everything you want from a great book --- it's not rushed or tacked on or phony or commercial or cynical. It's at once heartbreaking and inspiring, and it makes you both elated and very, very sad. But, most of all, it immortalizes Patty and Walter and confirms what you are, by then, already feeling --- these imaginary people are in your heart, the way your closest friends are.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Elizabeth Whalen</user>
	<review>

I bought this book based on two reviews: New York Magazine's ("it reminds you why everyone got so excited about Franzen in the first place") and The Economist's ("brilliant") combined with the fact that I thought The Corrections was a very good book.  The Economist gives out reviews like that about as often as Simon Cowell, so I thought, "even I, who am very picky, am going to like *this* book".  For the first 381 pages, though, the only thing I liked was that I was coming closer to either being finished with this book or to what I thought had to be an incredibly good ending to justify the incredibly good reviews.  The characters were immature, lacked perspective and were in many ways unconvincing to me.  Walter was obsessed with overpopulation issues but directed most of his anger at the Catholic church for this problem and wanted, it seemed, to discourage people from having any children.  We humans, he makes very clear, are a "cancer on the planet".  I certainly agree the overpopulation is a problem and only growing in scope, but I had a difficult time believing a 50-year old who had supposedly spent so much time "thinking" about the issue was so unwilling to do what it takes to actually make a difference in solving the problem.  Instead of advocating policies that might actually work, such as trying to reduce the number of unplanned pregnancies in the world, he starts a non-profit to try to encourage 19-year-olds (who will certainly *never* change their minds!) to never have children.  Perhaps a 30-year old would be convincing in this role, but not a 50-year old.  As a result, it seems Franzen is not trying to make a policy argument but rather using the issue to represent Walter's anger with people in general.  Unfortunately, this did not work for me, and this is just one of many examples of unconvincing behavior by characters combined with the unsuccessful use of metaphors in this book.Another disappointing feature of the first 381 pages was the onslaught of information about characters, policy issues and family histories, much of which was not directly or even indirectly relevant to the story.  Several minor characters and a few subplots could have been eliminated without detracting from the book.Sexual tension -- will they or won't they?? -- also played a significant role in the first part of the book, but it often felt like a ploy to keep you reading when a good editing job could have achieved the same effect, saved us all a lot of time, and the world some trees.  Even Walter would have approved of the saving of the trees!Finally, beginning with the section entitled "Bad News", the news for the reader actually becomes good.  Characters become people to whom we can connect rather than just people about whom we know many facts.  The theme of "Freedom" stops being so heavy-handed.  The word "somewhat" is used less frequently.  The phrase "significant look" finally disappears.  Rewards for all the time and energy spent reading begin to appear, and even better ones appear to be coming soon! I consider myself a patient reader, but as emotionally affected as I was by the ending of this book, I gave it three stars because I do not believe the time spent getting there was worth it.  I considered giving up around page 250, and at that point would have given it two stars.  If you haven't read The Corrections, I suggest that book instead, but many people (not including me) found the characters to be unlikeable.  If you are impatient, or prefer your books to reward you all along the way, as I believe they ought to, skip this one.  
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Professor Donald Mitchell "Jesus Loves You!"</user>
	<review>

"Then many false prophets will rise up and deceive many. And because lawlessness will abound, the love of many will grow cold. But he who endures to the end shall be saved." -- Matthew 24:11-13 (NKJV) Freedom is the best new work of fiction I've read so far in 2010. Freedom looks at the pain, responsibility, and potential involved in doing what appeals to you . . . regardless of the cost to anyone else. It's a worthwhile trip that manages to touch on a wide variety of ways that freedom pulls us in some directions and away from others. There's plenty of food for thought here, parceled out in bite-sized nuggets that you can chew on for weeks to come. I was particularly impressed by the story's narrative structure. As the book opens, you see the Berglund family from the outside-in, the neighbors' view. Very quickly, one set of patterns are disrupted into a totally unexpected direction, drawing you irresistibly into wanting to know what happened. In part the answer is that no one who isn't in a family really knows what goes on in a family. In another part, it's that people keep secrets from one another . . . particularly what they see as their own dark sides that they don't want others to know about. From there, the story richly expands into four narratives, by narrators whose connections to others are rich and hard to grasp . . . even for themselves. It's only by overlaying the narratives that the whole picture begins to emerge. At times, you'll want to shake one character or another into doing something different, but of course you cannot do that with a fictional character any more easily than you can with most real persons. Jonathan Franzen is a well-read author and a talented writer so his narrations dig deep into a variety of literary sources and methods to establish mood, color, imagery, emotion, psychology, physical sensations, and experiences that you'll find seem more than vaguely familiar . . . even when you cannot exactly place them. It's all subtly and humorously done, by an author who loves people and wants the best for them. There's a warm heart underneath all the Sturm und Drang that is what ultimately sets the book apart. I was pleased to see that the book takes seriously such important subjects as marital love, friendship, sexual attraction, depression, sibling rivalries, parental mistakes, social responsibility, and serving one's fellow human. Rather than treating each topic as a single point of light, Mr. Franzen steps back to give you a globe's eye view from both without and from within. It's at once both terrifically subjective and wonderfully objective.Be careful that you don't read any reviews that get into much of the story. You need to be surprised in places for this book to work its full magic on you.Bravo, Mr. Franzen!
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Sundown</user>
	<review>

I'm amazed at most of these reviews. I hadn't read "Corrections," but when almost every critic declares "Freedom" a literary masterpiece, I had to at least pick it up.  After 250 pages, I put it down for good. Instead of loving these characters, as Amazon.com's official review promised I would, I found them to be terminally tedious. The focus of part of the book on physical masturbation is just a metaphor for the mental and emotional processes of the characters.  The cardboard cutouts could have labels instead of names: The Unfulfilled Housewife, The Dull But Well-Intentioned Husband, The Irresistible Other, The Rebellious Son, the Weird Girlfriend, The Sexy Adoring Assistant, etc., etc.  There's an occasional insight, but not enough to justify spending a big chunk of your life plodding through 576 pages.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Norma Lehmeierhartie</user>
	<review>

I purchased Freedom: A Novel the day it was released and meant to write a review. Just got an email from Amazon, announcing that Freedom is the newest Oprah pick, so decided to review it here.As a non-fiction author, I have always been awed at the ability of (good) fiction writers because they take characters and bring them to life! To do this successfully is a true gift--a gift that Jonathan Franzen possesses.   There are few things more satisfying than a great novel...and a long great novel is even better! Jonathan Franzen managed to keep me riveted for almost 600 pages. You know the feeling...when you are reading a terrific book, all you want to do is read it! Now, Freedom is just the type of novel I love, as he depicts characters from a sociological point of view. While I also enjoy sociological books from a historical perspective (Sinclair Lewis, Steinbeck, Dostoevsky, etc) I also love a novel set in our current times.Without giving away the plot, suffice to say this novel deals with life in the 21st century and that Franzen does an excellent job of portraying both the minutia and the bigger picture.I found myself nodding throughout;as in, I get this. But I also laughed...and, warning--do not read ending in public if you don't like crying in front of people! Ultimately, this book will have you reflect on your own life and the choices you ultimately make.Highly recommend.Non-fiction author, reader, reviewer
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Joseph M. Powers</user>
	<review>

I found things to enjoy in this book, but perhaps not as many as some of the adoring reviewers have found.  I might be in the sweet spot of Franzen's target audience--an NPR-listening, Big 10-educated, Obama-supporting fellow with a few midwestern and generational overlaps with the novel's hero, Walter.  But by the end, I wanted Garrison Keillor's radio troupe, who were no doubt St. Paul neighbors of Walter and his wife Patty, to drop by and give them some words of wisdom from the Ketchup Advisory Board.  And maybe some trimming by Keillor's Professional Organization of English Majors would help.  Yes, Walter and company had their moments, but all in all, they, and their games of musical beds, bored me.Not enough however to keep me from plowing through the book in three long sittings.  The theme of freedom was woven nicely throughout in a way that resonates with today's reality.  Franzen has an attention for detail that often captured me.  I especially liked his portrait of late 70's/early 80's college life, as well as some of the foibles of upper middle class urban living.  By and large, he gives an accurate portrayal of my generation and our times.  And that bothered me--mainly because on reflection I prefer the literature and mores of days gone relative to those of today. Adoring reviewers, no doubt inspired by Franzen's "War and Peace" references scattered throughout "Freedom," raised my hopes that we may have a new Tolstoy on our hands.  Alas, no. A few years ago, I also rushed through "War and Peace" and was dazzled.  It was an utter joy to read through its emotional highs and lows.   I was more quietly dazzled after reading "David Copperfield" this past summer.  Franzen's characters always seem to have some sort of pharmaceutical assistance to temper their extremes, and so does the novel.  So unless a friend who suggested I come up for air and read some twenty-first century fiction can come up with some better suggestions, I may well find myself regressing back to the nineteenth century for my reading pleasure, with an occasional interruption by Phillip Roth.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0312600844</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jennifer</user>
	<review>

A disappointment.  Does Franzen have children?  I suspect he doesn't, and that's why the descriptions of the Bergland family dynamics, while having the ring of truth, are just missing something.  We never really get a glimpse inside the house.  Their lives are told at a distance from the point of view of friends and neighbors.  Within the average American household, marital relations, at least those that go the distance described here (birth through college), are much messier and yet a whole lot more loving in ways that are just not shown in this book.  There's also this made-for-t.v. aspect to the novel, one in which the cost of living - actual dollars and cents -- is completely missing from life's equations. (It's like those t.v. sit-coms in which presumably working class households have perfectly matching furniture and everything is spic-and-span. Who paid for that divan?) I don't know a married couple together today who doesn't think about the financial implications of a break-up as much as the emotional ramifications.And while Patty Bergland is recognizable, I think I speak for most women here:  working for wages (i.e., outside the home) is not an option;  it's a necessity.  Stay-at-home motherhood of the variety that also includes cupcake-baking, kids' sports activities, and Victorian house renovations is only possible for people with some serious (probably inherited) money.  A spouse's environmental activist/lawyer's salary would be a reach.  Finally, the Richard Katz character...well, those of us who came of age in the late 70s and early 80s can certainly relate to his sense of alienation and his reluctance to commit.  But does he have to rag on the youth of today to make his point?  Sounds like an old codger to me, one not too different from every other embittered emissary from an earlier generation who couldn't handle life's realities.  Does he not form any lasting relationships in the music world itself?  What happened to his Grammy-award nominated band members?The main characters' childish solipsism carried through to middle age makes them unlikeable, if not unrealistic. I think I understand what Franzen is trying to do, but it's not quite the America I know or see around me.  Those kids attending that concert that Katz goes to with Walter?  More likely than not, they're more mixed ethnically and racially than ever before.  Not too many pure whitebread households around anymore.  And that's not necessarily a bad thing.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>