<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>P. Nicholas Keppler "rorscach12"</user>
	<review>

With the endless barrages of big-budgeted, simple-minded, ray gun-blasting movies and absurdly complex, geek-aimed fantasy trilogies and tetralogies that have ruled the genre during the past decade, it is difficult to believe that science fiction stories were once compelling, introspective works that employed strange and surreal methods to carry great sociopolitical and philosophical weight. The Man Who Fell to Earth by Walter Tevis, first published in 1963, is a paradigmatic example of that fine, long-gone variety of space age tale. Mr. Tevis' protagonist, a tall, slender, frail humanoid that calls itself "Thomas Jerome Newton," is sent to Earth from Anthea, a planet where the only knowledge of our world is from the television broadcasts that reach it. Between the glossy commercials and the startling news reports, the Antheans see Earth as a green, watery utopia in some ways and a nuclear powder keg in others. After falling from the Kentucky sky in a one-man spacecraft, Newton embarks on a shady and ambiguous mission. The reserved and methodical stranger's true intent is way too surprising and well developed for any measly reviewer to rightfully give it away. Without letting slip too many precious details, I will tell you that the flimsy extraterrestrial discovers the darker aspects of human society, the feelings of futility, the addictions and vices, the ignorance and distrust and other stigmas not shown on TV. From Newton's fragile eyes, Mr. Tevis does nothing less than paint a striking portrait of the frustrations of being an Earthling.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Amanda Pike</user>
	<review>

I have found myself to be something of a fan of speculative fictions.  And The man who fell to Earth by Walter Tevis has been, for a long time now, a book that I have grown to appreciate in what it says and how it expresses it, about the human condition through an inhuman perspective.  And I happen to own an edition that was published in 1963, so you can imagine my disappointment when I bought a new copy and found the revisions, which were not only unnecessary but also inconsistent.           Now, I agree that some equot;datedequot; books are in need of revisions, however, when Walter Tevis (may he rest in peace) had revised his book, The man who fell to Earth, he left it lacking in it's original believability by leaving inconsistencies in the dates that the novel takes place within.                      The novel was always meant to take place ten years or so in the future and I believe that before his death in 1984, Mr. Tevis had intended to possibly revise it yet again but hadn't the chance due to his fatal run in with cancer.                The original novel opened with the Section Icarus Descending 1972, the revised version opens with Icarus Descending 1985.   The second section of book is Rumplestiltskin, 1975, in the revised version this is 1988. The final section of the book is Icarus Drowning, 1976, and 1990 in the revised edition novel.  Now this might not seem a bother at all really but here's where my qualm lies...                 The section called Rumplestiltskin begins in autumn of 1988.  And in that December (not to spoil the plot) late on Christmas night, Thomas Jerome Newton, the protagonist of the novel confesses to the Chemistry professor, Nathan Bryce that he is in fact an alien visitor from another world.  The following morning, Thomas Jerome Newton is taken captive by the American government and held for two months.  It should be about February of 1989, or there about.  However, he is interrogated, at the end of those two months, and the interrogator is commented as saying equot;It just happens that this is 1988.  And 1988 is an election year.equot; - (Page 180 of the revised edition of The man who fell to Earth.)             Allowing this little flaw to slide, we move on.  And Thomas Jerome Newton is carelessly blinded by his captors and for two weeks he is kept in a government hospital where nothing can be done to help him.  The next section of book starts, Icarus Drowning 1990.  This gives you the impression that it's at least a year later.  However, according to page 197, the very first page of Icarus Drowning, it is only seven months after the end of Rumplestiltskin, let's see...  From the end of 1988- Seven months, plus two weeks, plus two months, equals nine and and half months.  At most it should be October of 1989.  What happened to 1989?   Perhaps I have not lived on planet Earth long enough but I'm fairly certain that nine and a half months is not a full year.                 A second thing I dislike about the revised version of The man who fell to Earth, is something that is missing from the original text.  In the original novel, published in 1963, there is an allusion towards the end when Thomas Jerome Newton, our protagonist is compared to Winston Smith, the hero of George Orwell's Nineteen eighty-four.  I had liked that.  And I don't like that it is missing from the version currently in print.                 The man who fell to Earth is a wonderfully surreal novel but I just wish that someone would drop the revised version and go back to Tevis' original text from the American 1963 version.  I know that it had been Walter Tevis himself to write the revisions for the novel (1976 in the UK and 1981 in the USA) but the fact is Walter Tevis had been an alcoholic and that might have impaired his reasoning when revising his novel. If anything, I feel that people should have the choice to read the original, classic, unabridged text, or the cut, shoddy, inconsistent, and overly politically correct revised edition.              This novel is supposedly a science fiction classic and yet the only way anyone can actually read the whole, original text would be by buying a first edition from a used book shoppe or from ebay.com. And I think that it's a real shame, that other then seeking collectable stores or antique book markets, there is no way that anyone can really read the original book, which by the way, had consistent dates.               It feels, in reality, almost like the horrific tragedy of Ray Bradbury's Fahrenheit 451, that society, so obsessed with political correctness, have grown so very careless with it's equot;Classicequot; fictions.  And we, as a result, lose out in beautiful works on fiction that shall, as a result, fade off in to oblivion, it's original content forgotten or painted over and we are left with cut and equot;revisedequot; reprints which for all their gloss remain flawed with inconsistencies, bits and pieces missing, and abridgments. And these either insult us intellectually or give us to know that over all, our attention spans have grown so short as to not notice or care.          Ignoring the flaws and inconsistencies with the datings of the revised version of The man who fell to Earth (The only version that had ever been in print in the UK and the only edition available currently in America, since 1981), it is actually a very good, and intriguing piece of speculative- science fiction. And I just think that it's a real pity, a sin really, that no one has even tried to reprint the original, unabridged or non equot;revisedequot; text for over twenty-two years, even in the USA where it was first published.
      </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

The copyright page discloses that this book was first published in 1963, and yet on page 180 there is a reference to the Watergate scandal of the 1970s. The copyright page makes no references to any revisions having been  made to the original version, but obviously there have been some. I'd like  to know if these revisions were made by Tevis himself, and when were they  done, and why? And has anything else been added to the text since its  original publication? Why does Del Rey not disclose that this is a revised  edition, and not the original?
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

Okay, this isn't the ONLY book I'd take, but definitely in the top 10.  I read it long ago, initially because I was intrigued by the title.  Upon completing it, I was speechless.  There's so much substance in this book,  and the message it presents couldn't be any more clear.  The title  is so  appropriate, almost a joke on the author's part.It should truly be  considered a science fiction classic, so it's hard for me to understand  just why it's been out of print for so long... and even when it's back in  print, why an overpriced trade edition?  It's a shame when the shelves are  cluttered with layer upon layer of alternate-history/nanotech/  cyberpunk/shoot-em-up crud, but books like this are dismissed.  It's no  wonder that the field is so often dismissed with a scoff.  Read this book  and see that science fiction can have a worthwhile message.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

i, like some other people who have written reviews for this novel, had seen the movie many times before ever picking up a copy of the book.  it is one of my favourite movies, partly due to the fact that my idol, david  bowie, is the star of the film.now, that i have read the book, however,  i see the movie in a different light.  first of all, i now find the movie  somewhat more dissapointing.  it doesn't stay true to tevis's wonderful  novel.  hopefully, whoever wrote the screenplay has either improved his  skills or has found another line of work.now, to the book...if ever you  have felt lonely or out of place in your surroundings, which everyone in  the world has, then you must read this book.  it is a story of thomas  jerome newton, an alien from the planet anthea, and his mission to build a  space ferry so that he can transport the few remaining 'people' of his race  to earth, for their planet is suffering from something like  post-apocalyptic decay.  In addition, newton plans to implement his race's  knowledge of government workings into the governments of earth in order to  save earthlings and their wonderful, water-abundant planet from certain  destruction.however, the government (cia, fbi) interfere with newtons  plans, for they suspect that he is not of this planet, and arrest him, poke  and prod him, experiment on him, then finally set him free but with nothing  to return to...he is trapped on planet earth alone, with no real  companions.if you've seen the movie already, you know that it is rather  difficult to explain.  it indeed has many holes in the script, but the book  indeed fills in these gaps.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Melissa McCauley</user>
	<review>

Thomas Jerome Newton is the name chosen by an alien from Anthea who crash lands his small spacecraft in the Kentucky countryside, then begins a business empire by pawning diamond engagement rings. Antheans, the poor remnants of a once-great culture which almost annihilated itself, wish to stop Earthlings from meeting the same fate. The lonely Newton builds a multi-million dollar empire by patenting and selling his advanced alien technology aided by patent lawyer Oliver Farnsworth, chemical engineer Nathan Bryce, and drunken housekeeper/nursemaid Betty Jo Mosher. His goal is to finance building a spaceship to bring more Antheans to Earth and stop mankind's eventual self destruction. The Cold War belief that Earth's incineration is a forgone conclusion dates this novel, but thankfully there are no silver suits, ray guns, or robots. Instead, the author chose to explore Newton's role as a perpetual outsider on Earth, but in my opinion he missed the mark. The first 2/3 of the story concentrates on using all the whiz-bang alien technology to make oodles of money, which (I'm going to get flamed for this) seems geared to attract the readership of adolescent boys. Newton's loneliness and downward spiral into substance abuse is only mentioned in passing through the bulk of the narrative, and only brought into sharp focus in the last bit of the story. elt;Sigh This could have been a deft exploration of the term "alienation".  br /br /If you like this type of story, I recommend a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0441788386/ref=cm_cr_asin_lnk/189-0249321-1636801"Stranger in a Strange Land/a by Robert  Heinleinbr /
      </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

I have the 70's paperback with the Bowie movie picture on it, and  am also distressed that new editions have changed the story dates. I couldn't buy a replacement copy after noticing that, so I don't know who changed the book or why or what else was equot;revisedequot;. Certainly if they are going to muck with a great classic like this a word of explanation is in order. That complaint aside, this is one of the best books I've ever read. It's moving, evocative, thought provoking, full of the touches of a writer who was a real artist. It's one of the few books I always need close by so I can pick it up and be swept away by its brilliance. The original gets 5 stars...I'm taking one off for the needless changes.
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>M. Vanvorst "two left feet"</user>
	<review>

This story is about an alien who comes to earth with a missionto save the few remaining people of his own planet, and to saveus from destroying ourselves.It's an easy read, enjoyable, and believable.  The main characteris well developed and the pacing remains brisk throughout.  It'snot very science fiction-y, more of a human interest story.It's interesting to note that this was originally published in 1963 and bears the marks of cold war/nuclear destruction fears.This, and many other works of that time assume that we would nukeourselves to rubble at some point.  The story takes place inthe late eighties so the author is making some guesses about thattime, like every country would have nuclear capabilities and wewould be teetering on the brink.  I was amused when one of thecharacters went to see a movie and sat through a news reel.  Alsothat the alien states that there are no other solar systems thathe knows of.Those distractions are minor however, and I very much recommendyou read the book.
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Amber Overla</user>
	<review>

Okay, I put off reading this book for quite a while. I have been a huge fan of the movie The Man Who Fell to Earth, and didn't want to read the book and be dissapointed with either.  And now that i have read the book i am happy to say that i was not dissappointed by it, but sad to say that it showed me how butchered the story was when put to movie form.  Still a very good movie and still one of my favorites. The movie is actually better at conveying the way the equot;alienequot; becomes more and more human. That being said, this book is a sad one. Not gushy sad, but reality sad. I felt extremely sorry for the charracters, mostly because they all seemed to be unaware of how horrid human beings can be.  There really weren't any bad guys however, everyone in the story was just very misguided. That made it very real for me. I think everyone should read this just so they can re think how they are going about things. Its a great story with great charracters and ends with an unforgettable lesson.Now for what i've read in some other reviews on here. I totally agree that the revised addition is not the one to read. Find an older copy if you want to get the full effect of the book. The differences aren't huge, but i think they do make a difference. Second, i read somewhere on here that the revised addtion was the only one ever offered in the UK. That is not true. It might be hard to get one thats not, but when the movie came out there was a UK addition with a equot;bowieequot; cover that was a little different than the US version, but the inside was the same and unrevised. I don't know if that matters, but it might give someone something to look out for. In closing. Great book. Great lesson. Makes you think. Read it.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0345431618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>P. Nicholas Keppler "rorscach12"</user>
	<review>

With the endless barrages of big-budgeted, simple-minded, ray gun-blasting movies and absurdly complex, geek-aimed fantasy trilogies and tetralogies that have ruled the genre during the past decade, it is difficult to believe that science fiction stories were once compelling, introspective works that employed strange and surreal methods to carry great sociopolitical and philosophical weight. The Man Who Fell to Earth by Walter Tevis, first published in 1963, is a paradigmatic example of that fine, long-gone variety of space age tale. Mr. Tevis' protagonist, a tall, slender, frail humanoid that calls itself "Thomas Jerome Newton," is sent to Earth from Anthea, a planet where the only knowledge of our world is from the television broadcasts that reach it. Between the glossy commercials and the startling news reports, the Antheans see Earth as a green, watery utopia in some ways and a nuclear powder keg in others. After falling from the Kentucky sky in a one-man spacecraft, Newton embarks on a shady and ambiguous mission. The reserved and methodical stranger's true intent is way too surprising and well developed for any measly reviewer to rightfully give it away. Without letting slip too many precious details, I will tell you that the flimsy extraterrestrial discovers the darker aspects of human society, the feelings of futility, the addictions and vices, the ignorance and distrust and other stigmas not shown on TV. From Newton's fragile eyes, Mr. Tevis does nothing less than paint a striking portrait of the frustrations of being an Earthling.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>