<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0375714618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>WCallister</user>
	<review>This was a very good read, though confusing, at times, due to it's somewhat comic-book style.  It is CLEARLY written from a pro-Marx perspective.  On more than one occasion it made some very clear attacks on religion in general, but especially Christianity.  If you are searching for a "new philosophy," I would not recommend this, due to it's clear bias.  If you are fairly confident, in your ability to objectively analyze information, and discern fact from bias, then I would recommend this.  It does seem to give a fairly extensive view of the ideologies behind Marxism, without getting bogged down in the mundane mechanics of it.  Ironically, after reading this, I am even more convinced that Marxism cannot work, because it requires you to start with some assumptions about mankind, which I can't agree with, nor do I see any evidence for.  All in all, a good read, with some good information. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0375714618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>obscuresoul13</user>
	<review>This book is mainly a simplified explanation of Marxist theory  history. I greatly enjoyed reading it as it takes a humorous approach in explaining. It's complete with funny ways of wording  drawings. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0375714618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sgerbic</user>
	<review>Reviewed March 2000 A great book for beginners, but still confusing. All info on Marx and thinkers before and after are summarized. Only the bare facts are given which is quite enough. The author give a wonderful overview of thought from the beginning of understanding to Lenin. Everything is drawn in cartoon to help the reader grasp difficult concepts. I found it difficult to stop reading because there are no formal chapters or even paragraphs, and beginning again is difficult. Rius (Eduardo el Rio) gives communism and capitalism overviews from the socialist viewpoint, which is interesting. But a bit frustrating. In 1976 when this book was written, the USSR was still in power an thriving(?). It would be interesting to read a revised book. Marx claims over and over that capitalism will fail and communism is the future. The definitions listed in the the back are great..."Atheism ~ Democritus and Epicurus, who denied the supernatural and stated the world is nothing other than matter composed of atoms." "Communism ~ is the stage following socialism, when social classes cease to exist, USSR, China are still in socialism phases." 3-2000 </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0375714618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Clurb</user>
	<review>This is a short but comprehensive overview of Marx, part biography and part discussion of Marxism's philosophical origins and main tenets. Introducing Marx is written in a comic-book style which breaks the information up into more digestible chunks and adds an air of humour and irreverence to the topic. If you're wanting a quick introduction to Marxism this is as good a place as any to start. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0375714618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>McCaine</user>
	<review>I bought "Marx for Beginners", a cartoon introduction to Marx written by Mexican political cartoonist Eduardo del Rio ("Rius"), not so much because I needed an introduction to Marxism but to see how the theory can be summarized as pithily and shortly as possible. And indeed, Del Rio has done an admirable job on this. The reader is guided through all aspects of Marx' work as well as biography, even including an extraordinarily rapid overview of the history of philosophy and of the early socialists. Of the economic theories of Marx only the basics are explained, but nevertheless sufficient to get the point of what Marx tried to show in "Capital", if not how he proved it. As far as the political side goes, Del Rio usefully emphasizes the limitations of social-democracy and its inability to get beyond the exploitation of capitalism, as well as many quotations from Marx showing how he opposed this tendency. As criticisms, one could remark that Engels gets short shrift in this book - admittedly it is titled "Marx for beginners", but one wonders why not "Marx  Engels for beginners"? Also, Del Rio seems to take the connection between Marx and Lenin as a natural progression for granted, even including in the (otherwise very handy) vocabulary of terms under Marxism-Leninism: "theory of the proletarian liberation movement". Hardly something uncontested. The drawings are clear and funny, if a bit on the juvenile side compared to the content that he is trying to convey. This might have a good effect on younger people reading it though, making it possibly useful as a high school text on Marx, if there ever is a capitalist country brave enough to allow it. Due to the requirements of Del Rio's purpose, some of the summaries of earlier thinkers are so simple as to be simplistic, but this can't be helped. Overall, a practical and well-done introduction to Marx for the complete novice. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0375714618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>noaman</user>
	<review>A highly compressed overview of the development of Marx's views, the book is truly just for beginners. It's supposed to be a "documentary comic book" -- but I don't think that it makes use of the comics medium as effectively as it could: It relies less on narrative and more on an illustrated-history-book approach. Nevertheless, it is very good as a brief and quick introduction for those interested in getting a sense of Marx's ideas to study them further. It is quite useful for the introduction to the social, historical and philosophical conditions of and leading up to Marx's time, that makes up in breadth what it lacks in depth. Also very useful is the extensive glossary in the back. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0375714618</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shoomg</user>
	<review>Marxism is false, but it's still worth knowing what it actually stands for, and this book does a fairly good job of describing it. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>