<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

Long before Neale Donald Walsh and other spiritual writers is this short story that weaves a magical tale of the potential of looking at our physical plane of life in a different manner. A forgotten book that is most inspiring and has the potential to open ones mind to other dimensions. A wonderful read for those searching for the deeper meanings of our lives.Georgen
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Linda Dodrill</user>
	<review>

I have read Chopra, Myss, Dyer, Walsh, Choquette, Hay, Braden, Hawkins, Stevens, Murray, and a host of others, but this book started the journey, and in this book is the purest distillation of spiritual truths - manifestation, the nature of reality, the illusion of life on earth, manifesting, dominion over matter, energy, transmutation, magnetization, attraction and a sense of peace that could be described as harmonious empowerment.   Read it once as a fable, then read it again as life instructions.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Press On Qi Master "revealing the truth"</user>
	<review>

When my  Grandma handed me this book I was very young, as I grew reading the words I was revealed to myself.  This book has a way of talking to you, it becomes your friend as you journey together through the limitless nature of ones self.buy this book and enjoy a breath of truth
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>M. Honeycutt "MK"</user>
	<review>

This is a book you will want to read more than once. An updated (from biblical times) story of a Christ like figure helping a non-believer learn to believe. This is an excellent read and if you don't cry at the end - or at least shed A tear - I'm afraid something may be wrong with you!
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Sherry V. Daniel</user>
	<review>

Great book! If anyone is a bit down and needs a good lift. This book is for you. A very easy read. This book actually made me stop and think about my life and how things are in life. I loved it. A friend recommended it that I read it and He was dead on. Give it a try. You will not be disappointed. LOVED IT...
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JACQUELYN</user>
	<review>

I love this book, and I do enjoy Richard Bach's work. He teaches us to think positively. And brings us to a reality, that we can do whatever we think we can, and that everything is just an illusion. This book made me think about the little engine that could.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jill Lowy</user>
	<review>

This is a delightful book that deeply inspired me when I first began my journey towards spiritual enlightenment. It is so very down to earth on such deep metaphysical subjects. It will touch your heart and move you to explore the universe in a new way. TO JILL WITH LOVE: Memoirs of a Modern Day Mystic
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>S. Gardner "Sara Gardner"</user>
	<review>

This is my most favourite book ever and like so many others I too am always buying copies for others. If I ever meet anyone who doesn't love it I can't help but feel a little sorry for them.The book came to me in such a great way too. I was giving somebody some reiki and they just blurted out something about a reluctant messiah and spoke about a blue feather on the cover, I checked it out, ordered the book, read it and haven't looked back since. It's beautiful.Now't else to say really.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Aardvarks "Beau Chaine'"</user>
	<review>

Everyone can add credance to their own life if they try to get on the band wagon by reading of others who have been traveling trying to define themselves. "Illusions" is just such a journey.   Dillusioned Baby Boomers will better understand this kind of writing, having been there on similar roads to the ones described by the author, as the era mentioned was one of self discovery, hippies, free love, redefining christianity and Christ.  Reading this novel will shred self dillusions and make one wonder why they haven't thrown away previous beliefs that have handcuffed them to old ways and limitations so they can just walk on water at will or heal their ailing grandmother by holding her hand.  Quite a "trip" in literary timelessness, you will either think that Richard Bachs hould have stopped writing at his last novel "Jonathan Livingston Seagull" or changed his religeon.  A very interesting read.  You will never look at self discovery the same again.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0440343194</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Karen Frazier "Author of Avalanche of Spirits...</user>
	<review>

Way back in the old days when I was a teenager, I was given a copy of Richard Bach's amazing book, Illusions. At the time I read it, I was intrigued.Illusions set me on a path in the next 30+ years that I might not have followed had I not read the book - and what a wonderful path it is.In a simple and engaging fashion, Bach challenges the nature of what we perceive as reality by telling the story of Richard's interactions with Donald Shimoda, a reluctant messiah he meets while barnstorming.Even if you don't buy the principles being discussed in the book, it is a simple and engaging read that may just leave you thinking like it did for me. Illusions has been on my list of favorite books since I was 13 years old.
      </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>