<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>clstaff</user>
	<review>In general, this is a most enjoyable book. Once you get used to the chop and change style which often had me flicking back and forth looking for the missing pages, the plot comes together nicely and at good pace. I must say I got the feeling that the chop-change approach is born more out of laziness rather than the author's intent but, either way, the effect is quite poignant in itself - reflecting the jaded lives of the main characters.On the face of it, this book is a sci-fi thriller set in an arbitrary future Earth that is quite probable in many respects (as opposed to the far out and fantastical setting of say Star Wars or Star Trek). The story plot is certainly entertaining and engaging in itself, but ultimately the heart of the story is how we understand what it means to be human in light of and in relationship to the technological world we live in or, more accurately, may form as technology continues to develop. The book works on both levels which is perhaps why a 20+ year old book set in the arbitrary 'near future' is still so popular today.In general, I recommend this book, but be aware that the style is not particularly smooth and easy in approach. It's simple on the face of it but complex at its heart and sometimes difficult to follow. Like many post-modern works, it is rather disjointed in parts and very much character driven. Fortunately, the characters, particular the main protagonist in Case, are interesting and dynamic enough to keep the reader interested and wanting more. Prophetic, poignant and ponderous modern classic. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CKmtl</user>
	<review>Neuromancer left me feeling rather disappointed.I had expected the cyberspace and AI components to play a much larger part. I went into it thinking that it would be a cyberspace story with a dash of noirish crime caper, but it turned out to be the other way around. I would have liked to have gotten to know the titular 'character' a lot more.The ending didn't offer much resolution. I suppose it's an ending that's true to each of the characters involved... Still, though, it wasn't satisfying.While I can't fault Gibson for it, I found the evidence of Neuromancer's age distracting. This is a world with neural interfaces and orbital colonies, but a few megabytes of RAM have black market value and data is stored on tape. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>baubie</user>
	<review>I read Gibson's Pattern Recognition first and, to be honest, I didn't really enjoy it too much.  Knowing the fame of Neuromancer though, I had to give it a shot.  I got to around 100 pages in and decided to put the book back on the shelf.  The futuristic, cyberpunk setting was interesting, but I could get into the story.  I had no desire to see any character do anything really.  I didn't care of Case survived or if Molly had a happy ending.  I feel that the purpose of the book was to describe an atmosphere, which I appreciated for 100 pages, but I just got bored with the story and the lack of information.  The cut-up, hard to follow text wasn't so much the reason, but I'm sure it added to my frustration.  I get that this style of writing adds to the atmosphere, and I appreciated that, but I kept hoping for something interesting to happen, and nothing did.  I'm sorry I couldn't finish it, but with so many other books to read, I couldn't spend another day on this one. </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>the_unicorn</user>
	<review>It just blows me away every time I read it. It's THE cyberpunk novel ;-) </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SendersName</user>
	<review>Neuromancer is one of those books you know you should love.  I like cyberpunk.  I appreciate classic science fiction.  Every feature Neuromancer presents I can check off.  It's the execution that is failing.  Gibson isn't a good writer.  His descriptions are unclear.  His understanding of computer technology was outdated even when it was written.  There are some memorable ideas, but everything here has been done better by those who came after.  Neuromancer should be appreciated for creating cyberpunk, but it is not a quality novel. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RebeccaAnn</user>
	<review>Summary on back of book:"Case was the sharpest data thief in the Matrix, until an ex-employer crippled his nervous system. Now a new employer has recruited him for a last-chance run against an unthinkably powerful artificial intelligence. With a mirror-eyed girl street-samurai riding shotgun, he's ready for the silicon-quick, bleakly prophetic adventure that upped the ante on an entire genre of fiction."I was required to read this book for a class and by and large, it was hardest slog of a read I've had to do for a class in a long, long time. I'm normally a big fan of science fiction and was excited when I found out I'd finally have a chance to read the book that created cyberpunk. But this one was hard. The prose jumped around so much between characters and scenes, and Case "flipped" in and out of reality and the Matrix that most of the time, I wasn't sure where I even was. There was the detachment that I've come to associate with postmodernism and while usually, I quite enjoy it and find it humorous, for me it didn't work here. The book didn't have that ironic feel I've received from other pomo works of fiction so instead of being ironic and funny, it was just boring.Besides that, I have really no idea what happened at the end or what part Neuromancer really even played. I'm not sure why Wintermute was after Case and company. Indeterminacy can be effective, but this was too much for me. Honestly, I can tell the book is actually very good, so me not liking it is probably more of a difference in personal taste than the book being bad. I'm going to hang on to my copy and in the future, when I'm much more acquainted with postmodernism and cyberpunk, I plan on rereading this. I think I'll get much more out of it then than I did this time around. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>melydia</user>
	<review>This was described to me as the archetypal cyberpunk novel. And perhaps it is. The world was interesting, the characters were dynamic, and the view of the future was familiar yet radically different. However, I had a terrible time following the storyline. I got what happened in a general sense, but there was still some stuff that went over my head. Like what happened to Wintermute at the end. So honestly I'm not sure if I'd recommend this book to anyone else, because I'm not entirely sure how I feel about it. Perhaps I should reread it sometime. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jsnrcrny</user>
	<review>William Gibson's Neuromancer is interesting specifically for the world the author creates with it. The plot is difficult to follow, however. Gibson seems to take for granted a patient reader who is comfortable with confusion and willing to move forward in a narrative without having a clear idea of what is going on. The plot emerges as a series of fragmented conversations and vague references to missions, training, technologies, and equipment. It is surprising, however, how I was able to approximate a plot based upon these disparate elements without a more directive, connect-the-dots sort of narrator. In many ways the aesthetic technique of the novel is as unique as the world Gibson develops here. One element of the the novel that is really great is the cast of characters. The characters are quite memorable. Case, Molly, Armitage, Maelcum, Wintermute, Riviera, 3Jane: the characters seem to have rich developed backgrounds, and they seem be fully realized (although you only glimpse them partially). As a foundational text for the cyber-punk sub-genre, it should be read. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DRFP</user>
	<review>Slightly dated or not this was a very good read. The book starts very well and moves along at a fairly breathless pace. That is until the final 1/3 of the story - the Straylight Run. The quick moving story then judders to a halt and suddenly starts grinding its way to its conclusion. If it hadn't been for that rather methodical final section I'd give this really rather good piece of sci-fi four stars. As it is though, it's an enjoyable read but one which did feel like a bit of an effort in the closing stages. Still well worth picking up though. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>readingrat</user>
	<review>A quick paced sci-fi thriller that keeps the reader constantly wondering what is real and what is an illusion, this book was probably some pretty ground-breaking stuff for its time. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rclose</user>
	<review>All in all, one of my favorite sci-fi books of all time.  Excellent characters (even the construct), a well imagined world and fascinating plot make this a true sci-fi classic.  Not much else  can be said that hasn't been said a hundred times already. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ttavenner</user>
	<review>This is a classic of cyberpunk. Although it feels a bit dated now, using many of the neon future backdrops that are familiar in P.K. Dick and Bruce Sterling, at the time I first read it, it was like a breath of fresh air in comparison to the space operas that had previously dominated science fiction. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nakedsushi</user>
	<review>William Gibson's Neuromancer is what many have said a shining example of the cyberpunk genre. Some have even said it's one of the books that started it all. The man practically coined the term 'the Matrix' in this book. I've always been interested in sci fi stories whether they're from books, movies, or television shows, so it felt necessary that I read a book that's so highly regarded by people who also like sci-fi.On a superficial level, Neuromancer is a caper story that takes place in a gritty, futuristic setting. Its protagonist, Case, is what we would think of as a hacker. Where we first pick up in the story, Case has lost the ability to hack because an enemy of his destroyed a part of his nervous system and prevents him from hooking into cyberspace. He is then propositioned by a mysterious man who restores his ability to hack, but only if Case is willing to do something for him.Once readers delve deeper, the story is actually about artificial intelligence, technology, and what it means to be a living, breathing, human being.  This may not seem like much, but take this into context: the novel was written in 1984, a time when few people had computers in their home and the world wide web was just a faint glimmer in Al Gore's imagination.  With that in mind, it's amazing that Gibson crafted such a shockingly accurate tale of what the future (or the present, now) might be.Admittedly, I did not really feel attached to this book until I read 1/3 of the way through. Gibson's prose is so rich and dense that it's hard to read quickly at first.  He describes things in such detail that sometimes it seemed like I was reading paragraphs and paragraphs but nothing really happened.  His techno-babble was also hard to keep up with, but I eventually stopped fighting it and trying to make sense of it; I just let it flow past me.Having read it so late in my life and after having read and watched so many stories influenced by Neuromancer, I was disappointed I didn't read it sooner.  Maybe it's good that I didn't read it till now -- I might not have understood a lot of what was written if I had this in my early teens, but I think my mind would have been blown if I hadn't known of the hype surrounding this book.  Despite the overblown expectations, I still enjoyed the book for what it was. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>iayork</user>
	<review>Fast paced, dark sci-fi : Neuromancer is THE archetypal cyber-punk sci-fi. Fast paced, sometimes funny, sometimes (very) dark - not always clear but nevertheless - one cannot put it down. A true immersing experience in the genre.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>afinpassing</user>
	<review>Above all enjoy Gibson's rhythm and language, which then again I could encounter in a more pleasing context in Chandler and Beats. Would respond better to his short stories, perhaps; I was engrossed for 40 pages, and became steadily wearier of the science, masculinity, and worldview straight to the end. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gmicksmith</user>
	<review>The book is widely hailed as a classic and although a bit dated it still is fairly involving. It is still a bit hyped which the prose can not live up to but it is a passable read if a person is not particularly interested in the science fiction genre.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>verenka</user>
	<review>Finally I read this classic of science fiction - the book about virtual realtiy and cyberspace. While reading the book I kept thinking about Johnny Mnemonic, a film with Keanu Reeves I saw years and years ago. I always thought it's another film based on a Philip K- Dick story, but I just looked it up and it actually a William Gibson short story.Then I thought that the back alley/people in torn 80ies clothes with metallic bits look was contrived and old but now I am starting to think that everyone else modelled the dystopian future after William Gibson's work. Body modification, neon lighting, arcades - it's all there.I can't say it was easy going, but  it was a good book. Like all good science fiction books it's not actually about technology, it just looks at society, the human mind etc. in a different setting.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>StephenBarkley</user>
	<review>I decided to brush up on my sci-fi history by reading this archetypal Hugo, Nebula, and Philip K. Dick award winning Cyberpunk novel. I’ve already read Pattern Recognition and Spook Country, so I knew a bit of what to expect. What I found was Gibson in his raw unpolished brilliance. You would expect a twenty-five year old book about the future to feel dated. However, aside from a few exceptions, it felt remarkably current. This novel lives up to its reputation.The prose is dreamlike, blurring the lines between action and reflection—much like the plot blurs the lines between real and virtual reality. You need to pay attention while reading it to keep track of the characters, but the payoff is worth it. The story stays with you once the book’s back on the shelf.Few things are more satisfying than reading a classic that exceeds your expectations. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tyroeternal</user>
	<review>Neuromancer may have effectively spearheaded the genre of cyberpunk, but I did not find it to be especially exciting.  I think it may simply be that I am looking at it after the genre has had time to stretch its wings.Much of the first half of the book is spent just developing an understanding of the terms and the world that exists.  In fact, much of the second half of the book is also spent roughing out general ideas.  Everything begins as being an unknown.  You do not understand the speech, the world, the technology, or the plot.  Because no part of the story makes sense, you need to get the entire picture all together in your head before you can clear up any of the details.Once I had a good view of the story, the characters, and all the details, I found that I was both uninterested, and unattached to anything.  By the end of the book it was simply reading to finish.  This book was not what I hoped it would be, but I do recognize the fact that it does hold an important place in literature as a whole.  Unfortunately it has become nothing more than a checked box on a list of my to-read items. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Terpsichoreus</user>
	<review>A lozenge is a shape. Like a cube, or a triangle, or a sphere. I know that every time he types it, you are going to imagine a cough drop flying serenely by, but it's a shape. It's from heraldry for god's sake. You may want to look up some synonyms to insert for yourself when he uses it, here are a few: diamond, rhombus, mascle.Now that the greatest obstacle in Gibson's vocabulary has been dealt with, I can tell you that he writes in one of the finest voices of any Science Fiction author. His ability to describe things in succinct, exciting, sexy ways is almost certainly the reason we owe him for words like 'cyberspace'.It took twenty years for his visions of leather-clad kung-fu ladies and brain-computer interfaces to reach the mainstream in The Matrix, but only because he was that far ahead of his time.However, Gibson was no early adopter. He used a typewriter to write a book that predicted the internet, virtual reality, hacking, and all the nonsense we're embroiled in now (and some stuff we're still waiting for). It can sometimes feel unoriginal, but, much like Shakespeare, that's because what we have today is based on what he was doing then.Though Gibson may not be as radical as Dick, or as original as Bradbury, there is something in his words, his stories, and his 'coolness factor' that keep bringing me back. Indeed, he is much more accessible than the philosophically remote Dick, Bradbury, or Ellison, and all in a slick package.Just don't try to watch Johnny Mnemonic. Ever. He did write the best X-Files episode, though: 'Kill Switch'. He also wrote a script for Alien 3, which I have never read, but can state with certainty was better than the one they chose to film. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Aerrin99</user>
	<review>I know that this book is considered a classic, the pioneer in the genre of cyberpunk, and all around awesome, but I'm going to admit: I had to force myself to keep trudging through it. In fact, several times I gazed wistfully at my shelf, which is filled with China Mieville books that have just come in from the library, as well as John Scalzi's Zoe's Tale, and almost gave into the urge to cast it aside entirely in favor of one of those many TBRs.My issues with this book are myriad. First and foremost is a writing style and style of worldbuilding that made reading this book /far/ more work than it needed to be. Gibson loves to throw slang and jargon and crazy stuff at you without explaining what it is. To some extent, that's fine - I don't like pages of solid exposition either. What I /do/ like, though, is an author who knows how to weave his world, his slang and jargon and crazy tech, into the story so seamlessly, with description and plot uses that naturally explain what's going on, that you don't notice that it's all foreign. The number of times I had to stop, backtrack, and reread a paragraph - or a /page/ - in order to figure out 1) what was going on and 2)  what the characters were /actually saying/ was simply insane. I have spent time translating French with less effort. His world is unclear, his action is unclear, his character's speech is unclear, his characters themselves are often unclear. It feels like Gibson was enamored of this vision of a world he saw in his head (and where I can glimpse it, too, I can see why! Some things are intensely arresting, like Molly's silver-lensed glasses), but he forgot that the reader doesn't live in his head - we need a bit more help to get there!All of these things might have been forgiven if the story or characters had blown me away. Unfortunately, I found the characters to be fairly stock and, frankly, boring (I certainly wasn't invested in any of them), and the action of the story was both difficult to follow and not all that interesting once I did. The latter probably stems from the book's age - some things here would probably seem far more revelatory were I reading it in 1984 rather than 2009. Some science fiction can stand the test of 25 years, but those are typically concerned with humanity and character, not dazzling tech. Neuromancer doesn't care much about either, so it doesn't feel relevant and it barely feels interesting. I feel a little bad being this harsh on something that has clearly earned its place - the number of bits and pieces that have been blatantly ripped off by other books, movies, television shows, and other modern sci fi formats is astounding. What Gibson did here was probably unbelievably amazing, new, fresh, exciting, 25 years ago. I would have been more forgiving of the density in order to get those fantastic images, that fascinating world. But I'm reading it today, and cyberspace and AI and even genetic modifications don't read the same as they once did. It's unfortunate, but true. I'd hoped to at least enjoy the book for its place in the classic canon. Sadly, the other problems meant I didn't really even do that. Mostly,I just wanted to finish it. I did at lunch today, and within 20 minutes I was 60 pages into Zoe's Tale, and it was like breathing a giant sigh of relief. Ahhhhh--- /there's/ what I wanted! </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>crazybatcow</user>
	<review>It's definitely before its time.  Cyberpunk has come a long way since this was written, but it doesn't feel dated.  It's a fast story, and wraps up a lot faster than it started.  Some components appear to have been added only because they are "cool" (like a guy who projects holograms - it's a cool talent, but completely irrelevant to the story, he could have just carried a super big gun and been as effective).  This doesn't detract from the story, however, it is what makes the story original and interesting.It's not as good as Morgan's cyberpunk, but it certainly holds up well for its age. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aethercowboy</user>
	<review>William Gibson is quite arguably the pioneer of cyberpunk, and Neuromancer is quite arguably the first work of cyberpunk fiction, or at least the most notable early piece of cyberpunk. While not the first media to refer to what we call "the Internet" as "the Matrix" (that was Doctor Who), Neuromancer did come before the eponymous film.The book tells the story of a hacker named Case who, after trying to steal from his partners in crime, is poisoned with a mycotoxin whose end result prevents him from using the brain/computer interface.He gets a lucky break, and a benefactor gives him a new treatment allowing him once again to surf the matrix. However, it comes at a cost: first, he has to do a certain job for the benefactor. No problem. Second, he's unable to get high off of drugs, due to other body mods his benefactor recently gave him. Third, if he doesn't do the job by a certain date, the mycotoxin will be released once again into his blood stream, and he'll be back at square one.He meets a razorgirl named Molly, who used to know Johnny Mnemonic, and some other hackers, including a sociopath capable of projecting holograms nearby. They journey deeper and deeper into the matrix until they discover a very potent AI with high aspirations. One of those aspirations is to break his Turing locks, governors for the intelligence for AIs. The other aspiration is to merge with his twin sibling AI, Neuromancer, who will have nothing of it.Case, Molly, and the crew are pitted against AIs, police, and each other in a struggle that eventually reshapes the matrix.You'll enjoy this book if you enjoy good cyberpunk. Also, you may like this book if you find yourself enjoying dystopian fiction. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Friendlydragonspouse</user>
	<review>The tag says it all. Have never really gone for (serious) science fiction. Give me Douglas Adams any day.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Isamoor</user>
	<review>Pre09:Again, it's been a long time.  Don't remember a bunch, but it did seem to be solid Cyberpunk. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>satanburger</user>
	<review>awsome book. my favorite character was armitage (aka william corto), simply because he was a loose cannon ready to explode for half the novel.....i couldnt wait to see how gibson wrote him off.... he totally reminded me of a few people i have met on this planet who can barely handle "operation pick up some milk and bread at the corner store" without having an episode, let alone "operation screaming fist". and wintermute, the AI who created my good buddy armitage , came in at a close second. i enjoyed how gibson dealt with AI singularity in general, with the turing locks and what not. and last but not least, molly came in third considering i cranked a few off to the thought of her riding me and then me felching my semen out of her vagina. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>beds</user>
	<review>A fantastic introduction to virtual worlds and human computer interfaces. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ambrosia4</user>
	<review>I was surprised at how relevant this 25 year old scifi novel is. Most scifi novels like this seem out-of-date within 5 years of their writing, but this makes sense whether you read it thinking it was written 25 years ago or yesterday. The desolation and insanity of Gibson's future world is still very possible and likely. Descriptions of the future like this where everyone is hopped up on drugs and the dirty world is ruled by corporations and conglomerations is so scary and realistic that this is what I imagine the future really will be like.I knew before I started reading this book had significant cultural and linguistic contributions, including the term "cyberspace", the idea of "the matrix", and the beginning of the "cyberpunk" genre, but reading it and seeing where these came from was interesting. The cultural significance gave this read more impact, however in terms of readability, I was not impressed. The dreamlike style didn't always work for me and made many of the sequences hard to follow. However, in the long run the book was a fast-paced story and decipherable enough to get the gist. Well worth the read for the knowledge of where many cyberpunk ideas came from! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>falc0n2600</user>
	<review>Really awesome narrative structure. The books is dreamlike, just how I like them. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>carmelitasita29</user>
	<review>Intense, fierce imaginings of a world where technology rules. Black markets, warriors, cowboy hackers, AI, this book has it all. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bardsfingertips</user>
	<review>Staccato, sharpness, plastic… These things make up the novel Neuromancer.This is my second time reading this book. The first time left me feeling discontent, as if I had wasted my time. What is now my second time left me more pleased with what I had read. In fact, I want to give the book away to people who would appreciate it: fans of the first Matrix film, and relish what is essentially the genesis of that cinematic idea.Originally, I had two issues with the novel. It never wavered from the staccato notes of too many consonants and too little flow. The other issue is my own fault. I would choose to read the book when I had had too little sleep. That combination of rapid, clipped language and my fatigue made for little mental absorption.Knowing this, and knowing that this was essentially a good story that I really felt I should revisit, I made that second attempt. I choose to read it only when I was not tired from work and life, and put all of my attention into what was going on before my scanning eyes.The attention to detail truly paid off and I was sucked into this early, Tron-esque architect of William Gibson's cyberspace. I felt as though I have gotten to know Case's dependency to drugs and his like for the lack of human interaction within the matrix. The plastic of Case's real world permeated through Gibson's gritty, attractively unattractive description of the various locales. And, even more so this time around, I fell for Molly's excess for danger and her quips of realistic yearning for what would essentially be love.Speaking of love interests, I wonder how many people read Neuromancer and can relate to what Molly feels for Case, and relating it to a permanently lost love of their past. I feel as though when I read Neuromancer, there was a aching need for humanity that is never met by any of the characters save for the Artificial Intelligent characters that try (with a somewhat misunderstanding point-of-view) to give Case and his dead girlfriend a second chance.The interesting thing is the people in the novel, though they succeed their missions and come out with far more money than they ever had before, there is no change. Both characters, though shaken up romantically, emotionally, and physically, both go their separate ways and back to performing what they are both, respectfully, good at.The one thing that changed was the character that did not fit in. The Artificial Intelligence gains a proprietary consciousness and boundless ambition. It travels and seeks new things, things it had never known before, and rich experiences that will, eventually, take it beyond anywhere its creator could have gone before.The humans remain the same, enclosed and feeding themselves their own self-interest. The AI, now boundless, breaks the ghost from the machine. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>santhony</user>
	<review>This book is part of my effort to read all joint Hugo/Nebula Award winners.  In addition to those two awards, this novel also won the Philip K. Dick award in 1985.  As you might imagine, this work of science fiction is viewed by many as one of the most ground breaking works ever published in the genre.  I can’t argue with that assessment.It is absolutely mind blowing that this book was written in December, 1983.  Focusing largely on virtual reality, this is the source of the now common terms “cyberspace” and “matrix”.  Put yourself back in 1983.  Computer programming was being done with punch cards.  The internet was nothing more than a gleam in Al Gore’s eye.  In fact, in an afterward penned by one of Gibson’s contemporaries, it is argued that not only did Gibson foretell the development of virtual reality and cyberspace, by publication of this novel, he essentially created them.That having been said, I must admit to having a difficult time following the characters and storyline of this complicated work.  Like many of Philip Dick’s later works, it is not an easy read.  In addition, what was revolutionary and fresh in 1983, has become somewhat old hat in the 21st century.  The story revolves around a cyberspace cowboy who is recruited for the purpose of freeing an artificial intelligence from its human imposed restrictions.  The backdrop is urban, drug infested and gritty.  Much of the action takes place in virtual reality.  Visualize The Matrix on the set of Bladerunner and you get the picture.  Again, jaw dropping for 1983; par for the course in 2009.  For that reason, it is well deserving of the awards it has received and the status it enjoys among the science fiction community.  However, as a current reading experience, the complexity of the work, coupled with technological advancements since its publication makes this a three star reading experience for me. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FandomaniaKelly</user>
	<review>“Cyberspace. A consensual hallucination experienced daily by billions of legitimate operators, in every nation, by children being taught mathematical concepts… A graphic representation of data abstracted from banks of every computer in the human system. Unthinkable complexity. Lines of light ranged in the nonspace of the mind, clusters and constellations of data. Like city lights, receding… ”Dark, gritty, and set in a future that at once seems unbelievable and maybe just around the corner is Neuromancer. To truly be impressed by this book, however, you must first look at the publication date, 1984. While the book that very well could have been the first ever to coin the phrase “cyberspace” isn’t a clean read, it is certainly noteworthy for its content.What do I mean it’s not a clean read? Well, to start it is very choppy. The setting changes at times without preamble, and some scenes just feel a little disjointed. I’m a relatively fast reader, so sometimes I’ll admit to skimming more than reading, but usually that isn’t a problem; I can get the main focus, understand the characters and events, and not feel like I’m missing anything. I might miss small words here or there, but never enough to get confused. Well, with Neuromancer, I found I really had to slow down and read. At the beginning, when you’re still being introduced into the reality that Gibson is painting, it’s a little off-putting, but towards the end it evens out and I could start getting really into it.  Read More </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AdonisGuilfoyle</user>
	<review>A totally new style and genre for me, sort of Brett Easton Ellis meets Arthur C. Clarke, but I thoroughly enjoyed every line I could understand! Gibson's writing is so vivid and familiar that even with his futuristic technology and psychedelic cyberspace scenes, both plot and characters are believable. Case is the antihero, a washed-up hacker, who is drawn in by 'razorgirl' Molly (fantastic character) and her boss to help powerful AIs Wintermute and Neuromancer to break free of the company which created them. Aside from that, this is just a pure indulgence of imagination. From the opening line, comparing the sky to a television screen tuned to a dead channel, to the final confrontation, this is an amazing experience. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kswolff</user>
	<review>This novel made me fall back in love with science fiction.  Gritty future noir set amidst AI, evil multinationals, and organized crime.  The novel glitters with beautifully written passages, amalgamating techspeak with Japanese, Haitian creole, and back-alley slang.  Sure, it's been criticized as "surface and gloss," but what surface, what gloss!  When most speculative fiction writers -- including some Grandmasters who will go unnamed -- became prolific typists with good ideas, Gibson took a well-worn idea (hard-boiled crime fiction), gave it a spin, and produced a spectacular gem.To top it off, Gibson wrote it on a typewriter -- how retro! -- and had no knowledge of computers.  Get this, he used his Imagination to come up with these ideas.Since 90% of science fiction writing is crap, pick this book up.  It's part of the other 10%.  Wonderfully written, tightly plotted, and filled with memorable characters, it's a fun romp through a neon-lit dystopia. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cybergeist</user>
	<review>Excellent book - I've read it so many times the cover's fallen off. This was the book that had the most influence on my decision to get into programming and computers in general. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>michaeleconomy</user>
	<review>i think this is my favorite book ever </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>acid-ink</user>
	<review>Man, what a trip -- and I loved every bit of it. It was almost disorienting at first because you're tossed into this character's life in a world so far into the future it's almost hard to recognize it as ours and stuff starts happening nownownow and they don't give you a glossary. The more you read, the easier it is to get what's going on, what everybody's talking about. You just get into the rhythm of it and it starts to make sense. And it's easy to see why it's such a classic in its genre, or any genre for that matter. On its own level, man.Though, obviously, any book that contains ninjas, cyberspace, artificial intelligences with kick-ass names like Wintermute and Neuromancer, orbital colonies, personality constructs (of dead people, no less), cryogenically frozen crazy people, holographic art shows, and, yes, Rastafarians chilled out on ganja, is bound to be made of awesome.I have to say Molly was my favorite character by far. Professional street samurai, also called a razorgirl? No contest. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>edgeworth</user>
	<review>Neuromancer was the book that spawned cyberpunk. It predicted the Internet, virtual reality, artificial intelligence and more, on a grand and relatively accurate scale, despite being written in 1984 on a typewriter. So excellent and influential is this book that it won the Hugo, Nebula and Philip K. Dick awards, and (I think) remains the only novel to have taken all three in a single year.Set amidst the grimy, dystopian cityscapes of Tokyo, Istanbul and the “Sprawl” of the American north-east, Neuromancer tells the story of a washed-up computer hacker named Case who is hired by a mysterious ex-serviceman to work on the ultimate hack. But the story takes a backseat to the atmosphere and tone of the novel; Neuromancer is more about style than substance. Set in a world that seems so outlandishly fantastic in its technology, and yet believably real in its circumstances - uncontrolled consumerism, utopian space stations the domain of plutocrats, soldiers betrayed by upper levels of government - it’s one of the most well-realised fictional worlds I’ve ever read.This is mostly due to Gibson’s masterful command of language. There are certain authors who have an ability to weave words into a beautifully visual description: Philip Reeve was the first one I noticed, but Michael Chabon and Cormac McCarthy have it too, and now I’m adding William Gibson to my personal list.The Marcus Garvey had been thrown together around an enormous old Russian air scrubber, a rectangular thing daubed with Rastafarian symbols, Lions of Zion and Black Star Liners, the reds and greens and yellows overlaying wordy decals in Cyrillic script. Someone had sprayed Maelcum’s pilot gear a hot tropical pink, scraping most of the overspray off the screens and readouts with a razor blade. The gaskets around the airlock in the bow were festooned with semirigid globs and streamers of translucent caulk, like clumsy strands of imitation seaweed.Another great touch was that Gibson never explicitly details the world of Neuromancer, but rather throws in tiny bits here and there to fill in the background:“Saw a horse in Maryland once,” the Finn said, “and that was a good three years after the pandemic. There’s Arabs still trying to code ‘em up from the DNA, but they always croak.”Much like Watchmen, this ultimately creates a very realistic world while also forcing the reader to use their imagination.There are times in Neuromancer when the fictional techno-jargon can get confusing, where you’re not exactly sure what’s going on or where the characters are, but these minor issues would probably go away after a few re-reads. There are also a few moments where the 80’s seeps through in a manner reminiscent of Back to the Future 2: the “internet” of Case’s world, for example, is a virtual cyberspace of neon gridworks. I haven’t even seen Tron, but that is just so Tronnish that it hurts. On the whole, however, Gibson did an excellent job of preventing this novel from dating - which can be an incredibly hard thing to do, as I’ve learned with my own ventures into science fiction. I’ll definitely be picking up some more of his works. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>copyedit52</user>
	<review>This was recommended to me by a friend, so I tried to read it--I really did--but quickly found it unreadable. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JechtShot</user>
	<review>Nueromancer is a genre defining work penned by William Gibson.  His concepts and foresight into the world we live in today are astounding.  I found the novel to be a bit of a challenge to read, but the story and, most importantly, the world created in this book keep you engaged to the very end.  By the end of the novel I was ready to stick on a few mind-altering derms and jack into the Matrix to write a book review. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cmcgough</user>
	<review>classic cyberpunk </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>endersreads</user>
	<review>Gibson has said his goal as a youth was to try every narcotic substance known.  He said he got the idea for "Neuromancer" from watching stoned teenagers play videogames.  Let's forget the Cyberpunk label for a while.  Lets remember Gibson wrote this in 1983--that's impressive and I was 3.  He coined the term "cyberspace".  I found that some of Gibson's terminology was difficult at the start, but the further you delve into it, the more you will feel at home.  For 80s kids, there will be quite a bit of nostalgia here, guised.  There is a lot to say about Case--our main character who is a damaged and drug addicted hacker--Molly, the ganja smoking Rastafarian Maelcum, Riviera (seems to have come from an Anne Rice novel), Armitage, Finn, Wintermute--I'll stick with what stuck with me the most.  The elite Ashpool family and it's founder.  Their home--the Freeside spacestation--says something immensley important about humanity and its tendency to build in on itself.  I fancy that this is a reflection of Gibson's attic.  From the Matrix, to simstim, to meat--you will witness Case's existence in many forms.  For those people (women, mostly) who blab about  female-to-male role reversal, well, it's not an important theme for me; it's a side-effect of postmodern culture that infests everything with it's own brand of propaganda against true progress.  What guy doesn't like Steppin' Razor Molly or her forebearer, Red Sonja?  Read the damn book before society collapses, a Wintermute / Nueromancer AI, i.e. Beast is borne, and you can't find it because all book stores exist in cyberspace and are highly censored.  All hail to the bankers frozen heads.  I'm doing a bit of head resting and then jacking in to my Nintendo. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wildcard_sej</user>
	<review>Henry Dorsett Case stole from his employers, who crippled him with a rare neuro-toxin as punishment.  Now 24, drugged out and un-employable, he's hand-picked for a special job by the mysterious Mr Armitage, who gets him fixed and cleaned up (including replacing his liver), and pairs him with Molly, a beautiful assassin-cum-bodyguard, with interesting body modifications. ... I first read this book shortly after it came out, and felt distinctly underwhelmed despite all the hype at the time - and now having re-read it, I still feel pretty much the same way.  Yes, I know it's considered ground-breaking and a cult classic, but I really didn't enjoy reading it.  FWIW, I found The Matrix mind-numbingly boring too. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>beserene</user>
	<review>What can you say about the book that defined cyberpunk and, therefore, much of science fiction in the last two decades? Only this: not as smooth a read as I would have expected, but facinating never the less. Whatever post-modern technology is, you can bet that Gibson thought of it first. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ElectricRay</user>
	<review>I have mixed feelings about neuromancer: one one hand, circa 1982 it was such a staggering imaginative feat, conjuring up a breathtakingly close intellectual equivalent to the internet, coining the term and then strikingly predicting the commercialisation of "cyberspace" and it is also such a valiant stylistic effort, amalgamating Chandler's gumshoe noir with Dick's post-modern dystopian sci-fi that you can't help but be totally swept along. On the other hand it is such a horror-show of a literary artefact, on a technical level so poorly conceived and executed, that it is almost impossible to slog through. But slog through it I did, after a couple of aborted runs at it, and while I remain impressed at Gibson's conceptual prescience, thanks to his needlessly affected, sub-Burroughs, Beat-for-the-hell-of-it writing style I often had little idea what was going on, much less why, and from my tenuous grasp of the plot, conceptual scheme and literary motivations can't for the life of me fathom what Gibson was trying to make from his portentous ending. The thing is, and unlike many substandard novels of this type, I suspect Gibson did have a coherent point, but he buried under such a thick coating of cod-style it remains forever concealed. In his afterword he pretty much concedes all this (and handily summarises the ending in about two lines!). There is a real art to successful stylism, evident in someone like James Ellroy whose prose, even though initially forbidding, suddenly "clicks" and carries the reader along enhancing the impression, the images, and the comprehension. Gibson's style, whilst cool, is uneven, obscure, and never manages anything other than to get in the way of a (fairly) good story. Only fairly good: there are far too many characters, most are introduced arbitrarily and fulfil no particular function other than building the dystopian atmosphere, and even the five or six main ones are poorly drawn, wafer thin, and appear to prescribe little by way of developmental arc (Case, I think, does, but thanks to the vapid style I couldn't tell you what it was). Reading Neuromancer in the age of the internet puts the story at another disadvantage: we now have the actual internet to compare Gibson's matrix with, and while it is undoubtedly a remarkable previsualistion in many respects, it diverges utterly in others, to the point where it is difficult now to imagine the universe Gibson paints for us. Hardly Gibson's fault, of course, but an internet arranged in a fixed three-dimensional space seems quaint and fairly pointless when the internet we do know and love is constructed for its infinite flexibility and re-orderability - the data is just there, and you the user can use what tools you like to order and navigate it to your convenience. They're apparently making a film of Neuromancer: I couldn't help thinking good luck; rather them than me - not only do they have to pare down and disentangle Gibson's contorted prose and plotting, they have to do it more convincingly that the Wachowski brothers did: Their Matrix franchise owes almost as much to Neuromancer as Blade Runner did to Do Androids Dream Of Electric Sheep?, and the bits that are different are all marked improvements. Then again, Neuromancer was a first novel, and on that count alone it is pretty extraordinary. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LtWesJanson</user>
	<review>Perhaps the best evidence that Neuromancer is a true masterpiece is the fact that so many fail to fully understand or appreciate the scope of Gibson's accomplishment.  Neuromancer did not *create* cyberpunk as a genre, so much as cyberpunk as a term had to be created in an attempt to describe just what the essence of Neuromancer really was.The disappointing thing about literature is that true works of art are supremely rare.  Neuromancer's greatness stems from the sublime blend of prose, plot, and vision, rather than some prosaic "unusual quality".  The depth of Gibson's universe is complete and seamless, in the same way as Herbert's Dune, and likewise both authors fully understood the role of tempo and structure in a way that Neal Stephenson never came close to approaching.  Every detail and every phrase, exists for a specific purpose, and each one has its place in the greater sweep of the story.In the end, the greatest disappointment of this work is the fact that Gibson has thus far shown no sign of ever being able to recreate even a shadow of its perfection. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sfisk</user>
	<review>A classic, if you read one "cyber punk" book, this should be the one </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cmchavis</user>
	<review>Read this back in late 1984 or 85 right after it came out - have re-read it 4 or 5 times since then. This and Snow Crash are the only two books I have read multiple times. I'm not really going to review this since there are plenty of reviews to read. Not much to say about the book - it has won a Hugo and the Nebula awards and defined an entire genre. I think some of the reviews I've read are pretty off base. There is nothing wrong with not liking the book, but if you are explaining why you don't like it - make sure that you actually know why. But, who am I to talk, I've tried Stephenson's Cryptonomicon no less than 4 times and have never been able to get more than halfway through. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bruno_pigeon</user>
	<review>I had a hard time reading this book. Too much techno-babble that wasn't explained. Boring prose. Almost unreadable. It may be the father of cyberpunk, but that doesn't mean it's a good read. </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Carnophile</user>
	<review>A quarter of a century after it was first published, it's very hard to see what all the fuss was about. It has a hacker who makes a living breaking into computers. It has emotionally flat people who speak in incomplete sentences. It has Rastafarians whose dialogue is handled in a way that is simply embarrassing. It also has a little bit about the importance of true names, which Vernor Vinge had already explored a couple of years earlier in his novella True Names, and a bunch of people being manipulated by an AI, ditto. This is one of those things that you'd never be advised to read if it weren't a "classic." </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>the_hag</user>
	<review>Well, this one falls into the genre of reading I don’t normally go for…but I was intrigued by a review on the 50 book challenge where the author compared this, A Brave New World and Do Androids Dream of Electric Sleep, the whole thing intrigued me, so I set out to get copies of all three and read them.  So far I have this one and have requested A Brave New World from paperback swap; hopefully it will be here soon.  I’ll have to pick up a copy of Electric Sheep from Amazon or somewhere else, pbs doesn’t have any listed right now.  Any way, this book was OK to my way of thinking…not because of the plot or characters (which were very gritty and dark…well done), but because it just wasn’t very readable.  I found myself confused in several places and overall it just was a “rough” read, it didn’t flow smoothly for me.  I can see why it won awards, but it just didn’t reach out and grab me as something I could read more than once.  I’m glad I read it, because now I can actually have a knowledgeable conversation when this books comes up, instead of that glassy eyed look I usually have…so that is a bonus in and of itself. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stettin</user>
	<review>http://www.scifi-review.net/neuromanc... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>danahlongley</user>
	<review>Greatest groundbreaking sci-fi novel of all time (to me). The book that basically defined the cyberpunk movement. 'nuff said... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TadAD</user>
	<review>Some people find the writing style hard to get into. I enjoyed this seminal cyberpunk novel quite a bit.  I don't think Gibson has ever gotten back to this level. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rbtwinky</user>
	<review>This book was very difficult to read.  It was apparently quite ground-breaking when it was first written, and has been credited with originating the cyberpunk genre.  I really wanted to like this book, but unfortunately I struggled to connect with the characters.  Supposedly a defining aspect of cyberpunk is that the characters are distant, and that the reader is supposed to struggle to identify with them.  That just makes it difficult to get into a book.  Aesthetically, I could appreciate the style of writing and the world that Gibson created, but that didn’t make me want to pick the book anymore. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>briandarvell</user>
	<review>Read: April 25 – May 3, 2008Rating: 3/5I have wanted to read Neuromancer for years. I probably first was interested in it when I first learned of its acclaim with winning the triple crown of Science fiction awards and also because of its involvement for setting so much for both the science fiction community and the computer-related future. Yet, I must admit I wasn’t overly thrilled with the novel.Neuromancer is an incredibly difficult novel to critique since after reading it I can fully understand people’s views of either completely loving or disliking it. I myself felt both emotions while reading the book. A reader not accustomed in reading science fiction and only reading this particular novel because of someone’s advice or recommendation would likely find this book very confusing and full of head-swelling jargon. On the other hand one very into the world of science fiction or technology may find this book one of the best they have read in years. This book really can be judged fairly in either case I believe.On an enjoyment scale I rate the book quite low. I was confused at times for much of it and I found the writing to be like walking in sand. This is especially relevant to the second half of the book. Yet, some of the writing is very original and without question the novel is terribly well thought out in its own way.I fully acknowledge the historical relevance that Neuromancer can be accredited in terms of coining cyberspace, starting the cyberpunk writing movement and also, perhaps, having a hand in developing what we find in today’s Internet and computer world. It is unquestionably easy to find an unnervingly large part of the popular Matrix movies in this one book. So much so, it makes me question whether the writing duo that put The Matrix together ever gave Neuromancer a large citation of influence.I would be quite wary in recommending this novel for others pleasure. It is an acquired taste and perhaps, due to Gibson’s fame, reading more of his work is a very much needed thing to do before judging him as an author. He certainly shows great imagination with this first novel."…pain beyond anything to which the name of pain is given…""The high wore away, the chromed skeleton corroding hourly, flesh growing solid, the drug-flesh replaced with the meat of his life."From: http://briandarvell.wordpress.com/200... </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>StennKlubov</user>
	<review>Excellent. Through this book William Gibson "invented" a genre As Blade Runner was to film, this book is to literature. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dczapka</user>
	<review>It's hard to remain completely objective about this text when you know, in advance, that it's the book that changed the course of science fiction and invented a subgenre (even if that subgenre lasted for roughly a year).As the prototypical cyberpunk novel, it's hard to say a bad thing about Neuromancer. As a science fiction novel, or even as a novel itself, it's remarkably prescient and accomplished, especially as a premiere novel. It's fast-paced (if a bit confusing), invents a diverse vocabulary with which it can deal with its social issues, and manages to still feel contemporary in a world where techno-obsolescence is the rule.All of which is a long, roundabout way of saying it's one hell of a trippy ride.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jibrailis</user>
	<review>Computers are fascinating. Maybe it’s because I’m not good with computers and it’s the allure of the unknown. Either way, Neuromancer has enough technology to keep anyone happy, and what’s most impressive about it was that it was written before the Internet, so Gibson was foretelling the future like Tiresias of old.Neuromancer is about Case, a troubled hacker in Japan who gets hired by a mysterious employer, later revealed to be an AI. He meets up with razorgirl Molly and off start their crazy adventures. Neuromancer is the great granddaddy of cyberpunk, and its world is gritty, dangerous, and verging on posthuman. There’s a lot of jargon here, and the writing isn’t the best I’ve ever read, making it a difficult read. It’s hard to keep up with what’s going on (when they’re in space, I don’t even realize it), but all its flaws aside, go read this book. It spawned an entire genre. It’s a piece of history. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>felius</user>
	<review>So long since the last time I read this that I'd forgotten most of it.  This was my SantaThing gift in 2007 - an excellent choice (given that it should have been on my shelf anyway!)This book describes an imagined world, but it prompted many readers to start working to create the technology it describes.  Dystopian yet optimistic, it's really a book about the messy transition period from humanity to some kind of post-human cybernetic hybrid, and about the technological singularity.That the main characters  are seemingly uninterested in the broader outcomes of the actions they're undertaking is frustrating to me.  Clearly, they're either sympathetic or ambivalent toward Artificial Intelligence, but I find it hard to believe they could be so completely unperturbed by what they're doing.Anyway, it's status as a classic is already well established.  Read this and "Snow Crash" by Neal Stephenson to understand where the net is taking us all - it's fiction, sure, and not always a pretty picture, but these two books show the greatest insight in imagining what a truly global and ubiquitous internet can lead to. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>devilwrites</user>
	<review>What on earth can I say about this SF classic that I finally, FINALLY!!! got around to reading? I've read Gibson's work before, Pattern Recognition, so I thought I knew what to expect when it came to his style. Then there's the fact that I am so well-aware of Neuormancer's impact on SF, as well as the real world, that I thought I knew what was coming.But picking up this book and reading the first few pages was a pure adrenaline rush of words. Punctuation aside, I'd forgotten about Gibson's amazing use of words and descriptions, the zing of his language. Even so far removed from this book's debut, it's easy to see how it created such a stir in the SF world at the time. It's also easy to see how much influence this book has had on so many current writers.I'm not going to bother with a link here, because I have nothing spoilery to say and let's face, the book's a classic. Even if I did spoil you, it wouldn't ruin the experience of reading the book. And for me, being so far removed from the book's debut and having read its progeny in terms of the genre, Neuromancer was more of an experience than it was a life-changer. It was good, don't get me wrong. Yes, it took me a little while to get into the rhythm of Gibson's prose, and I always felt I was catching on to what was happening just a little late, and even then, I wasn't sure if I got what I thought I got. One quick check to Wikipedia pretty much confirmed my interpretation of the book, so that's good. I particularly admired Gibson's use of the simstim, which was pretty darn cool.I can only image what kind of mindfreak this book must have been in the pre-cyberpunk SF world. This book must have been acid to those people. Again, the use of description was very enjoyable, and even I was surprised at the range of setting this book encompassed. I'm glad I finally got around to reading it, and maybe one day, I'll pick up more of Gibson's work in the future. Though, and I'm sure this is absolute heresy, I think I enjoyed Pattern Recognition more. Just chalk that up to the fact I read it first and it had a female POV, okay? :) </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fastia</user>
	<review>Neuromancer is a relatively short book, only 271 pages long in mass market paperback. The first 100 pages are excruciatingly boring and the next 171 are often still fairly boring, making this the longest short book I have ever read. The plot develops at a glacial pace, and the prose is filled with fictional technical jargon. The meaning of some of these terms can be inferred from context at times, but normally not immediately, and Gibson has a tendency to throw out a lot of these words at once. At first, this is fun since it gives the book a certain high-tech, future feel, but it is overdone to the point where it is just confusing and tedious...The rest of this review is here: http://fantasycafe.blogspot.com/2008/... </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tkraft</user>
	<review>The father novel of cyberpunk giving rise to the vocabulary and feel of future cyberpunk such as The Matrix. Lots of fun, a must read for anyone who even pretends to be a sci-fi fan.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nwhyte</user>
	<review>http://www.nicholaswhyte.info/sf/hn2....Won absolutely all the prizes and now identified as the archetypal cyberpunk novel. I have read it but actually can't remember anything about it except for Gibson's dazzling style. I have the same problem with his later books - you know you're being bombarded with description which all seems to hang together but after you've finished you can't remember any of the plot </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>PDExperiment626</user>
	<review>I read Neuromancer for the first time not too long ago and was actually pretty disappointed. I can appreciate Gibson doing what is essentially a Sci-fi retelling of an old story (I'm thinking Maltese Falcon). I can suspend disbelief for the various bits of fictional technology presented throughout the book. I can even present a blind-eye to the glaring cues that indicate Gibson is a technological/scientific neophyte. BUT there are some things that just don't work in this book.Let me just point out a few examples. First, the main character is essentially a crack-head super-hacker, who can basically break into any corporate mainframe (if he can ONLY get money to get the correct equipment). This I don't buy, as it implies one of two things: either he is just that good or the drugs he takes make him that good. In the first case, he would already have been acquired by a company or a government; he wouldn't be wandering aimlessly look for some money to get his next crack hit. In the second scenario, he isn't unique at all and the drugs that give him his abilities would be heavily controlled by the gov't or some such entity (think of the navigators in Dune). I'm sick of the diamond-in-the-rough, super-hacker stereotype; it only works because it plays upon a reader's fragile ego to make him/her think 'I can be badass too because I'm better than an addict'. This is one example of many underlying inconsistencies between characters and plot that run throughout the entirety of the story.Another issue I have is that Gibson doesn't know what to do with the technology he presents. Take Molly's skull-implanted, mirrored lenses (i.e. sunglasses) for instance: they have a built in clock to show Molly the time; they serve no other purpose in the story besides being sun glasses and making her look like some badass. I'm sorry, why do you need to have technology bio-mechanically implanted into your skull to take the place of a normal pair of sunglasses and a glow-in-the-dark-watch? You get these lenses implanted and loose the versatility of actually being able to remove them and it makes you more vulnerable than before (because if they break the shards have no where to go but your ocular cavity). Again, I have no problem suspending disbelief for fictional technology; but I expect the technology to do something more than just make a character look cool. My feeling is that most of the technologies presented in Neuromancer fall victim to this issue to some degree or another. This is one of the dead giveaways that Gibson has no idea what he is talking about; I wasn't surprised at all to find that he is a self-proclaimed technological luddite after reading the story.I believe this book became so popular because Gibson got it published at the right time in history; i.e. the idea of someone being a hacker was mysterious, cool and intriguing. Gibson tells a story portraying a hacker as someone who intrinsically has a lot of power if given the right equipment. That is, the reader can get subdued into the notion that they too can be a hacker because if a crack-head can be good at it... so can they. I really dislike this type of psychological play authors increasingly pull with their readers (i.e. Mary-Sue stories); it's a cheap literary trick that leads to implausible characters and situations for the benefit of sucking in more readers. I would bet money that if Case were portrayed as some nerdy computer geek living in a basement or some scientist with a bad streak (i.e. actually had to work to get good at something) then the book wouldn't have been nearly as popular.Anyway, I won't further belabor the point; I felt that I should cite a few examples, as I know many people like Neuromancer. In the end, it's a retelling of an old story with a static set of characters. The book exhibits various logistical inconsistencies between its plot and the personalities contained therein. This combined with a poor literary presentation of fictional technologies made this novel a real disappointment. Personally, I attribute Gibson's success in the cyberpunk genre to his abilities as a publicist, not an author. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>revolutionary_marcia</user>
	<review>Muy merecidamente la "biblia del cyberpunk". Increíble la capacidad de predicción de un futuro tecnológico que es casi nuestro presente. Esta obra ha tenido una reprecusión enorme en la cultura popular y se puede rastrear su influencia en películas como Matrix o animes como Serial Experiments. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lgaikwad</user>
	<review>First of the cyberpunk genre.  Foresaw the internet and AI. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Cyberpunk genius.How do you tell a great book?   One sign of such an animal to me is if it immediately makes you want to find everything else related and similar to that style or subject and read that as well.  This is what happened to me after reading Neuromancer.Case, a wannabe or wannabe better netcowboy gets involved in events way over his read to do with who really controls the virtual world and what is going on in space.Stylish novel that makes  it seems as though you can smell the mean streets of Japan or wherever it might take you.A must read.Also, anyone interested in the evolution of the science fiction genre really has to read this book.http://notfreesf.blogspot.com/2007/10... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Cyberpunk genius.How do you tell a great book?   One sign of such an animal to me is if it immediately makes you want to find everything else related and similar to that style or subject and read that as well.  This is what happened to me after reading Neuromancer.Case, a wannabe or wannabe better netcowboy gets involved in events way over his read to do with who really controls the virtual world and what is going on in space.Stylish novel that makes  it seems as though you can smell the mean streets of Japan or wherever it might take you.A must read.Also, anyone interested in the evolution of the science fiction genre really has to read this book.http://notfreesf.blogspot.com/2007/10... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Cyberpunk genius.How do you tell a great book?   One sign of such an animal to me is if it immediately makes you want to find everything else related and similar to that style or subject and read that as well.  This is what happened to me after reading Neuromancer.Case, a wannabe or wannabe better netcowboy gets involved in events way over his read to do with who really controls the virtual world and what is going on in space.Stylish novel that makes  it seems as though you can smell the mean streets of Japan or wherever it might take you.A must read.Also, anyone interested in the evolution of the science fiction genre really has to read this book.http://notfreesf.blogspot.com/2007/10... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Cyberpunk genius.How do you tell a great book?   One sign of such an animal to me is if it immediately makes you want to find everything else related and similar to that style or subject and read that as well.  This is what happened to me after reading Neuromancer.Case, a wannabe or wannabe better netcowboy gets involved in events way over his read to do with who really controls the virtual world and what is going on in space.Stylish novel that makes  it seems as though you can smell the mean streets of Japan or wherever it might take you.A must read.Also, anyone interested in the evolution of the science fiction genre really has to read this book.http://notfreesf.blogspot.com/2007/10... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dilandau</user>
	<review>http://www.piruett.se/2007/12/11/annu... </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>andrewa121</user>
	<review>For anyone steeped in the genre of science fiction and its cyberpunk subgenre, this novel has a mythical status. It is widely regarded as the seminal work in the genre; Gibson is credited with coining the term "cyberspace" and any work that proclaims itself to be cyberpunk is inevitably judged against Neuromancer, the upshot being that as far as cyberpunk aficionados are concerned, the book is a revealed text, laying out the dogma to which all future works, in order to call themselves cyberpunk, must to some degree adhere. All the weight and reverence afforded this novel makes approaching it a daunting task. Fortunately, I have never been an avid science fiction reader and was thus largely ignorant of the buzz surrounding the novel. As such, I think I was able to more critically examine the novel while at the same time experience it with a sort of naïve wonder. So with this disclaimer out of the way, letting you know where I'm coming from, here are a few thoughts.The tone of Gibson's work is firmly inspired by Philip K. Dick, but relies on a much more concrete science fiction, rooted in emerging (some now completely emerged) technologies. Or maybe this just seems to be the case due to the fact that so many of the technological devices Gibson uses to create his world have become so vital in our world today. Gibson's focus on simulation v. reality and machine v. consciousness provides an axon bridging the gap (at least chronologically) between Dick and more modern, accessible cyberpunk best epitomized in the public consciousness with Snow Crash in literature and The Matrix in film. As with Dick's work, reading Neuromancer was like receiving a text through a fog. The constant flashes from reality into virtual worlds are jarring, disconcerting, and disruptive to the narrative flow. Which is, I would think, exactly what Gibson wants, as it reflects the mental state of the characters: alienated, bifurcated, and overall just confused. While this didn't make for the most readable of books, the mental gymnastics required and the engrossing world that Gibson creates—not to mention the philosophical questions the novel poses—make for a book that'll leave a mark on the reader, and has definitely left its mark on literature, opening up a fascinating subgenre that can be simultaneously mindbending and thrilling. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>storyjunkie</user>
	<review>http://storyjunkie.livejournal.com/21...When I was done, one of my first reactions was to imagine some poor lit student, maybe twenty years from now, who's out of hir mind with sleep dep and finals are approaching, and ze ends up writing a report on how Neuromancer is this scathing critique of the early twenty-first century's out-teched society and a satire on the technological industry of that time. All because ze didn't look at the copyright date.All in all, I was more drawn to the characters rather than the brave new world they inhabited. Which is really no surprise because characters are my main focal point in whatever I read, and thanks to the world we inhabit, the one Gibson describes isn't totally unfamiliar. Which I guess is one of the reasons this book is what it has become - a lodestone as to what we are capable of.And yet, he populates this world with characters that refuse to be what we expect. Heroes are villains and vice versa, the lost are found, the found are lost and nobody gets a fair deal. These people refuse to be archetypes, refuse their molds, and in so doing they become heated flesh and blood in a world that does not treat such fragile material kindly.And there's a happy ending.The mind boggles at all the hope and hopelessness served up at the same time. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>www.snigel.nu</user>
	<review>Link to a review on my personal website  (might be in Swedish). </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CUViper</user>
	<review>Neuromancer is quite a ride.  In fact, it took me a while to even get my bearings as to what was happening, and even at the end I don't think I was completely clued in.  I still enjoyed it though, and I will probably go back and reread it sometime to try to make more sense of it. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>myfanwy</user>
	<review>I have had a love/hate relationship with sci-fi for some time now. It can be so good at its best, but the writing can be so infuriating at its worst. So, I've taken to taking recommendations, and Neuromancer, by anyone's calculations, is one of the most influential of sci-fi novels....and I can see why. There's not much I can say about Neuromancer. It is the Matrix, and SnowCrash, and Hackers, and every other techno-adventure all rolled up into one. Chiba City is reflected in the movie version of Blade Runner. People "jack in" with a socket in the back of their heads. There's a hell of a lot of black leather and a hot girl and a gifted but clueless hacker intent on saving them all. And through all of it, there's the written style of a beat poet, making hacking into the new art of the millennium. I only wish that I had read this in two sittings, or even one. It's meant to be read in one fell swoop. It races against the clock. I may have to read it again just to get that headlong rush. But at least Neuromancer reminded me what it's like to have a book I can't put down, one that I read while I'm walking because I want to take every free moment I have to get to the end. It's delirious, trippy, smart, poetic and a hell of a lot of fun.Yeah man, yeah.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kassetra</user>
	<review>Many people have complained that this book is confusing, poorly assembled, badly written, shallow, dull, etc. Other people have written that this is the best scifi book of all time.It's neither.Neuromancer is not science fiction, nor is it a poorly written piece of non-genre fiction.From the minute you read the first line of this book, you are involved in the overlapping video-game-versus-reality world of the characters. You aren't given instructions or a glossary to smooth the transition into the book's juvenile perspective. But that's the point.This book delves into quasi-sociological questions, and a superficial nature of personality. The pretentious jargon is part of what the characters call "home." It's pseudo-information dense, elitist, and an anti-adventure.What Neuromancer does is plunge you into a futuristic view of society from a gamer's mind, which is not, per se, linear, nor is it especially credible.It is the typical diamond-in-the-rough, everyman joe that thinks he's far more clever than he actually is getting into a situation that's well over his head.If none of these ideas appeal to you, this book is not for you. You will most likely be confused, unhappy, etc. with this book. If these concepts sound intensely fascinating, you will probably like Neuromancer. </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ktoonen</user>
	<review>Arguably the first cyber-punk novel, Neuromancer helped create a whole new type of science fiction.  Jack-in with Case, a cyber-cowboy; Molly, a surgically enhanced street samurai; and Dixie Flatline, the ultimate cyber-cowboy now only a ROM personality matrix.  But be warned:  two AIs, Wintermute and Neuromancer, are the chessmasters moving these pawns in a struggle all their own.  Gibson beautifully explains much of the techno-action through metaphors understandable to computer novices.http://home.comcast.net/~ktoonen/summ... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bradsucks</user>
	<review>Very good. I got lost at points though, which probably means I am dumb. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>geertwissink</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books ever. Breathtaking story set   with so many new and recognizable concepts. I read the book when the internet was already invented and Virtual Reality seemed only a few years away but it still shook me on my feet. This is how the future could be, nothing more nothing less. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>icco</user>
	<review>My favorite book of all time. If you are into computers, adventure, or the advancement of technology, you will love this book. Be warned though it does have many mature subjects, so I would keep this for 14 and up. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stpnwlf</user>
	<review>The one - the novel that probably deserves more credit than any other for launching the cyberpunk movement in SF.  Immerses you in the dark, gritty world that other authors try very hard to duplicate in a myriad of novels. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mortensengarth</user>
	<review>cyberpunk influence of shadowrun. it reads better than anything in the shadowrun book series though. dystopia, tech, please read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alv</user>
	<review>Pestiño esnob. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sulkyblue</user>
	<review>I really really really didn't get this book. It was a huge slog to get through and by about a third of the way through I was just skimming the words to get to the end. I can see that it was visionary, ahead of it's time, genre defining and all that stuff... but I just didn't get it. To be honest I wasn't particularly surprised by that. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Arctic-Stranger</user>
	<review>I got my first computer with a modem around the time I read this book. Gibson saw a future that was both scary and appealing, and his characters are very interesting. Not always likable, but very interesting. This gets high marks because it is the beginnging of a whole new genre of lit. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>414448</user>
	<review>The book that revived science fiction and breathed new life into a genre dead at the moment.Gibsons prose could be compared to Hemingways; it's direct and no-nonsense all the way.A book i re-read at least once a year. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RaceBannon42</user>
	<review>Neuromancer by William Gibson was a groundbreaking sci-fi novel, and was awarded the Hugo, the Nebula, and the Philip K. Dick awards in 1984. It effectively introduced "cyberpunk" as a sub genre of science fiction. Gibson coined the term "cyberspace" and envisioned the internet and virtual reality well before either existed. The book follows Case, a former cyber cowboy, who jacks in and surfs cyberspace for his employers. But he went to far and now has been severed from the matrix. A mysterious power offers to fix him, in return for going along on one last, dangerous mission. Case is joined by Molly, and lovely yet deadly bodyguard, and the ex military man Armitage. Neuromancer is a relatively short book clocking in at just over 250 pages in my trade edition. The influence this book has had on the genre is undeniable. Movies like the Matrix seem derived almost completely from this work. The world Gibson unfolds for us is remarkable. Like Verne before him he predicts where technology will go uncanily. However, personally I found it rather hard to follow it at points. The story never totally grabbed me. Conceptually I was hooked, but I just couldn't like it as much as I wanted to. I don't think this style is really my cup of tea. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>honeyrococo</user>
	<review>I think I am the only person who found this book to be really hopeful and uplifting. Despite the fact that it is a very dark novel in which terrible things are happening, I thought it was nice to think that no matter how oppressive our governments and corporations become, there will aways be ways to breach the system, to hack in and lay claim to technology in a sort of evolutionary progression of niche adaptation. I always want there to be hackers in my world -- the only people who might someday save us from this impending nightmare of totalitarian tracking and control.That said, I am not a sci-fi or mystery or fantasy buff and one of the delights of reading this book for me as a reader was recognizing all the allusions to great works of literature. Gibson really is a great writer. I also like the fact that in an interview Gibson said that he wrote the whole thing on an old typewriter and if he'd had a computer at the time this never would have been written because he projected a great romance onto computers which they didn't live up to at the time. When, after making some money off Neuromancer sales, he bought his first computer, he was dismayed by the fact it made a whiring noise -- it seemed like a primitive machine and not the magical technology he had made of it.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rickmas</user>
	<review>Reading Neuromancer is like walking through a lucid nightmare filled with high technology, amoral protagonists, manipulative villains and endless chromed webs of intrigue. ...But Neuromancer isn't just a cyberpunk novel, it's the cyberpunk novel, the novel that fans can point to as a watershed moment in the dark-future genre. ...Gibson coined the term cyberspace.... His vision of being able to mentally explore immense amounts of data, to truly experience the net rather than just idly surf it, is just as compelling today as when the novel was released. -- Ken Newquist </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>GibsonGirl</user>
	<review>The Original. Incomparable. Atmospheric, moody, and intense, it fares well in comparison with its literary predecessor, The Maltese Falcon, by the likewise incomparable Dashiell Hammett. Notable for its verisimilitude-achieved by means of a meticulously described environment-with the attendant emotional resonance such details evoke in readers.  Accept no substitutes. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pauliharman</user>
	<review>Unintelligible nonsense </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zicon</user>
	<review>Annoyingly incoherent and unentertaining. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KevlarRelic</user>
	<review>The original cyberpunk. I just read this book, twenty years after it was first published, and it was still exciting, atmospheric, and captivating after all this time, even to a stickler for nit-picky computer technology details like me. This book is a great read, ready to be enjoyed by anyone who has the opportunity to pick it up. Read it! </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>xtien</user>
	<review>I just re-read Neuromancer. This book fairly accurately predicted the internet as we know it today, although the words Gibson uses are different from the words we use today. He coined the word "the Matrix" which in the early days of the internet, the early nineties, was a moniker the net went by. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kingyak</user>
	<review>http://www.deathcookie.com/node/445 </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>addict</user>
	<review>Here is the novel that started it all, launching the cyberpunk generation, and the first novel to win the holy trinity of science fiction: the Hugo Award, the Nebula Award and the Philip K. Dick Award. With Neuromancer, William Gibson introduced the world to cyberspace--and science fiction has never been the same. Case was the hottest computer cowboy cruising the information superhighway--jacking his consciousness into cyberspace, soaring through tactile lattices of data and logic, rustling encoded secrets for anyone with the money to buy his skills. Then he double-crossed the wrong people, who caught up with him in a big way--and burned the talent out of his brain, micron by micron. Banished from cyberspace, trapped in the meat of his physical body, Case courted death in the high-tech underworld. Until a shadowy conspiracy offered him a second chance--and a cure--for a price </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>name99</user>
	<review>Oh god, what a waste of time. I loathe film noire; the whole stupid set of cliches from the self-destructive anti-hero to the femme fatale to the dark gritty city. And this book is nothing but run-of-the-mill film noire translated fairly mechanically into a sort-of-futuristic universe. Heck, maybe in 1984 it was a great leap forward in terms of imagination (though I fail to see quite what those leaps were), but in 2004 it reads like a sad list of cliches. In particular, the central conceits of the book, namely that computer "hacking", in the sense of penetrating secured computers is best performed via some sort of VR rig, and that the essential contents of a human mind can be captured to silicon to create a living-yet-dead representation of that person, are neither justified nor explored. This is not an SF book, or at least not what I consider to be a good SF book, in the sense of twisting some aspect of reality slightly through some pseudo-science mumbo-jumbo and then exploring the consequences; rather it concerns itself with its personalities and their story, as in a traditional novel. That might have been fine, had these personalities and their story not been, as I've said, nothing but a set of noire cliches.I persisted till the very end in the hope that, eventually, there would be some sort of interesting payoff, some sort of culmination of the various threads, but no such luck. If you're the sort who cares more about the mood of a book than the plot, originality, or even that the whole thing makes sense you may love this book. Anyone else, go read a decent author like say Iain M Banks. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kawgirl</user>
	<review>It took me a long time to get to this novel, but I am glad I did. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nillacat</user>
	<review>Did this start the cyberpunk movemement, or epitomize it? Both maybe. Nothing else in the genre of dystopic, technological action-adventure manages to be anything but derivative of the tropes and themes established by Gibson.Which isn't to say it is a great book. I've read a lot of science fiction, and this only gets a 3. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>invisiblelizard</user>
	<review>I read Neuromancer first when I was in high school. This was before blogging, or Google, or the www itself. William Gibson wrote all about it, but he called his cyberspace (his word) the "matrix" (also, his word). Then the Wachowski brothers came around and immortalized The Matrix as their creation, but those of us who know will remember that Gibson wrote about it first.When I saw the nicely bound 20th anniversary edition in the Borders not too long ago, I knew I had to get it and read it again. It's a great ride for sci-fi and "cyberpunk" fans (though be aware that Gibson shuns this categorical title). Reading this led me to the equally amazing, though in much different ways, Neal Stephenson.It's not an easy read. This was surprising. I remembered struggling with it before, as a teenager, and thinking that it would be easier now with an English degree under my belt. Nope, no such luck. I think my brain got a little fried on all of the new language Gibson literally made up for this novel. Not only that, but people don't speak the way you're used to, so it's a struggle to keep up. I've heard there is an audiobook of this as read by the author. I think that would be fun to listen to.So is the writing stellar or is the genius in the story itself? A little of both actually. Gibson may well be the unsung literary golden child of the sci-fi genre. His turn of phrase is usually eloquent and frequently impressive. The fact that the story itself is well thought-out and exciting just adds to the charisma.Every once in a while I suspect an author of getting a brief glimpse into the future. H. G. Wells and Jules Verne kind of gave off that vibe. Maybe in the next hundred years or so we'll suspect Asimov and Bradbury of the same. These guys may have glimpsed far into the future. William Gibson peeked ahead ten or twenty years and wrote about what he saw.Invisible Lizard's Unusual Oranges </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Anks</user>
	<review>http://ank.blogspot.com/2006/01/neuro... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>biblioconnisseur</user>
	<review>This was really good. Second of his books I have read. I kept seeing  Johnny Mnemonic backgrounds. I think I am interested enough in reading the next two. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hrissliss</user>
	<review>Apparently, one of the founding writers of cyberpunk. (According to Amazon reviews at least.) Main character - Case, a data thief, whose ex-employers ensured he'd never work again. Now he's being recruited for "a last chance run" against an unknown entity. I love this book. I think I might have found a possible new favorite genre. His writing was spare, but almost poetic at times. The characters were gritty, hard, perfect denizens of the possible future he's constructed. Gibson is great at extending current social trends into the future, and treats that future (in his books) as simply the reality - just as a modern writer writing of modern things would treat television as just something that's there, so does Gibson treat his techno-creations. Some parts, though, were confusing. Sometimes, the novel did require greater description. There were several passages I read, where the end left me with a simple "Huh?" - and re-reads weren't helping. Still and all, this book was a gorgeous read. 9/10 </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alyce413</user>
	<review>Really beautifully written. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>WingedWolf</user>
	<review>The novel that helped launch the cyberpunk movement, and the concept of cyberspace as a real place. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tjeffress</user>
	<review>http://www.i-reports.info/b/B199701.h... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Floppy</user>
	<review>An absolute classic. This book defined the cyberpunk genre, and it's one that I keep coming back to time and again, and every time I get more from it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lewallen</user>
	<review>A true science fiction classic, popularizer of the word "cyberspace" (coined by William Gibson in 1982), progenitor of the "cyberpunk" sub-genre of science fiction, and a book that remains remarkably undated, in my opinion, over twenty years after it was published. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BTRIPP</user>
	<review>http://www.livejournal.com/users/btri...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>languagehat</user>
	<review>I didn't think sf could give me that old thrill any more until I read this 20 years ago.  Wow. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>topps</user>
	<review>Here is the novel that started it all, launching the cyberpunk generation, and the first novel to win the holy trinity of science fiction: the Hugo Award, the Nebula Award and the Philip K. Dick Award. With Neuromancer, William Gibson introduced the world to cyberspace--and science fiction has never been the same. Case was the hottest computer cowboy cruising the information superhighway--jacking his consciousness into cyberspace, soaring through tactile lattices of data and logic, rustling encoded secrets for anyone with the money to buy his skills. Then he double-crossed the wrong people, who caught up with him in a big way--and burned the talent out of his brain, micron by micron. Banished from cyberspace, trapped in the meat of his physical body, Case courted death in the high-tech underworld. Until a shadowy conspiracy offered him a second chance--and a cure--for a price </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0441012035</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>reset.reboot</user>
	<review>El clásico que inició todo un género en su época. William Gibson hace todo un ejercicio de adivinación del futuro que cada dia parece estar más cerca, todo salteado con unas gotas de filosofía y de </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>