<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Awesomeness1</user>
	<review>I won this in a Goodreads giveaway. Imagine my surprise when I received a 600 paged hardcover with a lovely cover. This book surpassed my expectations. I enjoyed the characters, and soaked up the drama. I am forever a fan of family sagas, and this was a good once. I connected with Mary's and Percy's stories more than Rachels. The book just seemed to repeat plot elements over again once it got to the end. Sometimes the pacing would be off, as is the problem with larger books. It would be very detailed in some parts, and it would mention other events in passing. Overall, a very enjoyable novel. Entertaining and time-consuming. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bermudaonion</user>
	<review>The Tolivers, the Warwicks and the Dumonts are the founding families of the small east Texas town of Howbutker.  The Tolivers own a cotton plantation, the Dumonts sell dry good and the Warwicks are timber barons.  The families have been friends for years and their histories are intertwined.  Percy Warwick and Mary Toliver were deeply in love but, sadly, never married.  That horrible mistake, and all of its consequences, have haunted Percy and Mary and their descendants for years.  Mary’s great-niece and Percy’s grandson find themselves trying to wade through all the deceit, secrets and lies.Roses by Leila Meacham is a grand, sweeping multi-generational saga set in east Texas.  It’s over 600 pages long, but once I got into the story, I found it went very quickly.  At first, I thought it would be difficult to tell the families apart, but found that wasn’t a problem since there weren’t too many characters and they all had strong, distinct personalities.  I liked all of the characters in this book, except for Lucy, and I couldn’t help but feel sorry for her.  I loved the fact that most of the female characters in this book are strong, driven women.There were enough unexpected twists and turns in the plot to keep me interested and I found myself staying up late more than once to find out what was going to happen next.  I enjoyed this book and think it would be a great read for cold winter days. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>