<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>K. Harris "Film aficionado"</user>
	<review>

Spanning three generations and nearly a century, Leila Meacham's "Roses" is a throwback to epic storytelling in the vein of Edna Ferber, Margaret Mitchell, or Colleen McCullough.  The book advertising, itself, makes the comparison to "The Thorn Birds" and those are pretty lofty expectations to set as McCollough's "The Thorn Birds" has endured as one of the most beloved romance sagas of its day.  In truth, I don't think "Roses" is the next classic in that vein--but I do believe there is a lot to recommend this sprawling tale of forbidden love and family betrayal.  In a small East Texas town, three families of enormous wealth and power come to reside.  The Tolivers are cotton tycoons, the Warwicks are lumber barons, and the DuMonts are retail magnates.  The mutual respect formed between these elite families set up a social structure that will have long lasting repercussions through the generations for all their progeny.  At the heart of "Roses" is Mary Toliver, a heroine we follow for 80 plus years.  Stubborn and single-minded, Mary is a terrific and maddening character--epitomizing the strong-willed matriarch necessary for just such a tale.  Her male counterpoint is Percy Warwick, a perfect foil and the love of Mary's life.  Of course, these two are made for each other--and of course, they can never truly realize happiness in each other's arms.  Their grand romance is played through the decades with enormous vigor, and their dance together is filled with small moments of joy but mostly great tragedy.The first two-thirds of Meacham's tale is terrifically engaging.  Fast paced and fun, I was whole-heartedly invested in the Mary and Percy story and all the subplots in the periphery. Galloping through the years, the ill-fated romance stays center stage even as both parties move off into new directions.  I enjoyed the characters and even as they created a new generation, that still remained a part of the main story line.  However, all good things must come to an end--and ultimately, for me, the book loses momentum for its final third.  Concerning itself with Mary's potential heir, Rachel Toliver (the third generation and Mary's double in both spirit and dedication to the family business to the exclusion of everything else), the story lacks some of the pizzazz that it had previously showcased.  Still a solid conclusion, it just didn't captivate me in the way Mary's story had--so there was a bit of a fizzle instead of a crescendo.I really recommend "Roses" to fans of the genre.  Ultimately, I'm probably not the book's intended audience but I like to dabble in soapy sagas every once in a while.  And, I found most of "Roses" to be entertaining and involving.  I genuinely cared for the characters of Mary and Percy, and if you're going to follow a family saga through the decades--that's got to be a positive!
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kokopelli</user>
	<review>

I am torn over where to begin with this review. The author had the makings of a great book here with a promising plot line and what could have been great characters. Unfortunately, especially in the first half of the book involving Mary and Percy, the characterizations are uneven and undeveloped, and the motivations and actions don't make sense. The second half of the book, involving Mary's granddaughter Rachel, is somewhat better in these regards, or maybe I just got used to the author's writing and filled in the blanks for myself. I was astounded to read that Ms. Meacham was a former English teacher, as her use of similes and metaphors is strained and off-putting, and her failure to correctly provide an antecedent for her many pronouns is rampant. Further, some of her sudden leaps in place and time can be pretty confusing, as they are indicated by nothing at all other than all of a sudden someone else is speaking or the action is taking place somewhere unrelated to what came immediately before.  Maybe these missteps were present because I was reading an ARC, and they will be corrected in the final version of the book. I can only hope so, both for Ms. Meacham's sake and the sake of her future readers. A good editor would have been a godsend for this version that I received. All that said, I was held by the storyline and the suspense until the last page, and I was never tempted to put the book down and not finish it. I think Ms. Meacham does capture the ambiance of small-town Texas (I grew up in a small town in West Texas myself) and it's entirely believable that there were two or three "ruling" families with immense wealth and property and also great respect from the town. She reveals the secrets of these families in a convincing manner and maintains plenty of suspense along the way. My earlier comments about characterization refer primarily to the fact that the actions of the characters are not sufficiently explained by what we've come to know and understand about them. For example, Mary's willingness to accept the vagaries of fate and not fight for true love does not square with her stubbornness about holding on to Somerset regardless of the consequences. Also, Mary's realistic and straightforward approach to the farm and life in general doesn't lend much credence to her devastating actions taken because of belief in a family curse. Of course, people are complicated and do have blind spots, but somehow the most critical step Mary takes is never justified at all by anything we've come to know about her. And Rachel's final decision regarding her law suit is never explained at all. I've tried to avoid any spoilers in the preceding but I felt that I needed to justify my own statements by giving a few examples. I also think some family genealogy charts would have been helpful to remember who's in what generation and their relation to the rest of the family. I hope the final published version of this book will have taken care of all my misgivings, and with that in mind, I recommend this book to anyone who likes a multi-generational tale of passion, suspense, and tragedy.
      </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>M. D. Mulhern</user>
	<review>

I thoroughly enjoyed this book!  I started it one snowy evening and had to stay up and finish.  I was totally enthralled with Mary's life and what had happened to lead up to the opening moments in the first chapter.  The book sets the stage for flashbacks and the is divided into three parts:  Mary's Story, another main character's story (no spoilers from me!) and then the present when everything wraps up.  Even though I knew how Mary's life had ended up, I was so captivated by her and the other characters that I kept hoping that she would make different decisions, change her life, etc.  This book was a wonderful guilty pleasure....kind of like 'The Thorn Birds" lite.I did think that the third section dragged a bit.  Maybe because I was so wrapped up in the past and Mary's life, I did not care as much about her great-niece Rachel, or maybe I was just tired.  But things started to seem a bit redundant, especially the symbolism of the red and white roses.But all in all, I HIGHLY recommend this book!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Linda Holman "L A Jewel"</user>
	<review>

This is the first book I have read by this author, and I loved every chapter!It is a quite volumnous book though it turned out to be a quick, enjoyable read.  It tells a story of the history of the DuMont, the Tolliver and Warwick families, who started their empire in small town in Texas, and it spanned over a century. It detailed their tragedies, their conquests, their romances and their heartache.  A lot of the book focused on each family's professions, and while I know nothing about farming, I truly enjoyed the information and came to understand it in a way I had never before imagined. The author's descriptions of the characters, the time period, and overall her attention to detail just swept me away to a magical era in a way that was not cumbersome or boring, and I did not feel the need to skim or pass over this book at all. Instead, I savored every word.  It had the feel of Gone With The Wind, in that it was an epic love story, yet bittersweet.I highly recommend this book to anyone that likes a good old fashioned saga.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Valerie J. Wood "Author, Breakfasts with Buster"</user>
	<review>

Roses is a book in the tradition of Gone With the Wind, Giant, The Thorn Birds, any Rosamund Pilcher book--thick, hefty novels that tell a TALE. This was definitely a hard-to-put-down novel. Once the story got rolling along, which was fairly quickly, this was a satisfying, enjoyable read. It is the story of two star-crossed lovers in the early 1920's-1920's thru the present, and the decisions they made that ultimately kept them apart. Mary Tolliver and Percy Warwick love each other thru their entire long lives and their regrettable choices may be duplicated by their grandchildren if changes are not made. This is a well-written, solid tale which takes the reader through the lives of these two very likable, stubborn and independent characters. A good, solid, read!!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tara</user>
	<review>

Deep in the heart of Texas in the 1800s, three families made a town. The Tollivers and the Warwicks are descendants of the English Yorks and Lancasters. Those familiar with the War of the Roses will understand the family feud and its continuance. The third family is the Du Monts from France and one could say the Du Monts are the glue holding the roses together. Roses is the story of three generations of these three families. In the early 1900s, there is Mary Tolliver, Percy Warwick, and Ollie Du Mont. Mary's love of her cotton plantation and her stubborness somewhat estrange her from the man she loves, Percy. She marries Ollie instead.. Why?? You must read it to find out. I shall not reveal the tantalizing details. Nevertheless, amidst this love triangle is war, despression, the trials of running a cotton plantation and family scandal. The results of these roses yield another generation. Matthew Du Mont, Wyatt Warwick, and William Tolliver make up the next generation and they live (and some die) in the middle 1900s. The last quarter of the novel is about the third generation, Rachel Tolliver and Matthew Warwick. Rachel must come to terms with her Aunt Mary's shocking will and make some life changing choices. Will she make the same mistakes that Mary did or will her heart dictate her path? My only complaint is the lack of war details.. On one page a fellow is leaving for war and on the next page, he is coming back after four years. I am quite fond of war stories so I would not have minded a little more detail on that. Nevertheless, it is not advertised as a war story so it doesn't cause the loss of a star. This author has a style very similar to that of the great Catherine Cookson. I highly recommend it to fans of the late English writer. In my honest opinion, Cookson is the queen of drama and scandal. Mrs Meecham is a very close second.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tonya Speelman "Hoarder of books"</user>
	<review>

I LOVE large books, so this one was right up my alley. I loved the whole idea of the multi-generational, soaperish type of book. I love the whole idea of the roses. The characters I really got into, not so much Rachel though. I got to know Lucy, Mary, Percy and Ollie a whole lot. Even Matthew and Wyatt more. I know there are a few reviews so I won't say the same thing, but I really think you will enjoy this book. Especially if you love a clean, enjoyable book! It has lots of romance, secrets kept here and there from everyone and family ties. Mary is my favorite character, she did what she knew to had to be done. Too bad she wasn't able to tell Rachel everything, but I am glad Percy was able to come through for Mary. Lucy ended up becoming a major character too! Loved her sass!!!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BermudaOnion</user>
	<review>

The Tolivers, the Warwicks and the Dumonts are the founding families of the small east Texas town of Howbutker.  The Tolivers own a cotton plantation, the Dumonts sell dry good and the Warwicks are timber barons.  The families have been friends for years and their histories are intertwined.  Percy Warwick and Mary Toliver were deeply in love but, sadly, never married.  That horrible mistake, and all of its consequences, have haunted Percy and Mary and their descendants for years.  Mary's great-niece and Percy's grandson find themselves trying to wade through all the deceit, secrets and lies.Roses by Leila Meacham is a grand, sweeping multi-generational saga set in east Texas.  It's over 600 pages long, but once I got into the story, I found it went very quickly.  At first, I thought it would be difficult to tell the families apart, but found that wasn't a problem since there weren't too many characters and they all had strong, distinct personalities.  I liked all of the characters in this book, except for Lucy, and I couldn't help but feel sorry for her.  I loved the fact that most of the female characters in this book are strong, driven women.There were enough unexpected twists and turns in the plot to keep me interested and I found myself staying up late more than once to find out what was going to happen next.  I enjoyed this book and think it would be a great read for cold winter days.
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>happy reader "d/mil"</user>
	<review>

Although I'm only a little past half way through, "Roses" has me absolutely spellbound.  Set in the Old South and beginning in the days of WWI, the characters are so realistic, it seems they could step right out of the book and speak. There  have already been some real surprises and I know there will be lots more before I'm finished. Believe me, this saga is a winner.  A great book for a long cold winter or,for that matter, a warm and sunny beach vacation.  But enough.... now I must rush back to reading it.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0446550000</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>delicateflower152</user>
	<review>

In "Roses," Leila Meacham has produced a novel that is engrossing.  It transports the reader to another place and time.  Mary Tolliver DuMont, dowager, Texas cotton farmer and heir to the Tolliver "curse," appears in the first pages of the book.  The reader is given a brief glimpse into the past and at the family mysteries and personal dynamics which will be expanded as the book progresses.   The other individuals, Mary's family and friends, who will carry the story are introduced.  While I found this section of the book interesting, I was about to jump to the conclusion that my choice of books might have been a mistake.However, that misconception was put to rest as I began the section of the book subtitled "Mary's Story."  It is there that Meacham weaves her magic and pulls the reader, mentally and emotionally, into the lives of her characters.  The history of Howbutker, Texas and its founding families, the Tollivers, DuMonts, and Warwicks, is briefly set out so that the reader gains a full appreciation for the events which transpire.  Further, the reader learns the significance of red, white, and pink roses in the lives of the characters throughout the generations.  More important than the background presented in this section is the impact and unintended consequences of Mary's inheriting the family cotton farm on Howbutker's three founding families.Part II of the book continues the saga, which has been set in 1985, and, by delving into their pasts, expands the reader's knowledge of the characters.  Like "Mary's Story," this section of the book has great emotional impact and will touch the reader's heart.  Part III moves forward with the story of Rachel Tolliver, Mary's great-niece, and heir apparent.  While portions of this section are outstanding and will impact the reader, there were portions where the book bogged down a bit, both in action and its ability to hold this reader's interest.  The romantic outcome between Rachel and Matt Tolliver, which was expected, could have been more strongly written.  Meacham writes a excellent romantic tale as evidenced by Mary, Percy, and Ollie's story and I did not feel the final chapter lived up to that storyline.I rated "Roses" as a five-star read because it is simply a good read; it is not great literature, but it does not claim to be.  If you are looking for another "Thornbirds" this is probably not the book for you.  "Roses" held my interest so that I did not want to stop reading; the characters were interesting and their stories touching."Roses" is an outstanding book for anyone who likes romances which are big in scope and long on emotion.  The love-story and its resulting heartbreak are written without eroticism, innuendo, or cliché-ridden prose.   Unlike some romances where the protagonists give in to their longing for one another, Percy and Mary, the star-crossed lovers, remain faithful to their respective spouses.  Meacham pulls real feeling from the reader through her use of the characters, their interaction, and their lives.  I am not an emotional reader, but I found myself reaching, more than once, for the Kleenex box.  Additionally, Meacham's ability to involve the reader in this story is unusual.  This is book to curl up with on one of those gloomy winter's days when you want to be anywhere but where you are.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>