<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Escushion</user>
	<review>

"The terror, which would not end for another twenty-eight years--if it ever did end--began, so far as I can tell, with a boat made from a sheet of newspaper floating down a gutter swollen with rain."This is the first line of "It," the beginning to one of Stephen King's masterpieces, and probably the most incredible story I've ever read. Those who complain about it's length... they need patience. Those who complain about its characters... they need to look around at themselves and others. Those who complain about it being vulgar, vile, or horrific... that's part of the story, and not to embrace it means you miss out on something extraordinary.In the summer of 1958, seven friends encountered something horrible in their town of Derry, Maine. This something fed on children, hunting them, preying on them, and devouring them. It could shape itself in any way It liked, whatever their nightmares suited, but always with one trademark: the semblance of a clown. The seven friends all had something in common: They had all escaped It at some point. And in that summer, they learned about It, confronted It, and killed It... or so they thought.28 years later... A boy named Adrian Mellon is apparently thrown off a bridge by two other boys for his sexuality. It seems like an open-and-shut case, but the boys claim that there was something down below... a clown and a cloud of balloons.Soon the friends are being called back to Derry, told that It is back. They made a vow, sealed in blood, to return if It wasn't dead. Each of them is now very successful, and the thought of returning to Derry, of going back to the horror that they'd all forgotten, is more than they can bear, but they had made a promise."It" is two stories being told at once. One is the story of their childhood, of their first encounter with Pennywise the Clown, their troubles with the local bullies, the impact of It upon their lives, their own personal struggles, and the eventual defeat of It. This is told from the beginning of the book to the near end of it. At the same time, the story of the return to Derry, of the research done to see what It was, the memories that were now urging to return, and subsequent events that followed which I won't spoil here. Both timelines alternate in their tellings to fit one another perfectly, even if not in perfect chronological order, and they're even further juiced with quick points of time long before their own, dipping into what else It has been up to. This construction is utterly beautiful in how it's placed, and completely builds the story up for all its plot points and climax. "It" also easily avoids a problem with many long Stephen King books: Plot threads that go nowhere. The characters are completely immersive and none are the all-too-well-known cliches. Bill Denbrough is the leader of the group, with a bone to pick with It, and his own problem of stuttering. Richie Tozier has a smart mouth and a big ego, one that hides things from the others that he's ashamed of, even in denial of. Eddie Kaspbrak is asmathic and weak, but he has courage within him to help his friends. Stan Uris is a sensible and supportive friend, who helps bring understanding of things. Ben Hanscom is an overweight and loving boy who brings his own ingenuity to the group. Beverly Marsh is a tough, yet sweet girl, whose own problems at home help prepare her for what she must face with the others. And Mike Hanlon, a boy chased by the bullies for the color of his skin, who comes across the group with a desire to help, and also leading to one of the more emotional parts of the story, the Great Rock Fight. These are the seven friends whose unity and circumstances held them together against It, and who vowed to return. It isn't long before they feel familiar, as if you've known them all your life, as well as the troubles they've faced, especially those of punk and bully Henry Bowers, whose endless torment drives them into the very heart of It's lair."It" is a story that does take some patience to get into after the initial hook, but afterward, you'll have trouble putting it down. The night I finished it for the first time, I was 200 pages from the end and it was already midnight, but I just had to keep going. I couldn't wait until morning. I had to read, see, feel... I had to know. Everything builds and builds, as well as giving off the love, excitement, and horror that abounds, and it doesn't let down. Every single event, be it touching, scary, or vulgar, is necessary to form the complete picture of what may be one of the greatest books you will ever read.-Escushion
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Will McCammon</user>
	<review>

After finishing IT for only the second time, I feel I must add my comments to those listed below. I found this book to be one of the greatest fiction books I have ever had the pleasure of curling up with for several weeks and  reading (any book that can have me go through the full range of emotions  over and over again and then get me to spend weeks reflecting on thoughts  from the last two paragraphs has to rank up there). SK has managed to write  the scariest novel I have ever read but also weave in multiple underlying  themes (Good vs Evil, racial discrimination, the reality of childhood as  seen through the eyes of a child - who can forget the schoolyard bullies?)  that kept me thinking the whole way through the book. Rather than bore you  with a long review - just read the book you'll be glad you did (although  due to the mature and sometimes inappropriate content of a number of  scenes, I don't recommend this book for anyone under 13/14). As a parting  comment, the book is best summed up by my dilema - Which is scarier:  Pennywise or the reality of what happens to us as we grow up and leave  childhood behind?
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gabor Lake</user>
	<review>

I was 12 years old when I was reading this book and, having a vivid imagination, it scared the hell out of me. I slept for weeks with lights on in my room and I always had a slightly bad feeling while going to the  toilet (read the book to know why)...I guess why this book captivated me  so much is that the heroes are children, young and not among the most  popular, smartest or strongest. Young boys and a girl you could yourself  identify with. They arent the most popular, strongest or smartest kids...  All are haunted because of their bad family situation, rough pupils, health  problems... And its those loners, finding together and finally confronting  a century-old evil force living in the Derry canalisation... An evil force,  IT, that the adults of Derry dont want to realize it exists...The books  is cleverly made, offering insight in the life of the main charcters both  as youngsters and adults, confronted again 20 years later by the evil they  thought they had destroyed in a memorable fight a long time ago...This  is the best Stephen King ever achieved.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Lexxi</user>
	<review>

I really enjoyed this book and have re read it over and over again despite it's lengths. I agree with many of the reviews in that it does get boring in the middle where King spends endless time talking about this and that about Derry which really makes you want to skip it and get back to the characters, who I thought were all interesting and well developed.This book really scared me, but I have cat's whiskers for nerves and I can't think of one King book that didn't scare me so perhaps I am not the most discriminating when it comes to what is scary?But my MAIN problem with this story was *SPOILER SPOILER* the last part of the book with the sex scene between the 11 year old children. And it wasn't even just regular sex, it was a gang bang with one girl having sex with 6 boys. How can an 11 year old girl take 6 boys on at once? I don't know grown women who can do that, and more to the point WHY DID STEPHEN KING PUT THAT IN THERE? It was justified as a way to bring everyone back together, but I honestly believe that there must have been some other way and I found myself feeling as though I was being molested by this scene because of the age of the children, and I am not shy about sexuality in literature. It just had no place.Also what was up with Bill getting to have his way with Bev when they became adults too? All the boys loved her, why was Bill chosen (and he already had a wife) and then RIGHT after Bev has sex with Bill she walks off with Ben...it just was tasteless.*end spoiler*Also there was never a real explanation of what It was or how the kids managed to hurt It. Everything just was. Nothing was explained as good as it should've been in the end.Other than that, the book was very good, like I said very well developed and even if you don't find it scary (which is hard for me to imagine) the story of friendship and childhood to adulthood will at least be interesting and intriguing and the book is hard to put down. I found myself in a lounge chair on hot summer days reading it for hours on end till the sun went down.An enjoyable read, just a lot of questions and questionable activities that never seeemed justified.
      </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bruce Rux</user>
	<review>

It's greatest curse is its length  -  the thing is worse than the Energizer Bunny, it just keeps going, and going, and going  -  and an ill-defined villain.  It also suffers from unbelievable (though admittedly appealing) characters, and stock King situations.The villainous "It" of the title is a God-Knows-What  -  an unexplained shapeshifting Something  -  that is inconsistent and incomprehensible, making it hard for the reader to get a handle on.  Its limitations are unclear, so the hapless band of heroes' eventual dispatch of the thing doesn't make much sense...or if it does, that sense isn't explained sufficiently for the reader to understand.In common with some of Dean Koontz's less believable efforts, King's characters in this piece suffer from Cinderella Syndrome  -  i.e., just how many people from one small, backward town can grow up to become nationally rich and famous?  One is a famous author, another a stand-up comedian who regularly appears on The Tonight Show, etc.  These kind of characters are manipulatively contrived to appeal to a Yuppie audience, and even they should have a hard time believing them.Despite these drawbacks, It is at least a good read.  The horror goes way over-the-top, far worse even than most of the author's efforts, but there are many very well-written individual scenes.  The characters are likeable and fully drawn, which goes a long way toward burying the book's other sins.  The plot is lengthy and involving, spanning generations, and as usual King's attention to detail is pretty thorough.Not the author's best, and not the best piece of his to start out on if you're a new reader.  But worthwhile if you're a fan, or just want to kill a lot of time in fairly enjoyable fashion.  (A LOT of time.)  The miniseries, if you're interested, is a faithful adaptation.
      </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ThePeoplesReviewer "Brad"</user>
	<review>

I feel that it is fair to warn anyone that is planning to invest their time in a book of this scope and magnitude that you may not be happy in the end. I have never written an online review before because usually when I read a great book most people already feel that its great and the existing reviews speak for themselves. However, as I was reading through these reviews, I could not believe how many 5 star ratings people gave. This is not nearly the masterpiece that it could have been and I think people deserve fair warning and a review that is more than: greatest book ever man! First off let me say this, I love horror stories, I am not easily offended, and I have read and enjoyed many other King books in the past. With that in mind, I started reading IT and was immediately absorbed into the tale.SO FIRST THE GOOD (EVEN GREAT):1) great buildup, some genuinely scary and disturbing scenes2) realistic character development and compelling characters in general3) IT is a very original, strange and frightening creature...most of the way through4) childhood events, friendships, conflicts, and experiences are realistically portrayed and sometimes even more frightening and tense than the encounters with the supernatural.5) Despite other peoples complaints with the length, I feel that it flowed nicely and the way the novel slowly revealed events of the past while building suspense in the present time was wonderfully done.SO WHY DID I GIVE THE BOOK 2 STARS? -- This book COMPLETELY falls apart in the last 100 pages or so. So much so that I had to shake my head and wonder if I was even reading the same book. I knew the ending would never live up to the buildup and I was willing to accept that, but what King came up with could not have been written any worse. When IT is revealed, the revelation is anti-climactic to say the least. Even then however, I still would have given the book 5 stars. What angered me to no end was the direction the book went from here. What was a scary foray into a world of creatures, nightmares, and psychological intrigue became a laughably bad mystical and celestial mess that changed the tone of the entire novel. Be warned, the final conflict and resolution is completely ridiculous and ruins what was a masterpiece of horror.PARTIAL SPOILERS (though they dont give away anything major, heres a little of what you are in for)1) a turtle god that barfed up our universe2) floating disembodied tongue the someone bites into 3) the deadlights (dont ask, it won't matter)4) a weak and pitiful IT that can simply not be the same cunning and dastardly creature from the first 3/4s of the novel (yet is)5)unsatisfying and weak explanation as to how IT is hurt (I understand what King was trying to do, but it doesnt come across well in the end)LASTLY: IF NONE OF THAT TURNED YOU OFF, PICTURE THIS: A group of six 11 year olds (yes, thats right 11!--all boys, 1 girl) are running around lost in some tunnels. And what is their solution for finding their why out?? Why, a group orgy of course. Im sorry, but even if it had something to do with the story line (which it doesn't) a scene like that is sick and uncalled for on so many levels. Beyond that, it makes no sense and is completely unrealistic after all the previous wonderful character development. Further, the scene is not even merely alluded to, it is specific and explicit bordering on child porn. Why that was included, I cannot begin to guess. It does make good evidence for my theory though: King HAD to have been on something when he wrote in the whole ending. Read if you must, but realize, I am not making any of this up. I sit here stunned and in disbelief as to how such a great novel could turn into such a train wreck. In an epic of this depth, a complete, sloppy letdown in the end is simply inexcusable.
      </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

I had never been a fan of Stephen King until I saw the film version of IT at age 10.  It effected me for months. Suddenly walking past a drain pipe became excruciatingly horrific.  One year later my brother bought the book  and I took it upon my 11-year-old shoulders to read it.  Being the same age  as the losers at the time I was intrigued.  While it is well over 1,000  pages long, I have read it about 6 times.  The time setting for the  childhood horrors couldn't have been better.  The innocence of the 50's  clashing with the evil living inside the drainpipes of quaint Derry, Maine.   I have never loved a book this much.  King does a great job of switching  from the respectable well-off grownups of the 80's to the strong children  of 1958.  On second viewing I hated the movie.  It did nothing but cheesily  retard the book.  It barely stuck to the storyline.  If you have some time,  definitely read this horrorfest.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>S. Wong</user>
	<review>

"It" is certainly one of Stephen King's most recognizable novels, if not the masterpiece on which his reputation rests.  Most are familiar with the basics of the story: an evil force haunts a small town in Maine that takes the form of one's worst fears (a clown, a spider, etc).  The book concerns a group of children who fight the monster (as children), and follows that confrontation, as well as the return of those children as adults to fight the monster upon its return years later.Taken as a light entertainment, "It" is more than successful.  King is effective enough at drawing his characters, and his famously twisted mind generates enough thrills in the horror passages to please readers.  While the novel's length can be intimidating at first, I appreciated the scope with which King draws the story, as he skillfully draws together the "Adults" plot and the "Children" plot in the book's final section.  A third section of "It", placed throughout the novel as effective intermissions, outline the history of the town (Derry) and the number of terrifying/horrible events that have taken place there over the years.  The strength of "It" is King's ability to use the book's length and scope as a means of enhancing the smaller details of his tale - it's easy to get enveloped by this world, and it's a wild ride.Those looking for a little more than entertainment, however, are sure to be disappointed.  Subtlety is not one of King's strong-suits, and the novel does not completely re-pay the time necessary to invest in the novel (1000+ pages).  At its worst, the book can feel formulaic, and weighed down by its structure, to the point where you feel that King is counting pages, so that a scene of "horror" occurs at least once every 30 pages.   For an imaginative tale to get lost in, "It" will certainly do the trick, but little of the book surpasses what is simply very well-executed entertainment.
      </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>M M "murphcleve"</user>
	<review>

I read this book when I was in college, probably around 1988.  Although I have read numerous books since, by many authors (Grisham, DeMille, Patterson, Cornwell, Clancy) and on various subjects, nothing has topped this masterpiece.  Few books stay with you like this one.  Not just because of the horror, but because of King's ability to make you feel like you are part of the group of seven main characters.  His detail is so astounding, you catch yourself wondering about these people as if they are real.  Normally, in a book with in excess of 1000 pages, you would expect some flat spots, but this book keeps you turning the pages all the way to the end.  I wasn't totally thrilled with the description of the creature at the end of the book, but in King's defense, in many of his books his writing is so brilliant, that no ending/villain/creature could possibly live up to the expectations created by the story.  I plan to read it again soon.  A comment on the TV miniseries:  Although it was entertaining, it does NOT do this book justice.  I would recommend this book to anybody...even those readers who are not fans of the horror genre.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>"koolio"</user>
	<review>

this was and is still the only stephen king novel I have ever read.  i have read it at least twice and plan on reading it again when time permits... it is a long book (over 1000 pages).it is the 1950s...the  book tells the story of a group of teens in derry, maine and their  horrifying experiences with an evil entity that lives off their city.  when  it seems the evil is put to rest, the teens part ways, grow up, and pursue  adulthood.  they have, however, vow to come back to finish the evil off if  IT is not really dead.enter the mid 1980s...  murders have started again  in derry.  IT has returned. the only teen who stayed behind in derry is now  a libarian.  he calls his friends back to finish the evil that is IT once  and for all.this book is absolutely amazing.  it makes for a very  enjoyable read.  the characters are so real, derry seems like it could  actually exist, and the horror comes on early and plenty. once I was  finished reading this book, it felt as if I had lived my life with these  people, experienced the terrors that they went through.  I was satisfied  emotionally and intellectually.  King's IT is a must read, if you like  horror or not.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>