<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sofiaraquel</user>
	<review>sorprendente y aún sigo sorprendiéndome: ¿cómo no la descubrí antes?</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>angievc</user>
	<review>A complete inspiration - caught my teenage imagination and changed the way I saw the world.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Dissidence</user>
	<review>In trying to make myself better read, I decided the best place to start was with some classics. It took me a little while to get into 1984, and I have to say it was immensely thrilling, disturbing and perhaps most worrying of all, almost believeable! I admit that in some instances I disliked Winston, but in the face of the Big Brother and Party regime, I desperately wanted him to prevail. It's been a while since I read this and I don't want to go into a detailed review and not do it justice. George Orwell's premise of double-think combined with the gullibility and devotion of the public was mind-boggling and frustrating. Upon finishing this book, I was entirely depressed, and yet grateful that the world had not gone this way - yet. The book also gave me some insight into the class divides relevant to our own reality. It made me a little pleased that I never really fit in at school! Just goes to show the power of the government, the media and of mass opinion. I'm glad I read it. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>theduckthief</user>
	<review>"The thought police would get him just the same. He had committed--would have committed, even if he had never set pen to paper--the essential crime that contained all others in itself. Thoughtcrime, they called it. Thoughtcrime was not a thing that could be concealed forever. You might dodge successfully for a while, even for years, but sooner or later they were bound to get you." Written in 1949, this book is George Orwell's imagining of a dystopian future where Big Brother is the ultimate control freak. Those in power, the Inner Party, control the actions in their own ranks and those of the the Outer Party who could also be termed the Middle Class. The world has split into three super governments. Oceania, Eurasia and Eastasia with a constant war brewing between one or the other. This book take place in Oceania and concerns one Winston Smith. We watch as he suffers through a life where a telescreen (read creepy camera surveillance) watches his every move and monitors his heartbeat and facial expressions for anything that could indicate he might be a dissident. People disappear every day in his life and everything is regulated. The Inner Party is even writing dictionaries to limit and dictate what people can talk about. Every subsequent dictionary is smaller, with fewer words because the party believes that by controlling words they can control thought. After all, if you never heard the word 'lemon' would you ever know what it was? What I liked was how accessible this book was even after almost 60 years. While some parts seemed quite archaic I found the piece quite modern and easy to read. The only place I was a little put off was the sentence "Winston's entrails seemed to grow cold." There was just something about that line that didn't work for me. The story moved along at a quick pace and then immediately got bogged down when Winston started reading "the book". Whether Orwell started to suffer from soapbox hysteria, spouting his own ideals and morals from his book, I don't know. What I do know is the story started to drag and I got bored with all the technical gobbledegook that didn't move the plot along. Orwell completely lost me at the end. It was as if the story had unraveled. When I reached part three I assumed the story would pick up again and quickly come to a conclusion. Things only became more confusing, especially where O'Brien was concerned. And Winston's transition at the end felt as if it was skimmed over. The very ending was a little surreal as well, though I don't know if it was meant to be. The first two thirds were amazing though and I would recommend the book just for that. The sad thing is that I really got into this book. I completely devoured it and in the end I was disappointed. I would almost recommend reading up to the point where Winston receives the book and then stop. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>marialluisa</user>
	<review>L'he llegit per tercera vegada, la última va ser el 1984. Crec que la novela es de total actualitat i encara diria que està superada! Em feia molta mandra llegir el què passa a l'habitació 101.L'adaptació teatral de Thim Robbins :  magnifica. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RichardRojas</user>
	<review>In George Orwell's 1984, Orwell depicts a future in which a "Big Brother" statewould control all of humanity. This future world is run by a god-like figure; "Big Brother". This figure is never seen in person however is feared by everyone. The telescreen is an object used to keep surveillence on all of society; not having any knowledge of when they will be watched.The novel represents the dangers of a totalitarian government. The corrupt society is living under constant war and restriction to travel. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Musyne</user>
	<review>Quel regard, quel message proposés par ce roman quasiment prophétique... Un roman d'anticipation formidable, qui fait froid dans le dos, et nous force à regarder l'Histoire, passée et contemporaine, d'une autre façon. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>theboylatham</user>
	<review>Eight out of ten.1984 is the year in which it happens. The world is divided into three great powers. Oceania, Eurasia, and Eastasia, each perpetually at war with the other. Throughout Oceania, 'The Party' rules by the agency of four ministries, whose power is absolute -- the Ministry of Peace, which deals with war, the Ministry of Love (headquarters of the dreaded Thought Police), which deals with law and order, the Ministry of Plenty, which deals in scarcities, and the Ministry of Truth which deals with propaganda. The authorities keep a check on every action, word, gesture or thought. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TinuvielDancing</user>
	<review>This is a book everyone should read, especially in these days of Patriot Acts and amorphous wars on terror. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BCR02Efan</user>
	<review>Der Klassiker für jeden Wahrheitssuchenden. Sollte als Warnung und Augenöffner gelesen werden. Viele Techniken, die wir heute zu Überwachungszwecken nutzen, waren Orwell seiner Zeit noch nicht bekannt. Orwell würde sich im Grab drehn, wenn er wüsste, wie die Welt heute ausschaut. Seine private Verbindung zur Fabian Society von Cecil Rhodes und Alfred Milner sind sicherlich kein Zufall gewesen. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BookshelfMonstrosity</user>
	<review>I find it very intimidating to review a well-known classic. I think since there is so much information on both the book and the author that I will just touch on a few of the concepts pervasive in the novel and, considering this is one of the daddies of dystopia, how the novel's presence has impacted literature as a whole.Big Brother is the ever-present leader of the party, staring at the citizens of Oceania wherever they go with the aide of...moreSee my full review posting here.I find it very intimidating to review a well-known classic. I think since there is so much information on both the book and the author that I will just touch on a few of the concepts pervasive in the novel and, considering this is one of the daddies of dystopia, how the novel's presence has impacted literature as a whole.Big Brother is the ever-present leader of the party, staring at the citizens of Oceania wherever they go with the aide of telescreens. Winston, an employee of the Ministry, isn't really sure if Big Brother actually exists or if he's really even an actual entity. The point Orwell is making here is that the party is always watching and has complete control over its citizens' bodies and minds. As party members go higher up in the ranks, vagueness ensues until one realizes that no one really knows who is ruling the country.One of the most disturbing examples of the Party's mind control, and there are many, is illustrated in the description of Winston's job. His role within the party as propaganda officer is to alter official government publications in order for them to fit with the Party's official version of how events really went down. The Thought Police are constantly vigilant, searching out dissenters of the Party. They monitor citizens to the point where having a dissenting thought against the party is against the law and punishable.Inevitably, Winston becomes one of these disillusioned dissenters,and he is arrested and tortured for it. During his interrogation, his captors explain to him that he will be re-integrated, or brainwashed, back into the Party.The influence of Orwell's 1984 is indeed extensive; how many times have you heard someone describe something as "Orwellian"? Anthony Burgess wrote 1985, which was intended to be a sequel to Orwell's original work. In more recent work, Cory Doctorow's Little Brother directly references 1984's Big Brother, and Doctorow's main character, Marcus Yellow, is a direct reference to Winston Smith.I recognize this book's extreme importance in the field of dystopian literature, and I found parts of it to be truly terrifying. However, parts of the novel, especially the segment in which Winston read entire chapters of the underground opposition party's manual, moved very slowly and were very dry. I'm glad I've read it but will probably not revisit it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Zommbie1</user>
	<review>The first time I read Nineteen Eighty-Four by George Orwell I was 17. I read it for my history class as an example of a totalitarian state. This time I am reading it for a Socio-Linguistics class.The main character in the book is Winston Smith. A 39 year old resident of London, Airstrip One, Oceania. This was once Great Britain but is now a totalitarian state made up of, in large, the English speaking world. Winston is a Outer Party member who works in an office job in the Ministry of Truth where he 'corrects' wrongs in printed material in line with the Party slogan "Who controls the past (...) controls the future: Who controls the present controls the past" (p37). Winston has dangerous thoughts of rebellion against the Party and its front figure, the mysterious Big Brother.The book is a frightening look at what could possibly happen in a world where everything is rigidly controlled by one entity, Big Brother. Big Brother plays the citizens off each other and themselves. Citizens are constantly watched through the ever present and turned on telescreen, through which the party can monitor the individuals and feed them propaganda. In addition to this the citizens are encouraged to inform on each other. Children are members of youth groups where they are taught to spy on their parents and each other and report any instances of unorthodoxy, so called thoughtcrime. Another facet of this dystopian society is the discouragement of sexual relations for other puposes than reproduction. The citizens live in constant fear of doing something that will get the reported to the Thought Police and taken away to the Ministry of Love (which really deals with torture).Winston shows an intellectual resistance to the ideas of Big Brother. Through his job he is exposed to the reality of the falsifying of information. He also has a memory of seeing proof that former members of the party could not have committed the crimes of which they were accused off. The books other important character is Julia, a young woman, whos rebellion against Big Brother is more physical. She has the apperance of the perfect Party member, but as Winston discovers, rebels in her own personal way. The books shows Winstons decent into full rebellion and what happens next.I would highly recommend that everyone reads this book at least once. I would actually say that everyone should read it every few years because there are so many layers to the book and as new things are learned and new events take place you see new things in the book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Psychless</user>
	<review>1984 depicts a dark world run by tyranny. I read it when I was thirteen, and it started my interest in politics.It really shows the "perfection" of the totalitarian government. There was no escape from it by the time it had fully asserted its authority.George Orwell really wrote a masterpiece of dystopian fiction, and I'd recommend it to anyone. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jjtyler</user>
	<review>You often hear 1984's lasting terms in today's society. Big Brother, a television show I've never watched but still an idea hatched from this book is one good example. Then there is The Satellite of Love, off of MST3K, a Satellite that has nothing to do with love but with scientific torture--a direct nod to the book's fictitious government buildings.A flag of the Ingsoc party as shown in and mov...Image via WikipediaThere are countless others, and to focus on the terms used in today's buzz worthy society would be exhausting: Thought Police, Double Speak, New Speak, etc. Not only does this book create an appropriate paranoid view of those in power, it's simply good. This book is a  masterpiece, no matter the message. The sentence structure of Orwell and his ability to use transparent, fluid language is astounding. It's almost distressing to read such work. How can one ever attain this magnitude of a story?Conspirators use this book often as a curb to excess government involvement in the public's life. It would be hard to say what Orwell thought about each group groping for quotes for their own advancement, but I think he said it best in the book, when he coupled socialism with its ugly cousin, fascism. I don't think Orwell was denouncing all socialism, but simply stating that it was a vehicle in which many could be abused.Minor spoiler ahead--one paragraph long:In reading 1984, I hoped that the story of Winston Smith would end well. I really did. But in hindsight, that would have lacerated the entire idea of the story's message, its warning. Orwell couldn't let us off with a rosy ending because he knew that this world he had created on page, Ingsoc, had no rosy ending. It's quite difficult seeing the character break down like he does, but it sheds the light on any romantic idea of resisting torture.The abuses of power almost seem comical at times. However they never leave the realm of possibility--it's not a parody of what can come but a frightful prediction.Favorite lines:"Socialism assumes that economic status is permanent.""The thing in room 101 is the most terrible thing in the world." </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lanewilkinson</user>
	<review>Hello! My name is '1984'. You probably remember me from that drunken political argument that you had at your friend's party last week-end. You know, when the discussion turned to the current election and the guy with the Converse All-Stars and messenger bag lamented how "Orwellian" the current administration is, and everyone nodded their heads because this guy seemed so astute, while you just stood there and thought to yourself, "Orwellian? That's all you can come up with?! Have you even read a book since you spent $3.95 on the '1984' Cliffs Notes for Mrs. Cliche's sophomore English class?"Yeah...that's me. But, I swear, I'm not just a hackneyed metaphor, I'm actually a really good read. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mindar</user>
	<review>Orwells' classic 1984 presents a chilling prospect for human society in the face of a totalitarian government and an ignorant populace.  With the language growing ever smaller, and the imagination growing ever weaker, people become less and less capable of free, independent thought, which is exactly what the government wants.  A small group of individuals, terrified to identify themselves, are still trying to stop the constant degradation of the human ability to think and reason, but perhaps it is too late, and no one, not even an independent thinker, can defeat Big Brother. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>crazybatcow</user>
	<review>It's a classic alright - bit too much talky talky, not quite enough action, but that could just be the frame of mind I'm in this month.Oh, it's horrible that "Big Brother" is so bad... or is it?  Do we really think the world isn't already like it's portrayed in this novel?  How would we know anyway?  Next time you think you're enjoying your McDonalds, or cut short a visit with a loved one so you can get home to watch your favorite show, think about just how much of your life isn't being controlled by outside forces.Sure, these forces aren't starving you to death, or making you rewrite books, but that's only because there's more money in selling you food and magazines and gossip about celebrities like it's a matter of life and death to know if Jon cheated on Kate.Don't believe the lies.  Big Brother has already gotten us. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>culturehandy</user>
	<review>Everyone needs to read this book to see how we are moving ever closer to living in a Big Brother world. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Awesomeness1</user>
	<review>A classic must-read. Orwell is brilliant. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>woodge</user>
	<review>Read in 10th grade for school.  Thought it was cool then, still think so now. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>schlimmbesserung</user>
	<review>The big daddy of dystopias. There's not much I can say that hasn't been said. Orwell was one prescient dude. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>datrappert</user>
	<review>I have probably read 1984 more times than any other book, and it never loses its fascination. In Junior High school, the oppressiveness of the police state (and the sex scenes) stood out, along with Newspeak, which was a lot of fun to play with when sending notes back and forth. Later on, the psychological and political aspects come more to the fore. I only wish Orwell had called it 2034 or 2084. It would be tragic if it falls off the required reading lists because someone thinks it is outdated. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>missravenx</user>
	<review>This is arguably one of the most frightening depictions of what our future could look like, once you get past the fact that it takes place in 1984. I have attempted to read this book several times but not being much interested in politics I always found it dull. I recently was inspired to read it again after watching The Zeitgeist Movie and found it much more compelling. Much of Zeitgeist appears to have been lifted straight out of 1984. But interestingly, while the totalitarian socialist world of 1984 comes about through communism, in Zeitgeist it is capitalism that leads us into socialism. After reading 1984 and watching Zeitgeist I have been left with an enormous amount to think about. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SendersName</user>
	<review>One of the most terrifying books ever written.  It has made me forever skeptical of government authority. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>HRawrgers</user>
	<review>I think it would have been cooler to read it before the year 1984 occurred. It would have been scarier reading it thinking that this actually could happen in 1984. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>melydia</user>
	<review>I've wanted to read this for a long time, but was never forced to in school and just didn't get around to it until now. It's an important book. Not only does it detail the dangers of totalitarianism, but also raises some really good questions about the nature of the past. Basically, if something happened in the past, and then all documentation was changed so that it appears to have not happened, and then everybody says it never happened, how can you be so sure you really remember it at all?A brilliant book, if a bit slow in places. It's driven much more by description of the dystopian land of Oceania than by character or plot. If you're interested in the inner workings of the socio-political landscape, you'll enjoy it. If you just want a fun little sci-fi romp, this probably isn't for you.All the same, I think it's a book people should read. The world of 1984 may seem overdramatic, but it is one plausible outcome of the gradual sacrifice of privacy and property in favor of governmental protection or the nebulous "common good." It's something worth thinking about. Indeed, that is perhaps this book's strongest point: it left me with an unusually large number of things to think about. That, my friends, is truly high praise for a novel.[Note: Star Trek: The Next Generation totally ripped off this book in the episode "Chain of Command" with the five/four lights thing. But Picard was a whole lot more badass under pressure than Winston, so they get points for that.] </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>phette23</user>
	<review>love the varieties of language and how much more thorough this dystopia is than others of its ilk ("We" specifically, haven't actually read "Brave New World" yet). Newspeak is a cool idea, and the emotions of the characters are pretty powerful throughout the second half. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pru-lennon</user>
	<review>when i first read this book, i loathed it. there's a section where winston (the main character) is reading a book and i found that part rather dry. i was inspired to read it again from a friend and i am so glad i did! there are some truly great scenes in this book which i won't write out for fear of giving things away. all i have to say is more than a few times, i felt my heartbeat quicken at crucial parts in the book. it's worth reading and worth considering what any society's future could turn into if the love of power outweighs everything else. in a place where you are never truly alone, not even with your thoughts, where even the language is changed to control your thoughts or ability to think outside the box and you're surround by perpetual war and less than stellar living conditions, what becomes of your humanity? i think orwell paints a thought-provoking, mind-blowing, soul-stirring picture of the possibilities. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DyanLZBB</user>
	<review>De verdad que este Libro es uno de esos que todos tenemos que leer, magistralmente contada la historia, una critica a la sociedad, al gobierno y a la evolucion.es impresionante como cada dia se va convirtiendo en una realidad tangible, eso de la reducción del lenguaje me sorprendió ya que precisamente los mensajes en Messenger y por celular están creando eso que describe Orwell en su libro.Debo decir que al final me dejó con el corazon "apachurrado" porque no supe si reir o llorar... pensar que la esperanza y la voluntad se pueden subyugar de forma tan total me dejo pensando verdaderamente.Ojalá pudieramos leer este libro y comprender a fondo su mensaje, entender su visión futurista y darnos cuenta que se convirtió en el aqui y ahora de nuestro mundo. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>msafarik</user>
	<review>Though the date 1984 has passed us by, no one who has ever read Orwell’s novel 1984 can deny the lasting and often accurate impressions it predicts about our world today. The novel centers around a character named Winston Smith, an employee for the Ministry of Truth. The Ministry of Truth is only one of group of government branches dedicated to keeping their dictatorship stable. By erasing the past through elimination and tampering with evidence, The Party (the government) in turn controls any desire for the public to disagree with the society. The story begins with Winton having doubting thoughts of the party, though never expressing them out loud for fear of death. The plot begins to thicken when he meets a woman named Julia, and together they stand up against the party in their own way. 	1984 has to be one of the most magnificently written books I have ever read. Orwell’s diction and imagination is beyond the vast majority of authors present in our culture. Even being written more than half a century ago, Orwell’s message is as clear as the first day he wrote it. In our class, we are currently studying utopias and dystopias. There could not be a more perfect book to fall into this genre than 1984. In fact, 1984 may very well be the king of this genre, combining all other points and opinions about a dystopia and combining them into one cohesive, skin-crawlingly realistic masterpiece. The world of Winston Smith is one of never ending oppression, where the individual soul and personality is not only discouraged, but mercilessly snuffed out. If it was not clearly stated earlier, this was one of the best books I have ever read. I would recommend it to anyone who actually wants to think about what their reading. No, this isn’t a Stephanie Meyer “comfort food book” which, while perhaps filling you up, will leave you utterly less wise by the end. No, this is a book that you can read once, twice, and then one hundred more times and still have material to try and wrap your brain around. It is a masterpiece, and its prestige is rightfully earned. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jwhenderson</user>
	<review>I first read this book when I was in high school and found it riveting.  Orwell's vision of the use of language to control the populace is brilliant.  As a result of reading this and Animal Farm I becam a lifelong devotee of Orwell the writer. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>15felfelima</user>
	<review>This is an interesting book that makes you think about life and how you would like the world if you weere in this book. It also has some romance, action, and rebelling. Overall I liked this book. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>funsize0</user>
	<review>The book 1984 is a book about the future. It is about a dystopian world all about hate. Winston Smith is the main character who falls in love with a girl named Julia. He also breaks a lot of rules and is then punished... It was written in 1949 so it has older words and phrases things differently. It stays on one idea for like a chapter at a time, and i think it is terrible. It was very very very boring. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>madforbooks</user>
	<review>This book hardly needs a review, I know of no one who has never read it! However, just in case there is even one person considering whether to take it up or not, here goes...This is a must read. Read it and you will know why. It will not be a pleasant experience. I read the book during my jr year of high school. I was in my boyfriend's car when I finished it and even though the car was moving, the ending so horrified me that I threw the book out of the window! We had to stop the car and go back for it as the book belonged to the school. If freedom means anything to you, stop what you are doing now and get this book. You will not regret it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rzalegowski</user>
	<review>Winston Smith lives in a world where there is no freedom of speech, mind, or press. Everywhere he looks there is a telescreen mounted on the wall, through which Big Brother, the ever powerful leader of Oceania, monitors his every move and emotion. “The Party”, of which Big Brother is the dictator, is the ultimate controller in the society in which Winston lives. The Party controls the past by erasing any history books and the future by rewriting old newspapers.  It is treasonous to even think anything against The Party or discuss The Party in anyway. 	The novel 1984 by George Orwell follows Winston in the year 1984 as he attempts to defy the laws of Big Brother. Winston, does not agree with the way he is forced to live under the rigid oppression of the party, living not as an individual, but a product of Big Brother.  He does not voice his opinions for fear of being killed by the “Thought Police. When Winston meets Julia, a young girl who works in Winston’s department, his hatred for the party only increases. Julia is a young, perhaps foolish, optimist concerned with having fun and defying the laws of Big Brother in any way possible. Together, Winston and Julia embark on a journey in the hopes of disobeying The Party without getting caught. 	Similar to the novel Brave New World by Aldous Huxley, 1984 gives readers a glimpse of a dystopia disguised as a utopia. Written in 1949, 1984 describes what readers are supposed to believe to be a perfect world. However, readers soon realize that the world depicted in the novel is far from perfect. Like in Brave New World, citizens of society have no freedom. They have become nothing more than identity-less, thoughtless drones, controlled by The Party. In his novel, Orwell warns us of the dangers of attempting to create a perfect society.  In attempting to achieve a perfect society through a totalitarianism government, people have lost all identity and freedom to think. 	Because I read Huxley’s Brave New World and Orwell’s 1984 simultaneously, I often found myself mixing up the two novels, as both share many common themes and characters. Both books describe societies in which the government is the ultimate ruler of society, and also the antagonist in the novel.	1984 is a good length, not too long or short, so the story moves quickly but still includes a fair amount of detail. I enjoyed the third person point of view in this novel as it allowed me to get to know one character in depth (Winston), and figure out the thoughts of other main characters (Julia) based on clues in the book. 	I would recommend 1984 to anyone who enjoyed Brave New World and reading about a frighteningly utopian society. I give this book four and a half stars out of five because of its ability to warn the readers about the dangers of creating an unattainable perfect society. This novel will make everyone glad that our world is not perfect, as the world in 1984 pretends to be, and that we are able to think and talk as we please. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Luiise</user>
	<review>HATE HATE HATE THIS BOOK...I CAN'T STAND GEORGE ORWEL..SORRY </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>laBradipo</user>
	<review>E' importante avere gli occhi spalancati, accorgersi di come va il mondo intorno, riuscire a capire se si ha davvero la libertà che si crede di possedere. Leggere un libro come questo fa riflettere sull'importanza di non abituarsi alle situazioni e al sistema che viene imposto, fa pensare a come siamo messi noi, se davvero siamo liberi. Un bel libro davvero. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Pestpruf</user>
	<review>http://writatlarge.blogspot.com/2009/... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brokensnowpea</user>
	<review>This novel is more important than ever. The themes and issues are real and visceral. Highly recommended for all. I include this book in my junior college preparatory course. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cobra1</user>
	<review>Very realistic account of how an entire population can become 'controlled' by a government bent on having total power.  It is all plausible and possible, even in this day  - all that's needed is the right political environment, the right politicians with such a 'vision' to become and remain 'all powerful' and a nation of people who are satisfied with the 'status quo', who won't see the signs of such a gradual taking over of their very basic freedoms....(it can never happen here....) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kjarcand</user>
	<review>I'm glad I finally took the time to read this classic. While I was rather disappointed with the ending, I found it to be pretty true to how humans really react to dramatic situations out of fear, ignorance, and self-preservation. The story read quickly and was for the most part engaging. The Thought Police are incredibly terrifying. How is one to control their subconscious? Just thinking about it makes me shiver </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>PureImagination</user>
	<review>Winston Smith vaguely remembers what the world was like before. Before the revolution, before the Thought Police, before Big Brother. But he can't remember if it was better.I wanted to read this book because its a classic. No bookshelf is complete without it. What I was surprised to find is that I really liked it. Sure, I knew I would like it. It's a classic for a reason but I really enjoyed it. I thought it would be hard to get through and reading it would take a lot of effort on my part. I was wrong.I'm not going to get into the plot very much. It's one of those books you just have to read. It's a story about the horror of human nature. The horror of man's obsession with power. This book was written in 1949. I can understand what an impact it must have had then. With Hitler and WWII still fresh in everyone's minds. Even in the 50's it might have seemed possible that something like this could happen. In today's day and age its not even feasible but it makes you thankful for the world we live in and the privileges we take for granted.I highly recommend 1984 if you haven't read it already. Like I said no shelf is complete without it.http://www.pureimaginationblog.com/ </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tsarstepan</user>
	<review>The single greatest work of written English. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>scarletwitch</user>
	<review>I've been meaning to read this book forever, and I'm sad to say that I didn't enjoy it as much as I thought I would. The writing was very dry and repetitive, though the subject matter was interesting.  At least now I'll get all of the big brother references. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KateForBooks</user>
	<review>Iconic.  Recommended to anyone living in the current world! The similarities with what's happening now is eery and discomforting. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zasmine</user>
	<review>Read after Brave new world </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Steve777</user>
	<review>Chilling. Uncomfortable reminiscent in many ways of where we are heading in our own culture. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DarrenElliott</user>
	<review>This is the story of a terrible world where men are not even free to think their own thoughts.I first read this book as a high school student, and it has always been one of my favourites. It was written more than sixty years ago as a warning, and some people say that its predictions about personal freedom are coming true - for example, nowadays there are security cameras watching us everywhere we go.It is a dark book, with complex ideas, and for this reason I can't recommend it to everyone. But if you like a book which makes you think, and makes you scared, then you might find it interesting. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kahlee2000</user>
	<review>http://thebookwormslibrary.com/?p=772... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ninefivepeak</user>
	<review>Why in the world did Orwell fail to anticipate a camera that didn't also have a big screen attached to it?  He correctly anticipated listening devices that could be hidden anywhere, but a simple video camera seems to have escaped him.  Other than little nits like that, it's a chilling portrayal of what can happen in a centrally controlled society.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AuntieClio</user>
	<review>Orwell's frightening vision of the future isn't so futuristic anymore.  Big Brother really is everywhere.  I wonder if he would take comfort from knowing he was right all along. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rogue3w</user>
	<review>I struggled five times to read this book over many years. There is a certain hurdle at the start where the story struggles to lift off (for me). It's certainly worth soldiering on because it is a fantastic story. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nycbookgirl</user>
	<review>Ok. To sum it up: it was good...wish I had read it back in high school. But I still prefer Aldous Huxley's Brave New World to 1984. Not so much because of the story...but because of the writing. I remember why I petered out at reading 1984 past the first few chapters...I still think those chapters are pretty dry. Stick with it though and it gets better. I do think that 1984 is more futuristically realistic than Brave New World...well, now with genetics stuff going on who knows. But I really liked the relationship between Winston and Julia. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>j_aroche</user>
	<review>mostly perturbing reading, we must ensure never get this reached </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>denis.willians</user>
	<review>Winston, herói de 1984, último romance de George Orwell, vive aprisionado na engrenagem totalitária de uma sociedade completamente dominada pelo Estado, onde tudo é feito coletivamente, mas cada qual vive sozinho. Ninguém escapa à vigilância do Grande Irmão, a mais famosa personificação literária de um poder cínico e cruel ao infinito, além de vazio de sentido histórico. De fato, a ideologia do Partido dominante em Oceânia não visa nada de coisa alguma para ninguém, no presente ou no futuro. O’Brien, hierarca do Partido, é quem explica a Winston que 'só nos interessa o poder em si. Nem riqueza, nem luxo, nem vida longa, nem felicidade - só o poder pelo poder, poder puro.'</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>laurab_53</user>
	<review>Amazing, eye opening book! Really gives you a different perspective of the government and how bad things really could be. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mieux</user>
	<review>Like most people here, I read this book for high school. Or rather, I stole a copy out of the lost and found freshman year, only to find that it would be assigned later on in my senior year. I love this book and I own both an english and french edition. As it stands, 1984 is such a significant literary piece that anyone who has not read it will find themselves missing out on a good many sayings which have worked their way into popular culture! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nebowers</user>
	<review>A story of the still-possible future that will make you both grateful for and fearful for the world you live in. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sszkutak</user>
	<review>I always wanted to read 1984, I had heard great things about it. So when I finally had a class that required it to be read I was excited. Sadly I didn't feel this way once I finished it. After all of the wonderful reviews I had heard over the years, I was disappointed. I wasn't looking for a spectacular happy ending but then ending definitely fell short. Aside from the disappointing ending, the story was not that bad. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gesigewigus</user>
	<review>It's surprising, I'll admit, it took me this long to get around to reading this book. I have my father's old copy he bought just before I was born (at the end of 1984) which I thought made an interesting personal touch to this copy of the book. Nineteen Eighty-Four is a novel about a negative Utopian "future" (at the time of writing), focusing on a nation state that is controlled by the government to a degree that is pretty much unfathomable to most people. It explores this world through Smith, a man with growing degrees of hatred for Big Brother and the government state he represents. The book paints a very disturbing and bleak picture for a future controlled by government and big businesses. It is interesting to see Orwell's proposed mental state of most people in this future, and the relationship of truth and language. I really did enjoy the book, even though I was surprised at how much some scenes bothered me. I feel I should tongue-in-cheek just say the book was doubleplusgood, and leave it at that. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wlchui</user>
	<review>Not Read</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kbellwether</user>
	<review>I can't really say I liked it, but it was a fascinating  terrifying distopian vision.  I actually had to put this down for about a month, when I was about 3/4 of the way through.  I actually skipped to the end and read the last couple of lines (which I've only done 4 or 5 times in my life), which were not a big surprise (I think I must have heard plenty of references to the ending over the years and it's almost inevitable that it could only end one or two possible ways) and I wasn't sure if I really wanted to see how Winston was going to get to that last line.  But I have to think a book isn't worth my time to be able to not finish it, and 1984 was very obviously worth my time. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ashleeisrad</user>
	<review>A must read classic that will make you thankful for democracy and open your eyes to the power a government can acquire. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lhicks5</user>
	<review>I really enjoyed this book. I'm happy that after years of knowing about this novel I finally got a chance to read it. This book would be a great tool for combining history/social studies with literature and opening up discussion about how the novel may reflect what is happening in today's world. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>vaughnslawns</user>
	<review>Orwell is a bit of an acquired taste, but I have to say that give the day and time- this book is spooky. How could he have known things would progress to what they are now? Government reading emails, listening to our calls and who knows what else-1984 is a Scifi that rings a little too true sometimes. The thing that always makes me so sad is that there is this feeling of no end in sight no matter what my come and the over whelming sense of loss. You just can't figure out where to direct all your emotions for the main characters, you do however start to cheer for the love that you thought was impossible.Great read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LarryWampler</user>
	<review>I read this book during the summer between the seventh and eighth grades, after seeing that it had been banned -- along with Catcher in the Rye -- from a community library.  Being a curious lad, I naturally wanted to see what all the fuss was about.  So I ordered both books from the Oregon State Library.  (This was a great service for a kid living out in the sticks; they even paid the postage both ways!)  It was my first experience of subversive literature, starting a lifelong habit.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Luxx</user>
	<review>1984 is one of those novels I have intended to read for years, and had never gotten around to. However, I finally managed to get to it, for better or for worse. Orwell's dystopian novel has left me feeling rather prosaic, and I'm not quite sure how to express my feelings regarding the text. In the simplest terms, I didn't like the novel; but I don't think I was supposed to. And I certainly don't regret taking the time to read it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rebeccareid</user>
	<review>As the story progressed, I became more and more horrified and uncomfortable. And that is, I think, Orwell’s purpose. 1984 is not meant to be a comfortable book.Winston Smith lives in a 1984 much different than the 1984 we really lived in. In his society, IngSoc (English Socialism) is the prevailing way of life and Big Brother is always watching for deviations from acceptable behavior via “telescreens.” There is little privacy and no freedoms. Your life is only lived for the party’s needs.Orwell indicated that 1984 was meant as an extreme example of the dangers of perverse totalitarianism. While 1984 had some flaws, it was still a chilling reminder of what “totalitarian” means.  In the end, Winston was forced in to a sort of insane half-life: a life in which he could never have any personal convictions.I hated the ending, I hated the forced betrayal, and I hated the government of Big Brother. And I think that’s the point.More detailed review on my blog</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mohi</user>
	<review>A true modern classic. A chilling look into a bleak future that is all too achievable. The section on Newspeak (the language used by the regime of 1984) was particularly breath taking. Even today, we can see how our own language is being shaped in order to mold our way of thinking. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CatyM</user>
	<review>I've been getting round to reading 1984 since about 1984. Okay, slight exaggeration. Since about 1994. It's one of those books that you feel you know, even if you haven't read it, because the concepts and terminology are so much a part of popular culture and consciousness - so when I finally did read it I wasn't surprised to find that there were no surprises.Orwell's portrayal of the mechanics of totalitarianism is masterly, and, particularly regarding the way the media was and continues to be used by governments, creepily so. Sixty years after it was written, it's plausible enough to be disconcerting, even frightening. It is a work of genius, although I couldn't help thinking it needed a little more oomph or action or something in places to be as great a novel as it is political statement and cultural icon.4½ out of 5(And I admit to chuckling at the statement "THE AUTHORITATIVE TEXT" at the foot of the blurb on this Penguin Modern Classics edition. Oh, the irony.) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>blondierocket</user>
	<review>A futuristic tale of what the world is like in 1984 with Big Brother watching and people getting arrested for just thinking something bad and/or going against Big Brother.After finishing it made me very glad that I was not born in the 1984 represented in this book, where children were often taken from their parents and raised in a group home to think pure and live a pure and unquestioning lifestyle to a very extreme sense.The idea that “Big Brother” decides that books and newspapers need to be changed based their beliefs seems so unreal but very futuristic. That with a click of a button history changes to the point where people don’t even remember what day it is or what even really happened in the history books before they were changed. Dictionaries were wittled down to a handful of words that could be used to describe everything, therefore elimitating all elements of impure thoughts and deeds from peoples minds because there is just no word for it.It’s always interesting reading futuristic stories and seeing how different the world really is. In movie form, this would be 2001: A Space Odyssey. While “newspeak” now isn’t how Orwell describes, we still have our own form. Like one review on Amazon says, we have our own version of shorthand with texting abreviations like LOL, L8R, etc. It is nearly the same thing and transforming kids using it, changing their form of dictionary into one that is not recognizable to the older generations.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wertygol</user>
	<review>La mejor y peor novela de Ciencia Ficción. La mejor, porque difícil es imaginar una mejor manera de contar lo que cuenta esta novela. La peor, porque este libro tiene de ciencia ficción poco, y es tan revelador frente a la gran mierda que es la humanidad que nadie sale indemne después de leerlo. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wikiro</user>
	<review>I like this book in the light of fiction.  Its a good story. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Fluffyblue</user>
	<review>Fantastic book - I'm not particularly a fan of dystopian novels, but having just read Animal Farm, and been challenged to read Nineteen Eighty-Four sometime this year, I thought I'd give it a whirl.Having seen the film fairly recently, I felt the book was far, far superior.  It is frightening to imagine that Orwell wrote this in something like 1949 because although some of it has dated, it really does seem to be set in the dystopian society that so many futuristic, post-apocolyptic world written about by so many authors.  If you've never read this book, then you should - you're missing a real gem of fiction. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>boweraj</user>
	<review>Amazing book! I was lucky to have been forced to read it in grade school. I hope that everyone else is forced into it as well. Recommended for all especially anyone who likes even a little SF. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brayzinski</user>
	<review>Can you say "George W. Bush Administration"? Phenomenal book and it's creepy how dead on about government deceiving it's people. Look at countries such as North Korea, the former Soviet Union and the good old U.S.A.! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ebba</user>
	<review>First time reading this classic book.  It could have been a better rating if it had not been for the quite boring part about "The Book".  The ending was also disappointing to me.  Very interesting read and well worth my time </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>samantha.digard</user>
	<review>I know that this is a classic but I just could not get into it. The entire time I was reading I kept thinking, “When are we going to get to the action part of the book?” I felt like Orwell was just describing what it was like and there was no action, no real storyline. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>reverends</user>
	<review>'He who controls the past controls the future. He who controls the present controls the past.'My definition of a truly classic novel is one that is so talked about and referenced that you can know all about the book and it's message without having ever actually read it. 1984 is one of the most glaring examples of this, as terms such as 'Big Brother' and 'Doublespeak' are now mainstream concepts that no longer require explanation.The book itself gained its popularity, however, by successfully reaching a broad audience through exaggerating and reducing the complicated debate of the illusion of free will and freedom of thought in any kind of government structure that strives to control and manipulate the populace for its own benefit in an almost unbelievable science fiction setting. The extremes that are reached in 1984 may seem only possible in a work of fiction (or, as the work is seldom referred to these days, Science Fiction), yet there is a truth beneath the pulp novel trappings that most readers can not avoid recognizing.For those who have already read this, I have a suggestion. Read 1984 again, only assume that the book actually takes place in our modern times, and that the narrator is a paranoid schizophrenic.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Paal</user>
	<review>This book has become a classic among dystopias.George Orwell wanted with his experience from The Spanish Civil War to warn us against totalitarian regimes like USSR.It is no coincidence that it was forbidden in most countries where free speech and thought were a dream.One could imagine a Big Brother with a moustache like Stalin brainwashing and controlling innocent citizens.Orwell made us aware as he wanted of those totalitarian worlds oppressing humans. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BookMarkMe</user>
	<review>My best dystopia novel. Despairing yet utterly believable </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>monapropertygirl</user>
	<review>A fantastic dark cautionary tale that just had me turning page after page. I've never devoured a book like this so fast! And I must confess that the end had me in tears. Perhaps I'm weak-willed or too easily affected by this sort of thing, but the rebel in me gave a disappointed whimper, consumed by hopelessness, as I read the final words. Thoroughly haunting, and demands to be read again and again. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>iceT</user>
	<review>My all-time favorite dystopian novel, and a great cautionary tale. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kellyhatter</user>
	<review>Probably my favorite book of all time.  Not many 7th graders would attempt it, but this one did.  And, even though I didn't completely understand it then, I have re-read it multiple times and it never gets old.  Good movie too. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cowpeace</user>
	<review>Blurp: Orwells roman 1984 is een klassiek geworden 'anti-utopie'. Het boek was door Orwell bedoeld als een waarschuwing tegen élk totalitair systeem dat zich, onder welke vermomming dan ook, opstelt als bedreiging van de vrijheid. In 1984 heeft een systeem van lugubere perfectie greep op de wereld gekregen, De Partij beheerst de ziel van de mens en dus het hele mechanisme van liefde en haat. Als Winston Smith, ambtenaar aan het ministerie van Waarheid te Londen, verliefd wordt, is zijn lot bezegeld. Vóór het verlossende nekschot zal hij met overtuiging zijn menselijke gevoelens verloochenen en ook vervuld raken van grenzeloze liefde voor de leider, Grote Broer. Dit wereldberoemde, steeds weer herdrukte meesterwerk van George Orwell blijft door zijn literaire overtuigingskracht en zijn heldere argumentering een onovertroffen waarschuwing. - Het blijft in de meest letterlijke zin van het woord een integer mens. - Stephen Spender in Encounter. - Toekomstmogelijkheden van een zo huiveringwekkende overtuigingskracht, dat het als een nachtmerrie in de geest van de lezer blijft voortleven. - Vrij Nederland.Samenv.: Visioenen van de westerse wereld anno 1984, waarin de enkeling ten onder gaat in een volkomen kansloze strijd tegen "de Partij" die met de meest barbaarse middelen de mens dwingt tot "vrijwillige" aanvaarding van een levens- en wereldbeschouwing, die zelfs de meest elementaire menselijke waarden vernietigt. Een klassieke roman in een vlotte vertaling en met tekeningen van Peter Vos.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cowpeace</user>
	<review>Samenv.: Visioenen van de westerse wereld anno 1984, waarin de enkeling ten onder gaat in een volkomen kansloze strijd tegen "de Partij" die met de meest barbaarse middelen de mens dwingt tot "vrijwillige" aanvaarding van een levens- en wereldbeschouwing, die zelfs de meest elementaire menselijke waarden vernietigt.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ani_Na</user>
	<review>This is one of those books you have to read more for its content than its plot or narrative style. The influence of 1984 on our language, politics, and pop culture is hard to overstate. Just for that reason alone, I'd recommend reading it. The plot isn't terribly compelling - contrast the powerful torture scene to the middling romance - and the characters pretty dull (predictably sexist, but not egregious) but the style? Orwell is a fantastic writer, and his twisting of language overwhelming in its insight and power. His warnings seem to progressively come true, sadly. I'd recommend reading this alongside his brilliant essay, "Politics and the English Language". </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mwhel</user>
	<review>I'm reading this book for the second time after many years.  I'm struck by how the tone of the book, and Winston's world, changes from dreary and monochromatic  to exciting and somewhat hopeful after meeting Julia.  Coincidentally I read this morning about Winston and Julia's first real encounter on May 2nd of whatever that year was.  Today is May 2nd!  Maybe it's an omen.  Overall though I'm getting the strong impression of anti-socialist, anti-communist propaganda, McCarthyism,  scare tactics and fear mongering.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BaileysAndBooks</user>
	<review>Even if you read it in high school, this is one you should take the time to read again </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LTJinja</user>
	<review>Despite the Sapir–Whorf hypothesis proven probably-wrong, still a great read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Shannan79</user>
	<review>I would like to say I found this book very disturbing yet interesting. Imagine the government controlling and monitoring everything you say or do. Telling you how you should eat and how you should dress. All this seemed to consume Winston Smith's mind. Every action he did made him wonder if the big brother(Government) was watching him.All this changed when he met a woman named Julia who eventually becomes his lover. She is the symbol of rebellion against the government(Party). She is everything that Big Brother aims to destroy.This book had me thinking about communism and how it would be if communism would have came to the USA. It is scary to think how the government could have that much power. This book is also a psychological thriller in which it makes you think and messes with you head.Some memorable sayings or quotes from the novel that make you think:BIG BROTHER IS WATCHING YOU how would you feel if the government is monitoring everything you do your right to privacy is violatedWAR IS PEACE is war really peace or is it a ploy for overall control.FREEDOM IS SLAVERY are really slaves to the government, are we truly freeIGNORANCE IS STRENGTH while keeping the outsiders of the government ignorant the government keeps its power.Its amazing how some of these says make you think today and how this book is still relevant to human fears today. The fear of communism and socialism.Overall I enjoyed this book and its one my favorites and I would reread it again. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bfertig</user>
	<review>This review has been reviewed by the Ministry of Information and subsequently deleted by Big Brother on June 23, 2009. The current review has been approved for your perusal. Big Brother is watching you. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>06nwingert</user>
	<review>George Orwell's take on what 1984 would have been like is eerily reminiscent of what 2009 actually is. Big Brother, euphemisms, and double-speak have similar current counterparts, such as warrentless wiretapping.  Orwell's bleak outlook for society isn't subtle, but that's what makes the book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lumber</user>
	<review>"If you want a picture of the future, imagine a boot stamping on a human face - forever." ~George OrwellThe future has been replaced with the past: "From the table drawer he took out a penholder, a bottle of ink, and a thick, quarto-sized blank book with a red back and a marbled cover...it was a peculiarly beautiful book. Its smooth creamy paper, a little yellowed by age, was a kind that had not been manufactured for a least forty years past." p.9 </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tid</user>
	<review>It may or may not be "generally known" that 1984 was intended by its author to be a code for 1948, and that the world portrayed therein was a thickly disguised attack on the neo-Socialist state that was Great Britain in that post-war year. Political dogma, the plethora of rules and regulations encountered at every turn, "organised" fun in the shape of Butlins Holiday Camps - these were the real targets of Orwell's cynical and bleak view.Of course, Big Brother has come about too in some respects, and not merely as a reference point in Apple Computers' famous 1984 Macintosh ad. We now have a TV show of the same name, and what is that other than a way to "amuse the proles"? Newspeak too, is with us, in a world where not only politicians (though they are by far the worst offenders), but football club owners and managers, representatives of bodies ranging from local authorities, health services, and large companies, talk in heavily guarded clichés and platitudes serving to disguise the real truth behind what they say. Even Room 101 has passed into common - and TV show - parlance.Of course, Orwell missed the mark in one major respect. Governments are too often too hopelessly disorganised to achieve the blitzkrieg oppression featured in 1984 : most politicians are too aware of elections to say or do anything remotely interesting, dynamic, or radical. What was sauce for Stalin's goose is not sauce for Western governments whose leaders are trying to avoid 4-yearly wipe-outs.Yet, when I read this book, as a schoolchild in a liberal democracy during a liberal era, I was spooked and frightened by its 'control freak' dystopian vision, and the memory of its nightmarish scenario. I missed - we most of us missed - its bitter satire and its real historical target, but it remains a monument to the deeply cynical, political disillusionment of its author. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FeegleFan2</user>
	<review>The ending was kinda lame, but apart from that, I liked it a lot. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>PeskyLibrary</user>
	<review>Love, loyalty, thought, and truth; these are the themes of 1984 by George Orwell. This novel, based in a future of global superpowers and oppression, is a book that touches on a political and personal future that is disturbing and is still relevant today. The concepts that Orwell puts forth have leaked into modern politics. Following the main character, Winston Smith, the readers sees these. One is the idea of Big Brother, who is the leader of Oceania. Big Brother is depicted as a person, but he is actually an idea; he represents the power of a government that is not run by one person, but the whole of the Inner Party.This book is very interesting and thought provoking. A fast read that, with the balanced mix of politics and personality, is appealing to a wide range of readers. SS</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lobarl2009</user>
	<review>This is one of the best books I have ever read. Even though the mood throughout the story is pretty gray, it keeps you reading. Also, the thought that total human control by a few chosen people is frightening. You should definately read this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>basvat</user>
	<review>Shocking book, don't read it when depressed. It makes you wonder which technologies are now in real life use </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Indy_115</user>
	<review>Orwell depicts a vivid portrayal of the ills of a totalitarian regime even the consequences of government overreach in general. His society is the most extreme one imaginable created by a government with absolute power. This is one of my favorite books. With the current state of our country (wire-tapping, cameras on every corner, thought crimes, mindless daily routine....ect.) make this book more significant than ever. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bitra</user>
	<review>Living in a totalitarian country would be my last option. And I'm sure it would be yours too after reading Orwell's Nineteen Eighty-Four. As far as I know, this is the ex-BBC journalist's best novel. Having humanity as a part of yourself is the most important thing. Especially when you finally realized that it is being taken away from you by an [b:absolute power|15159|Absolute Power|David Baldacci|http://photo.goodreads.com/books/1166671032s/15159.jpg|2837]. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ramirez</user>
	<review>My favourite book.Claustrophobic, powerful, essential, painful; a great lesson on the power of memory and language. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Prueni</user>
	<review>Dieses Buch ist ein oft zitierter Klassiker, auf den selbst in politischen Debatten des Öfteren angespielt wird. 1984 beschäftigt sich vor allem mit politischen Themen, wie Diktatur, persönlichen Freiheiten, Nationalsozialismus, geschichtlicher Manipulation, dem Einfluss des Staates auf Medien, Zensur, ständige Überwachung und Eingriffen in die Privatsphäre. Selbst in der heutigen Zeit haben diese Themen noch eine hohe Aktualität und vor allem die Diskussionen über Datenschutz und justizlich genehmigte Überwachung greifen auf den so genannten „gläsernen Menschen' zurück.Im Mittelpunkt von 1984 steht das Mitglied der inneren Partei Winston, ein Mann Mitte dreißig. Es ist eine düstere Welt in die uns George Orwell hier entführt. Eine Welt ohne große Hoffnungen, die Welt des großen Bruders, von dem es keine Beweise gibt, dass er wirklich existiert. Winston führt ein Leben in der ständigen Gewissheit selbst bei der geringsten kritischen Äußerung sofort bestraft zu werden. Keiner ahnt wie weit Winston bereit ist zu gehen, sofern sich ihm die Möglichkeit bietet. Es beginnt ganz unscheinbar mit einem Tagebuch und endet schließlich in einem der schlimmsten Verbrechen, die ein Mensch in der Welt des großen Bruders begehen kann, einem Gedankenverbrechen. Auf dem Weg dorthin begegnet er einem Mädchen namens Julia, welches er zunächst für seine schlimmste Feindin hält. Doch eine zufällige Begegnung bringt die beiden näher zusammen und lässt sie schließlich sogar ein paar werden, doch das Glück der beiden wehrt nicht lange, denn auch das ist ein Verbrechen. Schlussendlich führt sie die Geschichte in das Ministerium der Liebe, in Neusprache Minilieb genannt. Wo die finale Auseinandersetzung, das Brechen stattfindet.Ein Buch das jede Empfehlung wert ist. Jeder der sich schon immer mal dafür interessiert hat, was es mit dem gläsernen Menschen und dem großen Bruder oder Big Brother auf sich hat, der sollte sich hier einlesen. Für anspruchsvolle kritische Unterhaltung ist gesorgt. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>joeycgrant</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books, I just reread it and it was just as good as the first time.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Giorgia91</user>
	<review>Bellissimo, un libro che parla di dittatura, di un mondo che non vorremmo mai vedere in cui il governo ha il potere assoluto, qual'è il segreto. Il controllo e il revisionismo della storia, dei giornali della cultura. Da leggere assolutamente. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluedream</user>
	<review>This is my favorite book.  Yes. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>YagamiLight</user>
	<review>This novel has a nice concept and good ideas, however Orwell's writing and the general composition of the novel aren't that good. Another thing I disliked were the author's communistic views, shining through too intensively a couple of times.I liked Animal Farm better. Still, an interesting book to read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dheintz</user>
	<review>When we first read 1984 in high school we were awed by the seemingly helpless struggle of Winston Smith and his hussy, Julia.  O'Brien becomes a close friend only to eventually turn on us.  We are abducted by the simple language and relatively predictable plot.  However, after a decade of reading dystopias from other literary traditions and more reflection on Orwell's work, I find it increasingly both unoriginal and uninspired.  It lacks the visceral element of the Soviet dystopias (and Utopias)--people actually experienced the horror written about in them.  And, it lacks the literary acuity of works like Nabokov's Invitation to a Beheading.So, while we all must read 1984--it is culturally necessary--I think it best to reconsider its status as a great work. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raymundojimenez</user>
	<review>http://www.gandhi.com.mx/index.cfm/id...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>michaeleconomy</user>
	<review>pretty good, depressing though.  1984 is truly a sci-fi classic.weird what has and what has not come true since this book was initially published. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rfewell</user>
	<review>Wow, this was great!  I think newspeak is texting and chatting today -- are we digressing into an Engsoc society?  this is an amazing book - i don't know if the moral is that we can't possibly win in a fight against a super-power society or if we need to combine efforts and keep on plugging... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jmaloney17</user>
	<review>I am just not a fan of this book.  I could not get through it.  Not finishing a book is pretty rare for me.  I will have to try again at a later date. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fils</user>
	<review>There aren't many books that scare me- it's something that irritates me, actually- and I've never met a book that I don't want to read a second time merely because I'm too scared to read it through again. Until I met this book, that is. 1984 is one of the scariest books I have read, even though I'm not convinced we're all heading the same way. I became so attached to the two main characters that I became more emotionally involved with this novel than I ever have with another, and I was completely unprepared to cry to it. The ending left a bitter taste in my mouth, but this does not mean it is a bad book. Far from it, I completely understand why this is one of the epitomes of modern(ish) literature. I loved it from start to finish, but be prepared that it might not be the happiest book ever written.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dilandau</user>
	<review>http://www.piruett.se/2008/11/30/jag-... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>atheist_goat</user>
	<review>Maybe in 1948, or even in 1984, this book was chilling. Read in 2008 America, it was deadly boring. The heavy-handedness and lack of euphemism used by the Party were completely unrealistic - now, if Hate Week had been called Patriot Week, or the Two Minutes Hate the Pledge of Allegiance or something, it might have raised some hairs. As it is, after the last eight years, hate that's willing to call itself hate isn't scary. It's when you cloak it in love and faith and duty that it becomes horrifying.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>knitcrazybooknut</user>
	<review>Very creepy, very realistic, best opening line ever:  "It was a bright cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen."  Many of the political and cultural predictions in this book have come true. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hennis</user>
	<review>Not so well written, and unbelievable plot. You would say it was written by a very inexperienced writer, but interesting enough from a historical perspective. The society that is described in the book is so awful, so frightening, and so unrealistic. Even though, you see similarities between this book and what we hear of one of the latest remnants of bad communist states: North-Korea. Additionally, with computer technology, 1984 telescreens can now be seen as ordinary laptops and a Google, Yahoo! or any other datamining organization selling information to governments. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mr_Ibbans</user>
	<review>An insiders Utopia.  A Utopia without freedom.  Without feeling.  An extremely corrosive book to the fabric of society. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jessicawest</user>
	<review>This is one of those books that I have read at least three times, this most recent time being the third, I think. This image is actually the edition of the book that I own. It's so different from some of the others, especially the more modern editions. This is the 1984 edition, which is meaningless, because the book was not a prediction for where we would be in 1984. I just find it interesting.This is absolutely one of my favorite books ever. It's funny how you can read a book like this and remember things that seem so important to the story, you wonder how you forgot them. Even though I've read this book twice before, I still kept having, "Oh yeah!" moments. The story of Winston Smith and his comrades of the Party, of Oceania and Big Brother, is so compelling, so intricate, it should be read by everyone.One thing that I wanted to discuss about this book was the fact that in the various prefaces, forwards, afterwords, etc in the different editions they always talk about how Orwell did not mean for the book to be a prediction or prophecy, but a warning. But I think that even more than a warning against the future, he meant it as a warning to open our eyes to the present. So many of the aspects of the control that the Party has over the people of Oceania are things that we experience now. Doublethink is alive and well, but that is only important if you acknowledge it for what it is, and don't let it fool you. Orwell could not have known about the war on terror, but that is exactly the kind of war that the Party wages against its "enemies" Eurasia and Eastasia. An unending war, whose purpose is to create an economy (supplies and weapons), give the people an enemy to hate, and give the government permission to take away freedoms. There are so many other details that you will notice as you read this book - it really is a matter of reading to open your mind. If you've read 1984 before, read it again; and if you've never picked it up, now is a good time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Audacity88</user>
	<review>- </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thesmellofbooks</user>
	<review>A heart-stopping book, not in the sense of thrills chills spills.  A conversation on the breaking of the human heart. The movie betrayed the very essence of the book. Read the book."It was only an 'opeless fancy..." </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>andersonden</user>
	<review>A fascinating (and well known) look at a possible future. Orwell was disquieted by the trend toward centralized government and less involvement and understanding by citizens of how the state functions and who runs it. He poses a scenario of three main centralized future states that have no active citizen participation in politics or decision-making. The book is a warning against centralized government but also against apathy and propaganda. If you've never read it you'll finally discover where the phrase "big brother is watching you" comes from. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>afyfe</user>
	<review>I'm happy I finally read this book.  I liked it quite a bit, I wasn't a huge fan of the middle when Orwell put a large excerpt from Goldstein's book this kinda slowed down the story and I had a hard time getting through it.  Besides that it was very good, a little depressing in the end but still a good book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>theBandersnatch</user>
	<review>I read it in ninth grade and got chills. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>EnriqueFreeque</user>
	<review>My two cents on 1984:  The ideas and warnings Orwell presented far outweighed his writing.  The writing reads to me as if Orwell were a 19th century Russian master but the English translator mediocre at best.  Orwell wrote better than this -- a lot better -- and his journals proved it.  I wonder if he purposefully stripped down the prose in order to dramatically accentuate his dark futuristic visions, going for the effect  in the novel you can produce in printing when you reverse-negative text, making the white of the words, the ideas, pop out from the page because the page, now, except for the words, is completely inundated with black?  Don't know.  I rate Zamyatin's "We" higher because it's better written (and I say that even though I don't read Russian and am forced to read what very well may be a mediocre English translation!) and it's ideas, "We's," are as innovative, if not more so, than 1984s. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>PhoenixTerran</user>
	<review>One of the books that I read for Banned Books Week was George Orwell's anti-utopia classic 1984. This was actually a reread for me, having first encountered the book in high school--surprisingly enough, not for a class. Instead it was being passed around one group of friends and while it was important that we shared it with each other, we never really talked about it together; we were a rather strange and cynical bunch. 1984 was my introduction to dystopian literature, which remains to this day one of my favorite genres. For various reasons, I've been meaning to reread the book for a while, and reading it for Banned Books Week seemed to me to be extraordinarily appropriate. One of the reasons that it is often challenged is that it is felt to be "pro-communism." As with many banned and challenged books, this makes me wonder if those protesting have actually taken the time to read the material.Winston Smith is thirty-nine, an Outer Party member working in the Records Department at the Ministry of Truth where he corrects false information to suit the Party's current outlook. Except he know it is a lie, that it all is a lie. And he knows he hates the Party and Big Brother, its leader. And knowing this, he also knows he is guilty of thoughtcrime and that it is only a matter of time before he is found out and something is done about it. For Big Brother, and the Party, are always watching--and they probably already know.Winston is doomed--he knows it, and the reader knows it. False hope only serves to distract from the inevitable outcome; the only questions left is when it will happen and how long will he last when it does. 1984 is certainly not a happy book. Indeed, it is rather distressing, depressive, and ominous, not to mention disturbing and relentless. Big Brother loves you, and you better love him, too.It's hard to say, but I believe 1984 probably made a greater impact on me now than when I first read it. The book has aged amazingly well; even though originally written in 1949, it is still incredibly relevant. Perhaps even more so than when it was first published. The book is less about plot and action (there is actually very little of either) and more about the state of the world and how it got there--it is a "thinking" book. It is also a dire warning of what we as humanity are capable of, and what we could become. Some things aren't entirely plausible (yet), but one only has to look at the current state of politics and governments to realize that some things are frightening possible, and some things so probable they're likely happening now. 1984 isn't the greatest novel, but it is an important book. I may still be strange and cynical, but Orwell shows amazing insight into human nature. There is a lot of Truth in this work.Experiments in Reading </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>03swalker</user>
	<review>A novel that is very much considered a classic, and which is often regarded as becoming more like reality, 1984 was bound to take a while to read. Despite it's modest word count, it is the kind of book that needs to be mulled over between sessions.As a novel - discounting the political essay behind it - it is a highly readable book that will keep you reading - even when you find the main character changing. However to ignore the political statement behind the novel is to do it a great disservice.As a political work it is even greater. The empathy provoked with Winston is astounding, you can really find yourself passionately praying that the Brotherhood is real. Even a simple thing such as coffee is a reminder of the message - the poor, cheap taste is contrasted with the name "Victory Coffee" cleverly designed to in-still the sense that Oceania is on the brink of victory. The amount of thought put into the very names of such simple things sums up the novel as a whole - it is delicately crafted to give a resonance throughout the story that is constantly there - whether it's at the surface of the text, or just in the background.Finally, my one criticism of this text is the large dose of the political history and Ingsoc philosophy from Goldsteins book. Such a large block of text in one session is, in my opinion, too heavier dose for most readers who may well give up reading there.But, regardless, this text remains a literary and political masterpiece.5/5Originally posted at http://lambadasbooks.wordpress.com </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Chariton</user>
	<review>1984 är verkligen en klassiker och förtjänar benämningen. Den är också just så kuslig och svartsynt som jag upplevde den i yngre dagar. Trots att den är skriven 1949 är det väldigt få saker som känns daterade och än mycket att hämta ur Orwells verk. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brainlair</user>
	<review>I must NOT be as bright as others.  I did not like this book.  I did not think it was great.  I would not recommend it.  Classic or not...it was slow and boring.  Maybe someone can tell me what is so wonderful about it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nhurst</user>
	<review>1984 deals with the fears of totalitarian socialist government in the early-mid 20th century and projects those fears into the year 1984. The Party, an all-powerful regime that rules over the people of Oceania, constantly monitoring its citizens and making sure that nobody even thinks to defy their power. They weave lies through the mainstream media to help control people's thoughts, and those who still choose to defy the Party are "vaporized" by the Thought Police. This idea of an all-powerful, evil government is very similar to that in Brave New World. The Party rules over its people in a way that works to secure their grasp over the people perpetually in the same way the World State ruled over its "utopia" in the name of stability. It's very hard not to relate Orwell to Huxley as they were contemporaries, even though they never collaborated. Orwell creates a horrifying "utopian" society in a darker but similar way that Huxley does. Overall I found that 1984 was a better read than Brave New World. The writing feels much deeper and better thought out, so while it's a little more dense to read, it provides a much deeper intellectual experience. Huxley described a society while Orwell submerged you in one. This has become one of my favorite novels and would strongly suggest it to anyone looking to read a classic "cautionary sci-fi" novel. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>esullivan</user>
	<review>George Orwell’s novel, 1984, portrays a setting thirty-five years into the future where society is solely based on technology and physical control. The book was written in 1949 when the United States was going through one of the most crucial period of the Industrial Revolution. New technological advancements were being put on to shelves weekly for US citizens’ complete and total happiness. Orwell, a firm antagonist in this period, wrote 1984 to show what society will be like if we let the madness continue. In his story, he creates a world where everything is controlled by “The Party” and its leader, “Big Brother”. Cameras watch people wherever they go and if a word is mentioned or even thought about that in one way or another opposes The Party, it is subject to death. The protagonist in the story, Winston Smith, attempts to oppose The Party by having his own beliefs throughout the novel.	The main idea that Orwell is trying to illustrate to his audience is that the future will not be bright if society continues on the path it is going. He does this by using scare tactics and writing the upmost extremities of the problems. As we have all understood from similar novels like Brave New World and Candide, a true utopia is a place where people can make their own decisions and obtain a good life through hard work and love for your peers. Orwell believed that society was getting away from that idea. Therefore he wrote about the ultimate dystopia is prove his point. Orwell uses Winston Smith as a scapegoat to show what will happen to free thinkers in this technology based society. Inevitably they will be crushed and forced to conform to society. Again, as consistent with Brave New World and Candide, 1984 shows that the theme of happiness in our world can only reach a certain point before it is detrimental to society.	Overall, 1984 was a great book. The storyline is very intriguing and kept me always wanting to read more. The story was very well-organized and well written. The only concern I had was that I was a little skeptical about the ending. Orwell proves his point very well, but it is abrupt and sudden. In a way, I was sort of left scratching my head needed another chapter. I would recommend this book to anyone who wants a good read, but primarily to people, like me, interested in science fiction and wild futuristic ideas. Overall rating: 4 stars. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gaskella</user>
	<review>I read this first, as I'm sure many of us did, as a teenager. I'm also sure that the savage satire on totalitarian states went straight over my head - I was into Science Fiction, and didn't pay any attention to modern history.  Instead I was probably thinking how clever(!) the construction of doublespeak was - and was probably also fresh from reading the Nadsat in Anthony Burgess' 'A Clockwork Orange' too.Now I'm grown-up, the book's bleak vision sends a true shudder down my spine. There is nothing to enjoy in it at all, even the central romance seems somewhat mechanical, and O'Brien is the most doubleplusungood torturer I've encountered in literature. This profound novel has become part of our lives though - we joke about Big Brother and call the Politically Correct brigade the 'Thought Police' all the time. Yet there is a tiny tingle of relief that despite our nanny state and CCTV cams everywhere, it could never get as bad in a true democracy as in Orwell's dystopia ... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heathernkemp</user>
	<review>I can't really complain too much about any literature in the dystopic genre (especially Orwell).  I generally love how he helps you feel completely helpless as he's writing.  I honestly thought this book might have a surprising twist at the end (I know that hopefulness in reading dystopic literature is an oxymoron, but Orwell is the master at manipulating feelings), but he was classic and left me the way that you would expect 1984 to leave you--empty. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AlbinoRhino</user>
	<review>Frightening book.  A must-read for fans of dystopian literature. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>terriks</user>
	<review>Who needs slasher movies to scare the crap out of you when you can read Mr. Orwell? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zinf</user>
	<review>Straordinario e agghiacciante </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>suzyglad</user>
	<review>Jacob's summer 08 reading homework</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Listener42</user>
	<review>8.0</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Lililu</user>
	<review>Excelente libro, es impresionanate que despues de tantos años este libro refleje muchos problemas actuales, llamese capitalismo o comunismo, lo que opriemen y dominan siempre están presentes, las guerras absurdas, y  el constante bombardeo para idiotizar a las masas en beneficios de unos pocos. Invita indidudablemente a una reflexíon profunda. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>theportal2002</user>
	<review>This book was truly ahead of it's time.  No others like it, so similar to how society is emerging. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rosibenini</user>
	<review>Origem do Big Brother, socidedade controlada por grandes telas em casa. Saudações e cultos de adoração diários para o Grande Irmão. Minuto do ódio, incitava a raiva contra o "inimigo do momento", que sempre mudava.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>caim</user>
	<review>1984 is a scary look into a dystopian society of the future. Orwell tells a scary tale of what the future is capable of holding in store. In a world where thinking the wrong thing is a crime, Winston Smith begins to feel that something is wrong. It is an excellent tale that examines the corrosive nature of power. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cmbest524</user>
	<review>My favorite book for years.  If you liked this, also try We by Yevgeny Zamyatin, which is equally fabulous. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>teresakayep</user>
	<review>It's difficult to review a novel that has become such a significant part of contemporary culture. Even those who've never heard of George Orwell have heard of Big Brother. Obviously, 1984 has had an impact. But is it a good book? Returning to it on audio nearly 20 years after reading it as a teenager, I can report that it still has power to send chills down my spine.The part of Orwell's vision that is most well known is the picture of constant surveillance. This lack of privacy is not, however, the only means of control that the Party has. News stories and other documents are constantly being "rectified" so that Big Brother appears to always be correct. The language of Oceania, newspeak, is being revised so that it's impossible for citizens to even have the words to think of rebellion. Indeed, negative thoughts about the Party have become a crime. In fact, the Party's ability to get inside people's minds and control their very thoughts is no doubt the most frightening part of 1984. Although it's hard to believe that such control is possible, Orwell paints a convincing picture of how such a thing could be done.My more complete review is available athttp://shelflove.wordpress.com/2008/0... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TakeItOrLeaveIt</user>
	<review>typical dystopia book but so necessary. there is a reason they make you read this in school, like at how the world is going. especially England. and watch Brasil if you cant read. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>foof2you</user>
	<review>A classic that if the former Soviet Union was still around might still resinate with the reader.  Without the knowledge of this past this book seems hollow.  This was a especially tough read that loses whatever flow that it had in the middle.  This inclusion was unneccesary and the book would have been much better without the book in a book. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pollywannabook</user>
	<review>1984 is a captivating and haunting vision of a now-past-but-then-future world where the government has total control over every aspect peoples lives including their thoughts.It is an unthinkable reality.The first half of the book is compelling in its portrayal of this possible future.  The second half is less so as we are forced to read a book within a book for large sections at a time.  No story at this point, just political ideology.  The story does resume at the end, and it is the inevitable one that part of me still fought against. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>codeeater</user>
	<review>Recently watching the movie "Brazil" brought this book to my mind. I hadn't read it for 15 years or so and I couldn't remember the details. I wish I could say, that we have moved further away from the world in the book - but I'm afraid there are still far too many "Big Brothers" and "O'Briens" out there.I also liked the afterword by Erich Fromm, made me think about the everyday use of doublethink...Verdict: Doubleplusgood. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>janepriceestrada</user>
	<review>This is one of the great dystopias.  The concept and execution is the most original and awe inspiring.  It is fast paced and keeps you reading while you look over your shoulder. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kronos999</user>
	<review>Classic dystopian novel. There are enough reviews here that I don't feel like going into depth. Well-written, but I prefer Brave New World. Or, perhaps, Blakes 7. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tjsjohanna</user>
	<review>I can finally say I read this book.  And I probably won't ever feel the need to read it again!  (Although you never know - I might decide I need to read a variety of negative utopias just for the heck of it!).  So, very well written and imagined and just heartbreaking.  However, that said, I just didn't buy that anyone would invest that much time in controlling even the thoughts and hearts of an entire society.  I just don't believe that widespread efforts to change fundamental "humanness" could be successful.  There is an afterword in my edition, written in 1961 by Erich Fromm, that seems to think Mr. Orwell's view of the future is right in his backyard, so to speak.  From my perspective in 2008, nothing could seem further from the truth.  Despite all the attempts made to convince the masses (at least here in the USA), we insist on being wildly, all-over-the-chart, free in our opinions, in our pursuits, in what we believe and champion.  And in the world it seems that totalitarian governments seem to come and go as quickly as the next group can muster the strength to knock the reigning one down.  Anyway, definitely a book to make one think. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cameling</user>
	<review>It's scary to think that there are some countries and governments who seem to have taken some of the totalitarian ideas in this book and applied it to their own administration. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>big_brother</user>
	<review>Simply the book that influenced me the most. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ianracey</user>
	<review>Nineteen Eighty-Four is a seminal work, maybe the most important work of fiction written in English in the twentieth century. Like its only real competitor for that title, The Lord of the Rings, it is both a work of outlandish fantasy while also having something truly profound to say about our own post-Second World War world.What I find most impressive about Orwell's vision of the future are both its prescience and its political neutrality. All the most chilling aspects of Big Brother's totalitarian government--constant electronic surveillance of its citizens, rewriting history to serve the political concerns of the day, the infiltration of society by secret police--are really just exaggerations (well, one hopes that they're exaggerations) of practices that our own Western democratic governments engage in today, and have been engaging in for the past two generations. And what's more, they're practices that have been followed by parties at either end of the political spectrum--by supposedly small-government Republican (American) and Conservative (British) governments just as much as by liberal Democrats (American) or socialist Labour (British). Orwell's dark vision sees society as a whole, not just one ideology or another.Orwell himself, of course, was extremely left-wing, to the point of actually advocating revolutionary overthrow of the existing capital order, and also of fighting on the Republican side during the Spanish Civil War. For much of the Second World War he remained convinced that the national effort required to beat the Axis Powers would necessarily place such a strain on the British social order that it was guaranteed to result in Communist revolution on the Leninist model.But his Communism was not we now think of as Communism, the Cold War Soviet state of faceless bureaucracy and rigid suppression of individuality. Instead, he sought through Communism--or what he called "democratic socialism"--the opportunity to achieve the profoundest freedom for the individual, by freeing him from the fetters of capitalism. And that philosophy infuses Nineteen Eighty-Four, and is probably the biggest reason why it remains such a powerful story today. For while it is a novel of the inexorable expansion of government at the expense of the individual, its central theme is the necessity for the individual to maintain constant vigilance for the preservation of freedom (which is not the same thing as democracy). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ianracey</user>
	<review>Nineteen Eighty-Four is a seminal work, maybe the most important work of fiction written in English in the twentieth century. Like its only real competitor for that title, The Lord of the Rings, it is both a work of outlandish fantasy while also having something truly profound to say about our own post-Second World War world.What I find most impressive about Orwell's vision of the future are both its prescience and its political neutrality. All the most chilling aspects of Big Brother's totalitarian government--constant electronic surveillance of its citizens, rewriting history to serve the political concerns of the day, the infiltration of society by secret police--are really just exaggerations (well, one hopes that they're exaggerations) of practices that our own Western democratic governments engage in today, and have been engaging in for the past two generations. And what's more, they're practices that have been followed by parties at either end of the political spectrum--by supposedly small-government Republican (American) and Conservative (British) governments just as much as by liberal Democrats (American) or socialist Labour (British). Orwell's dark vision sees society as a whole, not just one ideology or another.Orwell himself, of course, was extremely left-wing, to the point of actually advocating revolutionary overthrow of the existing capital order, and also of fighting on the Republican side during the Spanish Civil War. For much of the Second World War he remained convinced that the national effort required to beat the Axis Powers would necessarily place such a strain on the British social order that it was guaranteed to result in Communist revolution on the Leninist model.But his Communism was not we now think of as Communism, the Cold War Soviet state of faceless bureaucracy and rigid suppression of individuality. Instead, he sought through Communism--or what he called "democratic socialism"--the opportunity to achieve the profoundest freedom for the individual, by freeing him from the fetters of capitalism. And that philosophy infuses Nineteen Eighty-Four, and is probably the biggest reason why it remains such a powerful story today. For while it is a novel of the inexorable expansion of government at the expense of the individual, its central theme is the necessity for the individual to maintain constant vigilance for the preservation of freedom (which is not the same thing as democracy). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Makifat</user>
	<review>I reread this novel in 2002 upon realizing the similarities between Bush's nascent "War on Terror" and Oceania's never-ending war with Eurasia/Eastasia. Media manipulation today is more subtle than Orwell's "doublespeak", as is the Bush campaign to erode the rights of the individual in America. Totalitarianism can creep up quite slowly, almost imperceptibly. The fears and tortures of Winston Smith are more terrifying now than they were when I first read this book in high school, simply because their potential reality is more imaginable than ever before. Didactic and perhaps a bit overwritten, 1984 has passed beyond literature into a state alarmingly close to today's reality.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>blackdogbooks</user>
	<review>What can I say about this dystopian masterpiece that hasn't already been said.  As evidence, look to the over 200 reviews by other LT'ers available.  The story here, with Brave New World, is the seed for much of the dystopian literature we have.  The novel also serves as a comment on modern day 'wag the dog' politics, with its Ministry of Information.  What is truly distubing about works like 1984 is tha they were written some time ago and acurrately predicted, in many cases, the state of the world today.  The relevance of 1984 stands undiminshed in today's world. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mebrock</user>
	<review>Not a book that will leave you indifferent. This is a social commentary in palatable novel form, thought provoking, quotable, and powerful in its influence. Worth teaching in upper high school, although be forewarned there are quite a few discussions of sexuality within. If I taught it in high school, I would read it aloud, and discuss at least as much as I read. I would probably skip some portions. It would not be a book I would hand over without comment.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dmcolon</user>
	<review>I read 1984 in High School after finishing Animal Farm.  I don't think I fully understood the book, but I remember taking to the book quite readily.  In high school, I was quite the Reaganite conservative and the book served as a warning against totalitarianism.  And yet as I look back at my political evolution to the left, 1984 was crucial in my leftward shift.  Orwell opened me to the idea that one could be a leftist and NOT be in the Stalinist/Marxist tradition (it was the 80s).I'm always amazed how the imagery of 1984 has persisted.  Everything from the Apple Computer ads in the 1980s to the adoption of the phrase "Orwellian" to Alan Moore's V for Vendetta series, the fear of an all-controlling state has stayed with us.  Orwell has given life to what otherwise might be a stale, cold image of the totalitarian state.  And yet I sometimes wonder if the book has done such an effective job that it's created an unhealthy distrust of the state.   In sum, I wonder if 1984 helped give birth to modern conservatism.  I don't think Orwell intended this to happen, but texts tend to lose control of themselves.  The impact of 1984 as a cultural text may indeed have been quite the opposite of my own experience -- liberals and leftists became conflated with Marxists.  It's all obviously more complex, but I do think 1984 contribute to this process.  As I listen to right-wing talk radio personalities denounce Barack Obama as a Marxist, I feel the chill of 1984 running down my spine.  They're misusing language for a specific political agenda and part of their inspiration is Orwellian.  It's all so very confusing, but I think that's what makes 1984 so powerful. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>amandrake</user>
	<review>Every thinking person should read this book. I'm quite serious. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jsnrcrny</user>
	<review>An extremely important novel about the horrors of totalitarianism, George Orwell's _Nineteen Eighty-Four_ stands as a reminder of the power or organized oppression. The narrative concerns the struggles of a party-member, Winston Smith, against the psychological oppression of his government as well as his brief romance with the mysterious and sexually aggressive Julie, a woman who operates outside the cultural standards of her community. A critique of Stalinists and their denigration of the Trotskyists, _Nineteen Eighty-Four_ is an effective political parody that transcends its historical moment and teaches it readers political and ideological lessons that are startlingly relevant for today's political environment. Recalling the cynical sentiment of Orwell's earlier _Animal Farm_, _Nineteen Eighty-Four_ is strikingly darker and more naturalistic, relying heavily on the techniques of realism rather than the mythological and allegorical techniques characteristic of the earlier work. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>arouse77</user>
	<review>classic dystopian tale of paranoia, love, and betrayal in the shadow of Big Brother. culturally one of the most powerful novels of the 20th century. a must read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wmswarriors</user>
	<review>Everytime you read you seem to learn something new. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>qofd</user>
	<review>This was a more enjoyable read than I expected (except the boring bit when Winston was reading the book - i just could not wade my way through that small print) Orwell created a frightening, mixed up world and he did it well. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siriaeve</user>
	<review>I've only read this once, and I think I will only ever be able to read it once. Few books give me such nightmares that I can't sleep, but 1984 managed to do that for my fifteen year old self with ease. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>endersreads</user>
	<review>Eric Arthur Blair, known to us as George Orwell, led a life which certainly gave him the authority to write such a book as 1984. His political views show us a man who was adaptive and intelligent, and most assuredly a realist. 1984 is a cold dark world in which hope is dead and all fall under the eye of big brother. Orwell said that 1984 was not a novel of the future, but a novel of his present world.  Today Orwell's work is as relative as ever; indeed, I believe the book should now be taken as seriously as the Bible and Mr. Dawkins are.  Evolutionary revolution is alive and well with many leaders today such as Alex Jones, Daniel Estulin, Michael Badnarik, Peter Dale Scott, David Icke, and so many other Conspiracy Theorist Libertarians—it would be impossible to list them.  These guys, like it or not, are forming a new movement.  Have no fear—as Trotsky found out, all movements lead to the same old crap.  This is why Trotsky called for perpetual revolution.I only hope the readers of Orwell's 1984 come to understand that his vision is one we live in today.   As Mr. Lysander Spooner so put it "A man is no less a slave because he is allowed to choose a new master once in a term of years."  I would only add that it is "the illusion of choosing a new master", as the Left / Right paradigm only exists within the masses little pea-brains.Awaken to the reality that you are Winston asleep.  Awake. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zdufran</user>
	<review>This is a great dystopian classic - the first I read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LadyMuck</user>
	<review>Once read, never to be forgotten. Orwell's magnificent dystopian vision is the stuff of nightmares (or is it the stuff of real life now?). </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>EloE</user>
	<review>Ein totalitärer Staat hält die Menschen im Jahr 1984 in ständiger Angst. An dessen Spitze steht ein fiktiver Führer, der so genannte "Big Brother". Unablässige Propaganda und totale Überwachung, durchgeführt über die überall präsenten Televisoren, nicht abschaltbare Fernseher mit eingebauter Kamera, sind die Mittel des Staates, um die Bevölkerung auf Linie zu bringen. "Newspeak", ein um potenziell parteifeindliche Begriffe bereinigtes Englisch, soll Englisch ersetzen. Wer kein Wort mehr für "Freiheit" hat, kann sie auch nicht vermissen.Winston Smith arbeitet im Wahrheitsministerium der Partei. Sein Job ist es, Zeitungsberichte zu fälschen, um so falsche Prognosen der Partei zu korrigieren oder von der Partei aus politischen Gründen getötete Personen aus der Geschichte zu streichen. Obwohl Smith für die Partei arbeitet, ist er in seinem Inneren ein Gegner des totalitäten Systems und versucht mit der legendären Brüderschaft, einer Untergrundbewegung in Verbindung zu treten. Ein ständiges Versteckspiel beginnt.Heutige Warnungen vor dem gläsernen Bürger und dem allwissenden Staat nähren sich zu einem großen Teil aus 1984. Die Datierung seiner Anti-Utopie hat Orwell damals mehr oder weniger willkürlich durch Umdrehen der letzten zwei Ziffern des Jahrs 1948, in dem er den Roman schrieb, festgelegt. Schon damals und noch viel extremer knapp 20 Jahre später hat die massive Speicherung und Verteilung persönlicher Daten im Internet das Thema von 1984 aktueller denn je gemacht.Auch wer sich die neuen Ambitionen staatlicher Überwachung im Zuge der Nach-11.-September-Hysterie vor Augen führt, fühlt sich unweigerlich an ein 1984-Szenario erinnert. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>briandarvell</user>
	<review>Read: March 25 – April 4, 2008Rating: 3.5/5Having always heard so much about this novel, I was eager to finally be able to read it and judge for myself if it was worth all the critical acclaim. I have never read another Orwell novel either so his style and method were completely foreign to me. I tried to begin this book with as open and clear a mind as I could form.The novel was good on the whole, the messages crystal clear and it was not hard to hate Big Brother and all it represented. I enjoyed the story more so in the first half of the novel. Basically, these were the parts involved with Winston and how he felt alone in being one of the few who hid thoughts against the mainstream. The time period’s Russian influence was also very much present and I was intrigued by how many similarities I saw between this novel and present-day America. Freedom Fries instead of Victory Gin for instance.If I had one gripe to mention it would be the long segments of the later parts of the story where Winston is reading from the book of the Brotherhood. To me this was long and much of a repeat from what was already mentioned at various other points through the storytelling. I imagine that Orwell just wanted to make his message clear though.I would still say that this is an adequate novel for a younger audience more so than for an older one. It is a somewhat cynical novel (what dystopian novel is not?) and I find as you age and your personal views change on things and one realizes that life isn’t so simple as what novels like these portray. Still, it was a good read and I would recommend it to keen high-school students still today.From: http://briandarvell.wordpress.com/200... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>silverwing2332</user>
	<review>This is an exceptional book, oftentimes I get the sudden urge to reread this book because I enjoyed it so much.  Its a book that is hard to forget, and although I read it for a class (and then reread it many times after) I loved this book.  Thankfully, overanalyzing did not kill the book, it made 1984 better.  I often find myself thinking about this book, it never got confusing nor too complex. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bear08</user>
	<review>I had high expectations for this book and they were not met. I was glad to finally understand all of the "big brother" references, but overall I found this book depressing and un-re-readable. This book has its merits, but it's not for me. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Nikolau</user>
	<review>Without a doubt a most read book.If you want to take a better look what too much authority can do and without restrains to it , this book will help.Although by the first glance it seems an anarquist favorite book (due to how the author critices the masses),it really pins down the major flaws in Totalitarianism.By the metaphor of a distopia , the author guides us through the life of a piece of the system , a simple man that tries to make ends meet.The cover of the book should have a warning :"This book will change you.PERMANTLY" </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hnkemp</user>
	<review>In typical Orewellian fashion, this book was ahead of its time in regard to social commentary and equally fitting to still be read today.  A definite classic that is a spot-on social commentary. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>silverwing2332</user>
	<review>This is a great dystopian book that will make you think deeply about society.  Its based in a utopian setting London.  I was forced to read this for my english class, and I would gladly read it again and again.  The message that the book conveys is one that will stay with you, and it will make you think about what you would do in this situation and how easily the human mind is swayed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>solitude1984</user>
	<review>Definitely an interesting look into the potential future of society.  Unlike some who have read the book, I do not feel that a totalitarian regime of this type is all that unlikely.  In fact, I was startled to realize that there were definite similarities between the Party and the government of George Bush.  Here are a few examples (note, if you have not read the book and do not want any specific content revealed, please ignore the following):The second that I heard "victory gin" or "victory coffee", my thoughts drifted back to Bush's "freedom fries".  On page 213, the book mentions that "... practices which had been long abandoned, in some cases for hundreds of years-imprisonment without trial ... torture to extract confessions ... - not only became common again, but were tolerated and even defended by people who considered themselves enlightened and progressive."Sound familiar?Further similarities include maintaining an "atmosphere of war",  through the use of phrases such as "war on terror", and by keeping people on their toes using the homeland security level.  My only complaint was that the plot was rather dry in some instances.  For example, the chapters that Winston read in "The Book" were a little too lengthy in my opinion..  Still, this is definitely a brilliant piece of writing ... perhaps the best account of a dystopian society that I have ever encountered. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rebeccler</user>
	<review>The movements of the book from longing to conventional fulfillment, to physical destruction, and to mental emptiness are my favorite part of this novel.  The second part fools you into hoping.  The let down hurts, but rocks. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wyvernfriend</user>
	<review>I found this deeply interesting.  More for what it says about the human condition than anything else.  Through the eyes of one man, Winston Smith, it looks at a society that could have been.  A world where thought is controlled, where imagination is fettered, where freedom is a word being excised from the dictionary.  It's set in a future that didn't happed, to a degree.  We lack some of the overt signs of a dictatorship but sometimes you have to wonder about some of the hidden dictatorships in our world.It is an exaggeration, it is a moral fable, but it is on some levels very moving.  It made me think about restrictions on speech and thought that flows through our modern world.  My husband's constant habit of putting the TV on.  How much information a lot of countries want to have about us.  Stuff that lingers, stuff that makes 1984 scarier day by day. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Koma</user>
	<review>fantastisk, slugte den på en tog tur. er fascineret og skræmt af det univers der opbygges </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pyro87</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books of all time </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>frazier193</user>
	<review>Nineteen Eighty-Four is a famous dystopian novel by George Orwell. Winston Smith, the protagonist, is a citizen of a totalitarian government. There is no privacy in Winston Smith's world, as the government is perpetually watching. Winston hates the government, and falls for a girl who holds the same volatile feelings for the Party as well.  They are captured by the police and are brainwashed into being compliant.The novel is a commentary on the strong presence of government in the daily life of citizens. Orwell portrays the society as futuristic, and the government has supernatural abilities of detecting rebels. Orwell is suggesting that if the role of the government does not cease expansion, then society could turn into the nightmare that is portrayed in his novel.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JoseArcadio</user>
	<review>"War is PeaceFreedom is SlaveryIgnorance is Strength"Orwell'sy eerie yet surprisingly familiar look into the potential future of society depicts the story of Winston Smith, an employee of the ominous Ministry of Truth. In becoming aware of his controlled life, Smith faces inner conflict with a conditioned upbringing and the struggle against untrustworthy forces trying to quiet him.Although the year 1984 has come and passed the warnings of Orwell are forever echoed by the ever increasing size and power of the State. Orwell's disturbing future is in important reminder for the necessity of skepticism for faith in the system. Although grim in its foreboding nature, the novel rewards all readers with the satisfaction that they still have the ability to control their fate. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>NolHol</user>
	<review>1984 is a tale written quite ahead of its time.  George Orwell has shown an incredible ability to simulate a future world that is far beyond anything of the date of the publishing.  Though it is not a compelling thrill ride, the concepts embedded within 1984 are intellectually stimulating.  The oppressive setting of 1984 is very frightening and seems today that it is entirely possible.  Some of the references within the novel are obviously outdated, but the fact remains the the process is what shines a foretelling light. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cram27</user>
	<review>I enjoyed 1984 even though I believe I read it with a lower level of understanding than I would now. I do plan on rereading 1984 before I finish college. I do not want to comment any more on the book until I reread it.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kaelirenee</user>
	<review>I'm sure this is said of all times and all politicians, but reading this book and understanding doublespeak and doublethink reminded me too much of how the political atmosphere is now. His understanding of how much words can effect how people feel about political issues is just amazing.Summary from my Dystopia Reading List Review:Title, Author, and year originally published: 1984, George Orwell, 1949 (One must start with the best-known) Power: Power lies entirely with the totalitarian government of the Party, headed by Big Brother. Social Structure: Big Brother, Inner Party, Outer Party, Prolies. There are also war criminals who are summarily executed and the revolutionary group, which may or may not exist, The Brotherhood. Role of individual: The individual exists to serve and love Big Brother, at least if one is a Party member. Prolies are allowed more individuality, but are generally accepted as sub-human with low intelligence (noted by the fact that Prolie children may test into the Party). Role of commerce: Negligible. A pseudo-black market exists. Party members are hardly even given a livable wage that would allow them to buy underwear or razors often enough. Role of government: Totalitarian, socialistic without the benefit of considering how it could help society. Thought Police keep citizens in line. Threat of Ministry of Love enough to keep most people in love. Executions and disappearances are everyday occurrences. Other factors (environment, religion, sex, overpopulation, etc.): Environmental issues aren’t discussed, since Party members are raised to fear nature since it separates them from the view of the Thought Police. No religion, except hero worship. Sex is frowned upon except as a necessity to be endured to produce children (“Our duty to the Party”). Since the city is an industrial center, overpopulation is clear. Commentary on modern society: Despite what a leader may say, an individual’s needs or wants are not high on his list of priorities. Government taken too far exists only to promote itself and keep its own power. Reminds us of the idea that the enemy hasn’t always been the enemy, despite what the current ideas are. Other comments: Doublespeak and doublethink are well explained, though not an entirely unique concept in history. Newspeak. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stveggy</user>
	<review>Great book </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>katie177</user>
	<review>It just puts it into perspective </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Awfki</user>
	<review>An important read given that the U.S. government continues to inch in this direction. War on drugs, war on terror. We have to be at war with somebody or they can't scare the voters into supporting the party, right? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jpace85</user>
	<review>Still reading. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KhrystiBooks</user>
	<review>This book might give you nightmares, but it's worth reading. Unlike some dystopian novels, it leaves no message of hope. It is a book purely of fear-but the worst fear is that we will let society get to this point in the first place. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>greathouse.28</user>
	<review>Even though the book is classic, it was not a captivating read.  Each page passed slowly.  It seemed grimy, dismal, and depressing.  It served as a good warning to our society.  George Orwell's use of symbolism and characters were effective, however.  This story was very thought provoking. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rajendran</user>
	<review>1984 has come and gone, but George Orwell's prophetic, nightmarish vision in 1949 of the world we were becoming is timelier than ever. 1984 is still the geat modern classic of "Negative Utopia" -- a startingly original and haunting novel that creates an imaginary world that is completely convincing, from the first sentence to the last four words. No one can deny this novel's power, its hold on the imaginations of whole generations, or the power of its admonitions -- a power that seems to grow, not lessen with the passage of time.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>duckwood</user>
	<review>How can you write a review for George Orwell's '1984'?I read 'Animal Farm' when I was quite young, and I got the symbolism, I thought. I was all set to move on to '1984', but my mom cautioned me I probably wouldn't like it yet - it was different - more grown up. And so I didn't read it for many years. It wasn't until my early thirties, until the first term of the reign of President Bush and his friends, with the Patriot Act in the news, that I finally read George Orwell's classic. Of course I was amazed and impressed and saddened by his dark cautionary tale of government run amok, and of regular people trying to survive within the confines of such a government which does everything in its power to control not only the actions but the thoughts of its citizens, using tactics that range from media propaganda to imprisonment and torture. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KnightofCydonia</user>
	<review>A compelling read. Truly it is a book that makes you consider todays society and how far ahead of this time Orwell was. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>whitebalcony</user>
	<review>Brilliant.. much better than "Brave New World" in my opinion and eerily astute regarding our own impending dystopia her in the States. The television is already pumping out exactly the same kind of bullshit propaganda that Winston is subjected to. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>joymarchand</user>
	<review>test test</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DeusExLibrus</user>
	<review>This book scared the crap out of me when I read it. Orwell is a master of sci-fi, especially dystopias used for social commentary, and this is demonstrated in his most famous work, 1984. I highly recommend everyone read this if they haven't already. A lot of what Orwell wrote in 1948 is much closer to coming true now than ever. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JeroenBerndsen</user>
	<review>Gelukkig wordt dit boek nog steeds gelezen op de middelbare scholen, het zou zonde zijn als niemand het meer zou kennen. Het beeld dat orwell schets van een mogelijk toekomstige maatschappij lijkt af en toe even dicht bij te komen. 'Big brother is watching you' gaat tegenwoordig steeds meer op, ook in Nederland. Dit boek is een pamflet voor het niet teveel inleveren van je vrijheid aan de regering en schetst een angstaanjagend beeld van hoe een maatschappij eruit zou kunnen komen te zien.... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>samantha464</user>
	<review>My favorite "Bleak Future" novels, with the possible exception of The Handmaid's Tale.  I love Orwell's take on the future of communisim, especially the seperation of the proletariat from the party class and their restrictions.  I nearly had three heart attacks while reading it, and that right there is an indication of a good book! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cal8769</user>
	<review>Makes you think about politics and the power of money. A very valuble lesson no matter how old this book is. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bibliobbe</user>
	<review>Yes, it’s a classic and quite frankly, it’s an insult to see it so low in the Top 100.  55?  It deserves a spot in the top 10, at least.  It just goes to show that the older the books are, the less likely they are to remain in our brain cells.  So, is this not as good a book as, say, anything by Marian Keyes?  (Stop it.  This is unfair.)  OK, so George Orwell wasn’t the nicest guy in town, but his depiction of a totalitarian state that even manages to censor people’s thoughts is a masterpiece.  The bit about the rats in Room 101 still gives me nightmares.  And of course, it’s always been a comfort to every conspiracy theorist who believes that we already have thought police.  And what self-respecting politician doesn’t believe in rewriting history?  Shame on you if you haven’t already read it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ysmng</user>
	<review>You can't go through life without having read this book. It is as important now as it was when it was written. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>caitlync1</user>
	<review>This is a story that takes place in the future, 1984. It is ruled by a totalitarianism government, and an ever seeing Big Brother. London is covered wqith decay - which symbolizes what will happen if totalitarianist governments prevail. Everywhere Winston (the main character) goes the Party watches him through telescreens; everywhere he looks he sees the face of the Party’s  leader, a figure known only as Big Brother. The Party controls everything in Oceania, even the people’s history and language. Thinking rebellious thoughts is illegal. Such thoughtcrime is, in fact, the worst of all crimes. If one were to committ such a crime, one would be vaporized - or tortured until death. Winston feels frustrated by the rigid control of the Party. They  prohibit free thought, sex, and any expression of individuality. Winston disagrees the party and has illegally purchased a diary in which to write his thoughts. Winston works in the Ministry of Truth where he alters historical records. He notices a co-worker, a dark-haired girl, staring at him, and worries that she is a spy who will turn him in for his thoughtcrime. He is also troubled by the Party’s control of history: the Party claims that Oceania has always been allied with Eastasia in a war against Eurasia, but Winston seems to recall a time when this was not true. One day, Winston receives a note from the dark-haired girl that reads “I love you.” She tells him her name, Julia, and they begin a affair, always on the lookout for signs of Party monitoring. Eventually they rent a room above the secondhand store in the prole district where Winston bought the diary. This relationship lasts for some time. Winston is sure that they will be caught and punished sooner or later (Winston believes in fatalism) while Julia is more optimistic. As Winston’s affair with Julia progresses, his hatred for the Party grows more intense. At last, he receives the message that he has been waiting for: O’Brien, a powerful Inner Party member  wants to see him.Winston and Julia travel to O’Brien’s luxurious apartment. As a member of the powerful Inner Party (Winston belongs to the Outer Party), O’Brien leads a life of luxury that Winston can only imagine. O’Brien confirms to Winston and Julia that, like them, he hates the Party, and says that he works against it as a member of the Brotherhood (An illegal organization with hopes of overthrowing the Party). He welcomes Winston and Julia into the Brotherhood, and gives Winston a copy of the book, the manifesto of the Brotherhood. Winston reads the book to Julia in the room above the store. Suddenly, soldiers barge in and seize them. Mr. Charrington, the owner of the store, is revealed as having been a member of the Thought Police all along.Taken away from Julia and taken to a place called the Ministry of Love, Winston discovers that O’Brien, too, is a Party spy who simply pretended to be a member of the Brotherhood in order to trap Winston into openly disobeying the Party. O’Brien spends months torturing and brainwashing Winston, who struggles to resist. At last, O’Brien sends him to the dreaded Room 101, the final destination for anyone who opposes the Party. Here, O’Brien tells Winston that he will be forced to confront his worst fear. O’Brien now straps a cage full of starved rats onto Winston’s head and is about to allow the rats to eat his face. Winston cracks, and begs him to torture Julia instead. Winston finally disobeyed Julia; something he plegded he would never do. O'Brien is satisfied and releases Winston. He no longer has any emotions ofor Julia and loves Big Brother. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ChandlerF1</user>
	<review>1984 is a terrifying, thrilling, and shocking novel chronicling the emotional and physical rebellion of Winston Smith against the all-powerful and controlling Party. George Orwell's nightmarish prediction </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MecenasPorto</user>
	<review>Grande livro, espero nunca viver em ditadura.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bethlea</user>
	<review>I read this so long ago, I should probably re-read it. I liked it then (when 1984 looked SO far in the future!) Hard to believe that 1984 now feels like so long ago...Now I believe we are closer to this scenario becoming real if we are not careful.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>readafew</user>
	<review>I managed to miss this book all through high school and college but felt the need to read it because of all the references to it.  This was a rather deep book and I was surprised at how off many of the impressions I got about it were from popular media.   For some reason I was always under the impression that it ended in a sort of major defiance or something.  Boy was I wrong.This book (for those who don't know) happens in an alternate earth history were totalitarian governments rule the world.  The story is about Winston a party member in the Ministry of Truth, which is the ultimate authority on the Truth.  Winston has a problem, he doesn't believe it, and he fears the thought police finding out this little nugget.This book has a great  message of warning and paints an incredibly bleak picture of the future should government get to much power and stabilizes it.  Excellent book but not light reading. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BlackKnightAvalon</user>
	<review>Despite how dated this book is, it still possesses a VERY valuable lesson. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cinesnail88</user>
	<review>I'm glad I finally read this, after much putting aside and delay. I thought Orwell's novel was excellent, much as I expected it to be, and it truly is the classic everyone claims it is. I'm sure it will be reread many times in the future. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Luc_Bertrand</user>
	<review>Grandiose ! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bkiker</user>
	<review>A classic in the dystopia or negative utopia genre. It will be a book that I will have to read over and over again to squeeze all there is out of the book. I am still haunted by the story and the warning that this book sends. The most disturbing thing I find about the book is not the power the state has over its people, but rather the power that society and the state has over history and language. I can help but think of today's Internet language and blog language when Orwell explained the concept of Newspeak. The changing and editing of history does add an element of horror to the story, especially when one begins to think and realize how important history actually is. Though the book is heavy with political theory and thought, much of it calling Communist Russia to mind, it still has an engaging story line. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>victrola</user>
	<review>Simultaneously entertaining and powerful. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Choccy</user>
	<review>WAR IS PEACE.FREEDOM IS SLAVERY.IGNORANCE IS STRENGTH.Those words keep sounding in my head since I read this book. Gosh, probably the most haunting not to mention frightening book I've ever read. 1984 should also be included in horror genre.1984 describes a Utopia. Not Thomas More's version of Utopia, but this is one is the antithesis, i.e. Negative Utopia. Imagine living in a country, whose leaders apply a totalitarian system in regulating their citizen, in the most extreme ways, which make Hitler, Mao, Stalin and that old bloke in V for Vendetta look like sissies.Working, eating, drinking, sleeping, talking, thinking, procreating...in short living, all are controlled by the state. Any hint of obedience or dislike can be detected by various state apparatus such as the Thought Police, telescreen, or even your children, who will not hesitate to betray you to the authorities. Even language is modified in such ways that you cannot express yourself, since individualism is a crime.The past is controlled, rewritten into something that will strengthen the incumbent ruler. Who controls the past, controls the future. Who controls the present, controls the past. There is no real truth. The "truth" is what the state says it is. Black is white, 2+2=5, if the state says so.The world in 1984 is divided into three states, originated from the ashes from World War II: Oceania (British Isles, the Americas, Pacific, Australia), Eurasia (Europe  Russia), and Eastasia (the rest of it). Continuous warfare between those three (who hold similar ideologies) is required to keep the society's order and peace. Si vis pacem para bellum. That's describes the first slogan.The second slogan, freedom is slavery, means the only way to be free is by letting you lose yourself and to be integrated within the Party. That way, you'll be indestructible and immortal.Ignorance is strength, means the division on high, middle, low classes in society will never be changed. The middle wants to be the high and they'll act "on behalf of the low" to dethrone the high. Afterwards, a new middle class arises, all will change except the low. The high and middle make and uphold the law, the low (proletarian) is just too stupid to revolt. The state maintains its structure by torture, intimidation, violence, and brainwashing.Blimey, Orwell's Animal Farm is already depressing, but 1984 gives "depression" a new meaning, at least for me. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hippiechick</user>
	<review>Of course I read this book in school. Back in the day, I didn't care for it so much. I've decided to revisit the classics after 15 years and discovered that I really, really enjoyed this book. It opened my eyes to several truths that do exist in our society today. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sarjah</user>
	<review>This was not a fun book to read one of the main themes is the absence of all hope. In my opinion this really detracts from the story. A better Orwell book is Animal Farm. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JRQ</user>
	<review>Not sure what more needs to be said about this classic social dystopia.  It blew my mind when I first read it in high school -- one of the first serious works of literature that I "got".  Reading it again recently as an adult, I found Orwell's grim totalitarian vision still so vivid and disturbing, I had to put it down for a while early on, knowing as I did what would happen and feeling uneasy about re-experiencing the events to come. This is one of the very best and most important works of fiction ever published. If you have never read it, you need to. Now. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kticesk8s</user>
	<review>I finally got around to reading this classic after referencing it for years (Big Brother, Thoughtpolice, Doublethink, Political Totalitarianism, Negative Utopia, etc.). Even though it was written many years ago, it is eerily relevant in today's society, albeit not in the extreme way that is depicted in the novel. The themes portrayed include: political parties controlling citizens' speech, deeds, and thought, the loss of religion, extinguishing of individuality, re-writing of the past, brainwashing, conspiracy theories, and execution of those who do not comply with the above. I would have appreciated this book much more as an adolescent, than as a post-9/11 adult, because I find myself asking vastly different questions than I would have asked in my idealistic years. Sociopolitical implications aside, 1984 is a well-written masterpiece that should continue to be a staple on our bookshelves. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>www.snigel.nu</user>
	<review>Link to a review on my personal website  (might be in Swedish). </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>smudgedlens</user>
	<review>I read this book in 1976, I was sceptical of  the premise that in less than 10 years this may come about, yet fascinated. Now I am blown away by how BIG BROTHER (BIG CORPORATIONS OR BIG BUSINESS)have infiltrated and now control our lives!! </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heidilove</user>
	<review>I read this the first time in 1984, thinking it would be a cute thing to do. I confess: I got totally sidelined by NewSpeak, and ended up writing more in my journal that week than i had all year. I picked it up again, some years later, and read the whole thing understood why a classic is a classic. This bears reading more than once, and continues to provide food for thought in our centralized, convenience-driven age. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sharrison</user>
	<review>Although a short book, it is equally as powerful as books 10 times its length. This is a novel absolutely riddled with political satire, written at a time when  it was believed that this could actually be the future in 1984, and it is not far off in the old Soviet Union, and many dictatorships. Because this novel is such a quick read, there is no excuse not to at least skim through it. This book is very similar to the book Fahrenheit 451 with this idea of a totalitarian government. I recommend this book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kynaratholis</user>
	<review>1984 is an incredibly well-written book. It is both very descriptive and minimalist. The world of 1984 is very accessible. The characters are interesting and complex. The plot is interesting and progresses at a good rate. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kjforester</user>
	<review>I have always shied away from science fiction because they tend to present bleak, hopeless settings not at all in line with my vision of life.  So,  I'm not sure why I decided to read George Orwell's 1984 at this point in my life.  It may have something to do with the contradictory messages I continue to receive from this administration concerning the war in Iraq and the mounting frustration and anger I feel as a result.But I did read 1984 and it was desperate and dark and disturbing, and I did not put it down.  Instantly, I recognized the term "doublethink" as Orwell so aptly defined it, "...the power of holding two contradictory belief's in one's mind simultaneously, and accepting both of them."  He goes on to describe the concept as "mental cheating" and illustrates the perception of war from three different points of view: those who are literally in the midst of a war;  those who are only "intermittently aware" of the war; and "those who have the best knowledge of what is happening..."  Orwell says the latter "are furthest from seeing the world as it is."  This must be the case now in the waning months of 2007 with the current President.  How else could it be?  Orwell also goes on to talk of the only three societies to have ever existed, the High, the Middle and the Low, he speaks to the nature of truth and, of course, the essence of humanity - free will.  With enough force and with the tools we possess as a civilization now, Orwell believed that human will could be broken and yes, even controlled.  Is that what is happening now?I encourage you to read this for the first time or again or a third time, it will scare you and remind you and, hopefully, inspire you. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>weradi</user>
	<review>Big Brother IS watching us all. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Sarcasm102</user>
	<review>Honestly ( I won't ruin it) but I love the ending. Does anyone believe the book would have been as meaningful if it ended any other way? Great, wonderful, awesome book. I was actually forced into reading this one in High School, though I am now thankful. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>plathbymoonlight</user>
	<review>An intriguing and terrifying look at the existence of a man within a Dictatorship and it's control over his every thought.  Often referred to the state of affairs in today's world.  Big Brother is indeed watching you. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ThatsFresh</user>
	<review>one of the best books i've ever read for school. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ktoonen</user>
	<review>delete_me </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>badgenome</user>
	<review>As with Animal Farm, Orwell's razor-sharp political mind is on display with 1984. It's maybe the single most famous dystopian novel, rightfully so; it has also come to be among the most abused books as well, thanks to the myriad mental midgets who try to hitch a ride on that intellectual giant's coattails. But today's complete over/misuse of the term "Orwellian" aside, it's an impressively bleak work that everybody should read at least once. Orwell's observations about the importance of controlling language and history are as timely as ever in these days of political correctness über alles. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lunaverse</user>
	<review>What can I say?  It's 1984.  Most people have seen enough references that they understand the word "Orwellian", "Thought police", or "Big Brother" even if they've never read this.  Nevertheless, reading it gives a much clearer view of these concepts.  1984 is on a short list of books that have probably prevented the very totalitarian societies they predict.  It fills the reverse function of the books fictional "Newspeak" -- it adds to our vocabulary and therefore to our ability to think and defend ourselves against oppression. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tonydal</user>
	<review>http://home.comcast.net/~tonydal/wise... </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Scaryguy</user>
	<review>A book about government control over society while a simple man and woman just want to be themselves and live in freedom. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kjames1220</user>
	<review>A classic. Extremely intriguing, and somewhat disturbing. I would recomend it to everyone. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gabeblaze</user>
	<review>A chilling look at a dystopic society where every action is watched. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mofroe</user>
	<review>One of the all time great dystopian novels.No review I can give would do justice the terrifying images of Nineteen Eighty-Four's bleak world view. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Hilde</user>
	<review>Whoa. I was not prepared for that, nor do I want to be.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ChicGeekGirl21</user>
	<review>Definitely required reading. 1984 is a timeless, frightening novel and one of my favorite books. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gwoodrow</user>
	<review>I should mention that I was not a reader in my childhood.  Hated it.  Especially hated being required to read certain books.  Hated still more that they were books about which the teachers were always passionate.  I didn't want to read, much less read anything that old people thought was cool.  When I became a voracious reader in my 20s, I had to reluctantly admit that many of those books did indeed deserve their love and praise.I say all this as a precursor to my review of 1984 for a reason.  I don't know if I personally think it deserves quite as rich of praise.  And this coming from a guy whose first real, intense literary love was "Animal Farm."  Perhaps I just lack the perspective of how jarring this book must've been at the time of its release.  I'm only 26, so in my lifetime there've been countless "negative utopia" stories.  (My personal favorites being "A Clockwork Orange" and "Fahrenheit 451.")  So the theme isn't new and fresh to me personally.   Maybe it had more of a new-theme smell during its original release.  (But even then, I think London's "The Iron Heel" and Lewis' "It can't happen here" preceded it, didn't they?)So then, what's new?  What makes "1984" stand out above the others?  I think it sustains mostly on the strength of great symbols that invoke powerful imagery with no additional description or embellishment even needed.  Big Brother.  The Thought Police.  The Ministries of Truth, of Love, of Plenty, of Peace.  So it has an always-resonant core (well, relevant so long as humans exist, of course), wrapped in great memorable symbols with striking names.  It turns a familiar theme into catch phrases, and it does so very effectively.Even if the story itself can be a tad flimsy at times and more than occasionally predictable, I am inclined to forgive Orwell.  Despite the chunkiness and the movement through certain plot points with fits and starts, I can see why some people revere and love it so even if I don't personally like it much above average.  Give me "Animal Farm" any day.  Glad I finally got around to reading it, and yes it does have certain relevance here in now (the political allusions being of course timeless), but still -- my rating of an "average" book is 2 stars out of 5.  I give it a 3.  So shoot me.  (In the back of the head walking down a corridor if you must.) </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>HvyMetalMG</user>
	<review>Intense book and a scary reality that may be our future.  Well, not that bad but a what if hypothesis way before its time.  Classic fiction. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Greatrakes</user>
	<review>I have just re-read this after 30 years. It wasn't, in the end, much of a predictor of the way the post-war world would turn out, either politically or economically. It isn't much of a romance, the love affair between Winston and Julia is Orwell at his most wooden. It is still compelling as a warning of the power of language to distort truth and history, and of the ease with which the population accepts the new world in which some things cannot be said, or even thought. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ksnoodle</user>
	<review>A must read, chilling, amazing. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Shava-chan</user>
	<review>Ein beklemmendes Buch, das so aktuell wie noch nie ist. Als hätte Orwell in die Zukunft gesehen.Zwar ist die Überwachung nicht so extrem wie im Buch beschrieben, hat aber schon stark die Richtung in eine totale Überwachung und gepolte Meinung.Außerdem ist das Buch für mich ein Muss, da ich im Jahr 1984 geboren wurde :) </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ejakub</user>
	<review>Must read classic! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tuff517</user>
	<review>In fifth grade [back in 1982/83] I had a teacher who would say, "Big Brother is watching you" and point her cane to a spot on the wall next to the blackboard. I was scared to death of her, but now I think she was a lunatic. If she was idolizing this book, then she was definitely a lunatic. What a horrible thought of what the future could hold. Nothing scares me more than a government that takes away all of our freedom. I mean, nothing like that could ever happen, right? The government can't influence the media, right? Right? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LibraryLou</user>
	<review>I enjoyed this, but wouldn't read it again, too odd. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>archivesman</user>
	<review>George Orwell's Nineteen Eighty-Four is arguably the most influential book in dystopian literature.  In this book, readers have a compelling story and are continually linking what they read with current events.  Winston Smith, the main character, lives in a nation called Oceania.  Here information is manipulated, and people’s actions are controlled and watched through ubiquitous two-way televisions and an extensive spy network.  Those who break rules either disappear or are ruthlessly punished.  Smith attempts to rebel by becoming more private, taking a lover, and joining a resistance organization.  Readers are engrossed to learn Smith’s outcome. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>marklewis</user>
	<review>Other people usually frown at me when I say this, but I really hate this book.  Maybe I'm too idealistic for dystopia to work for me, but the ending just doesn't ring true. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ljesse</user>
	<review>I read this book 12 years ago for an English book report. I've never been able to forget it. It's the haunting account of Winston Smith, an employee of the Ministry of Truth who hasn't forgotten the past, and who wants to change the future.However, Big Brother is watching him. Try as he might, our hero is trapped in a totalitarian world where he faces extermination if he wants to think as an individual and question the government.Published in 1949 during the Cold War, Orwell puts a spin on communism and totalitarianism that to this day makes my blood run cold. I shutter at the thought of our world ever becoming like Oceania, even in the slighest bit.Highly recommended book for the whole world to read. Let's hope we never come to this. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BrianDewey</user>
	<review>Orwell, George. 1984. Plume, New York, 1949. In today's world of the war on terror, 1984 is a reminder of why citizens of democracies must constantly watch those who hold power with as much care as those who would rob them of their power. There are a couple of eerie parallels between 1984 and 2003. The first is the way war is used to control the population (although Orwell is wrong in one respect: in 2003, war fever is highest among the proles). The second is the mutability of the past. 1980s: We're at war with Iran! 1990s: We're at war with Iraq! 2002: We're at war with al Queda! 2003: We're at war with Iraq because of WMD! 2003: What WMD? We're at war with Iraq because of al Quada! no, because of democracy! The third eerie parallel is the irrelevance of official statistics. The sunset clauses for sizing the tax breaks, the fact that the tax plan will create a million and a half new jobs. Keep the current tax debate in mind when you read the following passage from 1984: Statistics were just as much a fantasy in their original version as in their rectified version. A great deal of the time you were expected to make them up out of your head. For example, the Ministry of Plenty's forecast had estimated the output of boots for the quarter at a hundred and forty-five million pairs. The actual output was given as sixty-two millions. Winston, however, in rewriting the forecast, marked the figure down to fifty-seven millions, so as to allow for the usual claim that the quota had been overfilled. In any case, sixty-two millions was no nearer the truth than fifty-seven millions, or than a hundred and forty-five millions. Very likely no boots had been produced at all. Likelier still, nobody knew how many had been produced, much less cared. All one knew was that every quarter, astronomical numbers of boots were produced on paper, while perhaps half the population of Oceania went barefoot. Fourth: Can't you just picture Fox News leading a two-minutes hate against Osama bin Laden? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DCArchitect</user>
	<review>THE dystopian novel.  As insightful and as relevant (if not more relevant) than ever. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shrubbery</user>
	<review>Perhaps its greatest strength is the way its utter bleakness never becomes depressing. Visceral and cerebral at the same time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ktonks</user>
	<review>I read this book for English class back in high school and it was not at all the sort of novel I gravitated towards back then. But I am glad I pushed my way through it as it really made me think about things for the first time. That and expanded my reading horizons to a whole new genre.It's classic, you can't argue that, and I respect Orwell's style, holds nothing back, no matter how gritty. I think it should be in everyone's library. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rebecca.richardson</user>
	<review>This book opens the readers eyes to a new dimension on what could become of a society who has rejected democracy in favour of a more regimented, over the top communist leadership structure. Demonstrating the abuse of power for the benefit of personal gain, a fascinating read, if only for the ideology behind it. The characters lacked lustre and depth which I felt was missing and as a result failed to draw me into this story. Overall a fair read. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>amagicbeanbuyer</user>
	<review>Eh. I couldn't empathize with the characters-they didn't have enough personality. I guess that was part of the point but I have a hard time getting into a book if I can't get attached to the people in it. It's also very political . . . and I'm not so much. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Amzzz</user>
	<review>I have never read another book that has made me cry so much. Orwell is a genius, but a very depressing man! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Angelic55blonde</user>
	<review>One of the best books out there. In this book, Orwell has set up a society where "big brother" rules. The book actually seems realistic, even now, because there are things we can relate to. A great book! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>smilekb17</user>
	<review>An interesting take on the nature vs nurture debate.  You usually aren't glad that nature has such a strong hold on us that it could weather all of the bad nurturing Big Brother provided these characters.  Or could it?  In a society like this could this really happen?  What percent of the population would succumb and live happily?  How could the leaders retain their humanity among the drones they command?  Would it be better to be in power in this world or average in ours? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jennyo</user>
	<review>I may be the last adult on the planet to read this book, so I certainly don't need to do a plot synopsis or anything. I'll just begin by saying that Orwell set the mood perfectly with his first sentence:"It was a bright, cold day in April, and the clocks were striking thirteen."Strangely enough, my favorite part of the book was Emmanuel Goldstein's manifesto. I thought it had some profound and profoundly disturbing things to say. Here are two that made me shudder because I recognized them so clearly:"And in the general hardening of outlook that set in round about 1930, practices which had been long abandoned, in some cases for hundreds of years--imprisonment without trial, the use of war prisoners as slaves, public executions, torture to extract confessions, the use of hostages and the deportation of whole populations--not only became common again, but were tolerated and even defended by people who considered themselves enlightened and progressive.""Doublethink lies at the very heart of Ingsoc, since the essential act of the Party is to use conscious deception while retaining the firmness of purpose that goes with complete honesty. To tell deliberate lies while genuinely believing in them, to forget any fact that has become inconvenient, and then, when it becomes necessary again, to draw it back from oblivion for just so long as it is needed, to deny the existence of objective reality and all the while to take account of the reality which one denies--all this is indispensably necessary."Chilling, no?This should provide interesting fodder for my book club meeting Monday night. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>legoretrout</user>
	<review>Big Brother is Watching You...absolutely genius.  Orwell, will you marry me? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tharos</user>
	<review>http://blog.tharos-online.de/archives... (german) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Books4Bon</user>
	<review>This book is fantastic. The concepts and characters are touching and just concerning enough. The importance of the issues is vital. Even studying this book back in high school couldn't ruin it for me. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jglovesbooks</user>
	<review>I think this was originally published around 1947, and Orwell paints a grim picture of a utopian society gone horribly wrong.  This is much better that Brave New World, in my opinion. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kidrah</user>
	<review>Read it back in high school - probably didn't appreciate it as much as I would now if I read it voluntarily.  But, it is still one of those books that sticks with you b/c it is so widely referenced and alluded to. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ByrningBunny</user>
	<review>An essential read </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FionaCat</user>
	<review>This is one of my favorite books.  Even 23 years beyond the "future", this novel is still relevant and frightening.  We haven't moved on that much since Orwell wrote it, unfortunately. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jodyreadseverything</user>
	<review>I first read this book when I was fourteen and found it confusing and scary.  I'm not confused by it now but it seems more scary than ever as it becomes more relivant due to our improved technology. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fallentree</user>
	<review>double-plus goodthis book is a must-read, and it SHOULD change how you see politics and history. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kenikki</user>
	<review>Probably the best book ever written. Yet that's open to argument. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Girthii</user>
	<review>Every American should read this book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>elbakerone</user>
	<review>In this classic, George Orwell projects a dark and dismal future of the world where politcal power lies in the hands of a select few and is maintained by constant surveillance, propaganda and thought control of the masses.  This book was amazingly well written as evidenced by the way it has stood the test of time and many of its concepts and references (such as Big Brother) have ingrained themselves in our pop culture.  Almost sixty years after it's original publication and over two decades past its titular year, Orwell's negative utopia still raises many philisophical debates about the power of the media, the liberty of privacy, and the question of the strength of human spirit. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>carissa8402</user>
	<review>Awesome book! It has become one of my favorites! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jenptcfan2007</user>
	<review>http://jenisliterate.blogspot.com/200... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>adamallen</user>
	<review>Read multiple times and one of my top 5 favorite books EVER.  A love story set in a time not so different from our current projected path...Welcome Big Brother. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MerryMary</user>
	<review>So much of this book has entered into our popular culture (Big Brother, doublespeak, Orwellian).  Orwell hit a nerve, and well before the real 1984, people were watching to see how accurate an oracle he was.  In some ways - spot on. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dgussak</user>
	<review>In 1984, the world exists in a state of total war. In London, one of the chief cities of Oceania, the Party exerts a disturbing control over its citizens through a combination of sloganeering propaganda and personal surveillance, and punishes the merest suspicion of unorthodox behaviour with death. From every street corner looms the face of Big Brother, Oceania's mythical leader, drilling its message into every downtrodden soul. But small pockets of resistance remain. Winston Smith, employed to rewrite history in the Ministry of Truth, struggles to remember a time before the Party, before Newspeak, Doublethink, Hate Week and the Thought Police. Away from the prying eyes of the telescreens, he begins to commit a string of seditious acts, culminating in an affair with a fellow worker that will ultimately lead him to the horrors of Room 101. Over fifty years after it was first published, Nineteen Eighty-Four retains all its power to shock and terrify. Sounding a chilling warning about the dangers of totalitarian government, Orwell's dystopian vision fuses literary and political purpose with brilliant effect.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bookalicious</user>
	<review>It is clear from the very first page of this brilliant work why Orwell's 1984 is a world renowned classic.  We see in our times, today, much of his prophetic vision unfolding.  His use of fictional nation-states renders this a timeless work, for even in a future where the nations of today may no longer exist, this novel shall endure.How Orwell managed to bring to the forefront the hopelessness of oppression and the terrible suffering of people under the crushing force of tyranny is without question among literature's finest accomplishments.  I try to imagine that if in the Universe mankind is not alone, how fortunate we are to have within our achievements as a race a novel such as this.  Especially when juxtaposed to all of humanity's shameful acts.Along with Aldous Huxley's Brave New World 1984 is a must read and a must have in any library. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>the_terrible_trivium</user>
	<review>Amazingly dense and, guess what, it's a novel. Not just ideas, also plot and suspense and love and sadness and horror. And bleak as anything. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cestovatela</user>
	<review>One of the first pieces of literature I ever read and enjoyed. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>littlebookworm</user>
	<review>This book is terrifying.  I think the world is closer to his predictions than it was when he wrote it.  I found it stark, startling, and excellent. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bradsucks</user>
	<review>This is another book I had meant to read a long time ago. It was great. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tuesdaynext</user>
	<review>Saddly Orwell ahs become a fortuneteller. Everyone should read this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DLayton</user>
	<review>It is startling how many similarities there are in today's world. A sense of the main character's hopelessness and entrapment is imparted vividly through the text of this novel. The intrusive nature of this stifling world is so detailed, the reader will get consumed by the angst of the the main character and will be relieved yet a little sad when at the close of the book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>benmartin79</user>
	<review>Orwell was a genius. Not so much a literary genius, just - a genius. He combined a depth of perception to his own times surpassing that of almost everyone else, with an amazing predictive ability. 1984 is a good examplar of both talents, though especially Orwell's predictive skill. In fact 1984 is not so much a novel as it is a work of philosophy and sociology - and a brilliant one at that. It's difficult to overstate the importance of this book. It's a veritable prerequisite to reasoned discussion of modern politics both domestic and international, as Orwell exposes many of the most subtle and dirty tricks of politics. On top of all of this analysis of the system, Orwell also subtly (almost too subtly - or else I am simply making it up) raises the question of how one should respond to such a corrupt system. And on top of everything else he manages to craft an engaging and haunting story out of all of it. This book certainly cemented George Orwell's place in the English canon. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Redthing</user>
	<review>1984 is a good book, and I wish I had read it sooner! The only problem I have with this book is where Winston is reading the book. SO boring. Felt like reading a bunch of filler. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ix0x0L</user>
	<review>Very interesting and thought provoking. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rhinoa</user>
	<review>I can't believe I have never read this book before! It was published in 1949 and is set in the future in 1984 in London. Much has changed and the world is divided into three massive powers who are constantly at war with each other: Oceania (Britain and USA), Eurasia (Russia and Europe) and Eastasia (China and Japan). The Party led by central figure Big Brother govern Oceania.We follow WInston Smith as he secretly rebels against The Party and Big Brother. He does this by keeping a diary, hiding from his telescreen (which can be used to watch him as well as constantly putting out propoganda that people are unable to turn off), fornicating with fellow party member Julia and lastly joining The Brotherhood (a secret organisation dedicated to bringing down The Party). Of course Winston is caught by Big Brother and the Thought Police and is taken into custody at The Ministry of Love and tortured.This book was fantastic yet frightening look at a possible future. It is a future we could be heading towards and there are some aspects that are true already. You can see why this book has spawned the ideas for so many other films and books. It can be applied to the different cultures that exist around the world at any time and I believe this book will be timeless. ****1/2 out of 5 </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>scrip79</user>
	<review>http://www.ilpotereelagloria.com/libr... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DreamyEyed</user>
	<review>http://www.indialog.co.in/publication...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fisfia</user>
	<review>Den är inte så super för jag har fortfarande inte kommit igenom den. Har iofs bara försökt en gång så jag ska ge den en chans till snart.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RyanMatts</user>
	<review>Gets better every time I read it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jcovington</user>
	<review>A great read, infinately better than any of the movie adaptations.  Just brilliant. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brose72</user>
	<review>futuristic story that may have not come true in its entiety, but hit the target to some degree. Well written. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ejfertig</user>
	<review>This book has stayed with me over the years. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>janelittlefield</user>
	<review>Amazon.com"Outside, even through the shut window pane, the world looked cold. Down in the street little eddies of wind were whirling dust and torn paper into spirals, and though the sun was shining and the sky a harsh blue, there seemed to be no color in anything except the posters that were plastered everywhere."The year is 1984; the scene is London, largest population center of Airstrip One.... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>iamyuva</user>
	<review>1984 by George Orwell... is a highly antagonistic book of a totalitarianism government in a time of instability. BigBrother and ThoughtPolice constantly monitor all citizens of Oceania with telescreens and if people oppose the party, they were killed. The plot focuses around Winston Smith and the women he later falls in with (Julia) as they begin to realize the truth, quietly defy the party in any small ways they can, and eventually must struggle against the most terrible brainwashing of all.more @ http://toogood2read.blogspot.com/2006... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TheTwoDs</user>
	<review>How can one tell a book is a classic?  One easy way is to see how successive generations of readers react to the book.  Since its publication, readers have consistently proclaimed that Orwell was envisioning their times, their politics, in his story.  It has been regarded as a screed against communism, fascism, the military-industrial complex, and now parallels are drawn between 1984 and the Bush Administration in the United States.  For a work to have this effect on so many people in so many different situations, it truly must be a classic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>randomoasis</user>
	<review>I hate this book.  I was forced into reading it in High school and I hated it.  I tend to put myself into the situations that a protagonist is in, and this is not a book that you want to do that with.  It was awful.  I still managed to get an A on my paper though. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jennifermegan23</user>
	<review>A wonderful social commentary.  Can be applied to many undergrad and grad school classes, or just a fun/enlightening read on one's own.  There is a reason this book is a "classic." </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thall87</user>
	<review>http://littlegreenbook.vox.com/librar...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>In these days of Echelon, Satellite spying, and the ever-increasing proliferation of surveillance cameras, 1984 will definitely leave you with an uneasy feeling.The story of one man's doomed rebellion against almost total totalitarianism, where even the text record of the day and the past can be altered to suit those in power.Many concepts from this novel have entered the common lexicon.http://www.gutenberg.net.au/ebooks01/... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Pitti</user>
	<review>#1 Best book ever </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sfreader.com</user>
	<review>http://www.sfreader.com/read_review.a... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>paradise_city</user>
	<review>This was a classic I missed  in high school. It's a very powerful book, even though it shows its age a bit. However, the world in the story still isn't that far from the world in which we now live. That's disturbing, which was, after all, the intended effect.I particularly liked the way the story ended, with Winston's forced surrender. Not every story has a happy ending because sometimes that sort of ending isn't appropriate. Certainly this is a wake-up call, a warning, a vision that may yet turn out to be shades of the truth. It will stay relevant, as we continue to move forward into the information age, and it marries literature, reality, and ideological danger together quite nicely. It's a book I'd recommend to anyone who somehow missed it. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>coffeezombie</user>
	<review>"The" dystopian novel of the 20th century, and one of the most engaging political statements put forth in modern literature. A brooding parable about the dangers of totalitarianism in general and Stalinism in particular, it details the worthless, tragic rebelion of Winston Smith, a clerk who's job in this future world is to destroy the records of the past to bring them in line with the current political line. Orwell convincingly details a world that is entirely controlled by the all-seeing government authority, while also introducing a whole new set of concepts into our language for describing this sort of restrictive control. The influence of the book has been vast, and every generation has made comparisons to it and their political climate. Yet beyond the weight of that historical baggage is a powerful, intelligent read that is ultimately void of hope.(This review originally appeared on zombieunderground.net) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stipe168</user>
	<review>He called it out before anyone.. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gbanville</user>
	<review>This book may be profitably compared with [[Brave New World]] by [Alduous Huxley]. Both novels present a dystopia, and a world where the political powers have brought culture to a standstill. They deliberately prevent progress and maintain the same social order through a complete manipulation of the people. In this novel it is accomplished through discomfort, privation and conflict, in Brave New World it is accomplished through indulgence, drugs, mindless luxuries, conditioning and drugs. One of the most glaring juxtipositions between these two worlds is in the treatment of sex. In this novel sex is suppressed and attempts are made by powers to remove people's opportunities for it, and their enjoyment of it when they are able to get some. The purpose of this is to keep people frustrated with pent-up energy that can then be harnessed for combative purposes by the rulers. In Huxley's world by contrast people are encoraged to indulge in it frequently as a shallow pleasure and by providing it the masters of the society intend to keep people satasfied and complacent. The reader may choose between these interpretations or choose to see that sex may influence their behavior in different ways in different environments.In both this book and Brave New World the rulers find that improved processes of production require capital to be wasted in order to keep civilization in stasis. In this book they accomplish that through pointless conflict, in Brave New World it is accomplished through pointless luxury consumption.In both cases I would argue that the supposedly permanent power structures are vulnerable to any unforseen natural disaster which would make maintaining the stasis impossible. One might consider the stasis necessary to both situations after considering [[Virginia Postrel]]'s ideas about the stasis/dynamism dichotomy presented in her book, [The Future and its Enemies]. These worlds probably also suffer from the problems inherent in all planned economies as outlined by F. A. Hayek.[[C. S. Lewis]] might have some insights into these two largely artificial worlds in [The Abolition of Man], though [Brave New World] has a great deal more surface resemblence to his predictions than does this one. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>snozzberry</user>
	<review>I'm glad I finally read this book. It was a bit of a depressing read because certain parts reminded me of our current political climate. But the concepts of doublethink, thoughtcrime, and so on are definitely food for thought. In the week or so since I finished reading it, I've found myself thinking about those concepts, in particular when I see an ad or something that says exactly the opposite of what it really is (the "Clear Skies Act" comes to mind right now). </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Unabubbas</user>
	<review>So I picked-up 1984 for a buck in a bargain book bin full of Beverly Cleary and Rachel Ray. I decided to read it for the first time since high school (1989).  Can a book be over-acted?  .  Conceptually, of course, it is solid.  You cannot argue its place in Western history and it truly is a must read. But you know, it is an awkward book.  Fumbling is the word that comes to mind--much like high school.  (I will save you the 1984 Chevy Camaro backseat- with a girl- comparison.) </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>soylentgreen23</user>
	<review>I find it quite cunning on Orwell's part to include, at the end of the book, a glossary of "newspeak" terms. It reinforces the nature of the book, and at the same time hides the ending from those who would look at the last page first, or people like me, who like to know how many pages there are until the end.What more can be said about the book? There are nearly a hundred reviews here, and that number is likely to continue growing as time goes by, so what can another voice add to the chorus? 1984 is clearly an important book, but like so many its warnings go unheeded. Britain has "sleep-walked into being a surveillance society," to quote the BBC. Like so many other dystopian fantasies, this one is likely to become more and more relevant as we go forward. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pauliharman</user>
	<review>Depressing dystopian novel. Hated the ending, but perhaps I didn't understand it... thinking back on it now, that ending was inevitable , and "right" - anything else would not have fit the theme of the work. Doesn't mean I have to like it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>misscatie</user>
	<review>I just flat out do not like Orwell's writing style. He has admitted to writing words for no other reason but for the sake of writing words. I think his message would sink in a lot more if he would just get to the point instead of being so repetitive. His tone also bothers me. It seems arrogant to me, as if he is the only one among us who can see the dangers of the future; that he feels all of us are blissful in our ignorance. </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heatoffusion</user>
	<review>Despite common perceptions, the book is a love story. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ChadReasco</user>
	<review>Oh man the future is going to suck, there's just no getting around it, there's just no way of getting around it man, what am I gonna do, huh?  I can't sleep with my girlfriend cause of society, man, cause of society, it just won't let me do it, oh look there's a camera hiding behind the picture oh yeah here's a lucid dissection of language and politics which I wrote in easy to understand prose form but instead you're reading it in propaganda form WHICH I HATE but anyway check it out it ended in a real bad way for the everyman which is a concept I hate okay I'm writing a novel? here's some poetic stuff at the end okay bye-George Orwell </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>woollymammoth</user>
	<review>I first read this when I was 8, right bang in the middle of my Enid Blyton phase.  A futuristic account of a nightmare tolatitarian future.  book that's become embeded in our culture. Added to this is the fact that Orwell writes wonderfully. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Boktips.net</user>
	<review>http://www.boktips.net/index.php?p=8...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>the1butterfly</user>
	<review>This is the classic story of a world ruled by Communists, as in, Communism as it has been in practice, not as it is in theory.  Like all sci-fi, it takes the possibilities to the extreme, with the entire world embroiled in this struggle for power and divided into three supercountries that constantly fight.  Everything is basically wretched in every way.I really enjoyed this book- I like the writing style, the simplistic fact filled narrative really appeals to me.  I suppose that in most reviews of this book you'd find a long discussion of the horrors the book entails, but I just really enjoyed it.  I didn't grow up in an era when Communism was a major threat, and the terrible future the book describes just doesn't seem possible to me.  Communism will never take over the world, because it isn't an efficient system that encourages people to work hard. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fanakapan</user>
	<review>Essential reading for everyone. Particularly appropriate in these days of CCTV and the nanny state. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MrKris</user>
	<review>I didn't like it as much as Animal Farm (which I read in High School), but when I re-read it for the second time acoupla years back, I couldn't help by be awed by it. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MrsLee</user>
	<review>I had to write down my thoughts as I read this book, which probably means it was a good book, in spite of the fact, or perhaps because of the fact that I kick against it.One thought I agree with, persecutors may be able to achieve control over our actions, but not our thoughts (though possible to some extent), and not what we feel. They may make us say or do anything, but they can't make us agree in our minds.This story seems very feasible and logical, but it doesn't take into account God and His actions. Therefore, I don't think any of this could be achieved on a large scale unless God's Spirit was no longer functioning on this earth and in the hearts of men. There are and have been small-scale attempts at this sort of thing, but they eventually fail because that which is human in us, our gift from God, rebels. Hitler, Russia, North Korea. Another good point from the book, especially in today's culture of no absolutes, "There was truth and there was untruth, and if you clung to the truth even against the whole world, you were not mad."1984 is a good example of what man would be without God, assuming he could be without God, and without His presence. Without God, there is no nobility, love, grace, hope or honor. The Bible says Jesus will return before we destroy ourselves. We usually think of that destruction as a bomb, but this is an example of destroying our "manhood", without actual death. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ErinAshley123</user>
	<review>Very good!  I read this in 10th grade, along with Animal Farm, and it is a good criticism on what the world could turn into if we stop thinking.  If we give up our right to think, we give up our right to live.  This is a great book for everyone to read to open their horizons! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aubergine</user>
	<review>Brilliant. I've read it several times and it's still just as thought provoking. I'm glad I read it in my own time rather then as a set text though, I think it would really loose its edge for me. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DanDanRevolution</user>
	<review>Forceful, provocative and thrilling. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lington</user>
	<review>Orwell's futuristic novel is often referred to as frighteningly accurate in predicting the mindset of the latter half of the 20th century. That may be due to the universal themes he employs. This book is memorable and conceptually strong; it spawned the infamous term "Big Brother" and has perhaps one of the strongest last lines in all of literature, made all the more powerful by its brevity: "He loved Big Brother." For all the pathos that this statement implies, the work is often simplistic in language and trips over a sense of self-importance, much as do Orwell's other works. Hyper-aware of his own use of symbolism, the author attempts to add third and fourth and fifth dimensions to concepts that would have been pleased enough with their lot if they had rested at two. His characters are alarmingly less developed, testifying yet again to the all-consuming nature of his Ideas. It isn't necessarily a negative assessment to say that his thoughts are strong enough to do this, however. This is certainly a book everyone must read and determine the merit of for his or herself. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pap_of_glencoe</user>
	<review>This is one of the few books you will read in your lifetime that is destined to radically alter the way you perceive the world. It is more a scathing critique of modernity than a mere piece of fiction, and tragically it is more relevant today than when it was written 60 years ago. If this novel doesn't absolutely haunt you, then it's too late for you... "Under the spreading chestnut tree, I sold you and you sold me." </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>athene1</user>
	<review>Powerful, inspiring. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sassywho</user>
	<review>Nineteen Eighty-Four depicts a totalitarian society of the future, ruled by an omnipotent dictator called Big Brother. In this society, called Oceania, people's thoughts are controlled as tightly as their actions. The government maintains an organization called the “thought police” and engages in constant propaganda.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>asphyxiad0ll</user>
	<review>Definitely lives up to its status as a classic, and worth reading at least once, if not multiple times. I read it with my best friend, and by the time we were done, everyone we knew wanted to read it because we had been talking about it so much. This is one of my favorite novels simply for the fact that it makes you think *so* much, even if you don't agree with the hype that it shadows the events happening in present day America. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ToDieToTruth</user>
	<review>The most brilliantly paranoid book I've read.  But beyond political paranoia.  It reaches into the realm of the death of our humanity.  What keeps us human, and what withers us away.  And who may try to wither us.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>David_Summers</user>
	<review>Orwell's 1984 is both peculiar and fascinating. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>carriey</user>
	<review>This book was everything I thought it would be.  Honestly, for a little while there, I was getting bored with the book; I told myself to read just a little more.  I'm glad I did because it got better and better! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kawgirl</user>
	<review>This was disturbing when I read it as a teenager. It's more disturbing now because it might be more relevant now. Definitely better than the movie. This book is a must read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alish</user>
	<review>В сборник английского писателя Джорджа Оруэлла (1903-1950) включены его наиболее известные произведения - знаменитый роман-антиутопия "1984" и сатирическая притча "Скотный двор", а также публицистика, в которой отразились острейшие проблемы политической илитературной жизни 30-40-х годов XX века. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lady.lovely</user>
	<review>Amazing book, loved the ending (in retrospect). </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tuckerresearch</user>
	<review>A classic of what could happen if you don't keep your guard up.  This book is about the erosion of individual rights at the expense of the State.  As such, it bears a closer read, particularly because a number of reviewers here and elsewhere make ham-fisted and impotent comparisons between Big Brother and George W. Bush.First, remember that Big Brother's Party is Ingsoc, not Ingtory.  It is left-wing ideology that created the Big Brother state.  It is a liberal party that erased class distinctions on one level (remember the guy in the novel who has a vague memory of top hats) yet governs by putting people into discrete classes.  This is reminiscent of any "democratic-socialist" party in the West today (from Labour to the Democrats) who rail against class and privilege on the one hand, then turn around and praise the "working class" (recall the "proles" in the novel) and demand a myriad of programs for their welfare.  Orwell said he wanted to warn against democratic socialism going arwy, well I, along with Churchill, think that any kind of socialism is impossible without some sort of Gestapo.  Any government that thinks it knows better than the people, then makes recommendations for the people, will eventually turn "recommend" into "demand," and then "force."  At its heart, "evil" Bush's Republican Party and the Thatcherite Tories want less government and less lordship over the individual, though Bush has not done as he should have, and has nothing on Calvin Coolidge or even Ronald Reagan.  But it is the Democrats in the US and Labour in the UK that wants further government control over the individual.  Don't believe me?  With socialized healthcare, for instance, will eventually come recommendations for "your own good."  Left-wingers propose a number of programs to take from one and dictate to another.  Left-wingers stifle any dissent of what they consider sacred, from abortion to global warming.  It is a warning against parties that would pervert JFK's maxim into "Ask not what you can do for your country, but what your country can do for you."  It is a warning against political leaders who promise baubles and monies to the people to garner their vote.  And later their submission.So please remember that 1984 is about Ingsoc, English Socialism, not Ingtory, English Conservatism.  If Bush was really as Big Brotherish as reviewers here would have you believe, you ever wonder why dissent is so loud in this country?  Would Big Brother Bush, if he was as evil as the government in 1984's Oceania, would he allow people to compare him to 1984?  No.  Are thousands of Americans tortured for no reason?  And, since we're on the subject, does giving an Al-Qaeda un-uniformed combatant three squares a day and maybe water-boarding him and sleep-depriving him really compare to the harsh tortures described in 1984?  Please, please, please, stop trying to make the villain of 1984 a "right-wing" Bush - it is manifestly a left-wing, dictatorial socialism (think Stalin) that Orwell is warning us against.  Not a "dictator" like Bush who can't even stop people from mocking him, can't even get his old press secretary to not write disparaging books about him, can't even fix the 2006 congressional elections, and can't even sneak a few old warheads into Iraq to point out to the press.  What a dictator, what a Big Brother.This screed has now ended.Perhaps in my attack on  those that see the book as right-wing, Bush-type stuff I am focusing too much on the left-wing aspect of the book.  Thus, I will now quote what I actually consider an excellent and fair-minded review from here at LibraryThing, by one user "ianracey," as I think it better captures Orwell's point than I can:"What I find most impressive about Orwell's vision of the future are both its prescience and its political neutrality. All the most chilling aspects of Big Brother's totalitarian government--constant electronic surveillance of its citizens, rewriting history to serve the political concerns of the day, the infiltration of society by secret police--are really just exaggerations (well, one hopes that they're exaggerations) of practices that our own Western democratic governments engage in today, and have been engaging in for the past two generations. And what's more, they're practices that have been followed by parties at either end of the political spectrum--by supposedly small-government Republican (American) and Conservative (British) governments just as much as by liberal Democrats (American) or socialist Labour (British). Orwell's dark vision sees society as a whole, not just one ideology or another."Indeed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DeusEx0352</user>
	<review>One of the first, and still one of the best, books on dystopias. One of those essential reads. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nillacat</user>
	<review>I didn't like this much when I was required to read it in high-school freshman English class. It was bleak and creepy and predictable. I should probably re-read it. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mortaine</user>
	<review>I read this to gain some insight into our political climate. I found it chilling. I also decided that you just couldn't write a book like this on a computer. No one would put up with the novel rather abruptly changing in little, insidious ways..... (unless that was deliberate? It may have been!) I'm referring, for example, to the hierarchy of the Party, which for the first hundred pages or so is not described. It's not that it's described one way and then changed. Rather, it's vague. And then it's as if Orwell shouted "Eureka!" and the Inner Party and the Outer Party were born. By the end of the novel, the classes are so stratified, Orwell can write a whole political tract on them.... and does. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>papskier</user>
	<review>Damn good book!  After reading, see the movie for an interesting view of it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dylanwolf</user>
	<review>Read it because you should. It's not the easiest of tasks, Orwell can be a bit ponderous, but this book is inventive and a true classic. Those that think our society has actually gone this way are deluded and should recognise that if anyone is controlling British society now it is capitalists and commercial interests not the government. People, we do not live in a nanny state, Brave New World is closer to actualite. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>transmutations</user>
	<review>Favorite book!  I've read this 5 or 6 times.  The tale is a great picture of life in a totalitarian regime, particularly of the Soviet Union and her former satellites. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bjfan82</user>
	<review>It's pretty eerie how many things word-for-word from this book seem to be happening in our world and country today.  This book is the king of the dystopian genre. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CaptainBroadchurch</user>
	<review>Boring and impossible to like.  A book for the kind of dreadful people who like to imagine that, of all the abuses and brutality a fascist state is capable of inflicting upon its population, they'd find distortion and control of the truth the worst - the street beatings, massive corruption and state approved murders would probably concern me more than the prospect of "being rehabilitated" and betraying the truth.Even ignoring this, 1984 is a dull novel that is so cluttered with ropey symbolism that it makes Animal Farm look subtle:  The snow globe, the nookie in the woods, the rambling on about the measurement of beer and gin, all combine to form a picture of Orwell forever mashing his overly laboured point into a human face.  The theme of human betrayal and Big Brother's corruptive influence on society that underpins much of the novel is just as awkward and clumsy as the devices through which it acts:  where some art may be said to mimic life, 1984 is a mere caricature of the horrors of totalitarianism.Even so, at least it isn't Keep the Aspidistra Flying. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Simes</user>
	<review>Newspeak and doublethink, Big Brother watching our every move. A terrifying vision of a future Britain;  how ironic that Orwell's real name was Blair. I think we should be told. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nakmeister</user>
	<review>One of the true classic science fiction novels, it's  got some revolutionary ideas, not least the concept of "Big Brother" (not the tv show!). If you're going to read it, I'd suggest reading it for the experience, to see for yourself the vision of the future (admittedly now 22 years in the past) that it so cleverly portrays. As an enjoyable, gripping read however I think it falls short. It's also quite depressing! </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>emcron</user>
	<review>finally i read the great Orwell. it was mindblowing. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jauntyjinty</user>
	<review>I love this book. I read it first when I was 16 and then again 10 years later.  I'm planning a revisit when I get to 36 and i'm sure it will be just as relevant as it ever was. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>joyriders</user>
	<review>I have read this book twice. Once in 1999, and again in 2005.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jediphil683</user>
	<review>Not exactly perfect, but more than a little readable and brilliantly bleak, Orwell's story has to be read to truly be appreciated. It's more than just a book at this point; it's permeated culture. Not enough to keep us on our toes as we should be, granted...My main complaint is the stiffness of his language, as is the case with every one of his books. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>saltypuppy</user>
	<review>One of the best books of all time! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>overthemoon</user>
	<review>by sheer coincidence this edition was printed in 1984 (and I only just noticed). I can't really say I like it, but it is one of things you just have to read. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kattepusen</user>
	<review>****1/2This was the first book I read in English! I have read it again a couple of times, and it still startles me. The characters are unforgettable and the mood is simply extraordinary. Furthermore, if you're are going to use the terms "Big Brother" or "Double-speak", make sure you actually have read the background from where you've taken the quotes. (Actally, for me the very name Winston always makes me think of this particular main character). Everyone should read this at least once in their life... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aMenalque</user>
	<review>Not as good as Animal Farm, or the criminaly under-rated Homage to Catalonia, this book is slow, relative to his other works, which causess it to lose momentum and power.Whilst on many levels this is a fantastic book in many respects, its intelligence and undercurrent of irony, it is let down both by itself, and by the people who read it. On its own, it lacks the sheer futility present in other dystopian books, such as Brave New World, or the claustrophobic atmosphere of others, such as We (Zamyatin, if you havn't already, read this). It is clever, especially in regards to the ideas behind the violence. The physical is only one aspect of the 'treatment', it is the need for Winston to love his tormentor, and hate and despise his lover that really are disturbing, the fickelty of humans.The main reason I have been slightly put off this book is that it is almost inevitable that 3 out of 4 people will insist on saying "who'd of thought, 1984 is coming true, just as Orwell predicted". Admitedlly the majority who say this have never read the book. But 1984 was NOT an attempt to predict the future (unlike Brave New World), it was purely aan assesment of the political situation in the Cold War. All the elements Orwell discusses were already in place in society in 1948, they were already true. This also dates the book slightly, especially refrences to Soviet, Nazi(until 1946), British and US youth enrollment schemes, British propaganda and the importance of individual leadership.This does deserve its status as a classic in many ways, and it did introduce me to the Dystopian genre. However, it is by no means the best in this category, and also not the best of Orwell's work, which most go to something more powerful, probably Animal Farm.aM </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sa54d</user>
	<review>Everyone should read this book. And then re-read it. Even after the year came to pass and some of the predictions did not come true (or at least not in exactly the way the novel describes) 1984 stands as the great anti-authority (and anti-authoritarian) novel of all time. Often not commented upon is the essay at the end about the language "Newspeak" which along with Orwell's other essays about the use and abuse of language has immediate applications to understanding present day media and politics. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Wanderlust_Lost</user>
	<review>This book is an absolute classic.  Orwell's futuristic tale of how a government who tries to keep its citizens happy by removing all their pleasures and controlling their every move actually creates more misery through its strangelhold than it does happiness.  A chilling depiction of a world where history is revised to suit the current governmental designs on war and those who dare to complain about a lack of food or clothing, or to even keep a diary or demand time alone or engage in love or sex are captured and tortured.  Big Brother is watching you!  This book is an amazingly prescient view on totalitarian police states. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>schmal06</user>
	<review>This is definitely one of my favorite books. I haven't read anything else by Orwell but I really should look into it. I couldn't put this one down. Even if you don't typically read political books (I certainly don't) I guarantee you will find this prophetic novel fascinating. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>christophax</user>
	<review>1984 was my set text for my English literature exam. I am usually able to grasp the plot and the character details that not many people can find, but with 1984 it is rather difficult. The rating i give this book is 3. Low does it seem, but i would've thought i was rather generous as i found this book too monotonous at times (too dark and depressing, as one of my teachers have said, you really do feel for winston at times). I would recommend this book to all those who like stories with many 'strings' to it, lots of twists, and even more so, by sir eric blair. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thf1977</user>
	<review>1984 is one of the most unpleasant and at the same time excellent books in my collection. I can't say much about it not already said, except that I was specifically inspired by the argument for the importance of language and vocabulary as the prerequisites for thought, i.e. if you haven't got a word for something you can't (easily) think about it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>k8_not_kate</user>
	<review>Probably one of the bleakest dystopian novels I have come across, 1984 centers on a timid but free-thinking man named Winston in an oppressive totalitarian government of the future. The novel documents Wilson's highly illegal affair with a woman from the government office in which he works and his (also criminal) private diary. While it certainly qualifies as a dark, if not hopeless novel, 1984 is an excellent read and will probably always be relevant. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>snoflingor</user>
	<review>I guess I am in the minority but I really did not like this book. I wasn't impressed with the prose and the plot wore thin. Though it may work as a political manifesto, as a work of literature I find it falls short. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zsms</user>
	<review>Thought provoking classic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>elonole</user>
	<review>Your every move is recorded by the government "Big Brother" who also controls everything you see and hear, including altering what was told and recorded in the past.I read this because it was a "classic" and it's referenced all the time i.e. "it's like Big Brother," but I'm giving it a 2.  I felt it was a nonstop rant from Orwell and it was depressing.  Unless your English teacher makes you... don't read this book.  P.S. It only gets the second star, because it's one of those "you haven't read 1984?" books.  rsr </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dirtyunicorn</user>
	<review>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nineteen... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>readingbackwards</user>
	<review>https://readingbackwards.wordpress.com... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>krissit13</user>
	<review>It's a classic, and you can't deny that. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>danbarrett</user>
	<review>This book was a huge influence on my band! And properly blew the mind of a young 7th grader. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>edwartica</user>
	<review>While reading the tenth chapter of George Orwell’s Animal Farm, I was reminded heavily of a principle that Orson Scott Card shows in Shadow of the Hegemon. That principle is as follows: Unity in the face of danger or oppression will dissolve once the threat or the oppression is over and at this point the group or leader shall replace the previous oppressor or threat. Aristotle’s theories might show this as a likeness. Consider the following: In Animal Farm, the animals revolt against the humans, the oppressors. The animals form a new society, and the pigs (lead by Napoleon) take the place of the original human farmer, going as far as wearing human clothes, walking upright, and even playing cards with the humans. In the end of the chapter, the pigs act and look so human, that one cannot decipher between the two beings. In Shadow of the Hegemon, the world is in the aftermath of winning against a terrible invader, the buggers. The unity and peace that the world saw during the war with the buggers quickly dissolved, while old hatreds, rivalries, and power struggles quickly reemerged. Eventually these struggles lead to the world lead by Peter Wiggin (who had been shaping public opinion for years), with the help of one of the masterminds behind the defeat of the buggers: Bean. 	These two novels do not share the same exact ground when it comes to this unnamed principle if in fact this principle does in fact exist (William James of Albany might argue that it does exist, but has just never been named). Animal Farm shows that nothing has in fact changed. The pigs have become human, and thus will lead the farm in the same way the humans did. Shadow of the Hegemon, also shows nothing has changed. The world still wars with itself. However, Peter Wiggin does not adopt the principles of the invaders, for the invaders had a collective “hive? mentality much like that of bees and ants. Instead, Peter will gather the nations (through a series of wars). At the end of Ender’s Game (the first novel in a parallel series) the reader sees that Peter Wiggin was (and will be) a dictator, but a benevolent dictator. Peter replaces the threat of the Buggers with the threat of his own empire, but rules in a different way. Therefore, this cannot fall under the category of interdependence (though Card more than likely read Orwell). There are too many similarities to follow contrast (although some arguments can be made for this category). These events do not share a connection in time (that anyone is aware of). While both happen on the same planet, the farm is not an important part of Shadow of the Hegemon, therefore this connection cannot fall under the category of connectives in space. Therefore, the connection must be a likeness, for while both books share the same concepts, they approach this concept differently. Though both books have many parallels, they do not coincide completely with one another. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kellibee</user>
	<review>I love this book. It shows you that skepticism is healthy, and you can't just go through life following and not questioning others. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>celestialfingerpaint</user>
	<review>This book was required reading in High School, and I enjoyed it enough to want a copy of my own. It doesn't end the way I wanted it to, but that just adds to the realism of the story. While I think people who see signs everywhere that the things Orwell wrote about are coming to pass are a bit paranoid, there's no denying that certain elements of the story are much more applicable to the world today than they were when it was first published. It's a well written book that draws you in, makes you feel for the characters, and lets you really experience the world they live in. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>notmyrealname</user>
	<review>It is a difficult thing to explain, but it is a funny feeling reading for the first time what everybody else has seemingly read before you. As you discover a whole new world, you then realise it has been discovered by others many many times before. I have seldom read a book which so twists the mind and the reality that we live in. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jhw</user>
	<review>A horrible but powerful book, and it is worth considering why. It is not that the society he depicts is really credible. Even if we could believe that religion would disappear so easily as he suggests, we cannot accept the idea of so much energy spent on retaining power for its own sake - power as an end and not as a means. But a satirist is not concerned to paint a credible picture. He is concerned to bring out the evils of his society by exaggeration or caricature, and it is by his success in that that he should be judged. Orwell's concern appears to be to show just how far control of men's ideas can go, and to make his point he imagines two terrifyin techniques: i) The systematic falsification of the records of the past so that it becomes absolutely impossible to prove that the Party has ever been wrong.ii) The development of  new language with a progressively dimishing vocabulary which makes it increasingly difficult even to think insubordinately because the words in which such thought could be expressed do not exist.Now these ideas do seem credible; and so do some of the deductions he draws from them, e.g.:i) that it is possible not just to crush the spirit of the rebel but to change his innermost mind and make him really believe that the Party is right after all.ii) that the younger generation, typified by Julia, would revolt, if at all, purely as individuals and on selfish grounds. The idea of the Party actually being overthrown is to them unthinkable. They take it for granted as rabbits do foxes, as he says somewhere.This is what gives the book its power. The society as a whole may be incredible. But the techniques of totalitarianism are not. They could possibly exist.It is odd that there should be a character in the book called Ampleforth.(notes written 1954)</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tjeffress</user>
	<review>http://www.i-reports.info/b/B199912.h... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ctroutma</user>
	<review>My favorite book from junior high.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sdtaylor555</user>
	<review>This was a great book.  This one will make you think, but it's entertaining too--unlike most classic books.  Don't miss out on this one. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mattviews</user>
	<review>Eric Blair's 1984 is not only his finest work but also one of the most influential and provocative books of our time. The work obviates to us to full actuality how the world had evolved for the worse during the dark period from 1932 to 1949. Winston Smith and O'Brien are the most important characters whose keystone dialogue raises alert for the prospect of human future. Prophecy or Caution?While we might prefer to interpret "1984" as a precautionary tale or some social warning, bloodshed, warfare, massive torture and murder, not to mention Stalin's cruelty, the Nazi mechanized techniques of organized massacre, the Cambodian, the Iranian and the Iraqi, the North Korean, and all the other countless horrors, have inevitably to a certain degree changed "1984" from caution to warning, further elevating the work to a 20th century prophecy.Despair about Future of ManA sense of hopelessness about the future of man hovers over the book. In a way "1984" is an expression of such a hopeless mood about the bleak future of man. It warns readers that unless the course of history (and leaderships) changes men all over the world will forfeit most of their human qualities and become soulless automatons without being aware of the depravity.In the Winston Smith-O'Brien dialogue, "Imagine a boot stamping on the human face-forever" might have exaggerated the current state of human soulness. The 20th century history has confirmed and fulfilled dehumanized practices as mentioned in "1984" like 24/7 surveillance of all sounds, activities, and conversations; deprivation of freedom of speech, penitence for thought crime and wiping out of existence and memory and thus forfeiting any way to make appeal to future. For example, a Party member lived from birth to death under the eye of the Thought Police. Even when he was alone he could never be sure he was alone. Wherever he may be, he could be inspected without warning and without knowing that he was being inspected.The Party tacitly encouraged prostitution as such outlets for instincts that could not be altogether suppressed. This unforgivable crime was promiscuity between Party members in order to remove all pleasure from sexual act. Even to his wife, a Party member was expected to have no private emotions and no respites from enthusiasm. A real romantic love affair was all it took to crumple the Party. Desire was deemed thought crime, which entailed death.The Party saw that it was not infallible and that all its belief rested on the omnipotent Big Brother. It therefore called for an unwearying, moment-to-moment flexibility in the treatment of facts-alteration of the past and rewrite of history in order to wipe out existence of certain human beings and historical facts. It was not merely that speeches, statistics, and records of every kind must be constantly brought up to date in order to show that the predictions of the Party were in all cases accurate. It was also that no change of doctrine or in political alignment could ever be admitted. Whatever the Party held to be truth was truth. It was impossible to see reality except by looking through the eyes of the Party. Notwithstanding the Party contrived to have its way and imbued the belief in people, how could the Party control people's memory? The Party had wiped out most of the older generation during the great purges and the few who survived had long ago been terrified into complete intellectual surrender (sounds familiar like the Chinese Cultural Revolution?) When memory failed and written records were falsified, the claim of the Party to have improved the conditions of human life had got to be accepted, because there did not exist, and never again could exist, any standard against which it could be tested."1984" is meant to be read as a warning, an exhortation, and not so much prophesy. However exaggerated and haunting the negative utopia is being depicted, the book is a startling work of an imaginary world that is convincing. 4.0 stars. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jayceebee</user>
	<review>I know this is a classic, but it gives me the heebie-jeebies.  I hate the ending and the thing with the rat or mice or whatever.  I much prefer other books in this vein like Brave New World or War of the Worlds. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hippietrail</user>
	<review>If you like this, I highly recommend Huxley's Brave New World and even more highly the not so well known We by Yevgeny Zamyatin. There is a direct line of influence between these three works. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Leikela4</user>
	<review>I've read this book (as of 12/05/05) 5 times.  Definitely a favorite. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Boost</user>
	<review>This is one of those great classic books that just HAS to be read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>robotheart</user>
	<review>Actually, the copy I have was my dad's, and is so old it's not in Amazon anymore. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>librarychick</user>
	<review>Nineteen Eighty-Four (often 1984) is a darkly satirical political novel written by George Orwell. The story takes place in a nightmarish dystopia where the omnipresent State enforces perfect conformity among members of a totalitarian Party through indoctrination, propaganda, fear, and ruthless punishment. The novel introduced the concepts of the ever-present, all-seeing Big Brother, the notorious Room 101, the ubiquitous thought police, and the bureaucrats' and politicians' language Newspeak. Many commentators draw parallels between today's society and the world of 1984, suggesting that we are starting to live in what has become known as Orwellian society.http://www.answers.com</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>josephtate</user>
	<review>Excellent edition. Worth having for Thomas Pynchon's forward. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tsinandali</user>
	<review>I have to admit that I read this book after finding out that Eurythmics were writing the score to a movie version.  Before that bulletin, I'd never even heard of the work.  A much better work than the movie they worked for.  I'm not much of a fan of much else Orwell wrote outside of Animal Farm--this work is better than that work in its human scope. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gnewfry</user>
	<review>Amazon.com"Outside, even through the shut window pane, the world looked cold. Down in the street little eddies of wind were whirling dust and torn paper into spirals, and though the sun was shining and the sky a harsh blue, there seemed to be no color in anything except the posters that were plastered everywhere."The year is 1984; the scene is London, largest population center of Airstrip One.Airstrip One is part of the vast political entity Oceania, which is eternally at war with one of two other vast entities, Eurasia and Eastasia. At any moment, depending upon current alignments, all existing records show either that Oceania has always been at war with Eurasia and allied with Eastasia, or that it has always been at war with Eastasia and allied with Eurasia. Winston Smith knows this, because his work at the Ministry of Truth involves the constant "correction" of such records. "'Who controls the past,' ran the Party slogan, 'controls the future: who controls the present controls the past.'"In a grim city and a terrifying country, where Big Brother is always Watching You and the Thought Police can practically read your mind, Winston is a man in grave danger for the simple reason that his memory still functions. He knows the Party's official image of the world is a fluid fiction. He knows the Party controls the people by feeding them lies and narrowing their imaginations through a process of bewilderment and brutalization that alienates each individual from his fellows and deprives him of every liberating human pursuit from reasoned inquiry to sexual passion. Drawn into a forbidden love affair, Winston finds the courage to join a secret revolutionary organization called The Brotherhood, dedicated to the destruction of the Party. Together with his beloved Julia, he hazards his life in a deadly match against the powers that be.Newspeak, doublethink, thoughtcrime--in 1984, George Orwell created a whole vocabulary of words concerning totalitarian control that have since passed into our common vocabulary. More importantly, he has portrayed a chillingly credible dystopia. In our deeply anxious world, the seeds of unthinking conformity are everywhere in evidence; and Big Brother is always looking for his chance. --Daniel HintzscheThis review has been flagged by multiple users as abuse of the terms of service
						 and is no longer displayed (show).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>oakesspalding</user>
	<review>1984 is the most profound work of fiction to deal with totalitarian communism. That particular evil seems to be over now--except, of course, for the poor North Koreans--so I suspect the novel will be read less frequently as the years go on.  While studying in London in the 80's, I remember a poll of Conservatives and Laborites on their most influential book.  The Laborites picked some now outdated sociological tract, while the Conservatives picked 1984.  Soon after, Thatcher and Reagan, building on the insight and determination of those who saw communism for what it was, brought The Wall down.  The novel did its work.  ***** </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nwhyte</user>
	<review>http://nhw.livejournal.com/459308.htm...Just a few things that struck me on rereading:   1. It's not so much a novel as a set of political statements framed as tragedy.   2. There is, however, a genuine moment of suspense for the first time reader when we don't know if O'Brien is really a counter-revolutionary or not.   3. Julia as a character is better drawn than I remembered. I think that when I first read the book I was hoping she would "really" be as ideological as Winston, but in fact her approach is an important contrast to his. "You are only a revolutionary from the waist down" is one of the most important lines in the book.   4. Room 101, taken on its own, actually isn't very terrifying - it only acquires its impact from what has come before. But it does give the plot another element of suspense after the main question - will they manage to overthrow Big Brother or not? - has been answered. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>peskymac</user>
	<review>http://www.peskyapostrophe.com/index.... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pippolo</user>
	<review>il protagonista vive in una sociata ipercontrollata  in cui non esiste liberta' di pensiero</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Natalie220</user>
	<review>This book was not for me, but it was something different for a change.  The way these people live is in ignorance and in fear and their surroundings sound like that of a prison. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451524934</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tedrick</user>
	<review>OUR WORLD FEELS JUST A TAD TO MUCH LIKE THE SCENARIO IN THIS BOOK </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>