<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sturlington</user>
	<review>Next to The Stand, this is my favorite Stephen King book. I have reread it several times and could read it many more without growing tired of it. It has a lot to say about childhood, growing up, what we're afraid of and how we overcome that fear. The bittersweet ending always makes me cry. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>oxlena</user>
	<review>I loved the movie, so I was afraid to read the book for fear that I wouldn't be able to watch the movie anymore. I was mistaken. The book only intensified the movie. SO much more happens in the book, the ending is totally different (much weirder than the movie), but at the same time, you can't help but appreciate both. The novel goes in depth in a way that the movie never could (unless it were five and a half hours long), but still without ruining the film for you. I definitely recommend it. If you're not afraid of clowns now, you will be soon. 4/5 clowns that you can't help but picture in fishnets. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TurningThePages</user>
	<review>I read this when I was 16, in high school.It took me about 3 months to read (and I considered myself a fast reader!), but it was so worth it. I had seen the movie first (I practically grew up watching it!), but the book was just...fantastic. It was the first Stephen King novel I read, so I wasn't used to his style of writing, which took some getting used to.I loved how he created this world that I felt so involved in, I felt like I lived there, and really CARED about these characters. I am glad I didn't let the size of it intimidate me, because I enjoyed every single second of reading it- it had me scared from the first page. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JordanLangston</user>
	<review>Stephen King's It is a horror novel set in the small, fictional town of Derry, Maine. The story revolves around six children and their encounters with It during the summer of 1958. Later on they return to Derry as adults to destroy It, once and for all.[SPOILER] 'It' is in actual fact a shapeshifting Cannibalistic Humanoid Underground Dweller who appears to have hibernated beneath Derry for millions of years since before even the arrival of humans. It frequently takes on the appearance of Pennywise the Clown, in which disquise he often tricks children and eats them. But Pennywise has been known to take on the shape of vampires, werewolves and such. [END].It, consists of around 1116 pages, the longest novel I have read to date, and if I'm honest however much I love this book, the length of it is, somewhat painful. Reason being is King takes pride in the creation of his storyline and the developement of his characters, many characters who appear for sometimes only a chapter of so have there own unique personality, no character is the same. The build-up to the climax, which is how you could say 'kick-ass', requires too much description so the reader is able to understand.This book was one of the best I've ever read and I had a feel of great self-satisfaction once I'd finished it, because I didn't let it beat me. Remember it has 1116 pages, I wouldn't recommend it to a person who has little time on their hands, but I would to those who are up for a challenge. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrtall</user>
	<review>Although it's not Stephen King's best horror novel --  Salem's Lot and The Stand slug it out for that honor -- it's perhaps his most characteristic. All of King's major themes and tropes are on their fullest display here: the Derry, Maine setting; the child heroes; the heavily-described yet still mysterious monster; and the astonishing breadth of story development, with innumerable subplots and memorable minor characters.I reread this recently, having not given it a look in many years. I was struck by how politically-incorrect it is! King has his child characters slinging racial slurs, mocking each others' physical flaws and disabilities, and never doubting that some people are simply evil, crazy or both. It left me wondering if some of the lameness that's crept gradually into his later novels is due to his need to tone things down, at the price of his ability to depict how people -- especially the child characters of which he's so fond -- really think.It's only flaw is its colossal length. At 1116 fairly closely-printed pages in paperback, it's quite an undertaking. Although no one section of the book really flags, I did occasionally lose patience just a bit with King stringing out the storyline with scenes that were if not exactly repetitive, at least similar.But don't let this one very minor criticism put you off -- this a superb read, and highly recommended. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>doreengraham</user>
	<review>Love this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>msouliere</user>
	<review>I read Stephen King's It last summer, for the first time. It's great summer reading, a good followup to reading Dan Simmons' Summer of Night during summer 2007.I noticed a couple of things in reading it. Number one, practically ALL my friends read it when they were young, somewhere around 12 or 13 years old. At that age I was pathologically opposed to reading horror on the scale of Stephen King, after an abortive attempt at reading Salem's Lot. It terrified me. I didn't realize until in my 20s that fighting against that horror and working through it is good. REALLY good.Number two, and leading from that, I think I would have been better off if I had read some horror then, especially It. I mean, yes, I enjoyed a singularly naive childhood, which in some ways (many ways) touches the quality of my life now. And I don't think it's always a good thing to grow up quickly as a child. But a little bit of the experiential information that Stephen King codes into his child characters probably would have helped me a lot.For instance: the segment where Eddie Kaspbrak is recalling his beating by Henry (Harry?) Bowers, and his epiphany about placebos and the needs of his mother. His instruction, both by himself, the adults, and the circumstances surrounding him is... well it's hard to describe, but reading it, the sense of empowerment and truth is palpable. I think I could have benefited from that as a kid. I spent too much time simply allowing myself to be led along, and then suffered when it came time to effect great changes on my own all at once.Musings... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BaileysAndBooks</user>
	<review>Confirmed my fear of clowns. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raznluke</user>
	<review>this is the first novel out of school that i read.  It was amazing.  I still walk past street drains and think of clowns. A must read</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brianclegg</user>
	<review>I was rather disdainful of horror writers and King in particular before I read this - but you really do have to admire both his craftmanship and his portrayal of small town Maine. The man knows how to write. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Luba_B.</user>
	<review>My all-time SK's favorite </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lnr_blair</user>
	<review>Stephen King is a master storyteller, and although this isn't among his very best it's an enjoyable brick of a book, with a dark tale running through the lives of 7 childhood friends, and coming back to haunt them nearly 30 years later.  Good old fashioned gory scary fun. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>beatbox32</user>
	<review>I've just finished my first Stephen King novel. I'm totally blown away. The characters in this book are top notch. The story, though at first seeming excessively long, really brought me closer to the Losers Club and to a deep understanding of what they were up against in the town of Derry. I was instantly transported to parts of my childhood and reminded of the fears that used to grip my naive little mind. I would definitely recommend this book to first-time King readers. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ruerue2u2</user>
	<review>the fears of youth coming to get you. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>PatrickHackeling13</user>
	<review>IT by Stephen KIng is the essence of horror.  It encapsulates almost every aspect of one's psyche and how to distort and ultimately destroy it.  A pinch gorier and a tad lengtheir than the movie, IT, the novel, is and will most likely be the scariest novel that I have ever had the... pleasure to read.Just like there is a slap-stick genre of humor, there is a bloody-mess genre of horror too.  IT is nothing like this.  Do not get me wrong.  It has IT's fair share of blood in it (it basically seeps off the page), but it goes so much further than that.  Now, whenever I hear the words penny and wise in the same sentence I bug out waiting for my worst fear to come true.  Because, that is truly what IT is.  Your worst fear coming to life.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jharp</user>
	<review>My favorite King book.  I love a good scary story, but this book actually scared me! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>skinglist</user>
	<review>I was never afraid of Clowns or storm drains before I read this. Pennywise is here. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kitana</user>
	<review>Esperava mais do autor, principalmente porque comprei o livro depois de ler resenhas falando muitíssimo bem deste título. Em momento algum, "A Coisa" sequer me provocou arrepios. Na verdade, parece mais com uma história de terror infanto-juvenil excessivamente comprida. Simplesmente não me convenceu. Quem quiser ler uma história assustadora de verdade, procure por outro título de King. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thesizzler</user>
	<review>I made it 300 pages and had to stop. Sadism and gore for gore's sake is apparently not one of my literary interests. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>JechtShot</user>
	<review>I have been a Stephen King fan for many years now, but for some reason It was always placed on the backburner.  I finally finished It and It is probably my second favorite King novel (The number one slot remains with The Stand).It tells the story of a primeval entity that haunts Derry, Maine approximately every 30 years.  King breaks the story into two basic parts; what happened to It when the main characters were kids and what happens to It now that the kids have grown up.  There are some fantastic scary bits to the story, but my favorite element is King's perspective on the old versus the young.  Yes, the story is clearly a horror novel with all the gruesome gore we have grown accustomed to, but there is much more to this particular novel.  I had to take pause towards the end of the book to try and remember some of the moments from my early teenage years and I was quite surprised how distant some of those memories have become.It is a must read for fans of the horror genre. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>princesspeaches</user>
	<review>To this day, I'm still scared of clowns. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>santhony</user>
	<review>One of those truly well written stories that is ultimately damaged when the story becomes too silly for words. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>PghDragonMan</user>
	<review>One of the creepiest King stories, but ends up only a little above average. The story is readable with enough hooks to keep you turning pages, but there is no real substance to it. Many of the scenes are mediocre and do little to advance the plot.  An example is the obligatory sex scene; it is not graphic enough to be a real sex scene and not vapid enough to be totally ignored. The characters are not overly well developed but they are not exactly flat either. Example: the young girl physically abused by her father; if not for that, there's no sympathy for her character.Good travel reading or if you cannot find anything new to read. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rachellek</user>
	<review>Scariest book I have ever read! </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ilvale</user>
	<review>Si legge bene anche se lungo, ma il finale è un po' troppo concitato e banale </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SlySionnach</user>
	<review>Great horror novel. There's very little that creeps me out lately, but this is definitely up there. The idea of having a Creature from the "Outside" that can appear to be anything that horrifies you and kill you that way is simply disturbing. I really enjoyed the way that King melded the original group in 1958 with the adult group in 1985. The chapters flowed into one another just like we flow back into memories. We could see from the seven Loser's point of view, or one of the evils (Patrick, Henry, It). I liked seeing how utterly innocent children are to believe in anything, and then to try and make the adults come back to believe it as well. I liked how crazy he made the insane characters, and how he tied everything about Derry into this one Creature.The only thing that really bothered me was the last 100 or so pages. I don't think we needed to read about what Bev and the boys do in the tunnels... especially under the pretense that it will "bond" them together. As a previous reviewer said, it's another level of creepy. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lalaland</user>
	<review>I wish I could say I remember this book's complexities, but it's impossible to recall all those details (even though I read it twice).  Despite the obvious downfall of not being able to remember the plot's nuances, I still count this book as one of my favorites.  The intricacies of the characters, the town and their relationship to each other is fascinating.  In this novel, the horror and monsters are secondary to the subplot about small town evil. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>micahcbrown</user>
	<review>Another of my all time favorites. A group of children must fight the evil in their town that feeds not only on flesh, but fear. It's a great tale of the loss of innocence and how things can happen that change your entire life. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>silversurfer</user>
	<review>Has some really scary scenes and great Plot, characters, but I refuse to give it even 3 Stars because of the STUPID ENDING, which ruined the entire reading experience for me. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BeckahRah</user>
	<review>Great story from the master. It will give you the creeps and make you terrified of clowns and sewer drains for the rest of your life.  The thing about all the 12-year-olds having sex at the end...a little unnecessary and more than a little creepy in a wholly different sense of the word.  Could have done without that. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>beckylynn</user>
	<review>The movie doesn't provide justice for this classic. It's a tale of a group of friends trying to find out who they really are all the while battling a horrific curse in their home town. Years after reading this book I still think of the characters and the issues that they went through. If your a King fan and enjoyed the Dark Tower or The Stand and don't mind long reads, do give this one a chance because it is well worth it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cefeick</user>
	<review>This was my first Stephen King, back when I was maybe 12. It scared the daylights out of me (all 1,000 pages of it!). It also hooked me on King's characterizations and storytelling abilities. At that time, most people dismissed King as "just a horror novelist." I'm glad people have begun to appreciate his talent despite his genre. Even back then, as an aspiring writer and avid reader, I appreciated what he brought to the literary world and continue to read his books when I'm in the mood for that sort of thing. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>spaz2011</user>
	<review>The best book I have ever read! It took me a whole month to read, but was definately worth it! I fell in love with the characters! and was so sad when it had to end.... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>andyray</user>
	<review>This is the top of SK's work, with the repetitive horror theme of the clown and his influence on the townspeople is central to King's idea (and Lovecraft"s) that a dimension of evil exists just next to us in this life. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nm.spring08.k.christ</user>
	<review>I am only about 100 pages into this book but I am already getting very into it. I have had a bad dream about it. Stephen King is a great author and I love his books. This book was made into a movie that is only a little like the book. Just like every other movie that is made form a book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>xavierroy</user>
	<review>Thankfully I never read this when I was a child. A nightmare-inducing  tale of growing up in a small town with a resident monster. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ghostlove</user>
	<review>I read the first half of this a couple of years ago and to this day I can still not bring myself to pick it up again. I don't get scared by horror films or books but this one scared the pants off me. If you can get to the end of this you're a braver King fan than I!</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LordRoe</user>
	<review>This is my personal favorite King book. Its also one of his most creepy/scary, so if thats what you like, you're bound to like this book. In scope, this novel is epic - it covers the lives of the main characters extremely well, to the point you feel that you are one of their friends. Pennywise is the ultimate monster, and makes for a very compelling villain. This book, however, is not for the faint of heart - neither those who are squeamish, nor those who are intimidated by huge books. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jodyreadseverything</user>
	<review>This is one of my favourite Stephen King books and my copy has been read almost to pieces now.  The story of seven children who face a real life monster who has been killing their friends and believe that they have beaten it, only to be called back home almost 30 years later when the monster returns.The monster takes on a variety of disguises but mainly appears as Pennywise the Clown.  We see him first in 1985 where he murders a young, gay man, Adrian Mellon, who has already been attacked by a group of homophobic teenagers.  We are then taken back to 1958, where Pennywise murders George Denborough, the brother of one of the boys who fights him in his various guises.With tie-ins to Stephen King's Dark Tower books (the turtle) but mostly as a stand alone story, this book is long but gripping and I can't fault a word of it.Pennywise is a fabulour villain but in my opinion he was outdone by Patrick Hocksetter, an absolutely evil child who got his comeuppence at IT's hands.  The scenes in 1958 were my favourite because they were the most believable.  Children believe in all manner of monsters and so their fear and isolation were all that more gripping than as adults. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DeanieG</user>
	<review>scared the crap out of me...been scared of clowns ever since!! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cnrenner</user>
	<review>A good read - extraodinary story, well told. Frightening, but you keep on reading. A part of the story is set in 1985, the other part in the 1980s - both parts are a kind of time travel now with King minding all the tiny little details quite a lot. I am not too much into reading horror stories, but this is a well-told story about the lives of children, about the summers of youth, about growing up, about evil in the world, and good, about courage and grit, about doom and redemption,as well.Just one thing: my (complete) version of Tolkien´s The Lord of the Rings comprises 1080 pages and you all know what epic tale is told within these - my paperback version of Stephen King´s IT (which is printed in a very, very tiny font!) has 1140 pages. `nuff said - I guess King uses words not too sparingly, does he? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mzzkitee</user>
	<review>I saw this movie when I was a little girl and it got me hooked on Stephen King. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>klarsenmd</user>
	<review>The best"horror" book Stephen King has written.  This one kept me awake at night when I first read it over 15 years ago. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AleAleta</user>
	<review>This book is freaky! I thought the story was good and so were the characters, but it kinda got a little too long around the middle. It circled around the same events and it made it a bit tedious. I did finish reading it and I do recommend it, but it is not one of King's best. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>baffiebabe</user>
	<review>Swapped on RISI for 'Vanish' by Tess Gerritsen. Also sent 'The Stand'. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shivedheart</user>
	<review>I first read this book when I was twelve years old.  It quickly became my favorite (well, one of my favorites)!  I have read it more times than I care to admit. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stpnwlf</user>
	<review>In a Penthouse interview right before this came out, King himself said it should be called "Shit" because it has everything but the kitchen sink in it.  Still an extremely compelling horror story - in some ways, the ULTIMATE horror story.  This is very good king capturing all the elements that have made him a great popular writer. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Maxy</user>
	<review>It is due to this book, and this book alone, that I am now very, very scared of clowns.I managed to both love and hate reading it but couldn't stop until I'd finished. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>buckeyeaholic</user>
	<review>CLASSIC KING!  Scared the crap out of me  I still won't walk near a drain pipe or sewer. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lportmann</user>
	<review>One of King's best books. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FlorenceArt</user>
	<review>The first Stephen King novel I read, and my favorite. It scared me and I hate being scared, but I couldn't put it down, even at night when I was even more scared :-) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>missylc</user>
	<review>This is one of my favorite Stephen King novels. I found it so easy to get caught up in the storylines of the children in the story and the evil they were fighting against was absolutely terrifying. As with all Stephen King movies, DO NOT judge this story based on the made-for-TV miniseries, which while better than many movies based on King novels still didn't do this book justice. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ALLLGooD</user>
	<review>I think this was the longest book I have ever committed to reading.  Maybe "Fortress of Solitude" by Jonathan Letham, was longer, but the print was definitely bigger.This speaks of how engaging this book was for me.  It goes without saying that the characters were deeply developed.  I could eventually distinguish who was talking by the content of the dialogue.The book reminded me so much of my childhood, and the importance of childhood friendships.  Although I was disappointed that the book wasn't scary enough, it is simply good storytelling.The freakiest part of reading this book is that parts of it eerily reflected my childhood.  My neighborhood friends and I built a dam in the woods behind my house at opening of a sewer outlet; it was the same sewer outlet that we crawled into to explore the network of tubes in our neighborhood (except, we only made it to the first sewer grate).  Thankfully, no Pennywise. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cicci</user>
	<review>En bok om monster, barndom, vänskap och fruktan. En av de bättre King böckerna! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>meursault06</user>
	<review>http://malaysianatheist.blogspot.com </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>starbytes</user>
	<review>http://bettysbooks.blogspot.com/2007/... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>booklover79</user>
	<review>Don't go by the movie, you must read this book to get the whole story of IT.  The movie doesn't do the book justice at all, you really don't get to know and understand the characters.  This book is more than about a horrifying shape-changing monster, It, that murders people, adults and children.  Yes, this is a horror book and has depictions of gruesome and terrifying scenes, but that's not really all that the story is about and you can't just shrug and group this book into the "just another horror book" category with the likes of Bentley Little, Simon Clark, Richard Laymon, or even Dean Koontz (another author I love to read).  It goes much deeper than your typical horror book.  It is about deep friendship and love, about goodness, facing fears, bittersweet childhood, and growing up.  The book is really two stories in one, the first set in 1985, and the second as a series of flashbacks to the summer of 1958 in Derry, Maine.  Every 27 years (give or take a year or two) It comes back and goes on a terror spree in Derry, Maine.  It is a cycle that goes back even before there was a Derry.  It pervades the very streets of Derry (you might say it is the essence of the town) and possibly is the cause of all the stife and violence that has occured there.  What is It?  I won't give that away, but it's interesting what explanation (if you could call it that) King gives for what It is and where It comes from.  The movie never really goes into where It comes from, and the book goes into more detail and even has a few sections where It is talking from its point of view.  Anyways, It is a part of Derry, in the sewers and drains, living there before there was even a town called Derry.  Its favorite guise is Pennywise the clown, with a silver suit and orange pom-pom buttons and a handful of ballons.  Seven children:  Bill Denbrough, Richie Tozier, Ben Hanscom, Beverly Marsh, Mike Hanlon, Eddie Kaspbrak, and Stan Uris.  Each confronted It and almost defeated It in 1958, and all have vowed with blood to come back and kill It for good if the killings ever start up again.  They each encountered It in its many guises, and lived through it.  Somehow, they are all fated to come together during that summer to fight It.  In the present time, 1985, the seven children who are now adults are called back to Derry to finish what they started back in the summer of 1958.  King is at his best with his characters.  I loved the characters in this book.  King goes into detail with each one, infusing life into the characters, so much so you feel like you know each one personally.  I didn't have one favorite character, they each completed the other and made the "Loser's Club of the Barrens":  There was Stuttering Bill (or Big Bill as he's called by his friends) the leader of the group, Trashmouth Richie and his many Voices, highstrung and nervous Eddie with his aspirator always handy, Stan quiet and thoughtful, Bev the tough but vulnerable girl, Ben "Haystack" who despite his weight was endearing, and Mike steady and always there.  You can feel the love, affection, and bond of friendship they have for one another in their good-natured ribbing and teasing, that easy bantering back and forth among each other, and in the various activities that bond them closer as a group (the building of the clubhouse or the Great Rockfight against the bullies).  So at the end of the book, you feel and understand the love mixed with sorrow Mike feels when he thinks of his childhood friends.All in all, a great story! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>amyfaerie</user>
	<review>I think this book gets a bad rap, largely due to the abysmal made-for-television movie based on it.  All I know is that when I read it for the first time, Pennywise scared the crap out of me.  The end? A little lackluster. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>herebedragons</user>
	<review>I first read thi book many years ago, and loved the story, but hated the ending. For the heck of it, I picked it up again this summer, and now I'm not sure why I disliked the ending so much the first time around. "It" is a fantastic story; gripping and scary and the writing pulled me along even though I didn't want to go, because I knew horrible things were going to happen. SPOILERS BEYOND THIS POINTPerhaps as an adult I can better appreciate the symbology of the turtle, and who doesn't think spiders are scary? (Well, I don't, usually, although this one was). Frankly, though, the scariest character in the book wasn't Pennywise in any of her guises; it's the abusive husband who terrified me (and if I've one complaint after my re-read, it's that we don't get to see him die "on screen." I'd have liked to have seen him "get his"). So, on a second read I find myself far more satisfied by this book than I was the first time around. It's a big book (took me a few weeks to get through; I think I owe the library money now since I kept it WAY past the due date), but it's worth it. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>guylyons2</user>
	<review>This book is by far the best and most chilling novel I have ever read. I was so addicted to it from start to finish! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>punkypower</user>
	<review>I first read Stephen King's "IT" when I was 13 years old. I had been on a camping trip with my fellow Brownies, and they were giggling about the graphic language he used. 15 years later, it is still my favorite book, and I just bought my second copy; for the first is all but torn in half from the many readings.When I first read it, it was my first "BIG book." I had read books that were around 500 pages, but this one was closer to 1100! I read "IT" in under three days, I LITERALLY could not put it down.King tells the tale of 7 childhood friends from (where else?) Maine. These 7 friends are known as the "Loser's Club." However, it is not their social status as children that holds them together as adults, but a pact. A pact that they made promising they'd come back if IT came back.King divides his attentions between the Loser's Club then and now. We learn their deepest fears and desires. We feel like the invisible 8th member.If I would have any complaint with "IT," it would be that it's not 5000 pages. ;Þ </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stipe168</user>
	<review>At times, absolutely terrifying. The story drags sometimes, but its well worth reading it all the way through. He can spin a good yarn, he can. some of the freakiest scenes ever put to pen. “the timing was just right enough so that things worked out badly for everyone”. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>krystalsbooks</user>
	<review>i can't watch the movie the entire thing still scares me.  This is still one of the scariest books i have ever read.  I was so into it that i could only read it with all the lights on. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jhowell</user>
	<review>I read this long ago and liked it -- I think it is middle of the road King though -- not his best, but far from his worst. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>placo75</user>
	<review>My first exposure to this story was the TV miniseries, and, to be honest, it scared me to death. That darn clown.After picking up a couple other King novels and being surprised by what I found, I decided I needed to confront my fear of the dark (something I've had since childhood and haven't quite shaken yet), and read this book.Lo and behold, the book is not nearly as scary as the TV miniseries. In fact, it's not too scary at all. Others say it is a scary novel, but I just can't figure out what they're talking about. That must mean I'm braver than I thought. Once you get past the cellar scene with Georgie, it's pretty smooth sailing, if you ask me.This novel is about being kids amidst bullies, and amidst unanticipated evils that are emodied in culture. In this way it is good.Now here are some negatives: I think the book could have been quite a bit shorter and still have been just as good. The scene with the dog and the refridgerator and the dude named Patrick I could have done without. Finally, dude, the clown came from another planet? Why not mid-world? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DerDoktor</user>
	<review>http://www.die-subkultur.net/Roman.ph... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Steebin</user>
	<review>Currently Reading </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>israfel13</user>
	<review>This was the book that haunted my dreams years before I actually got a chance to read it.  I used to get pulled along to the grocery store with my mom, weren't we all, and during the countless hours we spent standing in the checkout line I'd stare up at the impulse buy section and It would always be there.  The cover, and what it implies, was enough to scare the hell out of me at that age and years later I was delighted to find out that reading the book had the same effect. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>angelofmine1974</user>
	<review>This is one of Stephen King's scariest books, next to the Shining.  It creeped me out, definitely better than the TV movie version. I was always afraid of clowns, and this book did not help...one of Stephen King's best. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bookmarque</user>
	<review>Well done.  Boy can Stephen King draw characters well.  Each of them is unique, but similar.  They all have their crosses to bear as kids and each of them  turns out to be a successful adult with their past completely behind them.  King does some of his best writing in this book.  When he describes how when people become adults, they stop believing in the unseen.  They only believe in insurance and wine with dinner and things like that.  He makes you wonder if the adults can defeat It now because they have ceased to believe. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>llm822</user>
	<review>This is probably my favorite Stephen King book.  I love how it flip-flops between the two points in time and can't help but wonder if he wrote it that way or if he wrote the two sections whole and then pieced them together like that...? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>isiswardrobe</user>
	<review>I first read It in my late teens, and I remember that I could only do it in teh daytime, when I had company- it really scared me. But the best in this book is the description of a couple of 11-year-olds. Their lives are a compelling read, and would have been so even without the monster. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bsolah</user>
	<review>http://www.benjaminsolah.com/blog/?p=... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>smurfwreck</user>
	<review>This is one of the first King books I read when I was in the sixth grade, just starting to read novels that I wanted to read.  I think I picked this one because of its girth; the paperback weighing in at a good pound and a half, which I thought made me look smarter.I really dug the book at the time, and I've since re-read once and feel pretty much the same though I think this book falls into the same King trap ending that a lot of his books suffer from.  It seems like he is great at creating worlds and characters, but as soon as it's time to pony up on the goods, e.g. the lurking monster/villain, he always falls a little flat.  Though I'm sure we haven't seen the last of Pennywise the clown (I believe he pops up in the Dark Tower series finale) he is at the end of the day just a giant monster with a lot of potential that falls flat at the end.I will say though that as far as novels for children/teens, this is the type of work that I'd more like to see.  This and the Thief of Always by Clive Barker are light years ahead of the stuff that most kids get pushed at them (Harry Potter, et all) and have much better child characters and much more engaging plots than other teen fiction. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>asceria</user>
	<review>Great book until the whole turtle business at the end. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heidilove</user>
	<review>My dad got me this the yuletide it came out. It's important because it would become the first of my First Editions, and I've been hooked ever since. If you like King, this one isn't bad. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0451169514</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>trekbody</user>
	<review>It is one of Stephen King's best.  It is signature King in that it takes such normal kids and throws them into such bizarre horror that it leaves you teetering. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>