<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Michael Crane</user>
	<review>

equot;Animal Farmequot; by George Orwell was never required reading for me when I was in school, so it took me some time to finally get around to reading it. I found it to be a complete and enjoyable read that had me hooked from the very first sentence. It is an excellent exercise in symbolism and creative imagination. While the book may be a very short read, it brings a whole lot to the table by giving you an interesting take on how history can be reenacted in the most imaginative ways.  The animals on Mr. Jones' farm have had enough of what they deem to be slavery. They're tired of being ordered around by humans while they see no benefits in their daily work. This is all sparked by a dream that the boar, Major, had about a unique place where animals called the shots and never had to be ordered around by humans ever again. He tells them a revolution is very much needed. When Major dies, the animals act quickly and are able to overthrow the alcoholic farmer and his thugs from his very own farm. The pigs are in charge now, as they claim that they are much smarter than the others and know how to lead. What seems to be paradise quickly transforms into another form of slavery altogether enforced by propaganda and threats from the pigs. And yet, the animals do not know any better, as they are deceived by the new system that gives them the illusion that they are better off than they were with Mr. Jones calling the shots.  The book is greatly inspired by real events that went down during the era of communism in Russia, using animals as the actual people. While it helps to know about that time period, the book is written so well that it is easily understood even if you only know a little about what happened during that time. The use of animals was a very creative way to tell this story, as it gives you a big incentive to actually care for these characters. Had this just been about real people, then it would've just sounded like anything you could find in your history books. Orwell finds a much more interesting way of tackling the topic. He gives life to every one of his characters and they all elicit some kind of a feeling from you. There are times when the book is funny, and then there are times when it is just downright chilling (the last chapter will stay in your head for more than a few hours).  George Orwell's equot;Animal Farmequot; is a genuine masterpiece that quickly hooks the reader from the very beginning. It's an extremely easy read as well as an enjoyable one--not enjoyable in the sense that this is a equot;happy tale,equot; but enjoyable in the sense that you really feel like you're reading something great. If you haven't had the chance to check it out, make sure you add this to your reading list. It is something that should be read by everyone at least once in their life, even if they don't end up enjoying it as much as others. I loved every single word that was written in the extremely creative read. This is an important classic in literature that shouldn't be missed for any reason. -Michael Crane
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bel_78 "Curiosity killed the cat, but satisfa...</user>
	<review>

"Animal farm" is to this day one of the best attempts to criticize a totalitarian regime through the means that literature provides: the power of words. George Orwell (1903- 1950) wanted to help others to realize things that for him were evident, and attempted to do so by writing a fable that can easily be read as a satire of the Russian Revolution. Orwell said in an article that "Every line of serious work that I have written since 1936 has been written, directly or indirectly, against totalitarianism and for democratic Socialism, as I understand it. It seems to me nonsense, in a period like our own, to think that one can avoid writing of such subjects. It is simply a question of which side one takes and what approach one follows". Orwell also pointed out that "Animal Farm was the first book in which I tried, with full consciousness of what I was doing, to fuse political purpose and artistic purpose into one whole". He succeded beyond his wildest expectations, even though at first nobody wanted to publish this work because it was too controversial.The plot of this book is relatively easy to grasp, and I think that is probably one of the reasons why it is so popular. Some animals decide to take over the conduction of a farm, because they believe there is too much injustice, and that they would improve the situation if they had the power to do so. They make a revolution, and end up evicting Mr. Jones, the owner of the farm. From that moment onwards, the farm is called "Animal farm"...The animals establish seven "commandments", that they are supposed to obey at all moments in the new "Animal farm": 1- Whatever goes upon two legs is an enemy, 2 - Whatever goes upon four legs, or has wings, is a friend,  3- No animal shall wear clothes, 4 - No animal shall sleep in a bed , 5 -No animal shall drink alcohol, 6 - No animal shall kill another animal , 7- All animals are created equal.  At the same time, all commandments can be comprised in a maxim: "Four legs good, two legs bad".Everything seems all right for sometime, and all the animals work together for the success of the revolution, obeying the commandments and striving for a new order of things. However, after a while the pigs begin to think that being part of the animal revolution is not enough: they want to dominate it. After that first realization things take a quick turn for the worse, and we cease to be in the presence of a "wannabe utopical society",  having instead to be unwilling witnesses to the birth of a new totalitarian society. At that moment, the pigs even change some of the commandments. For example, the fourth commandment turns into "No animal shall sleep in a bed with sheets", and the sixth commandment says "No animal shall kill another animal without cause". Now, the commandments can be reduced to "Four legs good, two legs better". Finally, all the commandments will be replaced with one: "All animals are created equal, but some animals are more equal than others".All in all, I consider "Animal farm" extremely interesting, even though it is somewhat sad and pessimistic. The language is clear, and you won't find yourself wondering what the author meant by a phrase, or needing to read a paragraph again. From my point of view, that makes the reading process even more enjoyable.Despite that, I believe that this book will be considerably more appreciated by those with some basic knowledge regarding the Russian Revolution. Only then will the reader be able to take full advantage of what this short fable can offer him, due to the fact that he will realize without too much effort that some of the fictional characters in "Animal Farm" were inspired by historical characters. For example, Napoleon (one of the pigs) was quite possibly inspired by Stalin, and Snowball (another pig) by Trosky. When you read this book, try to find the characters that represent the proletariat, the Communist Party, the intellectuals, etc... :)On the whole, I regard this book as one of those you just need to read, but that fortunately you can also enjoy. The messages implicit in "Animal farm" are many, and the questions it makes you pose yourself are even more. But then, what better than a book that makes you THINK ?.Belen Alcat
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>J. S. Kaminski "j_s_k"</user>
	<review>

Animal Farm is, quite simply, one of the best and most powerful books ever written.  I first read it at 12 years of age but couldn't appreciate the author's entire message, not having the requisite knowledge of the Russian Revolution and its aftermath.  Reading it again, however, I came to understand and fully appreciate the genius of George Orwell.Animal Farm is a scathing criticism of Communism, or more specifically, the Communist system of the former USSR.  Himself a Socialist, Orwell detested the way in which its ideals were twisted and manipulated by those in power in the USSR, resulting in a terrible fate for the common people.  The story pulls no punches; although Orwell uses the fictional setting of a farm with talking animals, his aim is to expose the reader to the hypocrisy of the Soviet regime.  The figure of Josef Stalin is easily identified in the character Napoleon, one of the leaders of the animal rebellion.  The leaders were first inspired by Major, an aging boar on the farm who clearly represents Karl Marx.  Major had given the farm animals the idea that they should strive for a better life than their current plight .  After his death, Napoleon and Snowball, another character representing Vladimir Lenin, lead the overthrow of the human-run farm and establish "Animal Farm."  But Napoleon later assumes complete control over the Rebellion, and, as Stalin did, betrays virtually all aims and maxims originally put forth by the rebellion founders.  The story ends with the common farm animals in a far worse state of affairs than when the story began.Orwell used his "fairy story," published in 1945, to remind people of the dangers of Soviet Russia, and to differentiate it from the idea of Socialism.   It is also a condemnation of totalitarianism in general (one can clearly see Joseph Goebbels in the character of Squealer, the mouthpiece of the rebellion).These messages are just as powerful today as they were when Orwell first wrote them over half a century ago.To paraphrase the chilling Commandment from the last chapter:  "All authors are equal, but some authors are more equal than others."Read, and understand.  Orwell achieved a perfection rarely matched in literature.Five stars.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Iain McEwan</user>
	<review>

A quite excellent book and the best political satire I have ever read. Can only be fully appreciated if the reader is familliar with the history of the Russian Revolution. For those who aren't, here is a list of who, or  what, I thought the various animals and events represented.Jones:= The  Aristocracy. The Old Major:= Lenin. Napoleon:= Stalin. Snowball:= Trotsky.  Squealer:= Beria?. Boxer:= The male Peasants. Dolly:= The female Peasants.  The Pigs:= The Communist Party. The Dogs:= The NKVD. The Sheep:= The Army.  The Raven:= The Clergy. The Donkey:= The Intellectuals, maybe the Jews. The  Windmill:= Stalin's 5 year plans. Frederick`s Farm:= Germany. Pilkington  Farm:= The West. The Counterfeit Money:= The Molotov-Rippentrop  Pact.Hope this is useful.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gary F. Taylor "GFT"</user>
	<review>

Written as a parable, ANIMAL FARM offers the cautionary tale of Manor Farm, owned by Mr. Jones, who proves a poor manager and who treats the farm animals poorly.  Emboldened by the dreams of a long-lived, much respected, and recently deceased pig named Major, the farm animals rebel, throw Mr. Jones out, and seize the property.  The will run the farm to suit themselves, and none will go hungry, none will be mistreated, and all animals will live equally as brothers.It is a fine dream--indeed, it mirrors mankind's most cherished hopes for civilization.  But history teaches us that where the opportunity for explotation exists there is no shortage of those to take advantage of it.  Little by little the clever pigs, led by Napoleon, rise to power.  And the other animals are too trusting and often too ignorant to see that they have merely exchanged one task master for another.ANIMAL FARM is often described as a satire on communist Russia.  That is certainly true, and readers who have some knowledge of the history of the Russian Soviet will be quick to recognize the parodies of Karl Marx, Lenin, and Trotsky, among others.  But Orwell cuts considerably deeper than this.  Russia may have been the starting point, but in truth the parable of ANIMAL FARM can be applied to any culture where political leaders manipulate the public through a mixture of unreasonable hope, media "spin," and irrational fear to remain in power.As such, ANIMAL FARM remains as disquieting today as it was more than half a century ago.  And we can be sure that, in nations where power becomes centered in the hands of the few, it will continue to be among the first novels banned when that power becomes absolute.GFT, Amazon Reviewer
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

Animal Farm, written by George Orwell, is a brilliant metaphorical work that conveys a message of the ruling classes versus the working classes.  This equot;Fairy Storyequot; of animals rising against their oppressive leader is symbolic of the communist movements in Europe and Russia and reflects the characteristics of a society ruled by a dictatorship.  The book demonstrates how power can gradually corrupt an individual and lead to a system which may or may not be favorable to the masses. 	Animal Farm is a story that takes place on a farm in England. It begins with the boar, Old Major, at a meeting which includes all the animals on the farm, telling them of a dream he had about an animal rebellion against their care giver, Mr. Jones.  Upon contemplation, the animals decide to rebel.  Through key characters such as Snowball, Napoleon, and Boxer, Orwell intertwines their important characteristics and delivers an important message about the effects of a Totalitarian ruled society, its consequences, and the fate of this type of society.  Orwell depicts many relevant scenes that contain betrayal, heroism, cowardice, loyalty, and friendship, which are all important in reflecting the nuances and characteristics attributed to a totalitarian-ruled society.  	Animal Farm, in my opinion, is a truly wonderful book.  It deals with many complicated issues, but through the easy writing of Orwell, the reader can understand the issues of communism, capitalism, and the many aspects of a totalitarian dictatorship.  The symbolism of each character in the story is clear.  The reader sees, for example, that Napoleon represents Stalin, that Snowball represents Trotsky, and that Boxer represents the proletariat.  The book blends humor with tragedy.  Animal Farm deals with issues of inequality versus equality and the importance of education in determining whether or not one is being unfairly treated.  Naivete can be a dangerous characteristic, and Orwell conveys this idea in his story.  I strongly recommend this book.  It is an easy read compared to other books which try to explain and discuss the same subject matter.  With Animal Farm, one can grasp the concepts of Totalitarianism, due to the brilliant writing style of Orwell.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mr. Cairene</user>
	<review>

I have read and re-read Animal Farm since studying ithighschool, and yes it is a heart breaking allegory about the failureof organised idealogy, its also a gripping simply and sharply written story that can engage people on every level of the intellectual food chain. Many readers will start off by pinning the signs on the donkey's backside so to speak i.e. Moses the crow who tells the overworked animals that their afterlives will be bliss represents the church. Benjamin the wise, but silent donkey is the silent intellectuals who could see what was going, but did nothing to save their own skin and so on. It still shocks me how accurate Orwell is, I can recognise a Squealer (the government publiscist talking in fanciful meaningless figures), a Napeloen and sadly too many Boxers in my own country. Strange that what Orwell wrote about the Russian revolution applies to almost any third world country today. The simplicity of the prose of Animal farm is by design, he wanted his book to be accessable to the masses, afterall this is the man who changed his name from Eric Blair to Goerge Orwell just to appeal to the equot;average Joeequot;. I don't think he would have wanted this book to be discussed by intellectuals, he wanted it to reach you and me. Humanity has learned (in some parts of the world at least) that the only organised idealogy that works is the abscence of an organised idealogy. Utopia can never exist because 1- It can never be defined 2- It is against human nature not to strive to be better, superior, more powerful and richer then others. Unfortunate but true. The character of Snowball is in my opinion the most important of the book. He is full of good intent, he wants to start classes for the other animals to elevate their understanding of the world. He is also a careless and unrealistic character. What Orwell is saying here is that intent without action is useless. A person who cares about injustice and can't do anything about it is no better than a person who doesn't give it a moment's thought. Animal Farm is Orwell's masterwork, it is clairovoyant, the Soviet Union has indeed fallen. I believe the events of 1984 are only a few you years away, the government can already take pictures of your roof top. If you for some odd reason are among the few who haven't read Animal Farm, you must rectify that situation. It will make the inexplicable around you crystal clear.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Richard C. Geschke "In search of History!!"</user>
	<review>

George Orwell's classic satire of Stalin's Communistic state of the old USSR still can teach us a lesson.	Orwell uses a farm and its animals in a well thought out parody substituting animals for the main characters involved in the Russian Revolution unto the establishment of a Communistic State.	For example the prize Middle White boar named the Old Major is suppose to represent the father of Communism Karl Marx.  The Berkshire boar named Napoleon represents the long time Russian Dictator Joseph Stalin.	Orwell uses these characters to show the development of a treacherous and diabolical form of government.  In his quick and concise prose, Orwell shows the evolution of political brainwashing to develop a totalitarian form of government.	The Author presents a rather less than desirable picture of a government who at this time was indeed a major Ally of both Great Britain and the United States.	Indeed when this book was published in Great Britain in 1945 and the USA in 1946 it was censored by many governmental and non governmental organizations.  This book indeed did touch the very essence of the political turmoil in the beginning years of the Cold War.  It represents a brazen look at a brutal form of government.	I realize that this form of Communism is extinct.  But please take heed, we all can learn from Orwell's satirical dissertation of a dysfunctional farm.	A Classic read!  A Must!!  6 Stars!!!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bob</user>
	<review>

Animal Farm is a parable that can be related to nearly any system of government ever used by humanity.  	This story was written to reflect the real-life situation of communism.  All of the major characters of this  story were created to resemble a character in the true drama of the  communist rule of the Soviet Union.  Old Major, the philosopher-pig with a  dream, resembles Karl Marx, the man who wanted equality for all the workers  of the world.  Napoleon, the pig-half man, is like Vladimir Lenin, the man  who twisted Marxism so that nearly half of the world was working as his  slaves and they loved him for it.  Boxer the draft horse resembles the  workers of eastern Europe, who were convinced that Lenin was a great man as  he worked them to death.  Mr. Jones, the former owner of Manor Farm,  represents the czars of Russia who were murdered so that Lenin could take  over their position.  These similarities were created intentionally to  closer relate the story to reality. 	George Orwell raises an  interesting question with the close of this novel.  As it ends nobody can  discern between pigs and men.  The pigs had risen up out of the muck to  live as humans do, that is by enslaving all other creatures of god's  creation.  As the novel closed pigs lived and associated with men, acted  like men, and proved themselves as capable of holding a position of  leadership as any man. Through endless bickering, accusations, and general  laziness men showed themselves as no greater than pigs.  The enigma which  arises from this situation is this: Is Humanity nothing but pigs or are  pigs like humans with four legs and snouts? 	Napoleon the Pig is also  an enigma to me.  He used his fellow beasts' fascination with the  philosophy of Old Major to manipulate them into working towards his goals.   When he entered his position as supreme-commander-president-king of the  Animal Farm, he seemed like a kind and just ruler.  As time went on he grew  more and more tyrannical, beginning by lying to his subjects and eventually  executing everyone who disagreed with him, all in the name of animalism.   Although the pig exemplifies all the traits of humanity that I loathe, I  know a filthy swine is in the place of power and I am but a common citizen.   I am not sure about how I would feel if I were in the position of comrade  Napoleon.  On one hand, I would be happy that I was making out as a thief,  but on the other hand I would feel guilt about treating my subjects as  slaves.  Napoleon is truly the king of all vermin, a position that I wish I  could lower myself to fill. 	I think Animal Farm is an excellent story.   The story is an invaluable educational tool for the purpose of relating  the true story of communism to something that can be understood by people  who have not experienced it for themselves.  For this reason I would  strongly recommend this story as not only a very informative parable but  also as an enjoyable story for anyone with any knowledge of the Russian  Revolution and the Cold War.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Orwellian Disaster</user>
	<review>

I'm quite old now, but many decades ago I was forced to read this in school.  It was the first time I loved a book I was forced to read, and to this day it was the one I enjoyed the most at least until college.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>