<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nules</user>
	<review>I loved this book. It's well done. It's enjoyable. It's thought provoking. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ThinkNeil</user>
	<review>A clever political fairy tale where a utopian dream becomes a totalitarian nightmare and where pigs slowly adopt not only human attitudes but eventually physical characteristics.  The story of Animal Farm, where the animals led by pigs overthrow their owner and set up their own society only find themselves exchanging servitude to the Jones for eventual even harsher servitude under the pig Napolean.  Clever and thought provoking in a parable like manner. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bookworm546</user>
	<review>a brillant book of how the pigs take over and dominate the other animals becoming as human as the humans. a story of how good socialist idears can be exploited dumming down the majority shifting from socialism to hard line iron fist communism. how snowball was blaimed for the faults of others distracting the anaimals with properganda from napolean and his elite with the only ones that can read able to free themselves from the cloaked dictatorship </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Connor16</user>
	<review>In a very unique way Goerge Orwell tells the truth about how Joseph Stalin came to power in Communist Russia but uses animals to tell the story. A very powerful and interesting literary classic. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>theboylatham</user>
	<review>Nine out of ten.An allegory in which animals play the roles of Bolshevik revolutionaries who overthrow the human owner of a farm. At first all animals are equal but class and status disparities soon emerge. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ededman</user>
	<review>Animal Farm by George Orwell is a story about animals on a farm. The animals have this idea to overthrow the humans that own the farm. Once the animals do this, they write a set of rules. The most important rules are that all animals are equal and beings that walk on four legs or wings are good and ones that walk on two legs are bad. At first, the animals are very happy about the way the rules have changed on the farm and how they are all equal. But then, the pigs start to take leadership. The rules begin to start contradicting themselves, or they are changed so that the rules can benefit the pigs. This was a great book. It was interesting how the author made the story symbolize communism. The book also had a good plot. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>docliz</user>
	<review>Another chilling classic </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>christopherivie</user>
	<review>This should be required reading for all humans. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bruneau</user>
	<review>Once written as a parody of the communist system, it actually works just as well as a contemporary parody of Corporate America.  The pigs are ingrained in the corporate culture – from Wall Street to Big-Box-Marts – and there is no shortage of dumb horses working to death to support them.  Certainly not the author’s intent, but an extension that makes sense to anyone who has seen how small cliques of egomaniacs have managed to plunder the companies they drove into bankruptcy.  Barring an unexpected accelerated evolution of human nature, this is a classic that will forever remain relevant (and entertaining). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>katiemertz</user>
	<review>1999</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>schlimmbesserung</user>
	<review>Orwell's other work is so powerful in its directness that one wonders why he chose to use a barnyard metaphor here, but there's no denying how well it works. The man's satire is without equal. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>becker2558</user>
	<review>I would like to start off by saying that this is one of the greatest books I have ever read. It is just genius. There is no comparison by any other book to the political satire and very impressive representation and symbolism to that found within one of George Orwell's masterpieces. The thing that is most incredible about this novel is that the implications of it are literally everything. The explicit story has no meaning except the implicit, underlying statements. In my opinion, no one has ever managed to attack a form of government as cleverly and thoughtfully as Orwell does in "Animal Farm". His implications about the terrors of a Communist government do wonders in revealing the "true story" about this government type's history and motives. Governments such as the one represented in this book by pigs try to portray the idea that they are really trying to do something good and productive for society. However, this piece effectively shows that this is all just a huge lie. But the true genius behind it is that this is not explicitly stated. Animal representations are used to get ideas across, but in no way are these ideas subtle. They stick out for everyone to see and do a great job of revealing basic truths. "Animal Farm" is absolutely one of the greatest political statements in history. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jrosenfeld</user>
	<review>The satire and rhetoric in Animal Farm led to an interesting story with a great underlying connection to the real world.  Orwell got a serious agenda across in a fun and playful way.  The animals Orwell chose and the names given to the animals were ingenious because the personalities and qualities of the animals accurately represented real-life people.  The most emotional part of the book was when Benjamin was killed.  This sad act reflects on how the communists killed/punished those who couldn't work and those who were too intellectual.  Animal Farm presents complex issues in a simple way that even kids can understand.  The book was great but it wasn't perfect, that's why I gave it 4 stars.  The book lacked sophistication, I found it very plain.  Nonetheless, I would recommend this book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Anagarika</user>
	<review>I only have one thing to say..."All Animals Are Equal, But Some Animals Are More Equal Than Others." </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>melydia</user>
	<review>(unabridged audiobook): I'm pretty sure I saw the animated film at some point in my youth, but the book is far better. Orwell is brilliant as usual. And it certainly didn't hurt that the reader was very engaging. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kasey17</user>
	<review>I read the book Animal Farm by George Orwell. I read this book because Dr. Lawson had his class read it. It was very creative. It was also detailed. Animal Farm was creative because animals on the farm were people related to history. For example there was this pig named Napolean. And obviously Napolean was a very important person in history.The book was ok. It was about how animals overthrew human beings. At the beginning the animals made seven commandments and everyone was equal. There were wars and problems that they had to solve along with animals dying. But at the end the pigs were the higher power and they took away the commandments and they even lived in the farm house. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>emvuu</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is one of those amazing books you read at an extremely young age and can not appreciate the beauty held between its pages. I first read it at 11 entertained only by the talking animals but as I got older and held it in my hands again I realized there was so much more to it. Orwell uniquely displays the work of politics, beaurocrats, and  business savvy people within a few acres (maybe even smaller) of a farm. These animals holding their own fort, focus their parties into sections of important leaders and dominating almost and close to an aristocratic rule. They were held together by democracy but be honest, how long would that last with a pig leader named Napolean? I recommend this amazing work to anybody, a fan of political power or just animals in general ! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>redkit</user>
	<review>Animal farm - the perfect allegory for the events of Soviet Russia. A short book, it highlights the difference (or lack thereof) in living conditions pre- and post- communist rule, while portraying the horrifying effects that power can have on a once clear-minded promoter of utopian ideals. Ultimately, while the animals are too short-sighted (or lacking the necessary mental stamina) to see that things are the same as, or worse than before, the reader can see the parallels that are drawn thickly and vividly, and we are left feeling as if the nature of humankind (or pig-kind?) is tragically all too prone to corruption. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Cintuza</user>
	<review>Los animales de una granja, cansados de la explotación de los humanos, deciden tomar el control de la misma y armar una comunidad en la que todos los animales trabajen no para beneficio de otros, sino para ellos mismos. Pero a medida que pasa el tiempo, terminan siendo igual o peor que los hombres de los que clamaron libertad. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jwhenderson</user>
	<review>This is if anything a more powerful book than 1984 due to its brevity and the incisive nature of the allegory.  The images are magnificent. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lolmars</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is about animals overruling the humans on the farm and then operating it. There are a lot of arguments and disagreements which is what makes this book so political. When Napoleon, a pig, takes over the farm, he starts using his leadership as an excuse to have more luxuries than the other animals. I like this book because it gets to the point quickly and is a very easy book to read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>swimfreak</user>
	<review>Animal Farm was a really good book. It was about the Soviet Union but they used the animals as the characters. The pigs were the rulers or unfair people. The rest of the animals were just the people that were being treated unfairly. The book was about how the animals tookover the farm from the owner and ruled it by themselves. Their main motto is "four legs good, two legs bad" (animals are good humans are bad) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>The_Joker420</user>
	<review>This book is about a bunch of farm animals that overthrow their leader. They're tired of being pushed around. Animal Farm is a symbol for the russian revolution.I was not a big fan of this book, I just couldnt seem to get into it. I guess it just wasn't my style.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>soccerbolin16</user>
	<review>It was on okay book. It isn't boring like some of the classical books and some of the events that are in the book are really exciting and keep you on the edge of your seat, but some are somewhat bland. Animal Farm relates to politics and government. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>John00</user>
	<review>This book is about a group of farm animals that don't want to be ruled by their farmer, Mr. Jones.  They decide to do this by having a rebellion.  After the rebellion the pigs decide to take the lead position.  The rest of the book tells about how they survive on their own and the problems they face like wars and arguements. I didn't like this book because I never felt like I was "in" the book.  I didn't feel different emotions in certain parts of the book like I do in most good books.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TateOrTot</user>
	<review>This book is a obstract reanactment of the russian revolution. Georege Orwell uses animals to represent major people that were involved. The book starts, a pig, Old Major, has a dream about life with out the rules from man. Old Major's dream is to live without the farmers rule,  but when he dies, it is up to the animals to fulfill his lifelong dream. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dylanwolf</user>
	<review>Look, I cried when Boxer got sent to the knacker's yard, OK.What is it about Animal Farm that makes it so popular in the United States? I would even suggest it's not quite so celebrated here in the UK. Ah! it is because it is an allegory against communism! Now, whisper it my friends, but George Orwell was a socialist! Animal Farm is actually speaking out against totalitarianism and Stalinism. He fought in the Spanish Civil War and it was the most informative experience of his life. The impressive thing about Orwell is his continual questioning of his own views. He was literary editor at the left wing Tribune but also respected by right wing figures. The simple clarity and power of Animal Farm is what makes it a classic. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Luiise</user>
	<review>i really hate this book </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tro214</user>
	<review>Worth it just for Steadman's drawings! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jimmaclachlan</user>
	<review>Allegories  anti-communist literature often leave me cold. This is both  could easily have been done poorly.  Instead, it was perfect.  Orwell manages to fit a farm seamlessly to communism in a way that makes me want to laugh  cry at the same time.  It's short, sweet  to the point.  Wow!  What wonderful points he makes, too.  He pokes holes in the theories of collectivism until it's leaking like a sieve  wraps up in style.  It's been years since I last read it, but I still have images in my mind. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>supersam</user>
	<review>I liked the book because it was an ecelent example to the idea of comunism. i also liked the fact that it tied with the conflicts of the russian revolution. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dinabeb</user>
	<review>Trop évident, peu d’efforts d’imagination demandés pour cette lecture qui ne laisse pas d’espace de réflexion pour le lecteur. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>relah</user>
	<review>Pigs are delicious.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brassmonkey</user>
	<review>Deceptively simple..... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nebowers</user>
	<review>This story of the rise and fall of a communist farmyard society will make me forever eye pigs with a certain degree of suspicion. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>camarie</user>
	<review>I love this book. Children could read it and think it is about animals, but if you know anything about communism, you know this book is about it. I read this book and see why communism is so terrible, though if it worked out as it is supposed to work out, I think it would be a good idea. Everyone should read this book and interpret it in their own way. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>unlikelyaristotle</user>
	<review>This may be cheesy, but I did love it. The message is clear, and only an idiot would not be able to connect the dots between the metaphor and real life. What I love about this book is that every single bit of it is just so true, and it's done in a way that I just love. Not woe is me, but a statement of fact that really gets people thinking and talking, because it tells me the one truth which I believe in wholeheartedly, which is that humans (by analogy obviously) are fallible, so a system which doesn't allow for this fallibility is a system that will fail. I would read this book 10 times and don't thing I would get bored it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>khollis</user>
	<review>The animals drove Mr Jones out of Manor farm in search of a better life ... everyone was happy until things started to go horribly wrong. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>riptiki</user>
	<review>I want Snowball to overthrow that whole god-damned society.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SeriousEmily</user>
	<review>I can't believe I haven't read this before! The dynamic on the farm was amazingly creepy, I found myself picturing them all as humans and hating the pigs more than anything. It's interesting to see how similar the government and political activists have been in the past compared to today. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>spwebdesign</user>
	<review>http://spwebdesign.livejournal.com/61... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nerocristallo</user>
	<review>Tutti gli animali sono uguali, ma alcuni sono più uguali degli altri. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KGVLibrary</user>
	<review>The structure of the novel is skillfully organized by George Orwell, which allows the readers to learn more about the causes of the unworkability of communism.  The way he wrote does not only resemble Stalin but also other famous leaders such as Hitler.  Each animal in the story has different features and attitude. The way of how characters are portrayed, they resemble the some styles of human nature, for example selfishness. It clearly shows of what people can do in order to gain what they want. The happenings in the book also display how leaders do things in the past and also resembling other historical philosophers. The story proves the quote of "Evil happens when good people are silent."  From the story you can see that people's mind can change such as betraying their comrade, we can see that from Napolean and Snowball. Not just betraying a comrade but also killing them, their actions also involve innocent animals which is immoral. By the way of how the animals and Napolean is portrayed, it shows that he forces people to work, treating them as slaves. Giving all the luxuries to themselves and left nothing for the animals, merely saying that the luxuries are for pig's health for leading the team.  The leaders in the story allow nothing to oppose them and killing them if they do, all the animals are blindly agreeing to them, from such attitude can be found through history from many countries. They change rules to gain power such as from "All animals are equal" to "All animals are equal but some animals are more equal than others". They also decided how an animal live and their death, such as from "No animal shall kill any other animal" they added in the end "without a cause". From the start, no animal were meant to use and learn about human's ways of living. However later in the story as Napolean come into power, they learn to stand on two legs and regard the four-legged populace as inferiors. They start to wear Mr Jone's clothes, sleep in beds and drink alcohol. In my opinion, its worse than being cared by Mr Jones, there is no freedom for the animals and they get eliminated whether they have done something wrong or not. To the leader, all the animals are just tools for gaining what they want and it shows that in the past, the book shows that most leaders in the past were just selfish, uncaring, cowardly, lazy murderer. I would recommend this book to people as it is not only a mere fairy-tale, but also the historical analysis of the causes of the failure of communism, it proves that human nature and diversity prevent people from being equal and happy, which is a valuable lesson for everyone. Philip Fan </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BookMarkMe</user>
	<review>Communism in the farmyard, a clever way of packaging a political novella. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>curlysue</user>
	<review>I first read Orwell's Animal Farm in high school. I distinctly remember not liking it. Maybe it was because I couldn't wrap my teenage head around the premise of animals running their own farm with political innuedoes thrown in. My re-read of this political satire has changed my mind.This short (right to the point) book is Orwell's view of a rise and fall of a communistic type regime. Only farm animals are the regime.These farmyard animals overthrow their human owner to take control of the farm for themselves. A hierarchy is formed with the pigs as leaders by virtue of their intelligence and everyone else as common laborers. In the beginning their society started as a democratic one with the slogan All Animals Are Created Equal. As the pigs evolve in their leadership they succumb to the temptations of privilege and power. The totalitarian rule becomes reestablished with the changing of the founding slogan into All Animals Are Created Equal But Some Animals Are More Equal Than Others. There is a shocking betrayal of the faithful worker Boxer and moments of obnoxious superiority. When Squealer is seen walking upright (creepy) you know that they have come full circle in emulating man and have become no better then their human master Mr. Jones. I'am so glad I re-read this and I recommend anyone who read it as required reading in high school to re-read it again. You just might have a different take on it now. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LouCypher</user>
	<review>George Orwell's classic Animal Farm is a great story of all the animals on Manor Farm rising up in a rebellion and overthrowing there masters. Then they create the Animal Farm under a communistic type regime.I loved it. Very short and to the point but extremely well written and thought provoking. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ariebonn</user>
	<review>This book is genius. When George Orwell wrote this book he might have had Stalin in mind but it applies just as much today and will continue to do so. At first I found it a little strange to read about animals talking and planning a revolution against Mr. Jones when you're expecting to read a political allegory but then it all fell into place and everything made sense. It really is what we live every day, something which you're probably better off not thinking about too much.The different kinds of animals represent the types of people in society, there are the corrupt leaders that are in control, the people that work hard for the benefit of everyone but when it comes down to it they find that nobody is thankful for what they did, the people that are happy to follow, or kiss ass, in hopes that one day they too will be at the top, and the gullible that believe that what the leaders do is in their best interest. Every once in a while the people at the bottom decide that they had enough and a revolution takes place, but eventually it ends up just where it started from, someone needs to lead and the rest have to follow. It's scary how true it is. Read it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>g0ldenboy</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is a classic required in middle schools around the world. Weighing in at less than 140 pages, it's a quick read. Thus, I put Orwell's magnum opus 1984 down, and began this allegoric tale. I was expecting an exciting, more complex version of Charlotte's Web, with subtle themes meant to ridicule socialism. But there is nothing subtle about it.Animal Farm begins strongly. As a wise old pig edges toward death, he stands on a stool in the black of night to profess to the rest of the farm his dream of a world where animals are free from men. This scene is portrayed deftly; I couldn't wait for Orwell to relate the personalities of the animals to the roles they would play in the newly formed society. Surprisingly, the rest of the book is bland.Each character is modeled after a historical figure: Napoleon is Stalin, Snowball is Trotsky, Squealer is Molotov, Boxer is the proletariat man, the dogs are the secret police, and so on. Instead of a rich character study concerning the types of people who become the Stalins or Molotovs, Orwell merely slaps his satire onto a cardboard cast. Because the premise was so creative, I predicted the rest of the book would contain the same spice and excitement. I was wrong.I'm not saying Orwell doesn't describe animals like Squealer vividly; we see his persuasive mannerisms and speeches, just nothing deeper. In fact, Orwell grinds the reader against the pitfalls of Communist societies. I'm willing to accept the tale as a method of displaying this inevitability, I just can't tolerate repetitiveness. As others have pointed out, Animal Farm might have been better as a short story or lecture series. His idea doesn't sustain impact for long, as short as the book is.A page on socialism could sum it all up. If you've already read such a page, you'll trudge through Animal Farm mouthing, "yeah, I get it already." However, if you're still in middle school, this book might be just what you need to imprint the idea into your brain. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LucidLove</user>
	<review>I love this book; it's a classic, and it's a book that many people should choose to read before they die. The portrayal of people as animals is hilarious, and the whole story in itself does a good job of entertaining the reader and giving a nice idea of what happened between political leaders during the historical time this book mirrors. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Elferkid</user>
	<review>This was a good book. It is very interesting to have a book discussion about, especially if you know about world war 2. I enjoy relating the characters in this book to historical figures, and the events to historical events during WW2. I recommend this book to anyone interested WW2. This book is about a farm of animals who overthrow their owner, Mr. Jones. The pigs are the leaders of the farm. The animal farm goes by the slogan "four legs good, two legs bad." In this society every animal is supposedly equal and works for the good of there own farm and there own far only. This is the basic idea of communism. Through out the book the pigs gradually take over the farm. My the end the are worse than Mr. Jones! </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Fluffyblue</user>
	<review>Excellent book which essentially is about the Communist revolution but with animals.  I loved the satire within the book and the fact that Napoleon kept changing things to suit himself whenever things got a bit tricky.  The other animals came across as drones, simply doing whatever they were told and forgetting what had gone before.  They had no freedom even though they thought they were free because they got rid of the humans.  They were still controlled by rules and regulations which were harsher than anything that the regime they had overthrown could enforce on them.Excellent writing and very, very thought provoking. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>book_bliss</user>
	<review>"Four legs good, two legs bad."  Need I say more?</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AnnMarieC</user>
	<review>I was very disappointed when I read this book. I thought I would enjoy it from how my sister told me how it was, but it seemed that throughout the book, I became bored. I read through the entire book, but was also disappointed to find that a certain character(not naming any names) never came back to rightfully take what was his.I do find an upside to this though. I know that if I were to read this same book in another year from now that I will probably get more interested. I believe my reason for not liking this book is for the simple fact that I dont cherish these classics. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>football1</user>
	<review>great book</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cowpeace</user>
	<review>Blurp: 'It is the history if a revolution that went wrong - and of the excellent excuses that were forthcoming at every step for the perversion of the original doctrine,' wrote Orwell in the original blurp for the first edition if Animal Farm in 1945. His simple and tragic fable, telling what happens when the animals drive out Mr Jones and attempt to run their farm themselves, has since become a world-famous classic of English prose.Samenv.: Persiflage op het dictatorschap en de totalitaire staat, waarin vooral de draak wordt gestoken met het Russische communisme.Samenv.: De overbekende roman over de dieren op de boerderij, die tegen de wrede boer in opstand komen. Het tragische verhaal, waarin de varkens zich beter voelen dan de andere dieren en de macht overnemen, is steeds weer het lezen waard. Uitgave voor scholieren met informatief nawoord in het Engels. Kleine druk; geen woordverklaringen.Samenv.: De dieren op Manor Farm worden door boer Jones slecht behandeld. Ze moeten erg hard werken en krijgen weinig voer. Daarom roept het zieke varken Old Major alle dieren bij elkaar en vertelt ze zijn droom dat alle dieren in opstand komen tegen Jones en met elkaar als gelijken de boerderij gaan runnen. Als na Old Majors dood de dieren nog slechter behandeld worden, komen ze inderdaad in opstand en jagen Jones en zijn mannen weg. Ze stellen de 7 geboden op, waarvan de belangrijkste is 'All animals are equal'. Maar al gauw bepalen de varkens de gang van zaken en er ontstaat een machtsstrijd tussen de dictatoriale Napoleon (Stalin) en de idealistischer Snowball (Trotsky). Jones is tsaar Nicolaas; de schapen en Boxer zijn het proletariaat dat ten prooi valt aan propaganda. Uiteindelijk zijn de dieren nog slechter af dan in de tijd van Jones. Deze politieke satire op de periode na de Russische Revolutie is het bekendste werk van de sociaal-kritische auteur (1903-1950). Door de onderkoelde stijl en het simplificeren van de historische context is het boek zeer geschikt voor kinderen en wordt het veel gelezen voor de boekenlijst Engels mavo-havo-vwo. Maar ook voor volwassenen blijft het een prachtige fabel.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bookwormjules</user>
	<review>I finished this a few days ago, but exams got in the way of posting the review, so atlas, here it is.This book was a good book, an easy read and funny at times. Orwell did a fantastic job at creating a satire around the Russian Revolution, as well as showing what happens when society to puts to much faith in its leaders. You can draw a lot from this book, even if it isn’t related to the Russian Revolution, especially about power, leadership and how people though the “media” (words written on the wall) thought their political leaders and their representatives, and through intimidation, can be convinced to believe in pretty much anything you want them, even with little effort. He managed to do all of this under the cover of animals, as his characters. Using stereotypes of animals (smart pigs, stupid sheep), and in the end, made a very interesting parallel towards humans and our own behaviours, and humans behaviours when they are given too much power. I think it’s a great way to address what happened in the Russian Revolution, it has made me want to do my own research, as well as I think it can be a great way to teach other political issues and communities that are similar to this situation, especially with children.A great satire, but also some serious issues addressed, hidden under the lines in the pages.Review can also be found on my book review bloghttp://juliebooks.blogspot.com/2009/0... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ani_Na</user>
	<review>This is a book important if only for its place in canon. As a novel though, it's quite good - in style, even better than 1984, I think. The plot is the important element to this story, and the allegory on top of that - which I've also felt is just a good indictment of fascism as it is communism. ("All animals are equal, but some are more equal than others" - chilling in how many find that true.) I'd recommend this for its story and importance to anyone; pair it with "Snowball's Chance". </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Weirdbeard</user>
	<review>They will be people who read this novel nowadays with no conception of the USSR and its early leadership antics.  Needless to say, the satire still works in our modern so-called democracies.  At election time you'll recognize the pigs that covet your vote so that they can occupy the farmhouse while you languish in the stable... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kalashnikov</user>
	<review>Orwell's “Animal Farm: A Fairy Story” (1945), is a well known satire of, as the author acknowledges, the Russian Revolution. Rejected by four publishers in Britain, it was this work that established Orwell as one of the foremost writers of his generation.The story follows the animals of Mr Jones' farm as they first overthrow their masters in the name of equality, then struggle to survive in the environment they have created. Following the course of the Russian Revolution, the leaders squabble, maxims on which the revolution was founded change, and the egalitarian principles give way into totalitarianism in all but name.Many readers find this a rather poor satire of events of which they are already familiar. That may be so for some of the older generation, however remembering the climate in which this was written, where Russia was seen as a key ally and Western leaders, academics and media saw Stalin's indiscretions (read ‘purges’) as necessary in the name of the cause, it certainly holds a deeper meaning. The benefit of hindsight is an amazing thing, what is now obvious once was not always so. My edition (Modern Penguin Classics, ISBN 9780141182704) was worth buying just for the 'preface' Orwell originally intended for the first edition but which was not published till 1973, at the back of the book. It was a good introduction, through Orwell’s eyes, of the social state of Britain at the time, while giving a glimpse into the motivations of Animal Farm."ALL ANIMALS ARE EQUAL BUT SOME ANIMALS ARE MORE EQUAL THAN OTHERS"An oft quoted line, as relevant today as it was in 1943, certainly it applies to the animal kingdom. If we use the same major distinguishing characteristic Orwell does, intelligence; and disregard the physical differences between animals the same way we disregard the physical differences of humans. Does it apply to humans? With all the connotations that it holds?Rated 4.5 stars. (25/04/09) </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KendraRenee</user>
	<review>Meh, more social commentary in the form of a story that doesn't feel that relevant to my life.  Definitely echoes back to Orwell's time, though, and the current communist revolutions going on at the time.  It especially made me think of East Germany. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>WomblingStar</user>
	<review>This book is so easy to read and follow, much easier than I expected. I think the animal version of a revolution is very clever and he has been proven to be right so many times. It is at times upsetting to read but I would recommend it to everyone.It follows a farmyard of animals who overthrow the human owner to take control of the farm for themselves. The pigs become the natural leaders as they are the cleverest. However, the rules of 'animalism' change and very soon the farm is no better for the lower classes than before the revolution. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>elbakerone</user>
	<review>On picking up George Orwell's Animal Farm at my local library, I thought I knew what to expect.  I had previously sought out 1984, Orwell's later and perhaps better known work, and I was predicting Farm to be a similar novel of a dark dystopia. What I found instead was a thinly veiled allegory depicting the Russian revolution.The fable is set in the English countryside on "Manor Farm" and the reader is introduced to a host of anthropomorphic residents of the farm who are incited to rebel after the prophetic dream of an old hog.  The animals, under the devious leadership of a pig named Napoleon, overthrow farmer Jones and set up their own communist society known as "Animal Farm".  This point in the narrative is where Orwell's darker writing takes over, and the reader follows the journey of the farm residents from thriving in an animal-run utopia to miserable conditions under a totalitarian dictatorship. Orwell's satire is biting and as in 1984, his views on the ills of an overbearing government are anything but subtle.  The story reads quite quickly and the ending, though easy to predict from the downward spiral of life on the farm, still packed a powerful punch.  The book is not one to read just for fun, but rather as a thought provoking work of fiction.   For that reason, it earns its place as a classic. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>studioloo</user>
	<review>Orwell is one of my favourite authors. Definitely a great read! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AtaraxiaM</user>
	<review>Excellent satire on communism. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>06nwingert</user>
	<review>'All animals are equal, but some are more equal than others.' The most famous phrase from  Aminal Farm, another classic Orwell. Another bleak outlook for society, and a good take on capitalism v. socialism, communism v. democracy. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Conner23456</user>
	<review>i like this books, because of the the close reference to the Russian Revolution and Lenon, and other people in the Russian Revolution. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jmeisen</user>
	<review>Brilliant. Deservedly a classic. Concisely sums up and satirizes the history of the Soviet Union through Stalin, as well as being a warning against totalitarianism in all its forms. That the author was an avowed socialist just makes it better, as he has no political axe to grind.It seems as though recent Russian history, from glasnost through Putin, demands a sequel. Unfortunately, we have no Orwells these days. And the animals still can't catch a break. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FMRox</user>
	<review>Amusing. Totalitarianism. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rebeccareid</user>
	<review>By itself, Animal Farm is an odd, but amusing tale. The animals on Manor Farm are successful in their revolutions against humans and the reader wants to cheer them on. Then the subsequent slow transformation of Animal Farm back to the necessary evil of doing business with humans (for Animal Farm is, unfortunately, not completely self-sufficient) seems sad, for we wish success to the remarkable animals, despite the obvious treachery of the leading animals.Put into the cultural context in which it was written, Animal Farm clearly mocks the rise of communism in Russia. To me, Animal Farms‘ ironic humor becomes all the more sad when one realizes the correlating story among humans suffering in Orwell’s contemporary Russia. I liked rereading Animal Farm, and now that I understand a bit more of the context, I found it quite sad, and not nearly as funny as the first time I read it. More detailed review on my blog</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zenosbooks</user>
	<review>One is never too young or too old to read this tale of revolution gone awry. George Orwell’s ability to tell a complex story using straightforward prose is perhaps the reason for ANIMAL FARM's universal appeal. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zenosbooks</user>
	<review>One is never too young or too old to read this tale of revolution gone awry. George Orwell’s ability to tell a complex story using straightforward prose is perhaps the reason for ANIMAL FARM's universal appeal. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>zenosbooks</user>
	<review>One is never too young or too old to read this tale of revolution gone awry. George Orwell’s ability to tell a complex story using straightforward prose is perhaps the reason for ANIMAL FARM's universal appeal. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sturlington</user>
	<review>I finally got around to reading Orwell’s famous satirical allegory, and it didn’t disappoint. This is a classic story of revolution and the corruption of power, with the animals who take over Animal Farm each representing groups or types of people in the social structure, such as the elite (the pigs), the bourgeoisie (Millie, the horse), the working class (Boxer, the horse) and the silent cynics (the donkey, my favorite character). Even though I knew it was allegorical, I had to laugh at the mental image of pigs milking cows. The famous last line sums it up: "The creatures outside looked from pig to man, and from man to pig, and from pig to man again; but already it was impossible to say which was which." </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TogetherForGood</user>
	<review>The story is a necessary one to be aware of but was written so militaristically that I found myself having to push myself to read it even though it is a quite short book.  It took me a couple months to get through, reading it in the laundry room/bathroom. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bfertig</user>
	<review>Classic </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>michaeleconomy</user>
	<review>i was expecting more.Imagine if 1984 was about stupid farm animals and didn't have a protaganist. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>blackdogbooks</user>
	<review>Manor Farm erupts in revolution and the animals take over, with the pigs, the intelectual elite, in charge.  Renamed Animal Farm, the pigs initiate a democratic process, electing leaders, establishing rules, and reeducating the other animals.  The new animal utopia, however, begins to unravel, as the pigs are carried away with their own power.Orwell's Animal Farm is obviously an allegory about the cycles of human history, revolution, and the corrupting influence of power.  I was not particularly moved by this book, though it's well written.  Perhaps the build up to read it, as this was my first time, created too much anticipation.  I am much more of a fan of 1984.  I found that novel to have many more layers and not as obvious.Three bones!!! </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mene</user>
	<review>maart 2000 - boekverslag Nederlands brugklas'Dierenboerderij' is geschreven door George Orwell. De oorspronkelijke titel is 'Animal Farm'.Ik vond het boek zielig, want de boerderijdieren worden onderdrukt door de varkens, en ze hebben het niet door.De belangrijkste gebeurtenis is dat boer Jansen van de boerderij verjaagd wordt.Onderwerp in 3 woorden: varkens onderdrukken boerderijdieren.De titel zegt niet waar het boek over gaat, alleen over de plaats waar het zich afspeelt. Ik vind het een goede titel.De hoofdpersonen zijn alle dieren van de boerderij.Het boek verdient een prijs omdat het een verhaal is waar je wel wat van kan leren.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>trlchick25</user>
	<review>I really enjoyed reading Animal Farm. It was fun reading how animals took over a farm. George Orwell did a terrific job with the symbolism of the story. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sherton</user>
	<review>Read in high school.  A book you don't forget. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sarah408</user>
	<review>http://sarahbbc.wordpress.com/2008-bo... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>caandrews</user>
	<review>This is a great book that is sad, but it has a great message. It is done in such a fun way that really gets the message across without making everyone TOO depressed! It is a great book and makes the reader go though at least 20 different emotions. It is a blast to read! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sanne_terreur</user>
	<review>good book, nice allegory</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>matto1990</user>
	<review>A very good book. Very well told story with all the political meanings I expected. When you read it it makes you feel slightly uneasy about humans and really makes you think about how political systems function.Enjoyed it very much and would reccommend it to anyone. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jiles2</user>
	<review>Everyone to read, but not everyone to enjoy.  I'm always amazed how barnyard politics can reflect real world situations.  The analogy is brilliant, but the story becomes overbearingly heartbreaking in the end. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Audacity88</user>
	<review>'All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others.' What a brilliant skewering of coercive egalitarianism! </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thesmellofbooks</user>
	<review>Sobering and painful. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>guersonjr</user>
	<review>Utilizando uma fazenda de animais, Orwell faz uma paródia da revolução socialista e do Stalinismo mostrando que ao final, os revolucionários se tornam a própria aristocracia que derrubaram. Brilhante. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>liammurrray</user>
	<review>This book broadened my knowledge and interest on the issue of the Russian Revolution. Although the story makes no direct references to the revolution, Orwell uses symbolism to show the ideas and values of communism that affect a large populace in a negative way. While reading it, the reader will notice the progressive broadening of power held by the pigs. Initially it seems everyone is equal, but as the story unfolds, the pigs use their strong knowledge to precisely manipulate the rest of the animal farm population to work under their power. It is also interesting to see that one pig, Snowball, who is clearly intending to do well for the common good of the farm is exiled almost immediately after their revolution by Napoleon, much like the Stalin did to Trotsky. I would recommend this book to people of ages from age 12 and above, because it displays a common view of Communism through a very indirect way. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>eor</user>
	<review>http://eor.livejournal.com/250250.htm...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>davidweigel</user>
	<review>E-books I</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rose-Marie</user>
	<review>Se anmeldelse:http://no.librarything.com/work/1477/... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>elainepx2014</user>
	<review>this book is about a group of animals who live on a farm and they go against humans. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cookie11</user>
	<review>In George Orwell's story of a farm dictated by pigs the reader sees the strong comparisons to the dictators of his day as the pigs force the other animals to work. Not only are the animals interactions with each other relateable to dictatorships but the way the pigs gain trust from human farmers and begin trade. I like this book because it simplifies the ideas of a dictatorship and explains what really happens when one wrongly takes power.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>missyr46</user>
	<review>This is a story of the affects of communism portrayed through the lifeon a farm. The animals take charge over the humans and start their own democracy, but abuse the power and create a dictatorship among them. Main characters include various animals such as a pig named Napoleon, who dictates the farm, a horse named Boxer, who is popular among the rest of the animals and another pig named Squealer, Napoleon’s strong follower. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Nharry</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is a political satire centered around a group of animals who take over a farm and govern it themselves. After defeating the humans, the animals try to create their own form of government and soon end up creating something analogous to communism. In fact, the majority of the book is an analogy whereof every character and event relates to history. As the animals suffer and become more distant from their original principles, the story becomes bleaker and things continue to take turns for the worst. The wiser animals take more control and the other animals ignorantly believe that everything is equal and for the good of their society.In reference to utopias and dystopias, George Orwell’s Animal Farm was a perfect example of a dystopia. Bred to be a political satire, Orwell illustrated a world chockfull of historical figures doing foolish things consequently creating a terrible society. Though the point of view is 3rd person omniscient, since the animals are so ignorant the reader is left to wonder when the animals will realize what’s happening around them. Orwell’s dystopia is very similar to Candide’s cruel Europe and Brave New World’s World-State (where the people live in ignorance).Ultimately, I really enjoyed this novel because of the symbolism and meaning inside each page. While a younger audience could appreciate the idea of animals running wild and governing themselves, I thought Orwell did an excellent job incorporating analogies. By doing this, an entire layer of subtext was created that connected to reality and history. I really enjoyed this aspect of the novel because with my understanding of history I could follow this subtext better. Therefore, I recommend this book to anyone with a couple extra hours on their hand and those with a mild understanding of world history.9/10 </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Nigeria456</user>
	<review>This novel is a satirical allegory or parody of the Russian Revolution. Orwell uses farm animals in place of all the major leaders involved in the Russian revolution. After the farm animals become tired of the constant oppression of their human leader (or farmer), they run him out of his out farm and the animals set up their own farm. After reading this novel, I learned about what happened during the Russian Revolution. This was a good book.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Schmerguls</user>
	<review>1808 Animal Farm, by George Orwell  (read 11 Nov 1983) I heard of this book often since it was published in 1946.  It is a little short book, readable in less than two hours.  The edition I have just read is 155 pages.  The particular incentive for me to read it now is that it is listed on a panel's list of the 12 or 13 best novels first published in English since World War II.  This book is good reading.  Of course I am a literalist, and I had to catch myself so I would be feeling sad for the good animals.  Napoleon is a boar who becomes head of the farm taken over by the animals, and eventually he becomes the top tyrant, similar to what Mr. Jones was to the animals before Major inspired them to revolt and take over the farm.  I presume Major is Marx, and Napoleon is Lenin, and Squealer is Stalin, but of course the analogy is not intended to be exact, and the book mocks collectivism as practiced in Russia.  This book is a classic, and rightfully so.  Orwell has a clean, spare style.  I hope I enjoy the rest of the books on the list as much as I did this one. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ieroXway</user>
	<review>In a blatant metaphor for Soviet totalitariamism, a group of farm animals overthrow the humans governing them, and in the process realize that their society may not be so utopian after all. This book, among other things, was my first introduction to symbolism--something that would leave a lasting impression on my taste in books for years to come.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>berbels</user>
	<review>Of course I read this in high school english class. A novel about how the establishment is self perpetuating to all classes of the culture- even if you're not trying. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rose-Marie</user>
	<review>Se anmeldelse:http://no.librarything.com/work/1477/... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>callista83</user>
	<review>First you should know I'm the furthest thing from a history buff. I find history boring and in general prefer to look to the future. It is because of this that I have no idea who Stalin or Trotsky are. To me this book was pretty much nothing more than an interesting tale about animals who take the farm from the humans and run it themselves. If it was written just like this, it would be an awesome book. However it was written as a satire (is that the right word?) on what was happening at the time. It was written in 1943 but Orwell could not find a publisher who was willing to publish it till 1946. After finishing the book, although I still didn't know the history behind the novel, I could understand what parts of the book represented what in history. This version has a Preface and an Introduction, both of which I could barely get through and really have almost no idea what they said. However I did catch the part about those people who had a blind eye towards what was really happening and allowed it to go on. It is amazing what the animals will believe when persuaded to believe it. I'm glad I read this book and I think others should take the time to read this too. I do want to read up on the history a little, just enough to get the jist of what happened and to appreciate the novel more. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AlbinoRhino</user>
	<review>Good book.  Read it back in the ninth grade and enjoyed it even then.  This is a book that everyone should read before they die. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rose-Marie</user>
	<review>Dyrene på gården er misfornøyd fordi de presses til å arbeide mye for lite, og de føler at de lever under slavelignende forhold. Den alkoholiserte bonden følger opp driften svært dårlig; kuene blir ikke melket ofte nok, maten uteblir til enkelte måltider og dyrene har det i det hele tatt ikke bra. En dag gjør dyrene opprør, jager bonden og mennene hans fra gården, og overtar driften selv. Nokså snart skjønner dyrene at de trenger en leder, og etter en del rivalisering blir grisen Napoleon valgt. Han fremstår etter hvert som enehersker på gården. I begynnelsen er det mye glede og stor velstand på gården. Ingen trenger å overanstrenge seg, og alle har nok å spise. Men virkeligheten innhenter dem, og igjen oppstår misnøye og murring. Dette møtes med påminnelser om hvordan det var før, den gangen bonden styrte gården og dyrene var ufrie. Problemet er bare at dyrene for lengst har glemt hvordan det egentlig var i gamle dager. Frykten for fortiden er imidlertid så innprentet i dem at de gir seg uten å mukke. Handlingen i boka har helt klare paralleller til hvordan totalitære samfunn fungerer, og boka er helt klart politisk. Her får vi innblikk i utnytting av maktposisjoner og "folkets" avmakt overfor sin enehersker. Mantraet om at "all animals are equal" endres umerkelig til "all animals are equal, but some animals are more equal". En fornøyelig og tankevekkende bok, og utvilsomt en klassiker man "bør" får med seg. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mustreaditall</user>
	<review>This is how you do it. There's a reason Animal Farm is a classic of both literature in general and political satire specifically - it's damn near perfect. The allegory is simple enough for a literate child to grasp, even if they have no information about Stalinism or Soviet Communism to base it on, and for those who have studied history it maintains its worth as a fable.The telling of the story itself can scarcely be criticized. You know what's going to happen. It's obvious from Napoleon's first appearance that he'll soon be as much (or more) of a tyrant as the original farmer. Heck, I'd read it before, back in middle school, but I still felt the rush when the animals drove out their owner and burned the whips, seethed with anger at Squealer's endless propaganda (swallowed whole by the mostly-illiterate and trusting workers), shared Benjamin's rage and horror as Boxer is sold to the knackers to pay for the pigs' carousing.I believe it was Terry Pratchett who said something like, "There's a reason they're called revolutions - it all just keeps coming around to the beginning again." What I found interesting, though, was that the book really isn't a flat out condemnation of socialism or even communism - it's about a promise broken, power seized, and ideals twisted into a horrible shape. I think that's part of why, even while USSR-style communism fades into history, you can apply the Animal Farm allegory to any number of political situations. It's not strictly tied to the obvious.final thought: This book scared the crap out of me as a preteen. (I was already fairly paranoid and antigovernment way back then.) These days I find it less frightening, but I think it maintains a current of power found in very little political writing. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>birdhouse</user>
	<review>An allegory for the world political scene during the Cold War. Napoleon representing Stalin and his oppression which turns to corruption is vaguely humanizing. That he takes the best for himself while letting the other animals die is worse than capitalism's inequalities. Good read for anyone not alive in the Cold War era. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dorareis</user>
	<review>«À primeira vista, este livro situa-se na linhagem dos contos de Esopo, de La Fontaine e de outros que nos encantaram a infância. Tal como os seus predecessores, Orwell escreveu uma fábula, uma história personificada por animais. Mas há nesta fábula algo de inquietante. Classicamente, atribuir aos animais os defeitos e os ridículos dos humanos, se servia para censurar a sociedade, servia igualmente para nos tranquilizar, pois ficavam colocados à distância, «no tempo em que os animais falavam», os vícios de todos nós e as suas funestas consequências. Em A Quinta dos Animais o enredo inverte-se. É a fábula merecida por uma época − a nossa época − em que são os homens e as mulheres a comportar-se como animais.» Antígona</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>firebird013</user>
	<review>Totally gripping - I read this as a teenager and nearly went straight through my station on my journey home. One of the must-reads of life. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Listener42</user>
	<review>6.0</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>annaanna</user>
	<review>Perfect really </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Joanna12</user>
	<review>How did I not receive this book as required reading back in high school?  Well now that I've picked it up, I realize that I would have enjoyed it then as much as I did now.  This thinly veiled (perhaps obvious) critique on the Russian government at the time provokes many questions on the legitimacy of any government and the inability for communism to operate effectively.  The animals band together to overthrow the evil "human" to form their own government - animalism, where all animals are created equal.  This fact reinforced in the seven commandments of animalism.  However, corruption and power struggles quickly impede on the central tenets of animalism.  This story reads like an extended Aesop's Fable with messages much more poignant than "slow and steady wins the race" while adding a biting satiric wit to it all.   This is altogether a facinating allegory to the way Soviet Russia was; yet, it still remains unbelievably revelant in today's society.  After all, "All animals are equal (but some animals are more equal than others)." </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TakeItOrLeaveIt</user>
	<review>the communist manifesto told through animals! YAY communism doesn't work and Orwell knows it and states it beautifully. George Harrison knew whazup too, in his song "Piggies". The Georgies... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>janepriceestrada</user>
	<review>I found this frightening in comparison to 1984.  the characterization and their social structure is quite remarkable.  It is excellent and short so as not to get bogged down with too many details. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>eesti23</user>
	<review>This quick read was a fantastic book that I enjoyed very much.  The overthrow of the farmer and his staff by the animals with a vision was well written, right down to the 'typical' characteristics of everyday animals.  The story comes full circle as the pigs, who are of course as equal as all the other animals, become a little bit more equal than the others. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cameling</user>
	<review>This book never gets old. A good study in totalitarianism and how power can sometimes have a corrupting influence </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>arouse77</user>
	<review>classic dystopian fable about the dangers of communism. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mentormom</user>
	<review>A great allegory about Communism and the Bolshevik Revolution.  This is quick read for those studying worldviews. It's a great example about why Communism can never work.  Learning a bit of history will make it even easier to understand.Old Major - Marx (and Lenin)Napoleon - StalinSnowball - TrotskySquealer - Molotov, minister of propagandaMinimus - poet  admirer of StalinRebel pigs - opposition that is silenced and executed, symbolizes the Great Purge that occurred under StalinPiglets - children of the next generation educated under the regimeMr. Jones - Czar of Russia Nicolas IIMr. Frederick - HitlerMr. Pilkington - Churchill, representing the Western powersMr. Whymper - Western intellectuals who supported CommunismBoxer  Clover - working class/proletariatMollie - upper-class nobility that fledBenjamin - CynicsPuppies - Stalin's Secret PoliceMoses the raven - Russian Orthodox Church or religionSheep - the masses </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KingRat</user>
	<review>Two of my top ten books of all time were written by George Orwell. Both Animal Farm and 1984 rank as classics of all time. Animal Farm is the fairy tale about animals who revolt on the farm and run it for themselves for a time.(Full review at my blog) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kathryngw</user>
	<review>Although it may have its benefits in critisizing communism, I did not enjoy reading this book. It made me have an ugly feeling, a feeling of hatred for those communist brutes (the pigs) and great pity for the other animals toiling under the unjust, unfair communists. I would not like this book at ALL if it wasn't for the fact that it really does capture what communism really is.It helps people realize that those who live in communist countries really aren't bad, they're caught. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>karenraebennett</user>
	<review>This novel is a satire of the Russian Revolution and would be most interesting to those familiar with political systems.  It is an indictament, though disguised by using animals as the lead characters, of the theories of socialism.  It is witty, though I spent much time finding myself very annoyed at the characters for their willingness to be played so thoroughly.  Most likely this was the feeling that Orwell wanted one to have.  This book is ideal for middle school students in that the political concepts could be introduced and understood well through the use of animals.  However; it would probably only be the advanced student that would catch the satire easy. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>frizero</user>
	<review>An astonishing fable about animals who rebel against men - in fact, the most ferocious - and humorous! - book about 1917's Russian Revolution and the horrible regimes in Soviet Russia that followed the event.  Orwell was truly a visionary - his novel '1984' is inbelievably revealing - and a great writer who knows how to tell a story.  A must-read classic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kymarlee</user>
	<review>classic political satire which explores the tenets of communism and the history of the Russian Revolution.  This book can be discussed and analyzed at many different levels. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kjarcand</user>
	<review>I read this classic in one sitting (and got a good sunburn outside!). I find a lot of classics to be boring and drawn out, as well as written in language that is hard to follow and this book by Orwell was totally the opposite. Perhaps because of my interest in politics I found this book very well written. I think this is a great crash course for anyone who wants to understand a bit about Marxism and the Red Scare. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Helger55</user>
	<review>ANIMAL FARM was George Orwell's satirical shot at the then-new totalitarianism of the left. It is so accurate that no one has been able to do it better or more effectively, or even come close. Who can forget "All Animals Are Created Equal, But Some Are More Equal Than Others." By putting wisdom in the mouths of animals, Orwell uses an age-old artifice and proves again how the pen can be mightier than the sword. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thmazing</user>
	<review>http://thmazing.blogspot.com/2008/04/...http://thmazing.blogspot.com/2008/01/first-five-books-of-2008-movie-with.html</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Anna454</user>
	<review>This book was just as great as 1984. George Orwell did an amazing job showing all of the different types of reactions that form during a dictatorship. It was nice because it was right to the point without extra discription.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>veneta09</user>
	<review>awesome reflection of human nature in a way that can be comprehended by all ages </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hnkemp</user>
	<review>George Orwell is a master at writing dystopic novels that read like a straight-forward story, with rich symbolism that is accurate in its description of today's political landscape as it was in the original publication.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>poope</user>
	<review>วันก่อนเพิ่งอ่าน Animal farm จบไป สะเทือนใจหลายวันอยู่ แต่ที่สะเทือนใจที่สุดเห็นจะเป็น พวกหมูจับบ๊อกเซอร์ไปฆ่าเมื่อเห็นว่าเขาหมดประโยชน์อีกต่อไป ไม่ต่างอะไรกับ บริษัทที่ไล่พนักงานเก่าออกเลย คงจะจริงอย่างที่เจ้าลาเบนจามินพูด ที่ว่า ไม่ว่าจะมีการปฏิวัติหรือไม่มีการปฏิวัติ ชีวิตก็ยังคงเลวร้ายอยู่เหมือนเดิม อืมม.... หนังสือเล่มนี้เขาเขียนมานานมากส์แล้วใช่ไหมคะ แต่หนูคิดว่าการเมืองไทยตอนนี้ก็ไม่ได้ต่างอะไรกับที่เขาเปรียบเปรยเอาไว้อย่างเจ็บแสบนี้เลยที่หนูขำจนอยากจะร้องไห้มากที่สุด คือ เขาเปรียบเทียบพวกสัตว์กับระบอบคอมมูนใช่ไหมคะ ที่ประมาณว่า ผลผลิตรวมทางการเกษตรซึ่งแต่ก่อนตกเป็นของมนุษย์แต่เพียงผู้เดียวถ้าปฏวัติได้สำเร็จ ผผลิตที่ผลิตด้วยน้ำพักน้ำแรงจากพวกสัตว์จะตกเป็นของสัตว์ที่ผลิตเองและจะได้รับมากกว่าที่เคยได้อย่างเท่าเทียมกันทั้งหมด ประเทศไทยเปลี่ยนแปลงการปกครอง ปฏิวัติปี2475 คนล่ะแนวกับการปกครองระบอบคอมมูนส์เลย แต่ไม่รู้ทำไมหนูกับรู้สึกว่ามันมีหลายสิ่งหลายอย่างที่คล้ายคลึงกันมาก ไม่ว่าจะวิธีการคิดที่อยากให้คนไทยประชาชนมีสิทธิ์มีเสียงในประเทศ ผู้ปฏิวัติ ผู้ถูกขับไล่ ผู้นำเผด็จการที่ดัน**อยู่ให้รกประเทศ (หนูว่าจอมพลสฤทธิ์เหมากับสควีเลอร์มาก ถ้าเรื่องเดินนานอีกหน่อยสควีเลอร์อาจจะปฏิวัตินโปเลียนต่อก็เป็นได้)และที่สำคัญ ความเป็นอยู่ของประชาชนเหมือนที่เจ้าเบนจามินพูดเอาไว้เด๊ะ ไม่มีอะไรเวิร์กขึ้นมาเลย75ปีแห่งการพัฒนา หรือ 75ปีแห่งความตายซากกันแน่หนอหนูก็ไม่เข้าใจเหมือนกัน เห็นบ่นๆกันจังว่าเมืองไทยไม่พัฒนา ประชาชนไทยยังด้อยทางการเงินการศึกษา (ซึ่งมันก็จริง ไม่งั้นทักษินคงไม่โดนขับไล่ด้วยวิธีนี้ชัวร์ๆถ้าประชาชนอีก 70-80% ถ้าปากท้องอิ่มกันตั้งแต่ต้น) จึงต้องทำรัฐประหารกัน เพราะถ้าหากไม่ทำวิธีการนี้ ก็มองไม่ออกเหมือนกันว่าจะทำอย่างไรที่จะเอาผู้นำ(ตัว)นี้ออกไป ในเมื่อประชาชนอีก 16 ล้านคนตามโพยทักษินยังเลือกเขาอยู่ หรือถ้ารอให้ถึงเวลาที่ประชาชนเห็นความถูกต้องจริงๆมันอาจจะสายไปสำหรับเมืองไทย ในเรื่อง Animal farm ใครว่าอะไรสมาชิกก็เห็นตามโดยไม่ไตร่ตรอง หมูเห็นว่าสมาชิกโง่เกินไปจึงต้องให้หมูตัดสินใจกันเอง จนกลายเป็นกินกันเอง หรือถ้าใครต่อต้านเห็นชอบกับสโนว์บอลก็จะถูกฆ่า จนการปฏิวัตินี่คือกบฏเพื่อสัตว์ด้วยกันหรือปฏวัติเพื่อหมูกันแน่ แล้วถ้าปัญหานี้จะแก้กันจริงๆก็ง่ายนิดเดียว ขึ้นอยู่กับตัวสโนว์บอลเอง ถ้าจะแอบมาติดต่อกับเจ้าบ๊อกเซอร์ ปรับความเข้าใจให้เจ้าบ๊อกเซอร์เสียหน่อยเพราะบ๊อกเซอร์ก็นับถือสโนว์บอลอยู่เหมือนกันตอนสงครามโรงวัว หรือเจ้าบ๊อกเซอร์ฉลาดกว่านี้หน่อย และให้ไประดม หนูว่า หมาเก้าตัวที่หมูนโปเลียนเลี้ยงก็โดนล้มได้โดยง่าย เพราะบ๊อกเซอร์ย่อมแข็งแกร่งกว่าและมีคนนับถือมากกว่าอยู่แล้วประชาชนทั้งประเทศส่วนใหญ่มีโทรทัศน์ วิทยุ หนังสือพิมพ์ในการรับข้อมูลข่าวสาร ต่อให้อยู่ในเมืองหรือชนบทหน่อยก็ตาม ทำไมผู้นำที่เจ๋งๆหรือพวกสื่อที่น่ารักถึงยังไม่ประโคมให้ประชาชนเข้าใจ รับทราบถึง ความเป็นไปในพรรค ประชาธิปไตยที่แท้จริง หรือลักษณะผู้นำเลวๆ หรือแนวคิดอะไรที่ทำให้พวกเขามีความรู้และรู้จักความพอมีพอกินกันมากกว่านี้ (ย้ำ มากกว่านี้ ไม่ใช่การพูดเสริมคั่นรายการ) แบบที่เทกันลงข่าวดาราหรือโฆษณากันบ้างคะ(แน่นอนสุดท้ายประชาชนต้องดูอยู่ดี เพราะมันไม่มีอะไรให้ดูแล้ว)ทำไมสื่อถึงไม่มีอิสระในการออกข่าว รัฐบาลชุดนี้ถ้าบอกว่าทำเพื่อประชาชนจริงๆ น่าจะทำอะไรที่มันดูดีกว่านี้ให้ประชาชนเข้าใจนะคะและทำตัวให้ต่างชาติดูดีกว่านี้ ประชาชนมีสมอง รับรองไม่ใช่สมาชิก Animal farm แล้วแบบนี้บอกให้ร่วมออกความเห็นร่างรัฐธรมมนูญคงอยากร่วมตายล่ะ ก็ในเมื่อการปกครองยังเป็นเผด็จการอยู่เลย อยู่ไปนานๆไม่รู้จะกลายเป็นร่างทรงสุจินดาหรือเปล่า หรือเพราะคนไทยฉลาดแต่ไม่เฉลียวกันเกินไป เราจึงยังต้องเจอผู้นำฉลาด(แกมโกง)ต่อไปหรือคะ? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gaullaura</user>
	<review>Smart and historical political comedy that always makes me laugh out loud. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>artbunny</user>
	<review>I picked this book up last night, and read it in one sitting. It was obvious that the story was a satire of Communism (all the animals call each other “Comrade”), and at times it was very funny in its ridiculousness. But there was a disturbing grain of truth throughout the book which can make the reader uncomfortable. Here is a revolution that starts from a common spirit of cooperation and a desire to make things better for the whole group. But when one group takes control, and uses lies and intimidation, or even murder, to keep that control, one is reminded sharply of oppressive governments around the world that are very real. The ending was definitely a slap in the face: as the “common” animals look on, they find that they cannot tell the difference between their pig leaders, who now go on two legs, and the evil humans they had overthrown. This story is incredibly funny, sad, and scary all at the same time, and it amazes me that Orwell had the foresight to write it back in 1946, just after the Iron Curtain had fallen. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>leelerbaby</user>
	<review>Animals on a farm overthrow the humans and manage themselves with the hope of better living conditions. All their idealistic efforts lead them to them living under tyranny, being ruled by the Pigs. Pigs, who with every new unjust act committed on upon what they consider lesser animals become more and more like those they rebelled against, the Humans.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>acrn</user>
	<review>Such a lovely fable. In all seriousness, i think it would be a great book for children, as i didn't enjoy it that much within' my two decades of age, but would love to read it when i had some sensible imagination.But then, would the children get the impression that this is a fable? I think so. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jacey</user>
	<review>Interesting take on sociology - read over Christmas break </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ktoonen</user>
	<review>Parable </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>qofd</user>
	<review>Such a simply written story which left me with a frustration towards the greed and stupidity of the human race.  Wish the villain hadn't been a pig, I like pigs. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jholcomb</user>
	<review>The introduction to the edition I read, by Julian Symons, explains that the reception of this novel has a convoluted history.  Orwell had trouble finding a publisher for a novel apparently critical of the Soviet Union, not only a wartime ally but one traditionally looked upon favorably by his associates among the Left.  When the Cold War got underway, Orwell and his book were enthusiastically co-opted by the British and American right-wings as anti-socialist, though Orwell remained in favor of Democratic Socialism—it was totalitarianism that he opposed.  The negative of Animal Farm is much clearer than its positive.  There is no clear alternative to the events that take place on the farm.	Clearly, an essential component of Napoleon’s successful takeover is the ignorance and tractability of the other animals.  Animal Farm exhibits the interest in the control of memory which would find fuller expression in 1984; because most of the animals are illiterate, Napoleon and Squealer are able to alter their memories in order to control them more effectively.  Because the animals’ previous oppression has left them unsuitable for real citizenship, the essential factor, equality, can never be more than an illusion which gradually fades away.  Indeed, it is Napoleon’s mental superiority to the rest of the animals which allows him to slowly move from the illusion of equality to the totalitarian reality of consumption, nowhere more poignant than in Boxer’s removal by the knacker’s van when he can no longer work.  Snowball’s failure stems from the inability of the other animals to respond to his efforts, from his own naivety about those efforts, and from his failure to understand Napoleon’s tactics.  The books ends on a truly awful note, the exposure of Napoleon and the other pigs as having become like men, but this very similarity offers a note of hope—what is to prevent another revolution, as the animals revolted against the men?  It seems significant, too, that the banished Snowball never reappears in the novel; he might be dead, but he might also have a chance to learn from his mistakes and try again on another farm </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>audreydog</user>
	<review>Four legs good!  Two legs bad! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SanctiSpiritus</user>
	<review>George Orwell was a socialist who found the "socialism" of the USSR shockingly abysmal and nauseating. To the author, they were not following the "true" tenets of socialism. So much so that the country was spiraling towards two polar opposites: depravity, despair, greed, frugality, sated, starving. Such is the truth, and story that the author so greatly transcribes in Animal Farm. The book is astounding in its simplicity. However, the simple story is a profound one. The book is far from boring, and grips you with curiosity as to what on the farm will happen next. Every person should read this short work of art. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DeusExLibrus</user>
	<review>This book may seem simple on the surface, but its actually meant as a complex allegory about communism. I didn't really like it that much, but I can see how its historically important. Plus I get a laugh out of the fact that some idiot tried to ban it for having talking animals. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is a dark satire, showing us what the author considers are some of the worse implications of communism and its failures, and human politics in general.He uses a farm animal setting as the means to do this, as the various creatures set up their own class structures, leadership and indulge in repression and violence.http://gutenberg.net.au/0100011.txthttp://freesf.blogspot.com/2007/01/an... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ysmng</user>
	<review>Another Orwell must read. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lipringinspired</user>
	<review>We read this book in Freshman English and I remember half of the class did not read it because they had no idea what in the world it meant. In my opinion the book is better left until after you have a few history classes under your belt and can fully appreciate the tie ins between history and the story.However, I believe the story is good enough to stand alone without the history lesson if you are so inclined as to give it a chance.Read it and see for yourself, you might walk away with a better understanding of the world.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Luc_Bertrand</user>
	<review>Génial, le totalitarisme par des animaux! (un poil moins bon que 1984) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>agage</user>
	<review>Animal Farm follows the story of animals who take over a farm to rule and govern it themselves. After they run the humans off the property, the animals attempt to set up their own form of government order through basic rules such as "all animals are equal" and "four legs are better than two." Because of their intellegence, the pigs begin to rise to an authoritative power, and slowly begin to change the rules to assert their dominance over all the other animals. Ignorantly, the rest of the farm animals follow whatever the pigs, particularly Napoleon, say and are somewhat unaware of what is going on with them. The novel is based off of Orwell's response to the rise of Stalin in Russia. This novel relates to our Utopias and Dystopias theme because the animals attempt to create a perfect world (that is, one with no humans) so that they can work and eat as they please, but a power-driven breed tries to take over everything and forms a dictatorship. The other animals are blindly unaware of what is going on, even though it is apparent to the reader, and we can almost do nothing but sit and watch them be duped into believing someone who is hoarding all the power. Before I even began reading, I knew that many kids read this book in early high school or middle school. While I was reading, I could see why: the novel is written with simple syntax and diction so that anyone could pick up the book and get a story out of it, but the underlying message was complicated and symbolic, and would be something that someone older would understand. The book was a quick read, but would only maintain my interest during certain points rather than the whole way through. I probably would recommend it to a younger high school audience because it would be a good novel to get them thinking about literary techniques such as extended metaphors and narrative structure. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Osbaldistone</user>
	<review>A parable effectively, though simply, telling the story of what went wrong with socialism.  Orwell's work is a must read, but, with the hindsight of the 21st century, the 'cover' story is so transparent, and it's underlying message is so obvious, that Animal farm doesn't demand a second read. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Ambrosia4</user>
	<review>An extremely interesting look at why dramatic political change rarely works. While it is extremely depressing to read and think about, it's also a look at why socialism doesn't usually work- because usually someone smart comes around and abuses those of lower intelligence.A must read for everyone, if just to see what cruelty does to our world. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TheRiddler</user>
	<review>You hear about this book all the time!  Does it live up its hype?  HELLYEAH it does!  What an EXCEPTIONAL book!  One of my favorite books EVER!  Based on the Russian war, each of the animals connect to a human such as Stalin.  The moral of the story is very strong, and its entertaining the whole way through! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tmcarthur</user>
	<review>George Orwell's Animal Farm is a classical book regarding the slippery slope from revolution to a totalitarian society.  It serves as an allegory to the rise of Stalinist Russia and the decline of classical Leninist communism as well as the chasing away of Trotsky.  It also helps illustrate in a simple context the way a revolution can betray its own ideals, and how many systems perpetuate themselves at the cost of the lower classes, including some forms of communism.This story is about when the abused animals of a farm revolt at the behest of an old pig, and the results when they form a communal system of government, when tempers flair, when the leaders turn the commune into an aristocracy, and finally the fall of the tyranny.  It is an excellent book both for old and younger (think teen) readers to enjoy.  The allegory explains, from the point of view of Orwell, what happened after the death of Lenin in The Soviet Union.  A wonderful book that is applicable just as much today as it was when written, as a warning to those who would be idealistic, as a warning to those who would trust the idealism of others without looking for ulterior motives. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>phillynyc</user>
	<review>This is a perfect novel.  The abstraction of Animals used here makes the social commentary posed by Orwell enjoyable and accessible.  Anyone interested in communism, in history, in the world should revel in this masterpiece. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dpetersen24</user>
	<review>Product DescriptionFrom the pages George Orwell's political satire comes the animated version of Animal Farm! See what happens to yyrannical Farmer Jones when the animals revolt and take over the farm. See what happens to the lovable animals when greed, bigotry and democracy take them over. Politics and Economics - it's not jus the humans problems anymore!</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sharrison</user>
	<review>A personal favorite of mine, and an absolutely brilliant quick read, with a lot of history. This book by George Orwell is a direct interpretation of the flaws of both communism and humanity. Riddled with symbols, you are bound to find a new one every time you read it. George Orwell was known for his political satire, and this is a foremost example of such, although it could be said he dumbed down his writing for this piece. This book is easy to understand, as well as very short, and a recommended read for everyone young and old. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Piluky</user>
	<review>Sátira del comunismo en forma de fábula con el prólogo "la libertad de prensa". Recomendable. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>emhromp2</user>
	<review>I loved this book. It is so clever, and it is beautifully written. The message is loud and clear. Definitely one of my favourites! </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>john257hopper</user>
	<review>Timeless classic that can be enjoyed at various levels: adults, especially those familiar with Soviet history, can appreciate the political allegory, while children could still appreciate this as an amusing and frightening tale of animals taking over from people.  Orwell's original foreword, reproduced at the end of this edition,is also worth reading for its salutary lesson on how liberal intellectuals can sometimes fool themselves into supporting the most illeberal regimes. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pjackson</user>
	<review>Picture a farm, now picture that farm run by animals; how would that farm be run?  A utopia where all animals were equal?  Or would there be animals that were “more equal”?  That premises is what you find in animal farm, where the livestock take the farm over from their farmer and try to govern themselves.   The novel shows one view on how a good idea can lead to tyranny if people (animals in this case) stand up for what they know is right.	Governments are put in place to make our lives easier.  To create a utopia for it’s citizens.  But when that government takes too much power then the people are left powerless.  In Animal Farm, the animals try and make a form of governing that helps everyone, a utopia.  Sadly, as with most novels with the topic of utopias, the utopia doesn’t last long.  A group of characters slowly start to take power.  They use simple techniques like propaganda to help sway the thoughts of the other animals.  At times even using brute force. 	Throughout the novel you see obvious foreshadowing of what’s going on.  Most ideas on government and tyranny are not very subtle in their presentation.  Thus making the short book not as enjoyable.  I felt that there wasn’t much left for me to build upon through reading in between the lines. Everything was pretty much stated for me.  Either way, the over all writing was done well and I did enjoy several parts of the book.  It’s a short read so it’s very easy to make time to read the novel so there is no reason, if you enjoy books on utopian governments, for you to not read this. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>agrabfelder</user>
	<review>What?! A short novel where animals take over a farm and pigs are intelligent? That must be Animal Farm by George Orwell. Orwell creates a dystopia and criticizes a socialist system and the corruption of a ruler. The novel is about Animals on a Farm that can talk, think, and are the characters of the story. They find the farmer, Mr. Jones, who owns them to be a tyrant and overthrow him by running him and his farmhands off the farm. They set up their own system with their own laws. Slowly one of the pigs begins to usurp power. He eliminates competitions and threatens anyone who would oppose him with his attack dogs. The condition the animals are living in is becoming just like the one they rebelled against in the first place. That is the main gist of the book.	George Orwell is creating his dystopia through the Animal’s society on the farm. The animals’ society is sort of a socialist society. The upper class, the pigs, start gaining power. The stupider and less apt animals don’t realize the upper class’ gain in power and are manipulated easily. The animals rebelled against Mr. Jones for equality and a better life style and eventually they end up replacing the tyrant with a corrupt ruling class. Orwell is telling the reader the socialism will never be the best type of government because one group of people will always rise above the rest to rule and take more responsibility and therefore power. They aren’t always necessarily corrupt though. They class struggle in Animal Farm is another way Orwell makes the animals new society a dystopia. The upper class reaps all the benefits of the lower, working class and controls them completely.	This book is short, but is mostly a slow read. It seemed to go fast in the beginning, but after a certain point the plot became repetitive. It was certainly not a mystery book, and as juvenile as the character set up was the clues were also juvenile and not so subtle. It was about a four or five out of ten in my opinion. It had a very interesting point at the very end of the novel but I’m not sure that that one point was really worth reading the whole book for. I would assume that the book would have carried more meaning around the time it was written or around the time that the Soviet Union was still around. I would suggest to read this book if you have time, just because it is a classic and is a quick read. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Patentnonsense</user>
	<review>The paradigmatic portrait of Stalin's Russia, and a classic text in politiical science. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jbmartin</user>
	<review>After being frustrated with Mr. Jones and how he ran his farm, the overworked and mistreated animals of Manor Farm revolt against the humans- ultimately kicking out all human beings from their own farm. Thinking that they will be much happier on their own, set guidlines to abide by. What the animals learn, through a serious of unfortunate events, is that creating the perfect society is not always as easy as one would think.Animal Farm, much like the other books that we have read, shares the utopia theme because the main characters, being the animals themselves, work hard for a common goal: to achieve the perfect society. However, as we have learned from past books, achieving this goal is close to impossible- and Animal Farm sets out to prove that. By eliminating human beings from their lives, the animals believe that life will be much easier, but as they realize towards the end of the novel, life without humans is even harder. Overall, the animals also learn that though they all share the common goal of achieving the perfect society, others are more willing to achieve this than others- even if it means greedily working behind other's backs and murder to get it. Overall, I really did enjoy this book. Though the message is very deep, the reading was definately quite easy and very, very straight to the point. In fact, I found most occurences to be quite predictable. With that being said however, I was defiantely suprised by some random plot twists. I also really enjoyed this book not only because the animals clearly proclaimed that they were against everything having to do with humans, even though they acted and lived their lives like humans, but also because of the historical context. Orwell defiantely wrote this book as a satire, and it is quite clear. Growing up with a history major as a father, I knew quite well of the Stalinist Russia that Orwell based Animal Farm on, so it was interesting to pin-point the animals and try to figure out which historical icon they represented. Animal Farm was definately a great book, and I am glad that I had the oppurtunity to read it. I do reccomend this book for anyone who is looking for an easy read, but can also recognize the deeper meaning and purpose in the book. It really is much deeper than one would think, and it is brilliantly showcased through the lives of farm animals. Now I understand why it is considered a classic. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chocolatestarfishman</user>
	<review>This is definitely a 5 star, this book is just amazing!  It tells the story of the Russian Revolution, but with animals.  It may sound insane to those of you who have not read it, but boy it is great!  The story has a great plot, and although I don't want to give spoilers, its whole main idea is really great, and everyone who reads it will end up finding out its main idea.  This is a HUGE hit for a reason! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rotheche</user>
	<review>http://rotheche.googlepages.com/anima... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LegalMove</user>
	<review>A wonderful illustration of the aphorism, "Power corrupts, absolute power corrupts absolutely."  A must read for anyone naive enough to believe Marxism still has relevance. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>freudslip</user>
	<review>Where, oh where is the 21st century's Orwell?  The man is insightful, bold, and spot on.  Although this book is taught as a primer in High Schools across America (probably for its size and the obviousness of its satirical allegory of Soviet totalitarianism).  I loved it, and it still charms, as much as an allegory about totalitarianism can charm really. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>orangemonkey</user>
	<review>This wasn't my first time reading Animal Farm, but it was definitely the most rewarding read through it I've ever done.  There are two reasons for this: the first is that I was reading it with one of my students, who emigrated from a communist country for political reasons, and secondly it's the first time I've read anything by Orwell since the beginning of the "War On Terror".  Both of these conspired to create a sense of urgency to the reading, and also helped to illustrate exactly how relevant Orwell still is today.  While 1984 is entirely tied to totalitarian regimes, Animal Farm shows how they come about - through a combination of willful political ignorance by the masses, a government that wishes to maintain control by using a scapegoat villain who is blamed for all of the country's woes.  This is the kind of book that needs to be read by everyone in a democratic government as a warning - unfortunately, it's also too often ignored to our peril. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ThatsFresh</user>
	<review>I had to read this over the summer for an Honors Government class.  I didnt mind it, since it was so short, but I didnt like it much either.  I read it AFTER reading 1984.  Big mistake.  This is practically a summary of 1984, even though it was written before it.  If you want to read a much much much better version of this story, just skip it and move on to the Orwell's real telling of this story, 1984. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>badgenome</user>
	<review>A scathing indictment of Stalinism wrapped in the charming trappings of a fable, Animal Farm is a concise masterpiece and one of the best books you can read in a single sitting. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>robledo</user>
	<review>A través de la fábula del la granja de los Jones, Orwell realiza una sátira del estalinismo, y una crítica y análisis de cómo el poder genera corrupción. Es una denuncia contra todo tipo de totalitarismo. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>grady.cameron</user>
	<review>I read this book three times in middle school and high school, and only two of those times was I required to.  I read it again this year and it was just as awesome as I remember.  It is amazing how this story can act as a history lesson and a contemporary parable at the same time.  I think that it has always been topical and always will.This particular edition is a treat, too, because of the illustrations by Ralph Steadman...  The spilling ink and motion of the art captures well the grotesqueness of the pigs and the horror of the tale.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kid_shelley</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is literary social commentary at its best. An engaging allegory reminding one that power corrupts and absolute power corrupts absolutely. Accessible and thought-provoking; great for discussion groups. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mfassold</user>
	<review>Great book to introduce students to the role, function, and dangers of government.  Great writing and characters that still live on in the American lexicon. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Scaryguy</user>
	<review>Animal farm: A love story. Well, not exactly, but an interesting take on humanity were it in the animal form. Still nutty? Maybe, but this book uses allegory to show one of the biggest political struggles of the twentieth century. It's not for everyone, but, when in doubt, remember: it's just a story. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>llamagirl</user>
	<review>This, of course, is Orwell's farm-set satire of the Russian Revolution. It's one of my favorites and I find it more readable than 1984 if not a superior work. This "50th Anniversary edition" is illustrated by Ralph Steadman, which is another plus in my book. His frenzied style fits with the text nicely. Also included are Orwell's Proposed Preface (a scathing comment on the publishing industry's practice of hushed up censorship) and his Preface to the Ukranian Edition. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pauliharman</user>
	<review>Reading Orwell always makes my blood boil. Which, on occasion, is a good thing. Halfway through Animal Farm I was almost incoherent with rage - which, I am sure, was Orwell's intent. The man is a master. I felt the same way about Nineteen Eighty-Four; for a long time I hated that book as it was the first thing I'd read that didn't have a happy ending, and I felt betrayed. Now of course I'm old and wise enough to realise that for both books, their endings are the only natural and true ones that can follow from the material. Orwell's worlds are bleak and abhorrent, but he paints the terrifying picture of how similar they are to our own, if we do not take care to avoid that easy path to our own destruction, one seemingly reasonable step at a time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>snappa</user>
	<review>George Orwell's Animal Farm is quite deservedly a classic, and for many reasons.  I first encountered in at high school, in 1970, when I was 14 years old and in 2nd form. I was pretty naive at the time, and Animal Farm was my first real introduction to the harsh realities of life and that thing called 'politics' which, as the book shows, is so much driven by greed and corruption. Animal Farm was a good book for school because it was presented as a simple fable which anyone could understand, plot wise that is. As regards the deeper meaning and relationship with the past and present, well I know it was discussed at school, but a lot of that understanding would come with time and maturity. Comprehension of the book was assisted by the cartoon film version, all of which had an undoubted influence on my 12 year old brain. The book is timeless, because the issues discussed have not gone away. The lesson of history is not that we learn from our mistakes, but rather, that we learn how to improve upon and repeat our so-called mistakes. Greed and corruption is rife in our society like never before, and dutifully hidden under a blanket of spin. The story of the pigs and the farm animals is oft repeated in various cgi digital creations, though with much of the politics and the punch removed. For Orwell's story is dark, bleak and real, and therefore not really the stuff of kids entertainment. It is time for a remake of Animal Farm, in this post 9/11 Coalition of the Willing environment, though hopefully this time it won't be funded by the CIA and its ending changed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>keidz</user>
	<review>i read this book when i was in college for a book report. i found it good to my surprise. even if it was written several years ago, i still find it very much relevant to our present situation.  it's politically relevant and very much describes the "animals" in the government. Ü</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Karlstar</user>
	<review>A classic tale of politics from a barnyard perspective.  The farm setting removes some of the 'human' element and allows Orwell to focus on politics and rhetoric. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tnzgurl</user>
	<review>i had to read this book twicethe first time i HATED itthe 2nd time i didnt like it much eitheri dont reccomend it much </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>HvyMetalMG</user>
	<review>Talking pigs?  Chickens with a totalitarian mindset?  Orwell uses everyone's favorite farm animals to depict the struggle for freedom reflecting the time period of this book.  A book I read when I was way too young, but still stands out for me today. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>frenz</user>
	<review>Excellent - If anyone hasn't read this, you should read it as soon as possible..! It's a classic that everyone who reads, knows! Great fun to read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LibraryLou</user>
	<review>Reading this as an adult is so different to when I read it in class aged 11. We didn't understand the real complexities in it then, we thought it was just an animal story! </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ejakub</user>
	<review>Classic read! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hijohnmark</user>
	<review>A classic that I have read many, many times. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shoomg</user>
	<review>I don't think this book is as great as everyone else does. It is a satire on Communism, wherein the animals on a farm drive out their human exploiters in a Marxist revolution, only to have the pigs gradually become the new masters, just like the humans they drove out. Everyone seems to think this book is a denuciation of communism, but it is not. The ideal of communism is never challenged, just its corruption by the ambitious pigs. In other words, it's a satire on Stalinism. I think that Orwell's critique of totalitarianism in 1984 is much, much better than that in Animal Farm. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrsmauck</user>
	<review>This was definitely an interesting read, if it wasn't much of a page-turner. I think it would be a great discussion book for my high school students: which animal would you want on your side in case of battle? What rulers would you compare Napolean to? What part of the system did Squealer represent? Why is education important in a democracy? </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ClydePark2007</user>
	<review>You can't complain about a book that gets right to the point and says all that need be said in 128 pages. Not a moment is wasted in unecessary exposition or attempts at being more "literary."It is well written and deserves its reputation as one of the great English language novels. I know all about it being a statement against totalitarianism, but I'm not smart enough to discuss all that. It works just as well as a fairy tale that exposes the problems of power and greed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sadiebooks</user>
	<review>delightful.  i just saw an illustrated version at borders the other day.  perfect to read to small children so that they don't grow up to be fascists. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>surreality</user>
	<review>Plot: straightforward, with no side-plots branching off. It mostly serves as a backdrop for the character-driven story. Characters: aside from some exceptions, characterization isn't done for individuals but for species, playing on common stereotypes. The cast is fairly large for a short novella, and yet there is plenty of time to draw the character traits. Much of it also relies on the reader recognizing who is being parodied and adding it to the picture.Style: simple and powerful writing, with great use of symbolism. The atmosphere becomes more and more suppressing, which reflects in the vocabulary chosen.Plus: Wonderfully implemented metaphors. Minus: Too short, and the end is somewhat dissatisfying. Summary: Must be read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rabidcookie</user>
	<review>something like the russian revolution retold through the farm. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>guamo</user>
	<review>Too often overlooked as a simpler polemic than Orwell's "1984." I loved the book and its easy to read allegory. Its a great way to get into deeper political writings such as Marx without falling victim to an idealistic reading. Its small and good for high school students, but I would also recommend rereading it later especially after reading Marx or Engels. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kade</user>
	<review>A good book for a 5th-8th grade audience as long as they're at least somewhat aware of the political allegories in it. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nevusmom</user>
	<review>I read this the first time when I was in 5th grade, then read it several more times before finishing high-school.  We all know the story of the farm animals rising up against their oppressor.  Ultimately, though, this is a story of how power corrupts. I will never forget the line "...but some are more equal than others." </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>coffeezombie</user>
	<review>The Western literary canon sometimes seems a bit short of politicalparables involving animals. Thank god for George Orwell fillingthat otherwise empty niche. One of what you might call the "AmericanHigh School Classic" thanks to it's easily digestable themes and colorcoded characters, it's popularity hardly draws away from the fact thatit is a chilling political fable. Basically detailing a communistuprising on a small English farm, it matches Orwell's hatred of theSoviets with his hatred of totalitarianism in general, making for aquick, invigorating read.(This review originally appeared on zombieunderground.net) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Redthing</user>
	<review>I didn't like the ending, but overall, it's a good satire of Soviet Russia. I found it much more enjoyable than 1984. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lis</user>
	<review>Sátira del estalinismo, que surgida de la pluma de un ex-comunista como Orwell gana en credibilidad.Esta novela defiende como ninguna la tesis de que el poder corrompe, y que el poder absoluto corrompe absolutamente.Como su gran éxito 1984 nos encontramos con un alegato contra el autoritarismo que debería leer todo el mundo. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FionaCat</user>
	<review>Not quite as good as 1984 but still a very good book.  I always get upset when the horse dies, which is probably why I rate it behind 1984. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jodyreadseverything</user>
	<review>I read this when I was eleven and my brother brought a copy home from school.  I took it at face value as a story about some talking animals and really enjoyed it.  Further readings have made me appreciate what it's really trying to say but I still enjoy it.  I don't like to give too much away about the story and its meanings but this is a very readable book, well thought out and it makes it's point. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>boeflak</user>
	<review>This book continues to percolate through my consciousness more than any other in the 40 years since reading it in high school. Some of its phrases continually insinuate themselves into conversations at my place of business, such as "All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others." </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Amabel300</user>
	<review>I agree that this book was quite tedious and the comparisons were so blatant it was nearly painful. I found myself really reading TOO MUCH into this book. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sulkyblue</user>
	<review>If I'd known this book was so short, I'd have read it ages ago. While I can accept it's powerful historical importance, I didn't actually think much of the book itself. I found the lack of subtletly quite tedious and just didn't feel engaged by the book at all. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jaylabelle</user>
	<review>The allegorical tale of the Russian Revolution: what happens when farm animals revolt and drive the humans out... only to be ruled by the smartest and idlest of the animals - the PIGS! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cestovatela</user>
	<review>The path from social change to repressive dictatorship perfectly explained. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Akasha_evil</user>
	<review>This is one of my favorite books ever. If you love it also, you should check out Snowball's chance (a post 9/11 sequel). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kaelirenee</user>
	<review>The classic political satire by the same man who brought us ideas about Big Brother.  This is one of the books I was made to read in school that I've come back to years later and learned a whole new level of respect for. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>anlor43</user>
	<review>www.thebookpond.se </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MrsLee</user>
	<review>A good political read and a good story as well. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bradsucks</user>
	<review>I should have read this when I was 15, it might have blown my mind. Reading it at 28 though it came off kind of predictable and obvious. 1984 light. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jake15</user>
	<review>an all aurond great book </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>meursault06</user>
	<review>http://malaysianatheist.blogspot.com </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lilinah</user>
	<review>This is NOT a children's book, but for some reason, youth too young to appreciate it are often forced to read it. This is *serious political* commentary, disguised as  something lighter by featuring farm animals as the main characters. Excellent criticism of political systems that claim to be equally fair to everyone...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>eslee</user>
	<review>An eighth grade force-read. If you can't tell, I despised my eighth grade English teacher, her class, the school district, and its dumbed-down curriculum. In short, my hatred of her seeped into this book, and I really should read it again before making any solid decision about it. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LeeMoppet</user>
	<review>I had to read this book for school and found myself really enjoying it.  If you read this book, you must read it in an analytical way rather than just reading it as a story about animals.  It's a great read if you want to learn about the Russian Revolution. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>adriel</user>
	<review>A good classic, George Orwell presents what Communism can do to society. The end result? The leaders of the new society become exactly like their enemy. It is the journey there that is so interesting. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>burnit99</user>
	<review>George Orwell's classic allegory about what happens when the animals take over the farm, a vivid and humorously dead-on portrait of a Communist takeover. Written in 1945, it remains as valid and enthralling as ever. Any book that gives rise to the popular quote "All animals are equal, but some are more equal than others" has much to recommend it. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ashishg</user>
	<review>Well written tale satirizing communism. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>olyra</user>
	<review>this sad, amazing book shows how messed up politics are, and how socialism fails just as badly, and sometimes more spectacularly, as democracy. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jhowell</user>
	<review>I can't remember how old (or young really) I was when I read this in school -- but I loved it and thought it was incredibly clever to boot. My first appreciation of an allegory. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is a dark satire, showing us what the author considers are some of the worse implications of communism and its failures, and human politics in general.He uses a farm animal setting as the means to do this, as the various creatures set up their own class structures, leadership and indulge in repression and violence.http://gutenberg.net.au/0100011.txthttp://freesf.blogspot.com/2007/01/an... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stipe168</user>
	<review>orwell has a way of breaking down complex ideas into simple terms. Here, animals represent us, showing what pigs we really are. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>snozzberry</user>
	<review>I last read this in high school, and I remember it being great. I really should read it again some time! </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>soylentgreen23</user>
	<review>Not as popular here as "1984" it would seem; one has to wonder why that is. For me, "Animal Farm" is the definitive, angry Orwell novel, a scathing attack on politics and man's inhumanity to man (et cetera). A wonderful little novel; I know my father hated it, and the reasons he gave were sufficient to delay my reading it until only a few years ago, but now that I have, I'm glad I did. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ragwaine</user>
	<review>A smack in the face of society.  Mandatory reading.  Made me really angry. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bembo</user>
	<review>One of the earliest books I recall reading, (and am prepared to admit to reading!). It requires no introduction or comment other than to say it should be on everyone’s list. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>woollymammoth</user>
	<review>Come on, you know the plot. A great book. A story of animals taking over the farm and it all going wrong. The  pigs end up acting like the men used to. First read aged 7, when I was actually going through an 'only Orwell and Blyton' phase. Seriously. I totaly missed the point of it at 7 of course. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>reverdybrune</user>
	<review>What can I say? It's a classic. It's an interesting read with some particularly chilling parallels to today's world. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heidilove</user>
	<review>amazing. a must read for everyone who works in our Corporate Age </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>protikche</user>
	<review>A better satire on authoritarianism has perhaps not been written. Its simplicity is such that it can be enjoyed by children and adults alike, though enjoyed wont be quite the right word for adults, but enjoy we do, nevertheless. Though generally known as a satire on the Russian revolution and the ideals it finally betrayed, today it can applied to a large variety of example and instances, something that perhaps Orwell himself foresaw as well, as he remarked that it is a protest against every form of authoritarianism, whether right or left. One need not know the history of the Russian revolution and its aftermath to understand the implications in the book and the basic foundation of the book is something we can all relate to, relate to what Kafka said about revolutions that all revolutions come and leave a bureaucracy behind. Even if the reader does not know who “Major” or “Snowball” is portrayed on, they can relate to them easily, as they can relate easily to “Boxer”, the unknown idealistic man or woman who is ultimately sacrificed as a pawn by leaders who ultimately begin to become the men they have overthrown. In the end perhaps, it’s a dark book but in a vein that is humorous even when it’s immensely ironic.It’s a timeless book because it deals with an idea that is inherent with human nature and that is something that has little changed in all of human history. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DanDanRevolution</user>
	<review>Timeless, wonderful, wry. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>adam.bullen</user>
	<review>Although i had a fair idea of what was going to happen before i read the book, some things still came as a shock whilst reading it. Also i hardly put this book down, a great read, i felt that this was an example of a nice ideal destoryed by the inequities of those involved, much like the part of history that it satires. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kawgirl</user>
	<review>I read this book in high school as a high school assignment and found it disturbing then. It might be more relavent now. This is a must read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bjfan82</user>
	<review>Quick, easy read.  Shows basically why Soviet Communism was destined to fail from the beginning. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>timj</user>
	<review>Is there a better comment on politics and politicians? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Thalia</user>
	<review>After having this book on my shelf for more than 10 years, I finally read it. And boy am I glad I decided to pick it up. It's by far the best allegory I have ever read. Explaining and criticizing communism using pigs and other farm animals is simply brilliant. And that it's short and to the point, just adds to Orwell's genius. A true masterpiece. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mythos13</user>
	<review>This novella takes the saying short and sweet to a whole new level. It gets across it's meaning consisely and without dallying with other topics that have nothing to do with the subject at hand. Not to mention that it's a masterful satyre that pokes fun at Communism, and with farm animals no less! It's an ideal book for many ages, as the older ideas don't come across to the younger age group and to them it can be little more than a tale of talking animals doing great things, whereas older readers can quickly recognize the bigger message of the story. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Wanderlust_Lost</user>
	<review>A very well written allegorical tale about Russian politics. I didn't enjoy this when I read it as a bored 12 year old but I appreciate it a lot more now. 4 stars because it's hard to ignore first impressions, but also because it is genuinely a great book. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>magst</user>
	<review>Wonderful book! One of the best books I had to read during my sophomore year in high school. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shirazahmed</user>
	<review>A book caomparing communists to animals on a farm. It is very well written with phrases and pages that use emphasis on big events. The whole point of the story isn't actually the story, but showing all the events that lead from beginnind to end, with nothing that can be spared. Not for a light reader, although it is compparitivly short, it is quite serious. I don't think it's one of those book sthat can make you cry, mainly because animal tragedy isn't as sad as human tragedy. The book is a satire also, so you dont want to cry. I felt like I half wanted to laugh, but couldn't cause it is pretty much the communist government. Which takes all the silliness out of it and puts it in a point of view that anyone can understand. You can trick your children in to thinking it's a fantasy-happy story about animals...on a farm. Boy won't they be in for a surprise. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sorormystica</user>
	<review>Never having read this in high school, I found this a remarkable and important work - a must read for every citizen: individuals need to have social and political awareness of what lies beneath the constante deceptive propaganda with which we are bombarded. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>smartyhall</user>
	<review>http://eruditionis.blogspot.com/2006/... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>David_Summers</user>
	<review>Animal Farm is an easy-to-read and appealing novella. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>christophax</user>
	<review>Ok, first of all, i have quite forgotten the book cover of the one i read, but nevermind. Animal Farm is an attire of the russian revolution and perhaps all the communist countries. It also is a lighter/similar version of 1984. To be honest, i saw the film before i read the book. but the book and the film are equally good. Boxer is perhaps my favorite character - his humbleness makes you feel his pain later on in the story. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>drfishy520</user>
	<review>The hardcover illustrated version of this book is amazing. As if the story itself weren't brilliant enough, this just adds a whole new dimension. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bmy78</user>
	<review>One of the few books that everyone--and I mean EVERYONE--should read at least once in their lifetime. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>choebe</user>
	<review>I first read this book in high school, and absolutely loved it. Sadly, the experience was somewhat tainted by the majority of my classmates missing the point entirely. They didn't seem to understand why, at their age, they were being made to read a story about talking animals. They missed out on a great book. Animal Farm is on my list of books I think everyone needs to read, at least once in their life. The ending gives me a wonderfully disturbed, unsettled feeling (isn't it great when a book can affect you like that?), and its message is just as relevant today as it was when it was first published. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>celestialfingerpaint</user>
	<review>I read this book the year before it was actually assigned to me because I had come across it in the library and talking animals looked interesting. When the book was assigned to us, a friend asked me what it was about. "Communist pigs," I replied.While it has the eerie, almost prophetic feel of "1984", it's much easier to read. I think it's a book any middle or high school student could read and comprehend, but discussions about real world application of the story may be needed. There are simply some things you don't truly appreciate until you've lived in the adult world, and this book deals with a lot of them. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>moia</user>
	<review>Underbara floskler och genial betraktelse av en despoti. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ForrestFamily</user>
	<review>One of the classics of 20th Century literature, this dystopian 'fairy-tale' is an allegory that tells us much more about humans and their capacity for dictatorship than it does about any farm.It must be remembered that this book was published for the first time sixty years ago - the allegory may be bordering on the blatantly obvious at times, but this is a post-Soviet age where we are much more aware of the dangers of deluded dictatorships where the will of the people is mangled into the privelege for the few. However, it is still highly relevant - just think North Korea. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sdtaylor555</user>
	<review>Really good book.  I read this one just for fun too, not in school. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jbd1</user>
	<review>One of those I read over and over again. Still just as good or better each time. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>benfulton</user>
	<review>I read this book a few years ago and was not nearly as affected by it as I was when I started it for the first time at age 15, and was so overcome by outrage I couldn't finish it.  It may have led directly to my current Libertarian leanings :) </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ejp1082</user>
	<review>It's hard to write about Animal Farm without comparing it to 1984, so that's what I'm going to do. Especially because of the two, I find Animal Farm to be the better novel.Though both have their fair share of iconic imagery and allegory, on the whole I think that Animal Farm is Orwell's better work. To begin with, it's a more well constructed story and consequently an easier read. Whereas 1984 simply paints a picture of a dystopia, Animal Farm shows how a dystopia comes to be - how the noble ideals that began the revolution get perverted, and the utopian dream is lost. It's more fantastical setting involving farm animals enhances it as an allegory, as opposed to 1984 which originally put me off because of the poorly conceived science fictional elements. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ithilwyn</user>
	<review>When I first started teaching, this novel was pretty standard for freshman English.  While it is a good teaching novel, I'm not particularly fond of it myself. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>patf4444</user>
	<review>Este é o primeiro grande sucesso alcançado pelo escritor britânico George Orwell, a cinco anos de sua morte. O livro denuncia o totalitarismo político do ditador soviético Josef Stalin, interpretado nesta fábula como um traidor da causa bolchevista. Os animais de uma fazenda (no título original em inglês, "Animal Farm", não há a menção de revolta implícita na versão brasileira do título), fartos da dominação humana, rebelam-se em grande estilo, mas os propósitos de sua revolução são desvirtuados. George Orwell é realista, cirúrgico, exato, e sua escrita, contundente, um exemplar literário que ambiciona ao manifesto. -- por Rosane Pavam</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>patf4444</user>
	<review>Este é o primeiro grande sucesso alcançado pelo escritor britânico George Orwell, a cinco anos de sua morte. O livro denuncia o totalitarismo político do ditador soviético Josef Stalin, interpretado nesta fábula como um traidor da causa bolchevista. Os animais de uma fazenda (no título original em inglês, "Animal Farm", não há a menção de revolta implícita na versão brasileira do título), fartos da dominação humana, rebelam-se em grande estilo, mas os propósitos de sua revolução são desvirtuados. George Orwell é realista, cirúrgico, exato, e sua escrita, contundente, um exemplar literário que ambiciona ao manifesto. -- por Rosane Pavam</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tsinandali</user>
	<review>Orwell is best at is most simple, and this is it.  With this and 1984, he changed the face of literature.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gnewfry</user>
	<review>Amazon.comSince its publication in 1946, George Orwell's fable of a workers' revolution gone wrong has rivaled Hemingway's The Old Man and the Sea as the Shortest Serious Novel It's OK to Write a Book Report About. (The latter is three pages longer and less fun to read.) Fueled by Orwell's intense disillusionment with Soviet Communism, Animal Farm is a nearly perfect piece of writing, both an engaging story and an allegory that actually works. When the downtrodden beasts of Manor Farm oust their drunken human master and take over management of the land, all are awash in collectivist zeal. Everyone willingly works overtime, productivity soars, and for one brief, glorious season, every belly is full. The animals' Seven Commandment credo is painted in big white letters on the barn. All animals are equal. No animal shall drink alcohol, wear clothes, sleep in a bed, or kill a fellow four-footed creature. Those that go upon four legs or wings are friends and the two-legged are, by definition, the enemy. Too soon, however, the pigs, who have styled themselves leaders by virtue of their intelligence, succumb to the temptations of privilege and power. "We pigs are brainworkers. The whole management and organisation of the farm depend on us. Day and night, we are watching over your welfare. It is for your sake that we drink that milk and eat those apples." While this swinish brotherhood sells out the revolution, cynically editing the Seven Commandments to excuse their violence and greed, the common animals are once again left hungry and exhausted, no better off than in the days when humans ran the farm. Satire Animal Farm may be, but it's a stony reader who remains unmoved when the stalwart workhorse, Boxer, having given his all to his comrades, is sold to the glue factory to buy booze for the pigs. Orwell's view of Communism is bleak indeed, but given the history of the Russian people since 1917, his pessimism has an air of prophecy. --Joyce Thompson--This review has been flagged by multiple users as abuse of the terms of service
						 and is no longer displayed (show).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>winkleranett</user>
	<review>This is a fairy story about animals, whose would like to get their farm from their farmkeeper. That’s a very funny poem,cause I really enjoyed it. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Danielle23</user>
	<review>I can't believe I hadn't read this earlier! A great interesting read and one that also spooked me quite a bit.A great insight into the human mind. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0452284244</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tedrick</user>
	<review>WELLS HITS THE SPOT EXACTLY WITH HIS PORTRAYAL OF COMMUNISM </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>