<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0471180017</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

This is the first book I have ever returned. I expected it to contain the code and detailed explanations. Its not there. The code might be on the CD but based on a previous review it sounds like the CD is screwed up. I  didn't open the CD so I could return the book.  An example of what I  expected the book to contain can be found in Naughton eamp; Schildt's book  Java 2: The Complete Reference.  The last couple of chapters of that book  present some applets along with the code and some very good explainations.   Infact I liked those chapters so much thats why I bought Java-Sig's 100  Best Applets.  I wanted more of what Naughton and Schildt had provided. I  didn't get it. I guess I should have known based on the number of Applets  they are reviewing that they could not provide anything more than a feel  good explaination of why they like the applet. I wanted to be able to  review the code at my leisure, perhaps while I am lying on my couch or  something. Instead you are forced to sit at your computer to get anything  out of this book. Rather than buy this book just search the web for some  applets and their source.
      </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0471180017</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

I develop webpages for a living -- everyone wants Java applets.  This book gives my clients something to flip through, point at, and say equot;yeah, I want thatequot;.  The descriptions of the applets are dynamite -- clear, lucid (sometimes even funny) and the organization of the book makes it really easy to find the applets you need.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>