<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gep63@aol.com</user>
	<review>

I have seen many language books, but this one is the best. It's a British publication, but that is not a problem for me, being an American. Extremely well structured with great vocabulary and expressions -- all students seem to like and understand the examples and exercises. Every ESL teacher should have this book for grammar. It covers just about everything and handles the quirks of English thoroughly.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

This is one of the best grammar books I've ever found! Very didadict and with an easy to use step by step format (138 units) it's a very good source to the self-student (every unit has a lot of exercises and the book provide  you with an answers guide at its end)
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>"slmckeel"</user>
	<review>

This book has a strong emphasis on the use of English. The topics stand alone and can be selected for the students needs. The topics are delt with in depth and enough exercise are available to learn the topic well. The student can check his or her work and learn from any errors. The teacher does need to add some element of grammar structure to the study program. This is very good material to teach ESL students and they seem to enjoy discovering how to express themselves in English with the exercises in this book.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>K. Johnson</user>
	<review>

This is helpful for students who need some improvement on accuracy and the basic understanding of general or particular grammar concepts.  Some Intermediate students have more needs than others as more complicated facets of English are brought forth at this level.  If a student needs to more fully understand the difference between the usage of equot;forequot; and equot;sinceequot; for example, this particular point can be xeroxed and handed out to those who need it.  (Many students cannot afford to purchase this entire book in many parts of the world.)  There are useful illustration timelines and examples for many grammar functions here.  The table of contents makes a point quick to find.  A very useful supplement to the curriculum textbook, especially in communitive textbooks (i.e., Headway, Interchange) that are focusing on fluency-based methodology.  In sum, students with grammar (accuracy) problems can get specific aid parallel to the text and activities being used in the curriculum.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

For many year we have used this practice book with our students and most - if not all - of them liked it and had fun with grammar. Results improved dramatically and the teachers could sit back and relax. Not only do the comprehensive explanations shed some more light into many students' darkness of English Grammar but students welcome the variety of graded exercises that really give them a chance to progress steadily. Good book for all EFL/ESL students, no matter what their national background is.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

I came across this book a year ago and it was a  revelation for me. I have never seen such a well designed  book in any knowledge field and as a foreign student in English, I can tell I have learnt and understood a lot of grammar rules. I advise anyone to own this book because it is the equot;keyequot; to succeed in understanding English grammar. Many many thanks to the author.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>luegoo "luegoo"</user>
	<review>

This book covers very good the basic english grammar. I used this book when I was practising for the equot;Cambridge First Certificateequot; and it turned out very helpful. There is a good structure with grammar content on the left side of the book and excercises on the right. You easily find the grammar topics you are looking for, as they are listed in a logical order. I highly recommend this book, but I don't give it 5 stars because it's a bit dated and does not include any modern, usefull expressions.
      </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>qasim</user>
	<review>

I would say this is the best and simple book i have ever seen.  And i would highly recommend it to anyone.  It has got little pictures which makes it very easier to understand.  Thanks Mr. Murphy :-)
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mnrocks</user>
	<review>

this is the best book for esl students available in the world. i've been using quite a few different books (or i'd rather say, i've been trying to use...), and my resume is: raymond murphy is the most talented author and teacher you might find. what i like the most about this particular book is how easy it is to use. also, equot;murphy's englishequot; is more fun than any other english you can think of :) another yet great feature of this book is how well and unusual the material is devided into chapters. it's simply an all new understanding of what english is!   a very good example of a great work done by a person who LOVES what he's doing.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0521532892</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>R. Bacevac "ribac"</user>
	<review>

Well as speaker of another language I bought a lot of books to learn English.Although I learnt in high school Istill have been buying books to learn more.Finally I bought English Grammar in use and coudn't stop reading.I've never seen better book.It covers everything you need to know about English grammar.It covers especially British english which is strong on grammar than American english.I'm going to buy other book for Basics soon  which I don't need but maybe for reference.I just love this book.A++++++.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>