<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Widsith</user>
	<review>One day the world will be full of science fiction authors whose prose styles are as good as their imaginations. Yeah, there are a few. But on the evidence of this book, Alastair Reynolds isn't one of them.What this novel does have going for it is a great theory of how the galaxy might look in 500 years' time. The picture painted here – of a lonely universe, full of space and mysteries and still limited by barriers like the speed of light – feels distinctly plausible and, presumably, owes a lot to Reynolds's day-job as a working astrophysicist.There are other good points. Thanks Christ, here is a sci-fi author who writes good, strong women characters who are not just there to have a variety of unlikely futuristic sexual encounters. (...Although actually, thinking about it, one or two of those might not have gone amiss.)The problem is that it's just not written all that well. The dialogue never strikes you as very realistic, and often consists of characters sitting around explaining chunks of the plot to each other. The narrative is pushed along in brief third-person sections, which stop and start apparently for no other reason than to engineer some dramatic tension, and which tend to finish on portentous one-line paragraphs like "But she was not quite fast enough."Some sentences barely hold together. We are told strange things, such as when "Volyova dredged a clucking laugh from somewhere deep inside herself". Try visualising that if you can. And when Reynolds reaches for a suitably scientific metaphor, he has a way of bludgeoning the life out of it, with unintentionally comic effect.Sylveste examined his own state of mind and found – it was the last thing he had expected – total calm. But it was like the calm that existed on the metallic hydrogen oceans of the gas giant planets further out from Pavonis – only maintained by crushing pressures from above and below.I think that might be the worst paragraph I've read all year. It should be entered into some kind of competition.Anyway, I don't want to put you off too much. It's fun, it's interesting, it's just not doing much to fight for sci-fi's place in literature. Revelation Space: it's funky, but it's clunky. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>s3ntient</user>
	<review>“Revelation Space”, first published in 2000 and shortlisted for the BSFA Award and the Arthur C. Clarke Award, is the first novel written by Alastair Reynolds. Set in the Revelation Space universe, it is the first book in a trilogy.It’s the 26th century and humanity has slowly expanded into space, colonizing worlds, exploring nearby star systems and inevitably splintering into different factions, some of which are at war. There are some strange and intriguing entities in “Revelation Space” such as the Pattern Jugglers and the Shrouders, but space is nonetheless a very lonely and empty place, too empty. Remnants of long extinct civilizations have been discovered, but there is no sign of living intelligent extraterrestrial life. A mystery that is at the core of the story.On Resurgam, a planet on the outskirts of human expansion, Dan Sylveste is leading a team of archaeologists excavating the remains of the Amarantin, an extinct 900,000 year old civilization that was wiped out by a cataclysmic event. Aboard the decaying Nostalgia for Infinity, a ship capable of interstellar travel at near light-speed, Ilia Volyova and her crew of ultra-humans are searching for Dan Sylveste, because they believe he will be able to help cure their captain of a deadly technological plague. In Chasm City on the planet Yellowstone, the contract assassin Ana Khouri is hired for a job she hopes will lead her to her long lost husband but she needs to find a way aboard the Nostalgia for Infinity.Alastair Reynolds weaves with skill the stories of these three groups of unpredictable characters, each having their own motivations and goals. Their interpersonal relations are filled with maneuvering, machinations, subterfuge and conflict, their backstories adding even more layers of complexity. Khouri and Volyova are two strong female characters whose backstories and viewpoints I thoroughly enjoyed. Dan Sylveste on the other hand left me ambivalent and felt like a weaker character until the middle of the book, I just wanted to get back to Khouri and Volyova. While the jumping around between characters and timelines in the beginning means the story starts out fairly slowly, it also means you have time to take in the vastness in scale and time of the universe Alastair Reynolds has created. The pace definitely picks up as the the story progresses and builds into a page-turner you can’t put down.The weakness for me lies in the way that Alastair Renolds sometimes handles the information he gives the reader. At times he makes the characters withhold information or revelations from the reader at the time of discovery to be able to reveal them when he wants. Other times scenes feel like they ended abruptly, just when the reader was about to learn some information vital to unraveling the mystery. There are also big infodumps that sometimes cut into the tension of the story towards the end and could have been handled better.This being hard science fiction, the laws of physics apply, which means there is no such thing as faster than light travel, something that writers often rely on as a crutch when writing space opera to make their stories work. Here however, Alastair Reynolds manages to use this and other limitations to his advantage. An astronomer working at the European Space Research and Technology Centre at the time of writing, his knowledge of physics and astronomy is infused in this book and lends it a real sense of believability, even plausability. The parts of the book where his passion for science blossoms into vast speculation or mind-bending constructs are very strong. His ability to weave real science into his story really captured my imagination.The general atmosphere of the book is definitely bleak and oppressive, especially aboard the Nostalgia for Infinity, it all feels very Lovecraftian. There is always a sense that something unknown and dangerous is lurking in the darkness, both on the ship and in space.I thoroughly enjoyed this book despite its weaker points, there are more than enough big ideas and vivid visuals here and some brilliant prose to make up for them. It’s definitely one of the best first novels I’ve ever read, truely epic. After finishing this book, I dove straight into its sequel, “Redemption Ark”.http://blog.chaostrophy.org/articles/... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>isabelx</user>
	<review>Volyova had now less than five hundred metres to go before she dragged the cache-weapon into the flames. It was putting up a fight, thrusters going haywire, but its overall thrust capacity was less than that of the spider-room. Understandable, Khouri thought. When its designers had conceived the ancillary systems which would be required to move and position the device, the idea that it would also have to fend for itself in a wrestling match had probably not been uppermost in their minds.Well I finally finished after a couple of weeks reading on the train during my commute.The story takes place in the mid-25th century, and starts with three separate strands which gradually come together: Dan Sylveste, is the arrogant and single-minded former ruler of the human colony on Resurgam, which began as a scientific expedition from Yellowstone. He has been in prison since a coup eight years ago, fuming about being prevented from continuing his studies of the Amarantin, the dead race who inhabited the plant 900,000 years ago. Khouri is an ex-soldier now working as an assassin on Yellowstone, where she is hired to hunt the bored and rich, whose lives are given spice by their (usually successful) attempts to survive until the end of the contract. After a successful but unusual assassination a mysterious woman blackmails her into taking on a contract off-world. And then there is Volyova, one of the triumvirate running an Ultra trading ship whose captain is dying of the melding plague. the ship is heading for Yellowstone searching for the one surgeon who helped the captain in the past and may now be able to cure him with the help of a retrovirus engineered by Volyova.Although I prefer shorter books than this and the story didn't really get going until the protagonists got together, the plot was anything but predictable, the gradually unfolding of the central mystery kept my interest, and what the characters discovered near the end of the book was truly fascinating. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sgsmitty</user>
	<review>Not bad as I remember, good enough to cause me to read the second.  It was rather large.  I listened to this as a audiobook. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dread_dragon</user>
	<review>Starts slowly and needs some time to get into, but then becomes quickly a very exciting book. Recommended. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dread_dragon</user>
	<review>Starts slowly and needs some time to get into, but then becomes quickly a very exciting book. Recommended. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bgsu_drew</user>
	<review>Revelation Space is a great book, with clever ideas about technology in the distant future, and many surprises... which I won't spoil.  You have the Pattern Jugglers, that can imprint another mind on top of your own just by swimming in the waters of their home world.  There's the Shrouders, who have secrets (weapons!?) kept in the equivalent of a lockbox-in-space.  And the Amarantin, who mysteriously vanished a million years ago.Spaceships have firepower capable of blowing up planets, and you can get nukes the size of a pin head.  People have implants, and the implants can get computer viruses.  Artificial Intelligence is a reality, allowing people to essentially become immortal by being copied into a computer.There were weaknesses to the book, including the length - starting at an archaeology dig was unnecessary, as was the descent into Cerberus.  And near the end it started to feel more like a horror novel with characters dying in gory ways.Overall this was a very entertaining scifi novel if you can hold on until the end. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>penwing</user>
	<review>I'm torn by this book. On the positive side, it's a good story and an interesting universe. On the negative side, he write as if I'm an idiot - telling us the same thing in three or four different ways in the same paragraph and seeming to expect each time to be a revelation. Hint, if you call something a "cache-weapon" I already know it's a weapon. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jamclash</user>
	<review>Although the science and sheer epic stage this book revolves around is very interesting and imaginative, the over-written dialogue and descriptions of technologies, bantering between characters, and drawn out plot made this book drag for me. Finally, about page 600 or so it begins to explain things. It does make you wonder though. Why aren't there more known civilizations out there? Revelation Space presents one idea. I'll probably read the other 3 in the series. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kukkurovaca</user>
	<review>Take Pohl's Gateway books. Replace the pioneer society there with a decadent one. Add a dose of epicness and substantial pacing problems (think tv miniseries). Add some persistently intriguing characters, and you have Revelation Space.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Explorations</user>
	<review>Although I found the storyline and technologies in this universe quite imaginative, at some point about a third into the novel, I couldn't help but feel that the haphazardly constructed dialogue and cookie-cutter tough guy/girl characters severely reduced the pleasure I had reading it.A few passages consisting of essentially objective descriptions of locations and creative technologies left me wanting more, but instead I ended up having to drag myself through the rather muddled and cliffhanger-ridden final two thirds. Some interesting thoughts about artificial intelligence, sadly few and far between. Still, I might end up reading some more novels by this guy. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>harroldsheep</user>
	<review>I needed a second reading to reaaly enjoy this book.  Well worth the effort! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cherylthing</user>
	<review>chain-smoking sociopathic female spaceship captains of ambiguous orientation, women that carry their heads around on their hips like a basketball, cybernetic control systems so elaborate, extensive, complex and near-biological that the software viruses that get into them evolve into symbionts, then parasitic pervasive creatures that may or may not have agency of their own, disturbing rifts in once-human societies undergoing divergent social (and physical) evolutionary paths, then coming into conflict with one another over the light years difference --  hey! What's not to like? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Hercules40</user>
	<review>Alastair Reynolds is a fantastic new voice in the world of speculative fiction. Although this book was first published in 2000, I did not read it until this year. And boy, was I missing a wonderful book.But first things first: A little bit about Alastair Reynolds, born in Wales, England. He has a Ph. D in Astronomy. For some reason, many scientists make good science fiction writers. I dunno why. Alastair has done a wonderful job here. This book tackles that eternal question people seem to ask in different ways: "Are we alone in the Universe?"Now, it is true that question has been asked before, by many Science Fiction authors in many different versions. I always enjoy reading these different "takes" (as they are called) on this theme. What's new, or refreshing in this story is neither the setting or the build-up behind it, but the originality of the characters.You know, a long time time ago, a science fiction editor by the name of John W. Campbell, decided that characters were just as important to a Scientific speculative fiction story as the underlying science, the story itself. Without characters indeed, there is no story. Alastair Reynolds achieves this in spades. It's the characters that draw you into the story. Oh, there is enough scientific exposition to make you believe that you are 500 years in the future. But Dan Sylveste and Ilia Volyova will make you believe that you are there.Dan Sylveste is investigating the "Amarantin puzzle", an extinct race, whose archaeological traces humanity has been investigating for years on different worlds. Yet, on this world that humans have colonized, the "Amarantin" seem to have accomplished something. They seem to have achieved a level of technological sophistication, maybe at the humanity's current level or even beyond, a completely unexpected development. WHY? All previously extinct races that humanity had come across had never reached this level, EXCEPT for humans themselves.There are of course the "Shrouders", an unknown conglomeration of Alien entities or Alien intelligences hiding behind a physical shroud in space which is impenetrable...and then there are the "Inhibitors". Who are the "Inhibitors"? And what do they want with humanity?I do not want to give more of the plot so as not to spoil it. Suffice it to say, that A.I.s are central to this book, as well as Light-Huggers (ships that accelerate UP TO the speed of light) -- no FTL crap in this book. Dan Sylveste's father was one of the first people capable of downloading his mind into a computer. He was also the first to make contact with the "Shrouders". Since that time, Dan Sylveste himself attempted contact with the "Shrouders". And with this set-up we're thrown into a whirlwind, action whodunit with lots of mystery. The crew of the light-hugger Nostalgia for Infinity is of course central to the plot, as well as events set in motion hundreds of years in the past.I highly recommend this book. Although, it will leave some questions unanswered, the book reaches a satisfying conclusion -- yet it leaves you hungering for more! Good thing then, that Alastair Reynolds has written 4 more books set in the same universe as "Revelation Space":   1. Chasm City (2001)   2. Redemption Ark (2002)   3. Absolution Gap (2003)   4. The Prefect (2007) </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fastia</user>
	<review>http://fantasycafe.blogspot.com/2008/... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ben_a</user>
	<review>Enjoyable space opera, and quite imaginative peri-singularity society. Overlong, but a page-turner. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gyokusai</user>
	<review>This review was also published, in a slightly enhanced  more comfortable format, at my blog between drafts.When I bought Revelation Space back in 2001, I read about a hundred pages and then simply had to stop and take a deep breath because of its sheer awesomeness: it was the most fascinating “new” sf novel I’d read in ages. It’s not for everyone, I can see that, but for me this mixture of baroque space opera, Alastair Reynolds’s scientific knowledge, and his dry and sarcastic dialogs just blew me away.For years, I didn’t pick it up again because my life and head were full of other stuff—starting a new business with friends or writing my doctoral thesis, for starters—and I simply didn’t want to spoil everything but savor the reading experience. Now, with all these businesses taken care of and my dissertation handed in, I picked Revelation Space up again and started reading it from page one. And yes, it was still awesome, and still too short for my appetite in spite of its 600 pages (or rather 700, taking the slightly wider Gollancz format into account), while the numerous strands of its grand story got tied up almost too neatly in the end.[Note: Spoilers below.]Many people, I understand, actually like the novel but have a problem with the characters. I’d say they’re pretty well developed, but this is—and has to be—sometimes less than evident. In the course of the story, practically every one of them becomes remote-controlled in one way or another, subtly or obviously, temporarily or all the time. Some have characteristics suppressed, some are nudged into single-minded endeavors. And most if not all of them are not very likable either. All of which conspires to forestall or at least postpone possible identification with one or more of the major characters, aggravated by the fact that one’s never really privy to what they’re up to. But so, neither are they. Moreover, people often point out that Sylveste and Pascale falling in love with each other were less than convincing. Well, it depends: they worked intimately together on Sylveste’s/Calvin’s biography throughout Sylveste’s confinement after the Resurgam revolution for, what was it, about twelve years—which should do the trick even if they don’t seem particularly emotionally compatible. Professionally, besides, they’re close to a perfect match.Thirdly and lastly, one reviewer complained about the “sardonic, over-written” dialog. That’s true, but I enjoyed this style immensely. Also, this kind of dialog does have a function. Most of the interactions occur between pairs or groups of people forced to work together either physically or, well, neurologically, who don’t like each other very much most of the time and/or have vastly different agendas. The dialog style, one should notice, fits these predicaments very well: Sylveste/Calvin, Sylveste/Girardieau, Khouri/Mademoiselle, Khouri/Volyova, Sajaki/Volyova, and so on. The sarcastic, bantering style employed throughout isn’t just related to Reynolds’s “English” English, but also to a certain dialog style from American film, particularly between the ’30s and ’50s, where it is employed in much the same way: Rick Blaine/Captain Renault in Casablanca would fit right in. Granted, this kind of dialog is far from being “realistic,” but what good would it do if all the dialogs in all the books we read would sound like Hemingway.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Valashain</user>
	<review>My Bookspotcentral review </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wildness</user>
	<review>The Galaxy is Full of EnigmasAs humans finally reach to the stars in the 23rd century, they find more puzzling enigmas than answers as to why they seem to be alone. At first there seems to be no sign of other intelligent life, but the ruins of technological civilizations on the brink of space flight are discovered and studied. As Dan Sylveste, an archaeologist, struggles against time on Resurgam - the planet of the Amarantin who were wiped out nearly one million years ago on the verge of their spacefaring age by an external force - to discover the origin of the planet's fate and what it means for the future of humankind, a lighthugger interstellar ship is on its way from the Yellowstone system to find Sylveste. Its crew of cyborg Ultras wants him as he may hold the key to curing their captain who has been infected by the Melding Plague - a plague that uses nanotechnology for its own grotesque artist purposes. Also onboard is Ana Khouri who the Ultras kidnapped to be the new gunner for a cache of mysterious, semi-sentient weapons of awesome power and an unknown origin; unbeknownst to the Ultra crew, Khouri is an assassin who maneuvered her way into this position as she has been assigned to kill Sylveste. Reynolds masterly assembles a cast of characters across interstellar space and the extended timeframes involved in travel between the stars and brings them together for the climax. Along the way we learn, we learn of the Pattern Jugglers, the Inhibitors, and Revelation Space. This is the first book in a trilogy (not counting the related novel Chasm City) that will ultimately decide the fate humankind and the Milky Way galaxy. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrtall</user>
	<review>This wide-ranging and imaginative space opera starts off with such promise, but it's far, far too long to sustain its initial interest. Revelation Space follows three characters: Dan Sylveste, a colonial genius who’s fascinated by a vanished alien culture; Ilia Volyova, an officer on a decaying starship; and Ana Khouri, a soldier who’s been kidnapped and coerced into acting as an assassin. These three storylines start out separated by time and distance, but converge quite neatly. Reynolds’s major theme is human contact with several very alien cultures; on these grounds, it's pretty good stuff. He’s highly speculative, in the best sense of the term.And he's not an entirely bad writer. His descriptive powers are considerable, and there are some genuinely inspiring passages here. But he writes some of the very worst dialogue I've ever read, in any sort of fiction. Every character -- human, alien, mechanical, whatever -- speaks in precisely the same prolix, sardonic, over-written voice. It's initially just a minor irritation, but by the end of the book I wished every single character would just shut up permanently, and Reynolds would revert to simple third-person description in order to finish off the story. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Dan Sylveste is an archaeologist of sources investigating why a particular race of aliens became instinct.  Sylveste is also the only man to encounter the strange region of space called the Shroud and survive.Because of this, a ship full of transhumans, named the Nostalgia For Infinity, want to talk to him.These people converge on the strange planet Yellowstone, and another character becomes involved, a martially skilled woman named Anna Khouri, who ends up being co-opted to join The Nostalgia For Infinity.The mystery of the Amarantin is at the heart of this, and is the actual Revelation we are waiting for.http://notfreesf.blogspot.com/2007/01... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>clong</user>
	<review>I thought the first two thirds of this books was superb, and the last third was rather disappointing. At one point in the story I was thinking this is the best space-opera-with-a-hard-science-veneer I have read since A Deepness in the Sky. But in the end Revelation Space is a much less satisfying read on several levels.  The novel follows three main characters who start on vastly different paths but inexorably are brought together as the story builds to its climax: Dan Sylveste, the son of an infamous genetics experimenter, who is driven to unearth the remains of an ancient civilization nobody else seems to care about; Ana Khouri, one time soldier and current assassin-for-hire who finds herself serving a mysterious new master; and Ilia Volyova, cyborg weapons master to a massive interstellar ship. These characters are initially interesting and enigmatic (as are many of the supporting cast around them), but I found them to be less and less sympathetic as the story progresses. And I found the doomed romance between Pascale and Sylveste to be utterly unconvincing.  The plotting is at times clever, and offers a few nice surprises, and more than its fair share of inventive and intriguing concepts. But, as mentioned above, I felt the ending failed to deliver on the early promise of the book (indeed the ending seemed to make much of the earlier plot largely irrelevant).  Despite my disappointment with some aspects of the book, there is no denying that this is pretty impressive for a first novel. I will definitely plan to read more by Reynolds. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Homechicken</user>
	<review>Wow, what an amazing first book is all I can say. I don't usually read "hard scifi", I prefer to stay on the lighter side with humorous scifi, or just plain fantasy novels. This book was, indeed, a revelation. Reynolds is an excellent writer, and extremely knowledgeable about what he writes. His excellent explanations never get too boring or in the way of the story, though. He writes of a splintered humanity in the distant future, and of its discovery of an ancient civilization and its abrupt end. Some try to understand it, others are afraid of what it might mean, and that the same thing that eradicated the Amarantin civilization will destroy humanity as well.I'm very excited to have the next several books in this series, and expect to be reading them very soon. And I highly recommend it to anyone that likes to read science fiction.Books in the Revelation Space series:Revelation SpaceChasm CityRedemption ArkDiamond Dogs, Turquoise DaysAbsolution GapGalactic NorthThe Prefect </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lorelorn_2007</user>
	<review>I admit it; I’m a late arrival at the Alastair Reynolds party. But when I saw Revelation Space reissued with a shiny silver cover, I had to buy. Not that I’m obsessed with form over function or anything.As I get older, I like my science fiction hard. Space opera, galactic fantasy, call it what you will, I’m really not interested. Base your science fiction on science, and give me characters to get interested in, and I’m happy...http://icantstopreading.blogspot.com/... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mferrante83</user>
	<review>When reading sci-fi I find I gravitate towards stories with that feature humans (or something resembling a human) explore/discover the remnants of a dead advanced civilization. The Martian elements of Richard Morgan’s Takeshi Kovacs novels are an excellent example (Broken Angels and Woken Furies in particular). This aspect of my reading habit is what initially drew me to Revelation Space and, while the discovery of ancient alien mysteries plays a part in the unfolding story, it is in the end eclipsed by the rather expansive nature of Reynold’s tale. The plot revolves around Dan Sylveste’s quest to discover the reason why an ancient alien species was wiped out completely, at the same time we get a starship’s quest to save it’s dying captain, an assassin lurking in the shadows, and potentially murderous synthetic lifeforms.The novel gets off to a rather slow start and I found my interest hindered by the constant shifts between Sylveste, Triumvir Volyova, and Ana Khouri. The initial introduction to each didn’t seem to linger long enough to generate any major interest; at least in terms of plot. All three characters are well drawn, given enough eccentricity to draw them away from genre cliche, and situated in three interesting and diverse worlds. And while each of the settings used for these characters are interesting their geographic isolation from one another really stalls the plot and, unfortunately, it isn’t until about halfway through the book that these three worlds converge and the action heats up.While I found the Revelation space enjoyable it was not by any means a page-turner and I felt the Reynold’s writing wasn’t quite up to generating the level of suspense necessary to keep readers coming back for more. At the same time I can’t really fault his writing and I found that I really did enjoy his work. There are elements of the story that set my imagination running in particular the massive ship Nostalgia for Infinity could probably be the subject of a whole book itself. Reynolds did an excellent job of conjuring the mystery and hidden history of the ship enough so that I wish it had played a more central role in the plot.Despite the novel’s shortcomings I think it was a worthy read, especially for someone relatively new to the science fiction genre (I’m a fantasy fan mostly) looking to explore the genre. It serves as an excellent contrast to the more adventure/action heavy science fiction of Bujold (Miles Vorkosgian) and Weber (Honor Harrington). Revelation Space touches on some interesting themes, most notably the cost of science. Some of the elements in the story touch on the divide between cyberpunk and postcyberpunk fiction in particular when discussing the nature of humanity. Overall a recommended read.Final Grade: B- </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tcgardner</user>
	<review>A far future space opera on relatively small scale.  The story takes place in a small corner of known human space, but the feel of the story is grand.This is a theme throughout the book.  Reynolds has a knack of making the small in reality seem large and grand. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>planetrobbie</user>
	<review>http://yet.org/2007/03/lespace_de_la_... </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>domesticat</user>
	<review>My first experience with Reynolds. First hundred pages were a tough go; I had trouble keeping characters and dates straight at times. I decided to trust that he had a plan, and that the narrative threads would come together. They did. The first third of the book felt like an academic exercise, the second was intriguing, and the final third was compelling. I'll move on to Chasm City next. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>philosojerk</user>
	<review>this series, and specifically this book, is one of the most imaginative things i've ever read.  i'm not hugely familiar with the "hard science fiction" genre, but these books definitely left me wanting to find more of it.  not only is the futuristic science fascinating, but reynolds also does weave quite a story here, spanning centuries and interwoven masterfully.  highly recommended. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wfzimmerman</user>
	<review>Gosh, I hate the ultrawide Gollancz paperback format -- 80+ characters per line.  It is very hard to read!This is a great science fiction novel.  I just reread it for the first time in years, and I was impressed by the idea and action density. Every few pages, something important or interesting happens. Reynolds's characters are still hard to like, but the rest of it makes up for it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sulkyblue</user>
	<review>I spent most of the book not entirely sure of what was going on, once I accepted this I really enjoyed the first 400 pages or so as Reynolds carefully built up the layers of mystery and intertwining. However the last 150 pages or so when he tried to explain things and bring it all together I found pretty clunky and confusing. There was quite a large shift in scale from focusing on individuals and their plots to relatively suddenly dealing with millenia old alien races and their schemes for the future of the galaxy. I just found the ending all a bit overwhelming after the slow, careful and interesting build up. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jcopenha</user>
	<review>An impressive work, but at the same time hard to get through.  The first 150 pages were very confusing and I struggled to make it half way into the book.  AT times I felt like I was reading a rough draft of a story that should have been broken into 3 books.  It was a very creative and in the end captivating novel though. I have the second one in this series but I think I'll wait a bit before starting it.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Shrike58</user>
	<review>This book has something to annoy everyone.  It could be the lead character and supreme egotist Dan Sylvestre, whose nickname could be "Sushi" considering what a cold fish he is.  It could be the intricate intertwining story arcs between that of Sylvestre, that of Khouri, the assassin blackmailed into killing him, or that of Volyova, the starship officer who acts as the plot intermediary between the two, and this complexity will eventually make your head hurt.  This is as at fifty-page intervals Reynolds will let drop some bomb that will change your understanding of all that has gone before, though it at least keeps you guessing.  Particuarly when you start to suspect that the plot really isn't as complicated as you have been led to believe.  But mostly it's Sylvestre, who spends much of the book being a "McGuffin," even if he does wind up detonating the climax in the end.  This is a state of affairs that turns out to be damn frustrating.Still, this novel does have many virtues.  For one, Reynolds is (was?) a working astronomer, and this is the hardest real-science space opera I've ever read in terms of living without some of the "magic" that makes most space opera workable.  Two, Reynolds has incorporated a dizzying array of concepts in this book, and it does play quite well for the most part; even if you're sometimes playing the game "spot that influence" a little too much.  Three, even if his main character annoys the hell out of me, Reynolds does invoke a real sense of sympathy for his secondary characters Khouri and Volyova.  Finally, Reynolds also displays a fairly sly sense of humor in what is a wildly ambitious first novel. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>towo</user>
	<review>Reynold's first novel opens to an exciting world set a couple of centuries in the future.  Humanity started colonizing space, yet without the advantage of faster than light travel.  Only after the Conjoiners, humans which embraced cybernetic enhancements, experienced an event of technological singularity called the Transenlightenment, was mankind able to travel with speeds close to the speed of light. This lead to the rise of the "ultranauts", which established themselves as the spacefaring subculture of humanity, which lived perceived aeons due to time dilation.This is the setting of the story; three different character arcs in different times, converging into a seemingly random yet connected shared arc. Reynoldsshows much forethought in his writing, resulting in a story which just plain fits and allows for a lot of retroactive insight. In some places it's a bit predictable, but I'm not sure whether that stemmed from me already having read "Absolution Gap".Which also leaves me to conclude that there's nothing really special about the book. It's a good, solid read, rather exciting and interesting, but nothing special. In contrast to his later book, there's nothing that's spectularly "different" about it. Regrettable, but to be expected. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sfreader.com</user>
	<review>http://www.sfreader.com/read_review.a... </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fascination</user>
	<review>http://www.leftfield.org/~rawdon/book... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nasherr</user>
	<review>Reynolds' first book is exceptional. It comes up with many original ideas and often invoves more in depth, complex science than the average space opera. This fact lends validity to the whole series, making you feel that all the ideas are entirely plausible. It also contains some brutal aspects which gives it a real edge. The story is often quite dark. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>name99</user>
	<review>I can see why this author is popular. He does know how to spin a good story and keep you reading. But his one trick, cutting to a new scene just as something important is about to be revealed, is used far to excess. This is fun light reading but at the end of the day I found it frustrating.In particular I felt that it paid entirely too little attention to the most interesting issue, IMHO, namely how a future, much more wealthy, much more powerful society is structured. As such, while easier to read than say Iain M Banks, or Kim Stanley Robinson, I don't find it as interesting. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shieldsk1</user>
	<review>Difficult read </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>petwoe</user>
	<review>Not quite what I expected. Though the ideas are big and novell ones, the storytelling especially at the begin is tedious. Especially unnerving is Reynolds technique of producing cliffhangers between parts of his story-arch. There are some things that never get explained, like how the crew and the arboretra manage in deceleration phases (everything should turn upside down), how the janitorrats survive high g-loads, how the thrust of one g is mantained when nearing lightspeed (the mass of the ship should grow extremely according to relativistic principles), what happend to Calvin and Sun Stealer once Dan was absorbed, and a lot more of these little but nagging things.Nonetheless an interesting read, if you can ignore those quirks, and enjoy the ideas behind the book. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Black_samvara</user>
	<review>Not quite as good as Century Rain, quite slow moving. I liked the rich astronomical descriptions and so on but it reminds me of early science fiction writers who put more into the science than the story. It still had many interesting threads slowly converging and a steady build of ideas right to the end, characters were pretty unlikable. Am going to cheerfully hunt down his other books and read 'em.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mockers</user>
	<review>Who or what is the Captain? More geeky hard sci fi from Reynolds. Well written, good stuff, just what you'd expect from him really. And I've heard he's a nice chap too.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Skywolf</user>
	<review>Wow. Sci-fi novels aren't usually my favourite genre, and the last couple I've read have been slow and more than a little tedious. But this book has reinstalled my faith in science fiction literature. Packed with amazing, often mind-boggling concepts, this is a book that is not only highly entertaining and full of page-turning, edge-of-the-seat action, it is also a novel that makes the reader just stop and think. I don't think I'll ever look at the universe in quite the same way after this one. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>popomo</user>
	<review>http://sfsite.com/05a/rs80.htm</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>oakesspalding</user>
	<review>Great beginning.  Dumb ending.  ** </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0575068752</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>topps</user>
	<review>Alastair Reynolds's first novel is "hard" SF on an epic scale, crammed with technological marvels and immensities. Its events take place over a relatively short period, but have roots a billion years old--when the Dawn War ravaged our galaxy.Sylveste is the only man ever to return alive and sane from a Shroud, an enclave in space protected by awesome gravity-warping defenses: "a folding a billion times less severe should have required more energy than was stored in the entire rest-mass of the galaxy." Now an intuition he doesn't understand makes him explore the dead world Resurgam, whose birdlike natives long ago tripped some booby trap that made their own sun erupt in a deadly flare.Meanwhile, the vast, decaying lightship Nostalgia for Infinity is coming for Sylveste, whose dead father (in AI simulation) could perhaps help the Captain, frozen near absolute zero yet still suffering monstrous transformation by nanotech plague. Most of Infinity's tiny crew have hidden agendas--Khouri the reluctant contract assassin believes she must kill Sylveste to save humanity--and there are two bodiless stowaways, one no longer human and one never human. Shocking truths emerge from bluff, betrayal, and ingenious lies.The trail leads to a neutron star where an orbiting alien construct has defenses to challenge the Infinity's planet-wrecking superweapons.At the heart of this artifact, the final revelations detonate--most satisfyingly. Dense with information and incident, this longish novel has no surplus fat and seems almost too short. A sparkling SF debut. --David Langford, Amazon.co.uk --This text refers to the Hardcover edition.From Publishers WeeklyThis distant-past/far-future, hard sci-fi tour de force probes a galaxy-wide enigma: why does spacefaring humanity encounter so few remnants of intelligent life? Excavating the 900,000-year-old Amarantin civilization on its home world, Resurgam, archaeologist Dan Sylveste discovers evidence of a splinter cult that abandoned Resurgam for the stars but returned, only to be swallowed up by a mysterious cataclysm that destroyed all the Amarantins. Aboard the Nostalgia for Infinity, a vast light-hugger ship in interstellar space, the ominous Triumvirate of cyborg starfarers seeks Sylveste to heal its captain, afflicted by the deadly Melding Plague, which turns once-humans into their own semisentient spaceships. In Chasm City on the slum-ridden world of Yellowstone, assassin Ana Khouri joins the Nostalgia's crew intent on killing Sylveste. Clearly intoxicated by cutting-edge scientific research in bioengineering, space physics, cybernetics Reynolds spins a ravishingly inventive tale of intrigue. Hard SF addicts will applaud the author's talent for creating convincing alien beings and the often uneasy merging of human and machine intelligence, depicted here as nearly too frighteningly real for comfort. Others, however, may find these human-cybernetic hybrid characters chilling, dispassionate (except for their built-in drives toward revenge and murder) and foreboding. Reynolds's vision of a future dominated by artificial intelligence trembles with the ultimate cold of the dark between the stars. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>