<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Dissidence</user>
	<review>Not sure if I'll ever make it to the end, but we'll see.Update: I have to give this book four stars for the sheer ingenuity in the writing of it. This book is about the insanity of war, and the insanity of people at war - everyone's crazy in this book. The Generals are crazy, the main character Yossarian is crazy and after reading this book I'm crazy too!The book jumps between different times in different chapters, it refers to events that haven't been explained and then goes back later in the book to describe them. Each chapter is titled after a new character or event and we hear into the minds of different characters, but the book is mainly from the viewpoint of main character Yossarian - always going back to tell his story. Because of the jumps in time and references to the future and past, it's hard to give a plot summary and that's probably why I was never able to find one before I began reading this.The chapters are seamlessly sown together and the sheer brilliance of the contradictions in description and dialogue do emphasise the point. Joseph Heller manages to create a main chracter I both disliked yet wanted to prevail - he even got me contradicting myself!An example of the circular conversations in Catch-22 is when Yossarian is asking Doc Daneeka whether he can ground people on account of being crazy:"Is Orr crazy?""He sure is," Doc Daneeka said."Can you ground him?""I sure can. But first he has to ask me to. That's part of the rule.""Then why doesn't he ask you to?""Because he's crazy," Doc Daneeka said. "He has to be crazy to keep flying combat missions after all those close calls he's had. Sure, I can ground Orr. But first he has to ask me to.""That's all he has to do to be grounded?""That's all. Let him ask me.""And then you can ground him?" Yossarian asked."No. Then I can't ground him.""You mean there's a catch?""Sure there's a catch," Doc Daneeka replied. "Catch-22. Anyone who wants to get out of combat duty isn't really crazy."One thing I didn't like in this book, besides it being hard to get into and demanding a very laid-back manner regarding events, was the portrayal of women. Any woman mentioned only served as a vehicle for the men's sexual gratification, a role which the women in the book seemed only too happy to play. Yossarian's treatment of women, all under the guise that he's in love with all of them, is enough to turn you into a feminist - but I suppose that isn't central to the book's concept so it can be overlooked, but grudgingly. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ctorstens</user>
	<review>I've tried to read this 3 times now, but can't get more than 50 pages in. It reads like a collection of articles or short stories, which makes it difficult to get attached to. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tddlz</user>
	<review>I should have read this book 20 years ago... not because I have missed a gem but because I might have found it more interesting and less verbose.  At points I wanted the Author to 'just shut up!'  Favourite character was Major Major.  Least favourite part was the pointless intro into a non existent relationship  where, in the first chapters, Yossarian meets the Chaplain and Heller lead me to believe he would be pivotal in Yossarian's story.   I think the Author occasionally got lost in his own text. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ilprinze</user>
	<review>"Well, do you know what you are? You're a frustrated, unhappy, disillusioned, undisciplined, maladjusted young man!"I just finished reading Catch-22 by Joseph Heller, and before I start reading The Master and Margarita, I want to write a brief piece about what I think of Catch-22, a book often described as a 'cult classic' by critics.At the beginning, the book didn't click with me. First, it's a war book, and I'm not a big fan (of wars, or wartime books). Second, too many characters were thrown at me and I found that connecting to them was difficult. Third, I felt it was 'too American', which I later came to appreciate as the book was released post World War 2 predominately to an American audience, and served as a response to wartime books that glorified war as a noble concept.So why was I determined to finish it? Yossarian, of course. The protagonist of Catch-22 is a young man by the strange name of Yossarian who is constantly attempting to escape the increasing number of flying missions by diving in and out of insanity. What is so appealing about Yossarian, is that he is constantly referred to as deranged, crazy, and disillusioned. Yet, as a reader (and a disillusioned person, perhaps), found that the simple excuses he gave to escape war were quite valid. For example, when asked why he doesn't want to fly any more missions, Yossarian replies, 'because they want to kill me!'. Isn't that a valid reason to not go to war? I thought it was.Being someone who works in a sector that is completely immersed in bureaucracy, where what matters most is ego and reputation, I found the bitter themes of the book frustrating. Yossarian's commanders demand from his group to maintain a 'tight bombing pattern' only because a picture of the bombing would look good in the papers (as opposed to destroy a target effectively). Also throughout the book, Yossarian's Colonel keeps raising the number of flying missions of his group, putting their lives on the line, only to please his superiors.To appreciate the themes of the book (and despise them), I had to draw a link to my experiences (a weak link in this case, but relevant nontheless). Just think about the number of times you had to deliver a project bigger (not necessarily better) than the previous one, only because the previous project was run by someone that your boss was competing with? How many times were you told to omit data from a report only because it 'looked better' on one page and not two. Ah! The frustration!At the end of the day, most of us read books to escape our mundane reality, not to affirm it. I enjoy reading books that oppose and challenge my views and offer me an opportunity to change my ideas. With Catch-22, I found myself sighing in anger and frustration at the bitterly comical reality that it presented, and wished that I had opted for another classic that didn't raise my blood pressure with every page.Overall, does it deserve the 'classic' status it has? I think so, mainly because it was the first of its kind at the time, and challenged views that glorified war. Also, Yossarian is a timeless character that most of us would relate to in any situation when we've just had enough.The question that it sitting at the back of my head at the moment is, would this book be so great if it were released today? </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ccavaleri</user>
	<review>I especially love Major Major Major and the egg sales. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>markarayner</user>
	<review>This is one of those books that I keep coming back to, and I love this Folio Society edition.  (I still giggle every time I think of the scenes with Major Major.) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mrsdwilliams</user>
	<review>Joseph Heller was an American bombardier in WWII and the novel's main character, John Yossarian, finds himself in the same situation.  Catch-22 is masterful satire.  Yossarian wants to stop flying missions, but the fact that he questions the wisdom of flying more missions assures his commanders that he is sane enough to continue flying.The author's style can make the story hard to follow--the different points of view and events described out of sequence can be confusing.  Hang in there--you'll be glad you did. Catch-22 is a hilarious, tragic, and insightful anti-war novel. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>colagold</user>
	<review>Es la segunda vez que intento leerlo y no paso del 5º capítulo. Soporífero. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rlbenavides</user>
	<review>It is difficult, sometimes, to see such a large exaggeration as a squadron of World War II soldiers who no longer have any idea what they are fighting for as a reflection of the psychological effects such hostilities. Certainly, we think, this cannot have any correlation to real-life combat. And yet, when looked at from a different perspective, Joseph Heller’s Catch 22 is just that—by showing a mindset that is that over- the-top, the reader quickly discovers Heller’s intent in writing this novel, and throughout the rest of the book develops that idea even more. Catch 22 is about such a squadron, who have become so apathetic to the fighting that they no longer understand what their goal is, and whose leaders have ceased the information they divulge to their men. Furthermore, there is no way out for these soldiers—they are trapped by an illogical complicated concept called a “Catch 22” which has become absolute law because the men do not question it.And therein lies the problem. This book illustrates the worst kind of dystopia—the only source of utopia is complete ignorance, both from what is happening on the surface and what is happening behind the scenes. To be happy in the world of Catch 22, the soldiers must not only refuse to face the war that they are involved in, but the unwillingness of their superiors to show them the reason behind it, and the lack of answers they receive for the questions they do have. Eventually, the men stop questioning altogether because they know it is futile, and they simply serve without seeing the purpose. The only way to achieve perfection in a war is if you ignore it altogether.This is a crazy book to read at times. It is not in chronological order and the only way to tell one time from another is by events, especially the rapid increase of the number of required missions each man in the squadron must fly in order to be discharged. The writing is blunt and often absurd. But it is hilarious and traumatic all at the same time, and although it is not hard to recognize the satire, it only makes the book that much better because one can pick out the ideas Heller wishes to convey from early in the plot. I would definitely recommend this novel to anyone who wishes for a good laugh and a good lesson. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ieric</user>
	<review>The attempt at humor in Catch-22 was a rather poor attempt. The dialog was always a playful back-and-forth banter which at first was uninteresting, then grew tiresome, then I grew to downright dislike it.I admit that this is one book I could not bring myself to finish. Not worth my time. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sturlington</user>
	<review>One of my favorite books of all time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Porua</user>
	<review>Catch-22 is a satirical novel on WWII by Joseph Heller that was published in 1961. Even though I’ve always been interested in reading the novel, as it is often considered to be one of the greatest novels of the 20th century and I am fond of reading satires, I’ve also been intimidated by it’s complexity. It is complex in a sense that the story is told in a nonlinear style and contains multiple points of view. The events of the story unfold in a sort of unusual out of sequence way.Then a few months ago I became really sick. I had a high fever. I felt exhausted and my mouth felt like sand paper. That is when I started to read Catch-22. For some reason being sick made me appreciate the story. The lack of physical wellbeing (not being able to get up, not being able to eat) left me with a sort of an understanding of Yossarian's world. Watching helplessly and going slowly insane (or becoming more and more sane) as Colonel Cathcart keeps raising the number of missions while his friends die one after another, Yossarian's world falls apart all around him. The hopelessness of the rule of catch-22, the self -contradictory logic that keeps going round and round, a rule that no one can break and the impossibility of ever escaping it, made my mind boggle. The humour in it is so dark that after a while I forgot to laugh anymore. Joseph Heller creates a world that is stark and real and at the same time incredible and unreal. It's a paradoxical world. Reading it was an unsettling experience and I don't know if I'll ever read it again but Catch-22 definitely left a distinct impression on my mind.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bfarmer8</user>
	<review>Very witty and interesting anti-war novel. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brassmonkey</user>
	<review>A book as monumental as the task of reading it was. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AngieN</user>
	<review>This is neck-and-neck with Pride and Prejudice as #1--first read it in high school, and time stood still--contains my favorite book line ever (Chief White Halfoat): "Racial prejudice is a terrible thing, Yossarian.  It really is.  It's a terrible thing to treat a decent, loyal Indian like a n, kike, wop or spic."  I still remember sitting there in my drill team uniform, howling with laughter... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>horuskol</user>
	<review>"If you want to fly in this war, you must be crazy. If you're crazy, then we won't let you fly - but if you don't want to fly, then that is rational fear of death, so you can't be crazy which means you have to fly."Catch-22 follows a group of young men conscripted into service and flying bombing missions in Italy as part of a fictional squadron in the United States Army Air Force. It centres around Yossarian, a bombardier (bomb-aimer) who is reluctant to continue flying as friends and other squadron members are swatted down by anti-aircraft fire, or other mishaps, but has to keep flying as long he is demonstrating this reluctance (since this is a sane reaction to the evident danger of flying missions).The book seems to draw on real tales and experiences from the war - although they are obviously fictionalised and further enhanced by Heller's satire.There are some incredible sequences in the book - including Milo Minderbender's amazing ability to get eggs in Malta at 7 cents a piece, and then sell them on for a profit at 5 cents a piece. And then there is the hunt for Washington Irving, a false identity used by a number of officers in the squadron, much to the vexation of military intelligence, and Major Major's biography and rise to squadron commander, and more and more.The storyline is a little scattergun in places - talking about events and jumping about the timeline in order to provide more details a little later on in the book, but it is extremely easygoing to read, and even the crazy skews of logic that some of the characters take are fun to follow and reach the conclusion.One thing I find remarkable is that the book was written before the Vietnam War had even started, and even more years before the mass disaffection with conscription that started the protests and demonstrations of the late 60s and early 70s (although the film adaptation did hit the screens in 1970 alongside M*A*S*H). But, then, the book isn't really anti-war as much as it is a commentary on exactly how crazy can be. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>merciwillows</user>
	<review>I never wanted anything to do with this book when it was required reading back in school, but once I picked it up long after, could not put it down. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>truncoxx</user>
	<review>The beginning and ending of this book were amazing and wonderful to read. However, the middle of the book is a little dry and can become quite difficult to read through. It is funny, ironic, illogical and crazy which makes it a good book to read if you are silly or too serious for your own good. Don't get all caught up on the weird and funny, it does have a very serious message behind it and gets more serious as the book develops. I loved the symbolism and literary style of the author. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>southerncross116</user>
	<review>While I read this book a long time ago; this book is classic and biting satire at its best; and is much more about madness, than it would be specifically about the 'madness of war'. For that you need to dig out a copy of All Quiet on the Western Front.  It is clear that a lot of things motivated Heller in writing this book, but it most definitely was not a war book written for yucks, the points (to me) are subtle and biting. I love the part where the Germans contracted with the Army Air Corps to bomb their own bases, as it was all in the interest of business.... but what is really classic (and mind you, you may need some time in a bureaucratic setting to appreciate it ... is the going on and on about attention to bomb patterns ( who cares if you actually hit it ...) -all about arbitrary statistics and stuff like that.You know the ironic part is that -nothing has really changed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SFM13</user>
	<review>Yossarian was in a dilemma …how to live without betraying his friends. He certainly flew his share of missions, but quitting meant a court marshal. And then there were his “pals.” If he made a deal with Col. Cathcart, it would be sort of like ‘shaking hands with the devil.’ Unless he was crazy he was obligated to fly, but he’d have to be crazy if he flew again. Catch 22, no way out, “up a creek without a paddle …” Throughout the novel Yossarian saw death take his comrades with the cruelty and madness of war. When he learns about Orr’s escape, he jumps at a chance to run himself. As the final scene comes to a surprise ending, I’d like to think he made it safely. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lizzyjane</user>
	<review>A crazy, wonderful yet cruelly sane story, also hilariously funny. a disturbing insight into the larger struggle of today: the survival of mankind. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Alera</user>
	<review>This is a hard book for me to review, if only because it leaves me with a lot of mixed feelings. The anti-war themed satire is still incredibly relevant. There are many things that made me laugh, Milo's entire enterprise for instance. And I also felt and cared deeply for Yossarian. The jumbled, overly large cast somehow managed to feel far more close-knit and its an impressive display of writing. And it pulls no punches when it comes to making 'offensive' comments. All are things I find myself deeply appreciative of this novel for. At the same time, the narrative's tendency to just move from one scene and subject to the next without any notice can be quite jarring and make the read itself difficult and in some ways alien. Overall, I'm glad to have read it. I'd recommend it to others who have an appreciation for other books in the genre, but I don't know if it's a novel I'll ever reread. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heidijane</user>
	<review>This is a satirical anti-war novel centring on the experiences of the bombardier Yossarian and the many weird characters that surround him.This is a ludicrous, somtimes funny and sometimes tragic book, and depicts many bizzare situations from various viewpoints. For example, there is a period of time when everyone is asked to sign loyalty oaths in triplicate, but the person whose loyalty is apparently suspect is not allowed to sign the oaths.Although this is a war novel, even death isn't sacred. For example, the pilot Mudd ("his name is Mudd") died on his first mission and hadn't even had the chance to be properly registered so becomes a bureaucratic nightmare as he never officially arrived (apart from his physical possessions still sitting in Yossarian's tent). Every time Yossarian is approaching the maximum number of missions, the number is increased.This is therefore quite a unique book, and is one of those books that you don't forget in a hurry. It was, however, very difficult to get into, due to the many various characters being introduced and the confusing sequence of time periods in the early stages of the novel. Partly because it is a war novel, the book is very masculine in the early chapters, and female characters don't appear until much later, so again this made it more difficult for me to relate to the story. But, as I was reading it for two challenges, and the book had a continuing ironic and wry sense of humour managed (just) to carry it through for me. The book also had a whole series of funny, if slightly pathetic, characters which carried the story.As a whole, there were some really laugh-out-loud bits, but there were also some more difficult bits, which is why I would give this book a fairly average three out of five. When it was good, it was very good, but it was not consistently very good. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sjstuckey</user>
	<review>My favorite book of all time.  For anyone that has missed this classic, run, don't walk, to the nearest bookstore and pick it up.  This Heller classic portrays the horror and absurdity of war, politics and love. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aethercowboy</user>
	<review>What's the catch? Catch-22.If you've ever heard something described as being a "catch-22," congratulations, you've been alive some time between now and 1961!For those of you reading this in the future, however (hi future!), after the overlords make dictionaries illegal, a "catch-22" is essentially a no-win situation. In your future life, you might refer to this as "every day."Captain John Yossarian, a bombadier stationed in Italy during World War II, has desires that most of us have, such as not wanting to die. His desire to not want to die drives him to get sent home. He tries to fly as many missions as are required by him, but the powers that be continue to increase this number, seemingly in analog to his almost attaining enough missions to get sent home. So, he tries another tactic: he tries to get sent home because he's crazy.You're crazy if you want to fly more missions, and if you're crazy, you should be grounded, and quite possibly sent home, but if you ask to be grounded, because you're crazy, well, then, you're trying to save your life, and quite possibly the lives of others, because, let's be honest, who wants to fly in a plane with a crazy guy, especially while dropping bombs all over the Italian front? The problem with that, is since you're doing something rational by asking to be grounded, well, then you're sane. And that circular logic is, effectively, Catch-22.The book itself is an amazing work of fiction that is otherwise spoiled by vivisectionist English teachers everywhere. But if you read this, provided you get to that last page, you'll have a better appreciation for how the government really runs things (I believe that this book, or maybe a technical rewriting of it is the core rulebook for all government agencies).It's particularly more enjoyable if you do in fact work for the government. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cowpeace</user>
	<review>Blurp: De oorlog en alles wat erover wordt geschreven, oefent op veel mensen een grote aantrekkingskracht uit. Maar slechts enkelen weten de waanzin van de oorlog zó in de kern te treffen als meesterverteller Joseph Heller. Catch-22 is de grootste geschiedenis van een handvol van de meest roekeloze en moedige piloten uit de Tweede Wereldoorlog: het verhaal van hun kleine eilandje in de Middellandse Zee, en hun omstuimige Italiaanse vrouwen. Het is een roman over de oorlog en vrede, over liefde en lust, over het menselijke en het dierlijke in de mens. Realistisch in de gedetailleerde verslagen van bombardementen, hard, bitter en barbaars in de beschrijvingen van stervende mannen in exploderende vliegtuigen. Het is een boek over helden, roekelozen en fanaten. Over de vrouwen, de hoertjes en geliefden. Catch-22, een meedogenloos boek. Niet voor niets zijn er van Catch-22 al ruim 8 miljoen exemplaren verkocht! Van dezelfde auteur verscheen: Een incident (Something Happened).Samenv.: Op een Amerikaanse luchtmachtbasis op een Italiaans eiland tijdens de Tweede Wereldoorlog komt de absurditeit van de oorlog en het militarisme wel erg duidelijk naar voren.Samenv.: Tegen de achtergrond van de toenemende Amerikaanse Vietnam-betrokkenheid geschreven absurde roman over de anti-held Yossarian. Deze is gestationeerd op een Italiaans eiland en - net als de auteur - bommenrichter bij de luchtmacht in de laatste jaren van de Tweede Wereldoorlog. Hij is omgeven door volkomen verknipte figuren, stereotypen van de in ieder leger voorkomende baantjesjagers, idealisten, hardliners, angsthazen e.d. Zwarte humor en kolder, komische satire, realisme en onthullende, tegendraadse karaktertekening zijn de hoofdingrediënten van deze lijvige roman die de lezer steeds weer op het verkeerde been zet. Elke logica ontbreekt; alles wordt onderuit gehaald in deze tekening van de waanzin van de oorlog. Daardoor leest het verhaal niet eenvoudig en vergt het enige inspanning; de overdaad aan absurdheid - ook in het taalgebruik - vermoeit op den duur. Het boek was het debuut en het grootste succes van de Amerikaanse auteur (1923-1999); het is een klassieke maatschappij-kritische (oorlogs)roman, succesvol verfilmd. In 1994 verscheen een vervolg, 'Sluitingstijd'.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>krisiti</user>
	<review>Catch 22 by Joseph Heller (1996) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BookMarkMe</user>
	<review>I've mixed thoughts about Catch - 22. I appreciated the intelligent way it was written to convey the madness of war. I smiled at the dark humour and thought deeply about what it said but on occasions I found myself wishing for the end of the book to speed towards me, the frenetic nature of it just wore me out. I finished, but felt as if I'd been in a fight. Then again perhaps that was intended. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>artelsj</user>
	<review>"It must be nice to be in Sweden now, the girls are so sweet. And the people are so advanced." </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Paal</user>
	<review>Aldri hørt om krigsprofittører? Dette er en bok som ble igjen ganske aktuelt, når for få år siden man hørte om Halliburton og lignende som tjente virkelig mye penger fra krig.Joseph Heller hadde sin egen erfaring fra Annen verdenskrig og bruker ironi som våpen.Hvor mange fremdeles ligner på oberst Cathcart? En sjef som utnytter og tvinger andre som kaptein Yossarian til å gjøre mer og mer, selv om alt er absurd og kynisk.Tittelen beskriver dilemmaer mange soldater står overfor.Krig er organisert drap. Derfor er det normalt at man ønsker å holde unna slikt. Det betyr også at vanlige mennesker ikke er syke i hodet. Derimot en som elsker krig må bli sykmeldt.Det er virkelig en bok som gjør man skeptisk til krig og kynismen i samfunnet. Alle voksne bør lese den for å bli bedre borgere.Når man er ferdig med boken, anbefales også filmen. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Smiler69</user>
	<review>All I knew about this novel going into it was that it popularized the term “Catch-22” and that it was a satire set during WWII. Since I’m not very fond of books about army life and wars, I went into this one with the expectation that I would probably dislike it, only to find that it was much more entertaining than I could have imagined. At the center we have the bombardier John Yossarian, who desperately wants to stay alive and is trying by all means available to him to avoid flying more dangerous missions, though he is forever thwarted by Colonel Cathcart who increases the number of missions required of the men every time they reach his ever-increasing targets to ensure none of them can return home in hopes to earn greater esteem from his superiors. Heller’s wry humour and hilarious observations about human behaviour turns even some of the most violent and harrowing situations into opportunities for a laugh, although for some, altogether different responses—anger, sadness, frustration—might be considered more appropriate. The crudeness and zaniness of the characters and situations, the unflinching descriptions of injuries, death and aggression are sometimes difficult to read through, but they also contribute a feeling of immediacy which make this novel still relevant today, almost 50 years after the original publication. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kellyhatter</user>
	<review>Maybe I need to read this again but between reading it and attempting to watch the movie I understood nothing.  Maybe because I was still in high school. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brianclegg</user>
	<review>The worst book I've ever attempted to read. Crass. Hated it. Couldn't finish it. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LadyHazy</user>
	<review>I struggled through to the end hoping that this book would get better, but it did NOT. The story and characters are all over the place and as such it seems to demand a second read to fully comprehend; unfortunately I would not spend another minute on this book as I feel the time I spent reading it has already been wasted.The attempts at humour throughout the book are groan-worthy, and seem incredibly juvenile and unfunny when compared to the likes of Terry Pratchett.INCREDIBLY OVER-RATED!! </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>nwhyte</user>
	<review>http://nwhyte.livejournal.com/1210889...I loved this book when I first read it twenty years ago and I enjoyed the return journey now. The fractured narrative of Yossarian's response to the dehumanising horror of war is also very funny in places (my favourite scene is the mass outbreak of moaning at the Avignon briefing). Awful and yet hilarious. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AtaraxiaM</user>
	<review>The comedy and sheer randomness sprinkled throughout the book underscore the whole comedy of the novel's central focus, which shouldn't be comic at all. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>goddessladyj</user>
	<review>I'm sorry, I know this is considered a great classic.  But I had to struggle to make myself finish it.  Not at all my cup of tea.  Boring, somewhat disturbing (violent), not particularly funny (to me), and no characters to whom I could relate.  And maybe that's the point.  But I won't be reading this again. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>basvat</user>
	<review>Each day I come across Catch-22 situation, thamks to this book I can give them a proper name </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ecumenicalcouncil</user>
	<review>No other book has ever truely captured the insanity of war the was Catch-22 does. Heller draws you in. He manages to make you laugh, confuss you, and deeply disturb you all at the same time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fellowette</user>
	<review>http://unpretentiouslitcrit.blogspot.... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>FMRox</user>
	<review>Satire on WWII.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>miriamparker</user>
	<review>Major Major Major Major. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kblaas</user>
	<review>Call me a philistine, but I would recommend reading exactly 1/3 of this novel, and then walking away. The first few chapters are completely hilarious. Then, thinks slowly begin plodding to an absolute standstill. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mwphillips75</user>
	<review>Liked it a lot.  It was funny and depressing. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>chhebert</user>
	<review>Hilarious, tragic, dark, hopeful and brutally honest in its descriptions. A must-read, a book about war and its craziness, with in its center great characters who just want to survive. Far from the typical hero-types, some of them capable of an astonishing and Orwellian 'doublethink', they will be remembered as some of the best in American literature. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jpsnow</user>
	<review>I recall getting lit class credit for reading a book that completely captured my attention. It taught me about story telling.  To the best of my knowledge, it was the only book in English class that made me laugh aloud. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SteveBallard</user>
	<review>Best book ever written. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>vzakuta</user>
	<review>This book is completely hilarious in a dark humor kind of way. Imagine that suddenly all the rules that we take for granted are suspended and we have to make things up as we go. Imagine the world that has been turned upside down by war.  All our little rituals are gone, we can't use them anymore. There is no appropriate reaction, because all reaction is inappropriate. You are in a country on the other side of the looking glass. There are no social cues you can look for to ascertain whether you are behaving correctly or not. This is the world of Catch 22.Being from former USSR, this kind of world and this kind of dark humor is only too familiar to me, and it hits all the right spots. Some may consider the book too dark, but I think it's just for the doctor ordered. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alexnisnevich</user>
	<review>Hilarious, thought-provoking, and at times disturbing; a brilliant book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>efay</user>
	<review>When Joseph Heller's wonderfully hilarious novel "Catch-22" was published in 1961, World War II was celebrated as the "good fight." Popular memory held it as a noble stand against the Axis onslaught and a glorious victory for democracy, as opposed to the more recent Korean War, a somewhat muddled thing with no rousing cause beyond vague theories of "containment." Needless to say, many found the irreverence and dark humor of "Catch-22" somewhat disturbing. Its hero, Yossarian, spends the story trying frantically to be sent home and not fly any more missions, while the United States military is depicted as an inanely irrational bureaucracy. The multifaceted "Catch-22" tells many tales, including a contemporarily relevant account of rhetoric gone wrong and the wiles of words used justify a variety of dubious causes in ways that make nonsensical sense. The result is a highly entertaining dark comedy that takes absurdity to new heights."Catch-22" has often been described as the insanity of modern life as seen from the perspective of someone who is perhaps too sane. Yossarian is perturbed by the very logical fact that thousands of people whom he does not know nor has ever even met are trying desperately to kill him. Common sense would indicate that it is best to remove oneself from such a situation, especially given the basic biological instinct for survival found in all animals. However, such is the incongruous nature of war, here only heightened by the fantastically illogical organizations running it. In order for Yossarian to be properly discharged from service, he must be proven mentally unfit for combat. Unfortunately, the very act of self-preservation is indicative of a sound man. That, as Doc Daneeka explains, is the principle of Catch-22. Although he admits it has a "spinning reasonableness" and an "elliptical precision about its perfect pairs and parts that was graceful and shocking," Yossarian remains steadfastly bound to the primordial value of life. It is later revealed that he came into his dangerously good sense after the gory death of his comrade Snowden in an air battle, thereby launching his quest to not fly any more missions. Alas, Colonel Cathcart, constantly trying to please his superiors so he can be promoted to general, persists in raising the number required. In essence, "Catch-22 . . . says you've always got to do what your commanding officer tells you to."I think Yossarian's plight is perhaps that the individual must always work to oppose the domineering "vested interests" of business, government, and the military. Though vital to modern world, these establishments are often forced to rely on unscrupulous means to safeguard themselves against a populace rightfully dissatisfied with them. The core definition of Catch-22, according an old woman, is that "they have the right to do anything we can't stop them from doing." Of course, so that they cannot be stopped, Yossarian's goal must be to prevent those in the military command from continuing to utilize him like a tool for their own ends. Yet the individual can never entirely escape the officious, overbearing, yet coldly and impersonally distant bureaucracies of contemporary society. To do so would be to violate the shifting facades of principle upon which they rest. There is too little to be certain of. Still, there remains the old declaration of skeptical philosophy: "I think, therefore I am," as Descartes once phrased it. When the world takes on an air of unreality, when there is doubt of the very ground upon which one stands, there persists that one eternal verity: conscious life. Who wants a life, one character asks, if it is nothing but "a series of unfortunate events"? The response is another question: "What else is there?"When it was fist published in 1961, "Catch-22" received mixed reviews and moderate success. As the sixties continued on, however, Joseph Heller's novel took on a new significance. An entire generation was coming to question the authority under which they lived, as well as its rhetoric of black and white, good versus evil. Granted, there is little to have loved about the Communist dictatorship of the Soviet Union, although some American leftists came to believe that there was, but nor could the actions of the United States be seen as wholly in the right. President Lyndon B. Johnson subsequently found that he could not talk the public into supporting the Vietnam War with fuzzy affirmations of "Courage, Might, Justice, Truth, Liberty, Love, Honor, and Patriotism" backed by geopolitical jargon about the importance of the Third World in the liberty-or-death struggle against global Communism. In "Catch-22," Yossarian finally decides to flee to Sweden: since the war is almost over, he would be risking his life for nothing but Colonel Cathcart's clamoring to be general. Meanwhile, in the real world, "Yossarian Lives!" would become a popular anti-Vietnam slogan. Escape was not an option for millions of young Americans in the late sixties who began to take "Catch-22" seriously and help make it into the classic it is today. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>georgecwilson</user>
	<review>I try to reread this book or at least parts of it once a year. The madness and futility of war is the backdrop for an examination of the absurdity of life. Heller's interpretation of insanity helps me stay sane. Yossarian's fanatic devotion to surviving is a reminder of the importance of living life no matter how crazy the world seems to be. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>notmyrealname</user>
	<review>I'm just not sure what to make of this. I hated it to start with, but warmed to it as it went along. I understand why, in 1961, this book would be so shocking - what with the whores, and beatings and utter madness. However, it is somewhat a book of its times - now it seemed flat and I felt I was just reading for the end. Yet there was something about Yossarian that just lit up the craziness of war, the frustration and the anger that the world should feel about war. I ended with much warmer feelings than I thought I would. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>milkmanson</user>
	<review>This was the third read for me. I originally read it way back when. It is still great </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Pdore</user>
	<review>A really funny book.  I'll write more later when I read it again. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sburton</user>
	<review>In short, Catch 22 challenges the idea of an absolute bureaucracy, along with the inevitability of death. The novel's protagonist, Yosarrian, fears for his life in the war, and refuses to fly missions. To the normal person, fearing for your life is normal. The army, being the reasonable organization that they are, realizes this, and will ground you (no more flying missions for you!) if you become crazy. However, you are not crazy if you are fearing for your life, and thus must fly more missions, which creates a Catch; Catch 22.  Yosarrian, realizing this, invents various ways to get himself out of flying missions. This includes everything from faking illnesses to refusing to fly, which does not make the army very happy. I think that Catch 22 is more of a dystopia novel than a utopia novel. Joseph Heller uses satirical tools such as exaggeration and irony to pinpoint how corrupt the army can really be. I think that Heller's utopia is a world with peace, and a world where there is no corrupt government. The army he describes, however, does not care about the soldiers or death rate. The army only cares about winning the war at all costs, which is opposite to Heller's Utopia. Overall, I think that Catch 22 was a good novel, but very time consuming. There was very little dialogue, but chapters upon chapters of character descriptions intertwined with stories that help you visualize the mannerisms of that specific character. This is not a book that you can finish during a rainy day. If you want to read this book, you have to sit down and concentrate not only on the plot, but on the character descriptions as well, which might be hard to do right before bed time. But, if you have the time (over the summer, maybe?), then you should definitely read this book because I found something to laugh at on every page. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wanack</user>
	<review>I have to admit that I liked this absurdist World War II novel better the first time I read it many years ago.  I would have given it an easy 5 stars back then, so I'll average it out to a 4 now.  It's certainly very funny most of the time, but I found myself yawning through several sections. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bnbooklady</user>
	<review>Catch-22 is one of the funniest, weirdest, most unique novels I’ve ever read. It presents the story of Yossarian, a World War II bombardier who is constantly inventing illnesses and ailments in hilarious attempts to prevent himself from having to fly dangerous missions, which is a realistic concerned, given that whole armies—thousands of people—are trying to kill him.  The government bureaucracy is always one step ahead of poor Yossarian, though, and his attempts are thwarted by Colonel Cathcart, who constantly raises the number of missions the men must fly in order to fulfill their service.Heller’s characters and their experiences of army life are hysterical, maddening, and utterly mad, and his satire is spot-on. Catch-22 is a classic that should be on every bookshelf, whores and all.Full review at  The Book Lady's Blog  </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>caskating</user>
	<review>I’ve always heard the phrase “Catch-22” but never understood what it meant. So, when I was offered the opportunity to read it and get credit for it, I couldn’t resist. At first I was confusing as, I soon realized, it bounces through time. I also had to learn that the automatic thing seen as truth is automatically discounted. This book startles, amazes and overall shakes the foundations of belief. Sometime while I was reading this book, I was informed that the book was written during the Vietnam War. This helped my understanding of the book and certain actions/sayings of the characters. This book attacks the way the military is set up and the idea of being entirely a tool of your country. 	This novel fits the idea of Utopias and Dystopias because it portrays a dystopia. In this world, everything is confusing, irrational, and illogical just to start. Everything has to be followed to a ‘T’. Commands must be followed even if one is dead. Paperwork holds the truth because it is down on paper, so e.g. you are alive but the paperwork says you were on a plane that went down, then you are dead. Ideals like loyalty, honesty, camaraderie are disowned and made fun of. And the ever illusive “Catch-22” explains it all. I highly recommend this novel. Just don’t get too frustrated! :) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ianw</user>
	<review>A bit disappointing after all the rave reviews I'd seen prior to picking the book up. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>terriks</user>
	<review>Beautiful, beautiful - both painful and joyous to read - I can only imagine the impact of this book when it first came out.   Would love to have been able to do that, for our perspective now certainly skewers it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AAndrea</user>
	<review>Clearly a classic tale of war written uniquely with understated realism. As intense as you want to visualise - my rating says it all - now i know the origins of the phrase catch22! </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bohh</user>
	<review>I wasn't really impressed with this book. It seemed to be hyped up a lot, but wasn't anything special in my opinion. I was interested in some of the historical aspects and it was interesting enough to keep turning the pages, though. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>melancholy</user>
	<review>brilliant and hillarious. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hdshank</user>
	<review>If you don't laugh your guts out on nearly every page, you have no sense of humor at all. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aubade</user>
	<review>Heller's novel came with so many raving reviews from my friends that I decided to try it. It literally took me a month to read, because it felt so tedious and weighed down in characters. He accomplishes his point within the first half of the book, then proceeds to beat you over the head with it. His exposition style was confusing and unnecessary, which continued to the end. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>logmanw</user>
	<review>You get the point after about 200 pages, but it keeps going on and on.  I can understand how people could get caught up in the novel at the time because of the anti-war sentiments and Heller really does do a good job of making everything about war seem completely absurd and nonsensical.Everyone should read "Catch-22" if for no reason other than to understand that even the world's strongest organizations are far from perfect and that we still have a long ways to go as a country and as a society. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>beatbox32</user>
	<review>I know this is widely considered a classic, and I believe the idea of the novel was excellent; but I think the execution was unnecessarily long and uninteresting in many parts. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>janepriceestrada</user>
	<review>This is a great work about war and bureaucracy.  Although I’m sure those who have been in the army would find it easier to interact with the story it is quite brilliant and funny for anyone. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gwendydd</user>
	<review>A difficult read out loud, but a good book to share, so it was worth reading out loud.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mackrobert81</user>
	<review>A book which I had looked forward to reading but felt somewhat let down. Not sure exactly why. Maybe reflection over time will aid it as there were certainly some great points but I often found them lost in the overly wordy and too many central characters to follow coherently. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Honto</user>
	<review>Having read this years ago it was interesting to go back to it. It seemed a bit more long winded and laboured than I recalled, but still very funny. The levels of absurdity just increase all the way through as more and more crazy characters get introduced. The main events and themes are referred to throughout the book, mentioned several times before the full details are given. The characters are caricatures, but also very human in their paranoia, cowardliness and selfishness. Great book. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ddejaco</user>
	<review>"Chi è pazzo può chiedere di essere esonerato dalle missioni di guerra. Chi chiede di essere esonerato dalle missioni di guerra non è pazzo". Una battaglia contro l'insensatezza della guerra ma, soprattutto, contro l'insensatezza delle regole che ci governano. Ormai quasi un proverbio. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Othemts</user>
	<review>At first I couldn’t get into this book - I thought it was just going to be satire up the wazoo, ridiculous people having absurd conversations.  And heaven help anyone who ever tries to put the narrative in some type of timeline order.  But as I read, I began to notice patterns.  All the major themes are introduced early on, and as the book unfolds, each of the themes is returned to and developed more and more.  And things never turn out quite like I expected.  I really ended up in awe of this book for being a great bit of writing.  Frightening too that the narrow-minded thinking and patriotic platitudes parodied in this book seem all too familiar today. “It was miraculous.  It was almost no trick at all, he saw, to turn vice into virtue and slander into truth, impotence into abstinence, arrogance into humility, plunder into philanthropy, thievery into honor, blasphemy into wisdom, brutality into patriotism, and sadism into justice.  Anybody could do it; it required no brains at all.  It merely required no character.”  (p.372) “The country was in peril; he was jeopardizing his traditional rights of freedom and independence by daring to exercise them.” (p. 414) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>danahlongley</user>
	<review>To me this is the greatest, funniest anti-war novel of all time. I've read it several times and each time I find myself giggling uncontrollably as I page through the misadventures of Heller's group of rowdy, cowardly misfits. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thingwraith</user>
	<review>Brilliant!  I wish I had read this book years ago, but I don't think it would have affected me in the same way when I was a lot younger.  Maybe I was meant to read it at this age. :) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cdagulleiro</user>
	<review>Here is the catch: You get out of the war if you prove that you are mad, but wanting to get out of the war is proof that you are sane. Amusing, excellent writing, reminds of M.A.S.H but touches you deeper. Those who have been in the army or at war will get even more touched. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ameer_m</user>
	<review>Only one catch, and there was no way of winning. You were caught in the machine and you had to play along - the machine being, of course, the bureaucracy, in this anti-war epic. The main character is Yossarian - the first out of his squad to realize that him and his friends were nothing short of meat in the eyes of their superiors: col. Cathcart (and his constant increase of mandatory missions), col Korn, or rival generals Dreedle and Peckem. So many of the dialogues and actions are absurd or paradoxical that they end up being funny. At first you’re a bit taken aback by the seeming lack of chronology, but once you’re in, it’s easy to keep up, even amongst the many references to other cultural stepping stones. The book itself is something like a catch-22.http://meerchant.wordpress.com/2008/0... </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>yapete</user>
	<review>A great American classic and a must-read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bookgirl271</user>
	<review>This is one of my favourite books. It is incredibly funny, incredibly sad and incredibly deep all at the same time. The writing style takes a bit of getting used to, and it is hard to put the events in chronological order. This has put off some people I know. This book is about war  people's reactions to it. I feel this aspect is more important than which order the events occur in. I have read this book twice  will definitely read it again. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>richcon69</user>
	<review>great book that ends too soon</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MonicaAella</user>
	<review>I love this book.  I've never read another book that makes me laugh continuously like Catch-22 does.  It's absolutely brilliant.  It can be difficult to get into at first, it jumps between characters, time periods, and locations within paragraphs.  Once you get used to it though, it makes the book.  You should give it a chance, you won't regret it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pKay</user>
	<review>Note: I initially reviewed this here: http://pkayski.wordpress.com/2008/04/... but I copy/pasted it here for easier viewing pleasure:“That’s some catch, that catch-22,” [Yossarian] observed.“It’s the best there is,” Doc Daneeka agreed. Get in a comfy position! You will be sitting/lying/standing for a very long time once you begin reading this gem! Published in 1961, Joseph Hellerbegins his writing career with Catch-22; a masterpiece, surpassing all his subsequent books. Set in a random island in the Mediterranean sea of the coast of Italy, we witness the lives of an American bomber squadron near the end of World War II. With the novel being set in a random and incomplete order, you generally follow the stories and adventures of Yossarian, a bombardier that wants nothing to do with the war! Wanting to get out of it, he completes the requirements (# of bombing missions)  but every time he gets near the goal, the number of missions required before he can leave the war increases! Bureaucratic elements are filled in the book, making anyone who has dealt with annoying administration/service nod and cringe at the occasions. Furthermore, the logic that is ‘catch-22′ is coined from this very novel and that element is frustratingly implanted in many situations throughout the novel. At roughly 520 pages, it is quite a read. Furthermore the order of the book and the general style of Heller’s writing makes this a difficult and at many times a hard book to understand. None-the-less the dark humour is evident throughout, the characters are live, vivid and easy to relate to. Who can forget Yossarian,’Major Major Major Major’, Doc Daneeka , Clevinger, Nately and his whore, Milo Minderbinder and his mess hall, Orr, Scheisskopf (It’s something funny in German ;)) among many many more!Finally, the ending could not have ended in a better way! While the novel keeps getting darker and darker as it progresses from it’s initial humour, we are left satisfied (somewhat) in the end. Usually I borrow books from the library, but I liked this one so much that I had to own a copy. If you got plenty of free time in your hands and your into dark humour, give this a go. You do not need to necessarily be a war buff, but I am sure many who are got a crack at Colonel Cathcart’s insane antics and bombing pattern demands and so on. Rated as one of the 100 best novels of the 20th century, this is surely one you have to check out!One final comment: This book tends to be one of those ‘love it or hate it with nothing in between’ so don’t be surprised if you hate the book after the review I gave it :). Overall: 9.5/10 </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ConnieJo</user>
	<review>I read this at the insistence of several acquaintances, but I just could not get into it.  I can appreciate what Heller is trying to do, and there were a few things that made me laugh, but a lot of it was just too over-the-top for me... there were too many zany jokes, and I had a hard time following what was going on.  Even with two ardent fans of the book copiously explaining away anything I had complaints about the entire time I was reading it, I just could not get into the jokes or the plot. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>StuartAston</user>
	<review>It has been quiet a few years since I have read this but something just took my fancy to pick it up.It encircles around a group of colleagues and friends in Word War II Italy and the fact that every time they think they will be sent home after flying their missions the total keeps getting put up thereby making them all stay longer.The main character Captain Yossarian tries to find any way that will stop him flying the last few missions he needs as he reckons everyone is trying to kill him. Orr practices his escape by crashing his planes in the sea everytime but with no-one working out why he does this until at the end he gets to Sweden in a rescue boat.Major Major wont talk to anyone so people can only go to see him when he is out.An Milo the enterprenurial canteen manager starts making money by bombing his own barracks with the companies planes.And it all ends with Yossarian nearly killed by an demented Italian prostitute who found out here boyfriend is dead.A difficult book to start as it is a style of writing you need to really get into and follow. It it one though, that when you are there, you do not want to leave.Enjoy. If you never read it please do. If you have it - dust it off and re-read. You'll have fun :-) </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Autodafe</user>
	<review>Jump ! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Carlie</user>
	<review>It's not that I didn't understand Catch-22, but it took some time to get used to it. The heavy dialogue, circular reasoning, strange characters with bizarre behaviors, and an abstract timeline coincide with biting satire and an incriminating critique of national institutions, especially the military establishment, to form a chaotic reading experience. I kept waiting for a plot to issue forth, but slowly I began to realize that the plot was outside of the story altogether. The plot was in the reader, not the book. The plot is still occurring to this day, which is the real power of Catch-22: its remarkable ability to perform allegories of real-life in an astute and timeless manner.So, you ask, what is it "about"? It's about Yossarian, a World War II bombardier that is convinced that millions of people are trying to kill him. And he's right, they are - the enemy, the military, his commanding officers, incompetent fellow soldiers, an enraged grieving woman are all trying to kill him. But Yossarian is determined to stop them, and he does everything in his power to overcome the forces that are trying to defeat him and to regain control of his own life.Not a quick, easy read by any means, but worth the patience and the ensuing contemplation. This book is not meant for idle entertainment, and I found it helpful to read a couple of analyses to see the more subtle themes emerge.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>akandy</user>
	<review>It's hard to know how to describe this book. It is hilarious, it is disturbing, sad, laugh-out-loud funny, and confusing. You have to be willing to put in some effort for this one - there are so many characters to keep track of and the events are not always described in linear fashion - in fact, most important events are described multiple times, from different points of view, so it isn't until far later on that you will understand what you read about before. I found Heller's style of humor hilarious (it helps if you have seen the movie) but there is also a lot of smart commentary in here - about what war does to people and their personalities/values, about the uselessness of bureaucracy and the toll it can take on everyone's lives, and many social and moral dilemnas. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>elder18</user>
	<review>A rare book that insinutates its language and way of thinking into your everyday life. Hysterically funny and horrifying within the space of a page, or even paragraph, Catch-22 points out not only the absurdity of war but of many of the things people encounter throughout the day.I've read many books in my life, but Catch-22 has been my favorite and, I've thought for some time now, the best of them. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bobshackleton</user>
	<review>I remember my dad reading this book in a hotel in Garmisch in 1962 (I was about 6) and laughing so hard he was breathless. I tried to read it and didn't make it past the first two pages. I finally read it in 8th grade and loved it, and in 9th grade I made one of my closest lifelong friends over an evening spent laughing together over the book.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Seeker954</user>
	<review>A classic. Its namesake title penetrated the English language many moons ago. And everybody knows what a Catch-22 means, even those who have no idea what the book is about. Now, that's a classic. It's easy to be anti-war these days. It's not so easy to be anti-war and actually funny. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rivertondude</user>
	<review>My favorite book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Tonny</user>
	<review>One of my all time favorites. In danish and in english. If you agree, you'll probably allready know the "danish Heller" - Leif Panduro, or the Father of Sarcasm - Ambrose Bierce. Otherwise - try them... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>GoldenBeep</user>
	<review>Anyone who enjoys reading books about war should put the time into reading this one.  The novel follows several people who are entrenched in combat in the air force during WWII.  The book is extremely funny, going from mild satire to laugh out loud situations.  Heller combines characters that are absolutely insane with ones who seem like they are, and while this does have the potential to leave the readers doubting the overall zanyness, it makes for incredible fun.  The absurdity of war is perfectly portrayed in this must read novel. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluetyson</user>
	<review>Stop changing the rules.That is what the title refers to - that fact that you need to successfully complete a number of missions to get out of the war, but when you get close, the nasty people in charge keep upping the number.This is a black comedy that follows our protagonist as he tries to get by while stuck in this ugly war situation with a bunch of crazy and going crazy fellow military, locals and other whacky people around the place.Both funny and bleak at once.Definitely worth reading.http://notfreesf.blogspot.com/2008/03... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>NolHol</user>
	<review>Catch-22 seems to have affected everyone in some way or another.  Whether it is uttering the phrase that the book's title and premise has generated, or reading this great novel, Catch-22 is a work of genius.  Putting true personification to "damned if you do, damned if you don't," Joseph Heller has created a work that is extremely funny, scary, and downright mind bending. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ktoonen</user>
	<review>Crazy logic that starts to make sense after a whileA must read for mathematicians </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>helices</user>
	<review>En galen satirisk skildring av livet för stridande förband under krig. Ibland är det roligt, andra gånger är det inte alls särskilt kul, och jag letar inte sällan efter syftet med hela historien. Men kanske är det så "enkelt" att krig är vansinne.Måste dock säga att Heller blir lite långrandig från stund till annan, och att det faktiskt är lite pratigt. Och varken tillräckligt roligt eller särskilt gripande.Dessutom är den till och från dåligt översatt: vem säger i ett replikskifte "Sluta göra frågor, här är det vi som gör frågorna!"? </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mcur</user>
	<review>I've read half of this book twice. It's bloody funny. I must try a third time and see if I can get all the way through. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>briandarvell</user>
	<review>Catch-22 is a good novel of the satirical genre which rings true on most of its main themes today just as easily had it been written 300 years ago.After getting just a few pages into this book one realizes that it's going to be a read unlike any other. It was one of the few books where I found myself actually laughing out-loud and, except for a small drawn-out section about two-thirds the way through the novel, I quickly read through it at a very fast pace.The main theme of the novel is the basic uselessness of war but hidden underneath that rang a sound of how Heller believes devoted faith and blind following of any cause only brings about more tragedy and harm - even if that is what the original cause is against. A sense of self-preservation exists in this novel quite extensively in the main character as well.The comedy is utterly brilliant and there is a wide array of completely different, yet well-defined, characters which adds all the more to the story.This novel is readable by most age-groups but would be best for those with a somewhat satiric sense of humor. For those whom have read and enjoyed Douglas Adams then this would definitely be worth your time. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Amzzz</user>
	<review>The story of war, its ups and downs, the low points, the screw ups, the lack of glory yet the sense of humour in it all. Yossarian is an unforgettable character - all the characters are. This book made me laugh out loud and feel sick to my stomach, and I have no doubt I will keep thinking about it for a long time. Some parts were difficult to read and understand, but it was most definitely worth sticking with. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tkraft</user>
	<review>Couldn't finish it the author's intention is to confuse and befuddle the reader. One of the books where I just can't understand why it is a classic.  I think that nobody wants to admit that they don't understand, so they just say it is a great novel.  Don't bother.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SanctiSpiritus</user>
	<review>Joseph Heller was a genius in delivering such a masterpiece to his fellow countrymen. The style, and proses are evocative. Heller keeps the plot, and storyline right above the surface of the pages. He has you learning of one character make reference to one you will learn of later in the book, or one you just passed. The satire is fulsome, and majestically original. The book refreshes the reader in a way very few books can. It is disconcerting when one realizes this is one of a kind. Authors should take a stab at further developing Mr. Heller's gift. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bibliobbe</user>
	<review>So many of the books in here are new or newish, it’s pleasing to see some of the older classics make it in.  Would Catch 22 have been this far down the list ten or 15 years ago?  This one is a comic genius, and is the only title in the Top 100 (that I can think of) which has become a recognised phrase in its own right.  I may have been too young when I first read it – I recognised it as a terrific book, but found it hard going in parts.  All the characters seemed too manic, even the relatively sane ones.  But despite not having picked up the book for years, I can still recall Nately’s whore (yes, that is the only name she is given), Major Major, and of course, our hero, Yossarian, who somehow manages to survive the struggle.  I think.  It’s been a while, and no, I have no particular desire to read it again.  Once was enough.  Whew. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>flocu</user>
	<review>This is the single most brilliant book ever.Not kidding! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>petrojoh</user>
	<review>Mr. Heller has documented insanity. Beautifully absurd. Full of metaphor and worldly lessons. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>R.Donez</user>
	<review>Too  many down-right hilarious moments...with the not quite buried fear that war may just be real...if the characters let it be so...but no...the brutality is nearly overshadowed by the absurdity of the moment...Military "Intelligence" has never been so well portrayed. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>J.v.d.A.</user>
	<review>I read this so long ago that I honestly couldn't tell you much about it if it wasn't for having watched the movie so many times. Very amusing in parts. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ThatsFresh</user>
	<review>I had to read this for class.  Unfortunately didnt spark my interest.  Had some good things to say, but overall didn't grab me.  I SparkNoted the whole thing.  Sorry... </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>www.snigel.nu</user>
	<review>Link to a review on my personal website  (might be in Swedish). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>heidilove</user>
	<review>this is as funny and timely now as it was in the fifties. i'm a heller fan. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>myfanwy</user>
	<review>This book is quite simply brilliant. That really sums it up. It is hilarious. It is satirical. It is moving. The characters are detailed and distinct and change over the course of the story. And it contains one of my new favorite quotes. Paraphrasing: "Live forever, or die trying!"In following the history of Yossarian in the war you watch the patently absurd but utterly believable situations that result when certain attitudes are taken to their logical conclusion. The soldiers are simply caught in the midst of ambitious rivalries. Everyone from the general down to the lowest private has their motivations. And what seems perfectly believable, that so-and-so is blinded by ambition, that another is blinded by profit, that a third simply loves the thrill of a firefight, leads to a gradual escalation of absurdity until you are no longer rolling on the floor laughing but staring aghast at the page. The boundary between reality and the absurd is so blurred, it's difficult to tell where the book changes from funny to horrifying. I think the line is probably different for everyone.And the way it's written -- Heller wanders, one story leading to another, the timelines intertwined and referenced in as easy a manner as someone would when talking at a bar. "You don't say? Remember that time...." Somehow all of these snippets of stories end up collecting so that by the end you understand all that has gone on.As I said before, this book is just brilliant. I can't say anything more.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ctait17</user>
	<review>Excellent, a classic study of crazy life of war </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>DetailMuse</user>
	<review>It was the 1960s and I was very young, on a family road trip where all I heard was my mother saying, "Yossarian." All I saw was her laughing so hard she could barely keep reading aloud to my dad as he drove. Decades later, I learned Yossarian is the protagonist in a war novel (anti-war; anti-bureaucracy, really), and more decades later I finally picked up the book. The mess of its incoherent, non-linear presentation tempted me to set it aside, and the only thing that kept me in it was the hilarity.I’ve talked to more readers who abandoned the book than finished it, so there’s an element of pride in having persisted through a difficult read ... and come out loving it. Because, counter-balancing the hilarity, Heller does things like arranging just six discrete words to haunt us about the horrors of war:"I’m cold," Snowden said. "I’m cold.""There, there," said Yossarian. "There, there."If you’ve read the novel, you’ve gone now to get a tissue.http://detailmuse.blogspot.com/2007/0... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kettle666</user>
	<review>Crucially this was published at a time when I was consuming all kinds of books. I was at Art School, spending as much time reading as painting. Catch 22 seemed like an ultimate shake up to the traditional novel, whatever the hell that is. As a 'serious' reader I had gone through a lot of historical writers, and mainly enjoyed what I found. Dickens, Dostoyevsky, Wilkie Collins, Joyce, Cervantes, and a hundred others made me aware a lot of famous writers - who struck fear in you because they were so powerfully entrenched in the 'Canon' that they inhibited you picking them up - were, in fact, just fabulous storytellers. Okay, some were difficult to wade through at times, and it took a big push for me to actually get all the way through Ulysses, but when I finally managed it I had absorbed a tolerance and a willingness to go on. Salinger, Kerouac, Vonnegut, Donleavy, Chandler and Heller were extending that factor, and I was forever hooked on this path of literary discovery. And what an enjoyable path it remains. Catch 22 has a special place, because it made me laugh out loud for perhaps the first time. On a bus. A crowded bus. Back in those days, in the early 60s, a crowded bus was relatively silent. No mobile phones, no Walkmans, or ipods, or laptops; and a generally more peaceful atmosphere prevailed. So, if a person suddenly began laughing out loud, it impinged a lot on the passengers. Was I infectious? Mad? Stupid? Drunk?You did not consciously make a lot of noise on public transport then, and here was a book stimulating me to lose myself inside a hilarious logic that seemed entirely fresh and new. Thanks, Joe. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>becha</user>
	<review>I don't usually read (or like) war books because I either get irritated on lack of reality or the book is too realistic and therefore depressing. Catch-22 manages to portray the absurdity and chaos of war, without being too heavy a read. Definitely one of my favourite books ever. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Bbilly1</user>
	<review>Catch-22	Catch-22 is a novel by Joseph Heller that portrays in a comical fashion the process of war and the individual lives of those directly involved with it. The story follows a character named Yossarian, a bombardier, and his squadron as they progress through WWII. The story has an extremely satirical feel, as the author seems to make a mockery of the seriousness of war. The one aspect about this book that stands out, in my opinion, is the fact that it has an extremely humorous tone. Every war book that I have read has had a very dark and depressing feel to it; For Heller to change the normal style of a story like this is both unusual and refreshing.	Don’t think that Catch-22 is all happiness and smiles, however. War is war, and there are still plenty of depressingly realistic situations that take place, and this mixture of both happiness and sadness creates an excellent story overall.	One of my favorite aspects of this story is undoubtedly the characters. This book contained too many characters to count, each with their own uniquely funny personalities. Yossarian has many interactions with the many different characters throughout the course of the story, and each scenario seemed to be both funnier and cleverer than the previous one. These scenarios went from war-based to religious, and were all very smart indeed.	The only complaint I have of this book is the way it was written. Many times I got confused as to where it was going. Heller switched from the past to the present in no particular order, and this caused a lot of confusion for me. It always seemed to even out, but I had to stop and think about where I was too often.	Another slick move from Heller was his way of portraying war as a whole. All the characters in the book never seemed to care about what this war was for. Soldiers only worried about surviving, whereas their superiors only seemed to worry about their reputation and status in the military. Most of the high ranking officers in the book seemed to focus more on getting promoted than taking care of their men. Yossarian constantly tried to get himself out of the war. He believed that it was completely useless, and that high status people in the world were keeping it from ending. He tried to plea insane so that he could go home, but that was when cath-22 was first explained to him. As in the title, catch-22 is a rule that in a way binds a soldier into staying on the front lines. For him to not want to fly missions anymore, and for him to fill out a request to leave, it would in fact prove that he is sane, because no sane man would ever want to stay in battle for a prolonged period of time. This idea keeps him and many other men in the service. Throughout the course of the novel, Yossarian and his fellow mates endure violent battles, tough living conditions, and the feeling of being trapped in a seemingly ridiculous struggle. The sad thing about Catch-22 is that the sad life of these fictional characters is really not fictional at all. The book may try to sweeten things up with its satirical feel, but you still get a grasp for how stupid war really is.	Catch-22 was an amazingly clever, surprisingly deep novel that I have no regret of reading. Though it had its shortcomings, I feel that the book, though published in 1961, still has many similarities to our world today, and I believe that the author must have had an amazingly imaginative mind to come up with a novel this clever.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shieldsk2</user>
	<review>One of the best books I ever read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LibraryLou</user>
	<review>I think this is more of a man's book. I didn't dislike it but I found just when I was getting into the story the chapter ended and it didn't go back and tell me what happened about the bit I was just reading. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BrianDewey</user>
	<review>Heller, Joseph. Catch-22. Simon  Schuster, New York, 1955. I'm so glad I finally got around to reading this book. Both the story  the storytelling are captivating. The story is a stinging indictment of war with quite an emotional punch. The storytelling is even better. The roundabout way of unfolding the plot maximizes the story's emotional effect. The surreal events enforces the key message of the book on the absurdities of war. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shawnd</user>
	<review>I dislike reading about war stories so I endure this and Hemingway because the writing is so good.  An excellent book.  Tightly written, a crafted feel.  It's a good story, good characters, with a good social argument for its time.  I can see how if someone is not reading this slowly and for meaning it can come off weak and underestimated. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stpnwlf</user>
	<review>Heller's story is a classic tale of military bureaucracy gone overboard. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>keylawk</user>
	<review>Heller describes the experience of a bombadier in WWII during and after the actual combat.  He is dead on the money -- literally describing the profiteering opportunities in warfare.  Although others take Keller (and fellow WWII veteran writer Kurt Vonnegut) as a "satirist", many in the 60's generation, have taken the work for what it is -- a straightforward "AAR" (after action report).  There is nothing "funny" or satirical about it -- the War was FUBAR, non-combatants profitted by it, there were no heroes, and no "Great Generation" involved in the performance of unmitigated idiocy.  Heller died in 1999, apparently unapologetically, considering his considerable plagiarism from other authors, and his unrelenting contributions to erosion of Authority of all kinds.  By my lights, his greatest work was his 1986 GOD KNOWS, written from the point of view of King David, but CATCH-22, is far more influential, and remains so.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>coffeezombie</user>
	<review>One of the greatest satires in modern American literature and one ofthe classic trio of anti-war novels of the last century (along with"Slaughterhouse-Five" and "Johnny Got His Gun"). It tells the story ofan Air Force bomber captain during World War II who tries desperatelyto escape from active duty because "everyone is trying to kill him outthere." Deftly pointing out the various absurdities of war (and life ingeneral) in a keen and original voice, Heller here crafted hisunsurmountable masterpiece. The creative wit and twisted logic of thebook make it seem timeless. Brilliant work.(This review originally appeared on zombieunderground.net) </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>boeflak</user>
	<review>The ultimate send-up of bureaucracy, of military life and of war. A book that will outlive our great, great, great grandchildren. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>arthurfrayn</user>
	<review>Might still be my favorite novel of all time.I often call it my "Farenheit 451 novel", meaning, if there were one novel I was compelled to commit to memory, this would be it. So many wonderful passages. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jennyo</user>
	<review>http://bcjennyo.livejournal.com/21680... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>sulkyblue</user>
	<review>I didn't actually like this book very much, and to be honest, didn't really think it was that good. There were definitely some funny and some powerful scenes, but as a whole I found the book overly complicated and poorly structured. I continuously lost track of which character was which and how the various incidents fit together in the time line and while I'm sure with a bit more effort it would have become clearer, I didn't really feel it was worth the effort. The whole thing just left me with a craving to watch M*A*S*H again. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lizatoad</user>
	<review>I tried reading this book several different times, but could never really get through it. Maybe I will have to pick it up again, but I just didn't find it to be as great as everyone told me it would be. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kellepa</user>
	<review>As close to a perfect book as I've ever read- my favorite book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hawaiianobrien</user>
	<review>My current favorite. My older brother read it when I was 10 years old, so I tried to read it too. I didn't make it back then, but I succeeded 20 years later, and I'm glad I tried. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>syntheticvox</user>
	<review>A hilarious look at the absurdity of war by a master of wit and wordcraft. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bradsucks</user>
	<review>I tried to read this for the sixth time a couple months ago and failed again. I swear I will never try again. It starts strong then rambles, then I get bored and quit. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tropics</user>
	<review>A brilliant, timeless portrayal of the madness of war.  The characters are unforgettable. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Don1</user>
	<review>Fantastic military satire although it took me about 50 pages to figure out Heller's twisted writing style.  I read this book during a National Guard 2-week summer camp where I didn't have much to do.  That was the perfect setting to read this book. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>richardtaylor</user>
	<review>I'm struggling with this. I'm surprised that so many of the other LT reviews describe it as "funny". For me it is very dull so far... In fact, I gave up on it [which I very rarely do]. </review>
	<rating>1</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss2.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fisfia</user>
	<review>Den här boken har jag inte läst ännu. Har inte ens försökt. Får se när det blir. Det finns många böcker på listan över böcker jag vill läsa.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AstridG</user>
	<review>Loved loved loved this book </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mamorico</user>
	<review>A quirky story about a WWII bombardier named Yossarian who does everything in his power to preserve his own life in an environment in which life is cheap.  Makes an effective and humorous statement about the insanity of military life.  Not quite the powerful anti-war statement that I was hoping for, but it is an anti-war statement none-the-less. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>calvin_xa</user>
	<review>This is such a criminally funny book. I laughed so hard for so long. Though 5 years have passed and i've never re-read it for fear that it won't be as good second time around. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>miketroll</user>
	<review>Cult antiwar novel of the 60s, one of the most over-rated books in 20th Century literature. As a young man of the era, I found it mildly entertaining. I will soon re-read after an interval of 3 decades to see if the impression has altered. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ejfertig</user>
	<review>major major majorly good. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rajendran</user>
	<review>"Catch-22 has become a byword in its own time. It is a novel of enormous richness and art. It is deeply serious, yet at the same time, brilliantly funny. It is without question one of the great novels of the century.Catch-22 is, said Philip Toynbee in The Observer, the greatest satirical work in the English language since ""Erewhon"" -- a hilarious, tragic novel in which an American airforce base on a small island off Italy becomes a microcosm of the modern world as it might look to someone dangerously sane."</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>aletheia21</user>
	<review>classic absurdist WWII hospital/air fighter novel5.03 </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>NativeRoses</user>
	<review>No novel before or since has matched Catch-22 in its intensity and brilliance in depicting the brutal insanity of war.  Joseph Heller satirizes military bureaucracy with bitter, stinging humor, all the while telling the darkly comic story of Yossarian, a bombardier who refuses to die.  Heller introduces a new term into English – Catch-22 – by displaying the world in all its contradictions and absurdity.  The novel is a bitingly hilarious exploration of issues like identity, war, and the struggle of an individual against a crushing bureaucracy.  John Yossarian is a bombardier trying to stay alive in the middle of WWII in an American bomber squadron off the coast of Italy, where everyone in the military is insane in the middle of war’s hypocrisy and insanity.  Yossarian is furious because thousands of people he has never met are trying to kill him.  He also tries to decode the Catch-22:  Whenever a bombardier comes close to flying the mandatory number of missions to be eligible to go home, the mandatory number is changed.  There is only one way out:  A pilot who is crazy can ask a doctor to ground him.  But there’s just one catch:"There was only one catch and that was Catch-22, which specified that concern for one's own safety in the face of dangers that were real and immediate was the process of a rational mind. Orr was crazy and could be grounded. All he had to do was ask; and as soon as he did, he would no longer be crazy and would have to fly more missions. Orr would be crazy to fly more missions and sane if he didn't, but if he was sane he had to fly them. If he flew them he was crazy and didn't have to; but if he didn't want to he was sane and had to. Yossarian was moved very deeply by the absolute simplicity of this clause of Catch-22 and let out a respectful whistle." Men that Yossarian knows keep dying because they're sent on one dangerous mission after another in an effort by their commanding officer to show his zeal and to be promoted. Catch-22 is a brilliant look at the logical results of consolidating power.  In this world, Catch-22 proves that insane people are really the sanest, while supposedly sane people are truly insane.  Each chapter focuses on a different character or setting.  This allows the reader to see the inability of anyone to stop the crushing wheels of bureaucracy and the insanity of the overall situation.  In such a setting the only people who succeed are those who exploit the system for their own ends, while simultaneously proclaiming loudly that all their work is for the greater good.  There are a number of hilarious, bitter portraits of minor characters such as the man trying to get a picture of himself in the Saturday Evening Post.  Then there’s the man trying to be recognized for the sincerity of the form letters sent to families of airmen who have been killed.  Major Major Major’s big tragedy is that he looks like Henry Fonda.  Colonel Cathcart keeps raising the number of missions men must fly in order to finish their tour.  Major --- de Coverley has such a forbidding face that nobody has ever dared to ask him his name.  Milo Minderbinder is an entrepreneur who bombs his own airfields in response to German offers of an extra six percent. While, recent war novels such as Jarhead and My War provide details about the recent Gulf War from the perspective of a boot on the ground, none of them approach the brilliance of Catch-22. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>brose72</user>
	<review>A book about the absurdities of war filled with kooky characters doing nutty things. Entertaining and at times hilarious. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LiteraryFeline</user>
	<review>http://literaryfeline.blogspot.com/20... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Allovertheboard</user>
	<review>One of the most pointless books ever written. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>drutt</user>
	<review>A deliciously clever, funny and sad book all rolled into one. The futility of everything the characters went through left me feeling pretty down at the end, but it's absolutely worth reading.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gazzy</user>
	<review>Slap-stick anti-war (in the vein of MASH, McHales Navy and Sgt. Bilko) in which every plot line is turned on its head and put togehter again in the end. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>thelistener</user>
	<review>Brilliant!Laugh out loud funny, mad logic, poignance, clever repetition.It's not often something you read as a teenager is still so good in your 40s. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>burnit99</user>
	<review>The late Joseph Heller's wildly macabre anti-war classic, which has yielded a new phrase for the lexicon, "Catch-22", and one of my favorite lines in which Yossarian is asked by another about one of their comrades in the Army: "He's dead", Yossarian replies. "How old was he?" "I don't know. Old." "Old! replies another. "He was 24!" "He's dead," says Yossarian. "You don't get older than that." (Upon a re-reading in 2006, I find that this line only exists in the movie). There are a lot of similarities here to "M*A*S*H, which is probably not the literary classic that this is, but I enjoyed it more. A great book, occasionally so madcap it works to its detriment, but a great book nonetheless. And Heller neatly brings together the madcap elements of the book at the end into an inspired and inspiring conclusion. The book was made into an equally fine movie with a great cast. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>xiWen</user>
	<review>I didn't finish it, but I got far enough into the book to know what 'Catch-22' means. Catchy catch. Like "writestuff" said there were too many adjectives and adverbs. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>amancine</user>
	<review>So much of this book has entered our family lexicon, from someone having 'Orr-like' tendencies to 'moving the bomb line'. That's some catch, that Catch-22! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>writestuff</user>
	<review>I hated this book. It was boring, with crappy writing (how many adjectives and adverbs do you *really* need to make your point, Mr. Heller???). The dialogue was inane and repetitive and circular. Sorry folks, I don't understand why this is a classic. I quit reading on page 70 when I couldn't stand it any longer. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>feralchicken</user>
	<review>I don't find this sort of humour at all funny. Was a nightmare to read!! </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>readaholic12</user>
	<review>The funniest and truest book I have ever read. Personal record for most re-readings. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rolandarad</user>
	<review>I used to read this book while travelling on the Tiube to work and I would laugh out loud, especially in the sections about Major Major. This book influenced my early life and passages were constantly quoted by my friends. Even though I laughed alot it is one of the most tragic stories I have have ever read and as you grow older it becomes even more pertinent. You dont have time to read every good book but this is a must read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>soylentgreen23</user>
	<review>Somebody, it is said, once remarked to Heller, "You'll never write another book as good as Catch-22." I think this was after his second novel came out, which wasn't, surprise surprise, as good as "Catch-22." This may or may not be true, but Heller's response was: "Neither will anybody else." He may have been right - as far as I can tell the book is perfect. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>misscatie</user>
	<review>I thoroughly enjoyed Catch-22. It took me about three months to read, but it was worth it. Normally, I can crank through books in about 2 weeks tops, but I wanted to digest this one a little more. It was humorous, poignant, intelligent and a great conversation starter. I love when books make me consider concepts that don't exist in my little world and this book certainly did that. It was great. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ragwaine</user>
	<review>Very funny and excellently put together.  Many short vignettes each with a couple characters.  Great ending that really fit the story.  Very strange at first but you begin to get in sync with it after a while. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>violabelle</user>
	<review>Catch-22 is one of those books that you will read and re-read your entire life, each time getting something different out of the story. The dark sarcasm of the writing expresses the horror of war all the better. During WWII, soldiers on an island company of pilots and bombers live and survive within the bizarre rules of war and the military. The characters are vivid and sympathetic, and the terms and ideas long ago entered popular culture. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Thalia</user>
	<review>Thanks to LT I know that it took me a year minus four days to read this book... I see that it's brilliant and I did enjoy it a lot, but for some reason I don't quite understand I always had a really hard time to get into it and then stick with it. I put it down for months at a time, read a few chapters and put it down for a few weeks again.This morning I picked it up again and read the last 150 pages in one sitting. And suddenly I couldn't understand anymore how I was able to not finish it before. And it was a little hard to remember the dozens of characters that I had read about months before.But, it is one of the best anti-war books I have ever read. Definitely the best one that uses humor to bring the absurdity and pointlessness of war across. It's a fine line to walk, but Heller pulled it off elegantly and brilliantly.I'll definitely read it again. Next time it hopefully won't take me that long... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bespen</user>
	<review>http://www.brothersjudd.com/index.cfm...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mdevile</user>
	<review>One of my favourite books, this satirical war novel does it's part of portraying the absurdity of war and the way it's conducted while making one laugh and sigh.Tragically funny or funny and tragic? Maybe a bit of both. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ablueidol</user>
	<review>I took several attempts to read this, and in the end only succeeded by skipping the first chapter. I would have missed reading one of the best anti-war books of its type. Read the stories and views of those who come back not those who are going to war. You get a true picture of the horror and boredom of war. MASH captured it for the Korean war and I wished that Robert Altman had made the catch 22 film as the one that was made was a bit of a turkey </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tikitu-reviews</user>
	<review>A must-read. In a strictly literal sense: everybody should read this book.It's funny, and then it's funny and it's tragic, and then it's just tragic, and then finally it's triumphant, and the extraordinary thing is how Heller manages to keep the events he's describing largely unchanged while he takes us through the emotional wringer.The source of both the comedy and the tragedy is the implacable insanity of war; not the fact of war itself, but the way in which the war is conducted. The "Catch-22" of the title is a regulation that captures in miniature the unfeeling bureaucratic system that's needed to send ordinary sensible folk out to kill other folk and to die. It goes like this: to be sent home, all a pilot needs is to be declared insane, and to request a transfer on medical grounds. But requesting a transfer out of the war zone is evidence that the pilot is concerned for his own safety; this, in turn, is considered sufficient evidence of sanity, so his diagnosis will be overturned.The same structure turns up again and again. At first it's hilarious, as we see basically sensible and good-hearted characters trying to keep their lives going despite the insanity of their situation. Then while the same jokey situations keep coming up, the mood turns tragic as we realise that that very insanity can hurt and kill the characters we've learned to like, and that there is nothing they can do to fight back.I won't spoil the ending, but I'll say that the downward movement does get turned around. Even knowing how this happens, the moment that it hits still leaves me with tears prickling in my eyes. That's a pretty high achievement, given that the first half of the novel is basically pure comedy.Read it. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jalamb</user>
	<review>Best book ever? Quite possibly. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lacenaire</user>
	<review>http://www.kirjasto.sci.fi/heller.htm...http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_H...http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Catch-22... </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rcooper3589</user>
	<review>i never had to read this in high school and so i was sorta curious as to what it was all about. knowing it is usually a summer reading book, i was sorta skeptical about it and figured it was going to boring and i wasn't going to like it. boy, was i wrong! from the very beginning it is hilarious! it makes fun of everyone and thing. the movie is just as funny!! </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mourning_east</user>
	<review>This is definatly my favorite book.  Though it's not a book for everyone, the mixing of satire and seriousness kept me wanting to read more and more of it.  This is one of the few books that in a single page can make you laugh and cry. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mmh166</user>
	<review>My favorite book of all time. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rakerman</user>
	<review>A well-deserved reputation as one of the funniest books in the English language. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>danielmacy</user>
	<review>One of the best satires of all times.  No one should go through life without reading this book.  Its hilarity is timeless. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raphaelmatto</user>
	<review>Shocking, simultaneously real and clown-like. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>drruth</user>
	<review>The famous anti-war novel is not for everyone. Its complex narrative style is difficult for many readers. The alternating shocks and humor still pack their punch, and the satiric force of the title phrase remains even more pointed today. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shliz</user>
	<review>I just read this book in March 2006, and was struck by how true Heller's portrayal of the military still seems today.  Although Catch-22 was written about World War II, it could have been written today, about today.  The convergence of bureaucracy with life and death is something to consider.  The characters feel real, yet there is a certain whimsical air with which they endure the trials of life at war. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raxxq</user>
	<review>The perennial classic.  I read this book slowly during the summer that I was in Israel.  I also read A Clockwork Orange that summer.  I read Catch 22 with a folded piece of notebook paper as my bookmark.  Anytime I didn't know a word I wrote it down and looked it up the next time I found a dictionary.  It was a very neat way to read a book, and I learned some wonderful new words.  Unfortunately the list has been lost, I wish I still had that particular piece of personal ephemera. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>vikas</user>
	<review>LOL </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MeredithYvonne</user>
	<review>What a fabulous book!! It's a love it or hate it situation, but the story of a desperate pilot during WWII has some amazing black humor and is a definate classic. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alarra_c</user>
	<review>Very funny anti-war novel about the crazy things humans do to themselves and humanity. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ursula</user>
	<review>This is one of my favorite books ever.  Cynical, funny, sad, it's a little bit of everything.  Some of the most memorable characters you'll find anywhere, and eminently quotable."There was only one catch, and that was catch-22." </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>leapinglemur</user>
	<review>If you haven't noticed catch-22 elements in life and the world around you, you haven't been paying attention.  My favorite is Major Major who will only meet with you when he is not in his office and will go so far as to jump out the window rather than make contact with anyone. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>donttalktofreaks</user>
	<review>Surprisingly, this is one of my favorite books.  I love Yossarian and his sense of self.  A must read for anyone. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0684833395</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>shieldsk1</user>
	<review>One of the best books I ever read. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>