<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Schmerguls</user>
	<review>This is a dark and somber novel, sometimes held to be comparable to The Naked and the Dead or A Farewell to Arms.  Some of the action is highly dramatic and well-written.  But one does weary of the fact that no expletive is undeleted--surely so boring as to wean anybody off the tiresome crude laguage, one would think.  While there certainly is high drama and excitement I cannot compare it to a book like All Quiet on the Western Front. and whether anybody will read it in the years to come seems doubtfull.l  I prefer a little more idealism in fiction than this book exhibits. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>audiobookfans</user>
	<review>Matterhorn: A Novel of The Vietnam War will take you places you may not be prepared to go. From the very beginning you are dropped into the dense jungle of Vietnam to follow Lieutenant Waino Mellas of Bravo Company. Immediately you are combating immersion foot, jungle rot, dehydration, fatigue, tigers and leeches that rain down from above and quietly drink your blood.Matterhorn doesn’t just describe the Vietnam War it immerses you in it. It puts you on edge. You’ll feel your hea ...more Matterhorn: A Novel of The Vietnam War will take you places you may not be prepared to go. From the very beginning you are dropped into the dense jungle of Vietnam to follow Lieutenant Waino Mellas of Bravo Company. Immediately you are combating immersion foot, jungle rot, dehydration, fatigue, tigers and leeches that rain down from above and quietly drink your blood.Matterhorn doesn’t just describe the Vietnam War it immerses you in it. It puts you on edge. You’ll feel your heart rate accelerate as you walk point with Vancouver trying to avoid booby traps and detect ambushes in time to give yourself and your brothers time to take cover. Your stomach will cramp as the entire company conserves it’s meager rations in hopes of stretching them out long enough for the next resupply drop. You will understand their frustration as they realize that the position that they have fought and died for will simply be abandoned. You will feel their fear, you will know their pride and you will experience the grind it out guts and perseverance that holds Bravo Company together.Politics, racism and ambition may seem to get in the way of everything while Bravo Company is at base camp, but all these problems melt away when the point man drops to a crouch and raises his fist.Matterhorn masterfully illustrates the brutality, horror and futility of war.Narration: Matterhorn is a great novel right out of the box. That being said, the narration provided by Bronson Pinchot makes it one of the most memorable audiobook experiences I have ever had. Excellent job! His depiction of Lieutenant Colonel Simpson was particularly entertaining. I loved hearing his voice because Bronson nailed him but man I hated that guy so much!Side Note: I’m guessing that Bronson has never used the word “F#k” as many times in any other performanceOverall: Few books have impacted me as emotionally as Matterhorn. After listening to it I felt like I had gone AWOL and left Bravo company “in the shit”. I felt guilty that while these kids were fighting for our country and starving out in the bush I could just hit pause and go grab a cold diet coke and a bag of chips.It’s really hard to distance yourself from the characters you meet in Matterhorn. Even though this is a work of fiction you get the sense that this fictional depiction is as close to real life as possible. It’s easy to believe that situations exactly like these played out every day during the war. So when a member of Bravo Company is killed it is easy to imagine that you know that young man. It’s hard not to mourn for him and the other 58,267 American men who died in service during the Vietnam War.Matterhorn is a unique experience. Listen to it if at all possible (I am not joking about the audio production.. it is great). If you can’t or don’t want to listen to it then read it. You won’t regret it.Highly recommendedThis review originally appeared on our website at www.audiobookfans.comDisclosure: I received a copy of this audiobook for review from the publisher </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jhowell</user>
	<review>I still cannot figure out why a pacifist non-military type female like myself likes war novels - but I do. I have actually not read much about the Vietnam War so this was enlightening, as well as gripping.  This is the transformation of Lieutenant Mellas - an Ivy-League educated green officer lately landed in the bush - and scared out of his mind, yet still constantly thinking about advancing his career. By the end of the novel, he is a combat and jungle veteran having endured discomfort, hunger, horror, fear, self-doubt, self-loathing, exhilaration, love and hate. And we endure it right along with Mellas and the rest of Bravo company--pissed off at the injustice, insanity, and waste of war, run by men whose lives are not in jeopardy.Some parts, the endless marches, patrols in the jungle and the combat on Matterhorn were phenomenally done. Outside the arena of Vietnam proper, for eg. the scences on the hospital ship, or even alot of the racial imbroglio were not as convincing, but overall quite well-written. I thought much of Mellas' inner thoughts were especially poignant, I suspect because much of it truly was from the heart and mind of the author as the character perhaps was a bit autobiographical.Definately recommended for war historical fiction lovers - the jargon wasn't too bad and there is a glossary at the end. Well-done - I think an important book in light of current dragging political foreign wars. We surely cannot blame the soldiers. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TerriBooks</user>
	<review>This book begins with the arrival of Lt. Mellas in Vietnam, sent immediately to join Bravo Company in "the bush". The enemy is not as much the North Vietnamese as it is the jungle with its leeches, tigers, and jungle rot, and the officers back at headquarters tainted with ambition, pride, and by seeing the men as statistics rather than humans. The most humor in the book comes from the inflation of the body count; how one North Vietnamese possibly killed becomes four confirmed and 2 possible. And I'm not sure this was even intended to be humor. As you accompany Bravo Company, each of the men become individuals - guys you hope survive the chaos and horror of their experience. It's a page-turner as you just need to see who survives and what happens to them next. The irony is that, when Lt Mellas arrives, he can't remember all the names, but by the end of the book so few of them are left to know. This novel is not for anyone weak of stomach or sensitive to four-letter words. I was constantly confused by the military language, concepts and short-hand. But once I stuck out my initial distaste and disorientation, I didn't want to leave these guys. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Kinch</user>
	<review>By all criteria, the best Vietnam novel I've read to date.  I doubt a better one will come along. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>keninipswich</user>
	<review>Right up there with A Rumor of War as one of the best Vietnam soldier stories. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>repb</user>
	<review>A fascinating, hard to read and occasionally hard to believe account of the realities and complexities of war. Tough language was hard to handle, but necessary in this case. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TimBazzett</user>
	<review>This book is already getting a storm of media attention, mostly very favorable, so whatever I have to say will probably be somewhat redundant and won't matter much. But a book like Matterhorn DOES matter, and a helluva lot too! While the Vietnam war may have ended 35 years ago, its afereffects continue to resonate. And it seems even more relevant today with the U.S. embroiled in yet two more unwinnable wars - wars which go on and on with no end in sight. Why the hell can't America learn anything from history?!In the early parts of the book, I thought Marlantes had bitten off more than he could chew, because he continues to introduce more and more characters, both men and officers, dozens of names. I struggled to try to keep them all straight - who was in which platoon and which officer was in charge? And the plethora of details and description - of the mud and blood and pus and sores and leeches etc. - threatened to literally drown the book in a sea of misery. And this was mostly without ever making contact with the nearly invisible enemy, the NVA or Viet Cong. But I stuck with it, and it all began to gradually make sense - or, perhaps better, the NONsense that is war. About three hundred pages in, Bravo Company finally made bloody contact with that elusive enemy and everything heated up and the narrative literally began to race along. The misery intensified and the wounded and dead began to pile up. Many of the those characters I'd struggled to keep straight simply fell away as casualties, and the circumstances of each was often enough to make you cry. One scene in particular, after a bloody offensive over one more mountain top, really hit home, as Marlantes noted in terse terms how everybody loses in this kind of a battle or war."The day was spent in weary stupefaction, hauling dead American teenagers to a stack beside the landing zone and dead Vietnamese teenagers to the garbage pit down the side of the north face."Scenes of young men, many of them former altar boys (and not so long ago either), reduced to savagery and despair are enough to break your heart and there are many such scenes here. Marlantes is a master storyteller. The stories here, unfortunately, are mostly horror stories, interspersed only rarely with moments of humor, but laced throughout with deeply felt feelings of brotherhood and humanity.Matterhorn, while it is a uniquely special book, and one that obviously cried to be written, made up of feelings and memories that undoubtedly had haunted the author for over thirty years, brought to mind other stories of that awful war, some true, some fictional. I thought of The Thirteenth Valley by John DelVecchio, another fat novel of Vietnam, as well as one of the very first Vietnam War novels, William Pelfrey's The Big V. The latter novel is long out of print, but strongly deserves another look, as it bore strong similarities to another classic novel of war, The Red Badge of Courage. On the memoir side of the street, Robert Mason's Chickenhawk and Frederick Downs' The Killing Zone come to mind. The fact is there have been dozens, scores of books to come out of the Vietnam war in the past forty years. The fact that Karl Marlantes' new novel is getting so much attention as such a late entry is a testament to its power and eloquence. This is not just a book about the mess that was Vietnam. This is a book about the folly that is war. I will recommend Matterhorn highly. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mckall08</user>
	<review>I'm not a fan of Viet Nam Fiction.  But this reads like non-fiction.  Karl Marlantes, a highly decorated Marine took thirty years to write this book.  It tracks Melias, a 2nd Lieutenant squad leader.   We follow Melias through a series of missions of dubious value, intent, and mostly futile outcomes.  It doesn't take long for these Marines to realize they are pawns in a game of body counts, cover-your-ass, and command politics.  In spite of this, they soldier on with a  sense of mission, pride, and mostly, the love of their fellow marines.  The brilliant trick is that Karl Marlantes makes us care just as the soldiers he depicts care.  Included is an extensive glossary with common and not so common Viet Nam and other military acronyms and slang. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jmchshannon</user>
	<review>Matterhorn: A Novel of the Vietnam War is hands-down the best book I've read/experienced this year. Mr. Marlantes not only explores a realistic portrayal of life as a Marine during the Vietnam War, he expands into human nature, the idea of relationships, and how ambition and race can impact them.Through his cast of characters, their experiences, and their growth over a short period of time, Mr. Marlantes hints at questions that everyone should consider prior to committing to future wars. War is indeed hell, but who exactly does it impact/affect the most? For the Vietnam War, who exactly was the enemy? Was it truly the North Vietnamese Army, the politicians in Washington, rear command? Should we not figure this out before committing ourselves and our soldiers?Mr. Marlantes is not afraid to present the truth in all its horror. More importantly, he forces us to evaluate the idea of ambition versus heart - something to which even a reader in high school and college can relate. Should we let ambition rule our decisions, or is heart more important? Is there room for both in our life/careers? Much like the battles and situations faced by the Marines, the answers to these questions are not easy but need to be addressed if one hopes to grow as a person, just as Mellas has to address.What made this audio book so special was the narrator. Bronson Pinchot was fantastic. He inflected humor, respect, and emotion into each sentence. Each character not only has a unique voice, the personality shines through so clearly that the listener will always know which character is speaking through just a few words. The narration contributed greatly to my overall enjoyment of the novel and the fact that I had such a visceral reaction to the story as it unfolded. I laughed out loud, cried, gasped in horror, grew angry, and listened nervously at different points in time, all while at work. (My co-workers thought I was crazy.) It takes a lot to get me to react so violently to a book; the fact that I repeatedly reacted to it is a testament to not only the narration, but to Mr. Marlantes' ability to tell a vivid story.I will confess that part of my reaction is that my experiences as an Army wife helped me to be able to understand the acronyms, the organization, and life in the military. Indeed, I felt like I was living back in Germany, listening to my husband and friends share their anecdotes about their jobs and experiences as young lieutenants and captains in the Army. Mr. Marlantes is a veteran himself, and his first-hand knowledge of military life displays itself in the idiosyncrasies and the bureaucracy of the military. There is a timelessness behind these details that will make  Matterhorn: A Novel of the Vietnam War relevant for decades to come.I have been recommended Matterhorn: A Novel of the Vietnam War to anyone who will listen. It is an amazing novel, and all of my raving is not going to do justice to this historical novel. This is one of those stories people will have to experience for themselves. I sincerely hope you do. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>creighley</user>
	<review>The reality of war is shown here.  Gripping, hard to take...When starting out, I wasn't sure I could or would read this.  It captures you.  You want those young men OUT! </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SwampIrish</user>
	<review>I ran into a guy in Barnes  Noble the other day who was walking to the checkout with this book in his hand. I commented to him that I was reading this book on my Kindle and he said "I heard it was the best novel of all time". Well, depending on his reading list, he may be disappointed. Hyperbole aside, this was an excellent war novel with appropriate levels of gore and profanity. Most of the action happens in the bush and after you complete this novel, I suspect you will at least have an idea of what that experience was like. Disease, starvation, fear, and death are all prevalent. Add in a little post-civil rights racism in the mix and you will know what happened on the other side of the pacific when all of those pothead hippies were being persecuted by the same government who were humping our soldiers to death in the bush. I also like the way the author incorporates the lingo of the Marines. It gives the reader a ground level immersion in the action when the FAC calls in fire or Big John Six gives a frag order. You feel like a silent participant. Excellent read, but sadly not the best novel ever written. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>santhony</user>
	<review>I’ve read several novels focused on the Vietnam War from the viewpoint of the ground level troops, and have generally enjoyed them all.  I would say that they were, as a whole, very similar and hard to differentiate.  Despite the near unanimous five star reviews posted for this work, I cannot honestly say that it was any better than the other works I’ve encountered in the genre.Many times, reviewers decry the presence of stereotypes, however some works cannot avoid stereotypical protagonists for the very reason that stereotypes are developed for a reason; their near universal pervasiveness.  For example, how can you tell the story of a Vietnam combat platoon without the hard edged, “lifer” gunny sergeant; or the radical Black Panther fomenting discontent among the Black troops; or the fresh meat, callow Lieutenant; or the clueless, mid-level officers more interested in body counts and meaningless objectives than the welfare of their troops?This story contains all of those, but then again, so has every other novel that I’ve read in the genre.  And, to be honest, much of the dialog came across as a little forced and, at times, silly.  I’m certainly not going to argue that the story and the events are not believable or realistic.  The author was there, and he’s amply supported by other veterans with first hand experience.  There were a few very interesting occurrences that lent some originality to the work, but by and large, it was the same lingo, the same internal and external stresses and fractures, and the same micro and macro backdrops.  Bottom line, I found it no better or worse than several others I’ve already experienced.  And as I’d experienced them previously, this effort seemed little more than a rehash of things I’d read and experienced before.  Had it been the first, I might have been more impressed. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Stevejm51</user>
	<review>I must add Karl Marlantes to my list of favorite authors of the Vietnam War.  Not only does he immerse the reader in the war, but he wonders why we were there.  One character wonders, "If we're fighting communism, why aren't we invading Hanoi?" </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>USD-U.Libraries</user>
	<review>http://bit.ly/cmBzlTLink to title in USD Library catalog.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>NAFR</user>
	<review>570 pages go by quickly: vivid account, doesn't read like fiction </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bobbieharv</user>
	<review>A stunning book. Deceptively unadorned prose that guides the reader into the story that then builds and builds exposing the tragedy that was that war, that destroyed all those young lives and the psyches of those who survived. One of the most poignant passages just sticks in my head - after the platoon has gone a week without food and hardly any water, they're scaling a cliff, tears running down their faces, "like children who needed to be fed and tucked into bed."One of the finest books I think I've ever read. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Narboink</user>
	<review>“Matterhorn” is, in many ways, a familiar account of combat conditions in the Vietnam War: it’s a ‘total immersion’ experience of jungle rot, military jargon, and blood-and-guts moxie that cinema (most particularly) has made de rigueur in ‘Nam narratives over the past 40 years.  Told in a straightforward and unadorned way, it nonetheless manages to overcome the natural hurdles such familiarity can engender and to captivate the reader’s attention with surprising force.  Karl Marlantes has given us a story with a mature and insightful understanding of both the power and limitations of sentimentalism with respect to war, honor and even politics.  This is a simply written book about average people that is also a remarkable book about exceptional people. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RichardWise</user>
	<review>A wonderfully vivid depiction of the horrors of Vietnam. The main protagonist, a boot Marine 2nd lieutenant, is torn between fear and ambition, but is soon beat down by the physical and emotional demands of small company hand to hand combat. The characters he meets, the changes brought about in them and in him by the realities of an extreme situation make this a study in the human psyche pushed to its limits and beyond.Matterhorn, is a fire base, a ridge among several where guns ...more A wonderfully vivid depiction of the horrors of Vietnam. The main protagonist, a boot Marine 2nd lieutenant, is torn between fear and ambition, but is soon beat down by the physical and emotional demands of small company hand to hand combat. The characters he meets, the changes brought about in them and in him by the realities of an extreme situation make this a study in the human psyche pushed to its limits and beyond.Matterhorn, is a fire base, a ridge among several where guns are emplaced to support the activities of ground troops. Defended to the death one day, abandoned the next, as the tactical situation changes.The North Vietnamese are depicted as they were, tough, battle hardened, fierce fighters who often bested the marines with far less by way of equipment and logistical support. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wanack</user>
	<review>This novel about a Marine company in Vietnam is quite well done and certainly written by someone who knows what he's talking about. I've read that the original manuscript was 1,200 pages long, which got cut down to 570 or so, but it probably could usefully have lost another 100 at various points. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>hanque</user>
	<review>This is a book for guys.  It's about a company of marines in the Vietnam war.  The main character is Lt Mellas, a replacement platoon officer in Bravo Company.  His platoon and the rest of the company are holding on to a mountain called Matterhorn near the North Vietnam border.  Over the course of two months, the company is almost constantly on the mountain or in the jungles searching for North Vietnam Army units.  They stumble onto the fact that the North Vietnam Army has three regiments in the area and are staging a massive attack.  The company is then used as bait to hold up the enemy advance while the rest of the marine division deploys to trap the NVA.This is great adventure story although some of the characters seem to be too familiar, such as the alcoholic battalion commander. Four out of five stars </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>RSFox</user>
	<review>Many great works of fiction have come out of the tragedy of war. The Red Badge of Courage from the Civil War.  All Quiet on the Western Front from WW1.  The Thin Red Line and Naked and the Dead from WW2.  To name only a few.  While there have been a few very good books about the Vietnam war, none has even approximated the level of literary significance of those mentioned... until now.  Matterhorn by Karl Marlantes so thoroughly captures that visceral experience of  the average infantry men, in this case, Marines, that you find yourself feel the wet of the monsoons, the grime, the leeches, and the constant sweat of fear and exhilaration of this moral meat-grinder of a war.This is book make compelling and thoughtful reading as we slog through both the stifling bush and the disconnected bureaucratic, and often contradictory, decisions of the war.Here's a book that packs a greater cinematic wallop that the famous film, Platoon, by Oliver Stone.  This books deserves to take its place among those masterpieces of fiction forge in the crucible of war. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Stbalbach</user>
	<review>In 2009, nearly 40 years after the Vietnam War, Marine veteran Karl Marlantes published his first novel, Matterhorn. He worked on it for over 35 years, starting soon after coming home from the war. He wanted to show what it was really like fighting in the bush, and probably has done more in that regard than any other Vietnam novel to date. It's a long historical novel, the kind with detailed maps, a unit org chart, dozens of named characters, and a lengthy glossary of over 100 esoteric terms about Vietnam War culture. It's an adrenaline filled novel, reviewer Sebastian Junger (of The Perfect Storm) said Matterhorn is "not a book so much as a deployment, and you will not return unaltered."Racial tensions make up a big portion of the story, most Vietnam books/movies skim over this, not so in Matterhorn where about half the characters are black, an accurate reflection of the make-up of the Corp at the time. Race was just one of many aspects of the war. Vietnam was complex and has been resistant to realistic representation because there were so many fronts. On the surface it was America versus North Vietnam, but as many historians have said, it was as much a civil-war in America playing out in the jungles of South East Asia. Racial conflicts, sexual liberation, class warfare, generational warfare, drugs, music and counter-culture. O'Brien in The Things They Carried dealt with the surreality of Vietnam by using post-modernist techniques. More traditional narratives either work as non-fiction memoir, or come across sounding like WWII in the jungle. Marlantes has cracked the code in Matterhorn and written an entertaining, accessible and realistic work in the grand old tradition of realism that captures the many conflicts and difficulties of the war. Like Gone With the Wind, Matterhorn will probably be more of a popular culture achievement, not a literary one; it's already a New York Times Bestseller. But it may yet win some awards, Marlantes really does deserve credit for bringing a deeper understanding. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>HarvReviewer</user>
	<review>http://bookreporter.com/reviews2/9780... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>seaclifflibrary</user>
	<review>A very brutal accounting of the Vietnam War and war in general.  With painstaking detail, the author places the reader with a company of young Marines.  We see them building bunkers on a hilltop named Matterhorn only to be told they need to abandon it to go on a mission fraught with danger near the border of Laos.  In command of this platoon is Waino Mellas, an Ivy League educated officer who joined the military out of patriotism and ambition.  Readers get to experience the subtle changes in Mellas as the mission advances and we are also changed. The author presents the camaraderie and the nuanced and sometimes overt racism of the troops vividly.  This is a hard book to read but one that should be  widely read. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>VisibleGhost</user>
	<review>There have been scores of fiction books written about the US/Vietnam War. It is not unexplored territory. Matterhorn still manages to say some important things about the war. The focus is on a Marine company. It covers a period of around three months in 1969. The Marines in Bravo Company go through one 'shit sandwich' after another during this time. It captures the exhaustion of this period well. It exhausts the reader. Angers the reader. Makes the reader understand the 'bush'.Race relations that are teetering on the edge are explored. The horrors of war are vivid and presented matter of factly. Tensions in the chain of command are rendered from several viewpoints. The fighting spirit and camaraderie, including the love of fighting, is not left out. Respect and admiration of the enemy along with hating them is brought out. The political maneuvers down to the battlefield level results in frustration and anger up and down the lines. Territory loses its importance and the war becomes a war of numbers. Killed, wounded, and probables. An area is taken, then, abandoned, then retaken again. It becomes maddening for all involved. There is a lot of slang, jargon and technical terms but there is a glossary to guide through its use. Marlantes spent thirty years working on the book while pursuing a career. The effort paid off in a well written book that conveys the suffering, doggedness, emotions, despair, tragedies, and a time that is now firmly in the past in a near perfect rendition. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>080211928X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>SamSattler</user>
	<review>"Matterhorn," a first novel by Vietnam veteran Karl Marlantes, was some thirty years in the making and it was only published after Marlantes cut about 1,000 pages from his original manuscript. Despite the cuts, the book still comes in at close to 600 pages in length and it tells a story that will be stuck in the minds of its readers long after they have turned the final page. This one, too, is a reminder that the written word almost always tells a story more powerfully than the same story can be told on film. The life expectancy of newly minted second lieutenants dropped into the heat of the Viet Nam War was not a long one. Marine Lieutenant Waino Mellas, a young officer with dreams of wartime glory he could later parlay into a nice stateside career, was one of those men. "Matterhorn," written in the third person, focuses on what happens to Mellas during his first two months in the country. It can be seen as a coming of age story of sorts, an experience shared by the thousands of young men ("kids," as Marlantes refers to them) who were forced to scramble for their lives in the jungles of Vietnam. Lieutenant Mellas finds that all of his training has done little to prepare him for what he experiences leading a small group of men deep into the bush in search of hidden weapons and enemy soldiers. The old adage that "experience is the best teacher" makes perfect sense to him; he only hopes that he will live long enough to gain that experience. In two months, by the end of "Matterhorn," Mellas will be much wiser about the ways of war and the nature of those who fight it - and, just as importantly, he will be wiser about the nature of those who call the shots from the safety of their desks. Most of the novel's action takes place on, or around, a strategically well-located hill the marines have dubbed Matterhorn. Initially, the men work themselves to the point of exhaustion digging bunkers, patrolling the surrounding jungle, and otherwise transforming the hill into a suitable base for American artillery. To the company's dismay, changes in strategy soon result in the whole area being abandoned to the North Vietnam regulars who are happy to claim the fortified hill for their own purposes. Predictably, for a war in which victories are claimed by winning the "body count," the company is ordered to retake the hill because battalion commanders see the large number of enemy soldiers atop the hill as a prize not to be ignored. "Matterhorn" is not easy reading for those who lived through this period in American history. It is a stark reminder of how difficult this political war was on the soldiers having to fight it. These young men had to fight more than the enemy. They endured torrential monsoons, snakes, leeches, malnourishment, jungle rot and exposure to chemicals like the now infamous Agent Orange. They prayed for heavy fogs to lift long enough for helicopters to evacuate the wounded and to resupply the rest of them with food, water and ammunition. And tragically, they faced a black power movement within the ranks that sometimes ended in murder by hand grenade. Karl Marlantes vividly brings this 40-year-old war back to life, a war filled with lessons about how not to fight our next one. My only quarrel with the novel is the pace of its ending. What happens in the book's final three pages happens at such an abrupt quickening of pace that its impact is lessoned, and some readers will find themselves questioning whether a company commander would react to the book's climax the way Lieutenant Mellas reacts. Personally, I found the lieutenant's reaction to be not so much out of character as unrealistic. Rated at: 4.5 </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>