<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0812976533</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mr.Livingstone</user>
	<review>Una volta qualcuno, non ricordo chi, a proposito di un romanzo disse "Mio Dio, ma c'è un uomo qui dentro." A proposito di Midnight's Children, l'unica cosa che mi viene in mente è "Mio Dio, c'è una nazione qui dentro!"</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0812976533</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Gualtiero</user>
	<review>un'opera stronza e sfacciata, una continua profusione di stereotipi da soap-operas e da melodrammoni ottocenteschi (o bollywoodiani) cucinati e triturati con maliziossisima quanto esibita finta innocenza post-moderna. L'armamentario d'intreccio e di stile è vasto e rutilante (scambio di culle, guerra, amori impossibili/non consumati, matrimoni imposti, scene di varia umanità e storicità indiana per quanto riguarda l'intreccio; realismo magico, io narrante non affidabile, meccanismi scoperti e meta-disquisiti (letteralmente roba del tipo: "Ehi, guardate che quest'oggetto appena citato è un simbolo! E adesso ve lo spiego per bene, o almeno ve lo faccio credere!") sul versante dello stile), tanto che alla fine quello che stupisce è il fatto che il romanzo non provochi irritazione, ma divertito coinvolgimento.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0812976533</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Rpcutts</user>
	<review>I am not enjoying reading this book. I think I like the story that he is telling but I wish he would tell it. I don't like his style and I am often thrown by his way of setting the scene, it often takes me a whole page to figure out what is happening then once I figure out what's going on I have to re-read it with my new found enlightenment. I have finished part one and got a few pages into part two but by this point it has become to much of a chore to read. I may revisit this later but for now, I've had enough.</review>
	<rating>0</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0812976533</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Mawy3</user>
	<review>This is a five-star book. More than Rushdie at his finest, it's Literature at its finest.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
	<isbn>0812976533</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ambient pleasures</user>
	<review>The Booker of Booker Prize winners. Best novel in 25 years. Midnight's Children is Rushdie at his finest. The book is surrealist fiction that deals with the history of India from 1910 to the declaration of the emergency in 1976 through the eyes (and nose) of Saleem Sinai, born on the stroke of Midnight August 15, 1947. Midnight's Children, like most of Rushdie's writing, does have political overtones, yet the fog of larger events is never permitted to detract from the more personal experiences of all the multi-faceted characters in the novel.</review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>1</minrating>
	<maxrating>4</maxrating>
	<imgrating></imgrating>
</result>