<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>A Costumer</user>
	<review>

When District Attorney Tom Sneddon smugly announced that Michael Jackson was to be criminally charged, and that Neverland was being raided, he was so blinded by greed, jealousy and vengeance that he could not see that the degenerate family he had sided with, the Arvizo family, in order to try and take Michael Jackson's freedom from him, and ruin his reputation, all so that Sneddon could bask in glory, would actually bring Sneddon the ultimate humiliation.  Sneddon's case against Michael Jackson was built on lies, and was created by liars, and Sneddon got exactly what he deserved, failure!!!When Michael Jackson was put on trial, accused of having molested Gavin Arvizo -- who had learnt from his family how to extort people -- the media refused to tell the truth.  The media refused to acknowledge, or discuss, what was actually going on in the courtroom that was favorable to Michael Jackson.  The testimony that pointed to Michael Jackson's innocence, the success Michael Jackson's attorneys had in exposing the prosecution case for what it was, sham, was ignored by the media, the media refused to tell the truth.When prosecution witnesses who desired to fill their pockets with Michael Jackson's money, who hoped to become rich by selling false stories, who falsely accused Michael Jackson, and who made up as many lies as possible, as horrible as possible, to extort as much money as possible from Michael Jackson, were exposed, it was ignored by the media, the media refused to tell the truth.  When the accuser, Gavin Arvizo, and his family, mother Janet Arvizo, and siblings Star Arvizo and Davellin Arvizo, stumbled over their lies, contradicted themselves continually, became argumentative when presented with facts that proved they were liars and extortionists, it was ignored by the media, the media refused to tell the truth.When Michael Jackson's young cousin testified that the accuser, Gavin Arvizo, and Gavin's brother Star tried to get him to masturbate in their presence, it was ignored by the media, the media refused to tell the truth. When it was revealed that Michael Jackson's former employees only claimed to have seen inappropriate behavior by Michael Jackson AFTER THEY WERE OFFERED MONEY AND PAID BY TABLOIDS/THE MEDIA, it was ignored by the media, the media refused to tell the truth. (Michael Jackson successfully sued these former employees many years ago, they still owe him money.)When Michael Jackson's current employees testified that the accuser, Gavin Arvizo, and his family slept in guesthouses at Neverland (and not in Michael Jackson's bedroom), that they caused a great deal of trouble at Neverland, left a huge mess at Neverland, damaged and defaced property at Neverland, attacked the animals at Neverland, pulled knives on Neverland employees, stole from Neverland employees, stole from Michael Jackson, extorted Neverland employees by lying about their financial circumstances, extorted the government by lying about their financial circumstances, extorted other celebrities by lying to them and falsely accusing them, caused trouble wherever they went, and to whoever was unlucky enough to befriend them, overall having been shown to be users, liars, thieves, troublemakers and criminals, it was ignored by the media, the media refused to tell the truth..... until now.Aphrodite Jones, a reporter, ashamed of her behavior during Michael Jackson's trial, having realized that she was wrong, has written this book - "Michael  Jackson Conspiracy" - which is pretty much a compact version of Michael Jackson's trial. It details exactly what happened in the courtroom at Michael Jackson's trial (using actual trial testimony), the facts that were revealed and exposed, the witnesses and what they stated, how Michael Jackson's defense team managed to successfully destroy prosecution theories and witnesses on a daily basis, how the media did not want to report anything that was favorable to Michael Jackson or his defense team, how some media reporters had already secured deals to have access to Michael Jackson if he was to be found guilty and imprisoned (which is disgusting, because this behavior implies that these jerks preferred that a child had been molested so that they could profit), and how Michael Jackson was found NOT GUILTY by a jury that saw right through the lies, right through the Arvizo family, right through District Attorney Tom Sneddon and his sham case, and right through the media garbage that has been circulating for years about Michael Jackson.  So, if you want the truth about Michael Jackson, how he has become a target for liars who want to become instant millionaires, and the victim of a media that promotes and prefers lies, read "Michael Jackson Conspiracy".
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>F. Malik "The Faze"</user>
	<review>

During Michael Jackson's trial in 2005, the media did not report anything positive about Michael and were completely unfavorable toward him. For them, reporting anything negative and salacious was the way to go in order to sell their stories, and in return, gain viewers, readers, and more advertising dollars.Fortunately for Michael, the jury was forced to listen to the facts of the case, not the biased media coverage.  Aphrodite Jones has done a wonderful job of focusing almost solely on the facts of the case and the testimony and evidence presented during the trial.  It is because of those reasons that the book is highly riveting and eye-opening.  All of her trial quotes are taken from court transcripts, and give the reader a "fly on the wall" approach, as if the trial was being relived.  As a person who attended the trial whenever I possibly could, Ms. Jones' account of the proceedings are spot-on, and she should be commended for presenting the trial in a fair and objective manner.The vast majority of the public was misled by a biased media, and I highly recommend that this is THE book to read to gain true insight into not only the trial, but what went on around Michael Jackson before and during the trial.  I think many people would be shocked to discover how badly the accuser and his family were caught in so many lies and contradictions.  Simply put, the prosecution had no case whatsoever, and this is the ONLY conclusion anyone can come to after reading this book.Thank you Ms. Jones, for laying it all out for the world to see.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>W. Duran "fight for fair journalism, tired of...</user>
	<review>

Anyone who is anyone should read this book! It clearly describes all the details that were left out of the popular news media during the trial of Michael Jackson. It also shows how people conspire together for their own profit, even if it means destroying someone else. So many people stood to make so much money if this man had been convicted, so they convicted him in the court of public oopinion.  As a nation, we have become obsessed with celebrity gossip and propaganda, and more and more that is what is being reported, NOT THE FACTS! What happened to true journalism, showing all the necessary information so that we could decide for ourselves? I for one find it offensive, it is as if they are saying that the general public are not intelligent enough to decide for themselves, and that we are dumb enough to believe whatever they tell us! Also, with this trial the media is publicly implying that they feel our justice system FAILED! If you believe that, why wouldnt you fight to do something about it? If I truly believed that a jury was wrong, or paid off, or had some benefit in making a certian decision, I would call it a mistrial! Aphrodite, who was once reporting negative news during the trial, has seen the error of her ways. She reviewed all the court transcripts and documents and realized she was wrong. In this book she gives all the facts you never heard anywhere else. No one even wanted to publish it because they said people would only read smut, not something like this that was to the point and fair. Which, led her to publish it all on her own. She felt it was important that people hear all the facts, not only the smut that they have heard a million times. She took the high road and didnt even mention the many things such as race that others had previously mentioned. I think if you are interested in facts and true journalism, this book is for you. And if not, I think you should read it to prepare and protect yourself from the world we really live in where greed, money and lies are often in control! If it can happen to him, it can happen to anyone!
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Jude "rolling stock"</user>
	<review>

This is a fascinating read, not just because of its subject matter but because the author herself was, like most other members of the media, predisposed to think that Jackson was guilty of at least some of the charges brought against him. She admits to being prejudiced and reveals just how she came to realise that this time the media got it very wrong indeed. Ms Jones has thoroughly researched the book examining witnesses' testimonies, court transcripts, etc, and she reveals how the jury, onlookers and Jackson himself reacted throughout. Yes, you do feel that you are in the courtroom. The disparity between what actually went on in there and what the media reported is astonishing. And there's some interesting information about British journalist/interviewer Martin Bashir too. The background information about Neverland itself was all new to me. For example, it is only through reading this book that I realised that Michael Jackson's bedroom was not at all like the type of bedroom most of us have, i.e, just one room. Jackson's was a huge two storey, mezzanine construction - more like a flat than a room. I'm not saying Jackson was wise to have boys staying in his room (nor in his bed) but once you realise just how big this space was it kind puts a different perspective on these sleepovers. Aphrodite Jones also reveals that Jackson himself was not at Neverland for much of the time; it was his home but it was more a social experiment, an escape for children who were sick or poor. It's such a shame it didn't work out. If he had lived elsewhere but just run the place as a separate entity/charity things might have turned out differently. Or if only he'd only have stuck to surrounding himself with animals rather than other peoples' children he'd be viewed by the majority as eccentric rather than potentially dangerous or evil. I found the photographs of Neverland are startling. Everywhere is so cluttered - like a teenage boy's room. In fact, Jackson comes across as naive, vulnerable, lonely, somewhat deluded and while extraordianrily generous, lacking in emotional intelligence and 'street' savvy when it came to handling people who had their own agendas. My only criticisms of the book are that Ms Jones' text concentrates on peoples' appearances a little too much; I felt she almost implied that when it xcame to witnesses beauty equals truth. I'd have welcomed more indepth analysis by Aphrodite Jones on the whole affair and its aftermath. But a brave book. Buy it! 
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Edwin Lindholm</user>
	<review>

Michael Jackson Conspiracy is a great book for anyone who wants to know what actually happened before and during the Michael Jackson trial. 
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Barbara A. Chauvin "DrC"</user>
	<review>

Having followed the trial closely as it unfolded, I learned quickly that I could not depend on the media for an accurate view of what happened.  I was hearing totally different accounts from the news than I was hearing from acquaintences of mine who had been in the courtroom.  So I relied upon the published trial transcripts for all my information.  Because of this, there were no real surprises for me when I read this book.However, for those who did not seek out the truth on their own, there will be lots of surprises.  Jones has it right when she says that a majority of the media reporting from Santa Maria were either too caught up in the feeding frenzy, or to afraid to buck the system, to report on this event with accuracy or fairness.Jones has taken care to do so in this book, and I am glad that there is documentation of what really happened - documentation that is an interesting and readable form and readily available to any interested party to read.  Jones writing style is engaging and her reliance upon actually trial transcripts helps to bring the story to life while it remains a testament to the truth.If the media had reported this trial in a more objective way, there would have been no surprises when 14 not guilty verdicts were read out in that courtroom.  Instead we must depend upon an alternate source, rather than the very industry that has the resources and the power to keep us informed.  If the media had done its job, people would have been able to ask the big question:  Why was this case ever prosecuted?  Thank you, Ms. Jones, for doing their job for them.    
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mystery448</user>
	<review>

This isn't just another book to just to make some money of Jackson. No this is one serious piece of work. Ms. Jones gives you a brief synopsis of what you "didn't" really hear or see.How the media spun the truth of Jackson's dilemma for ratings, sensationalizing stories, and in the court of public opinion, Jackson had already been found guilty. How an overzealous attorney allowed his judgments to seek out revenge on Jackson at any cost, even reaching for past allegations to rip Jackson's world apart forever.And an ungrateful street smart kid, who suffered from an unknown cancer, was almost at death's door entered Jackson's life.  Jackson offered in kindness his home and the best medical treatments to help him heal. One should have been truly grateful. Instead the young man sought revenge because the life he was getting adjusted to was now coming to an end. Payback was all he could think about.Twisted evil minds don't stop there; let's not forget the mother, who is the mastermind in all this...their mother who taught her children so well, to lie and other things...went after Jackson with a vengeance. Because of his kindness and being naïve and his eccentric ways, Jackson's world had been ripped apart. He was humiliated and scorned.  His private life no longer his, was viewed daily in court by reporters' from all over the world.Will this change the minds of those in the mainstream, no, will it make those who felt he was guilty then, believe now he was treated unfairly, no. Then again, if Ms. Jones could change, then maybe she can reach one or two people. If so then the book would have accomplished something.Conspiracy of Michael Jackson is a compelling read. And Aphrodite Jones is to be commended for being brave enough to take on such project.  
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Carol K. Urich</user>
	<review>

She takes you right into the courtroom day by day as if you're watching tom sneddon and tom mesereau cross-examining people on the stand.  She also shows michael as a very giving person going thru the most difficult obstacle of his life.  In no way is she disrepectful and in my opinion, provides a fair and balanced synopsis of the michael jackson trial.  I'm absolutely baffled at the disinterest by many of our u.s. media personalities like oprah and montel not giving ms. jones the opportunity to show the OTHER side.  The side of michael jackson whose not a child molestor and as a decent person.  She reveals many things not told to the american public regarding the neverland raids, the arvisos, the prosecutions mishandling of this case (inflammatory comments by sneddon given to media outlets), etc.  I highly recommend this book not just to fans, but ANYONE that wants to know more about the case and esp. the TRUTHFUL way michael jackson was being mistreated.  Both as a defendant and also as human being.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mistermaxxx@yahoo.com "mistermaxxx"</user>
	<review>

this Book is the truth and long overdue. Michael Jackson was being frammed and this was a rail-roaded case to try to take him down at alll costs. the family that pressed those trumped up charges against MJ were shady and up to no good from the word jump. the DA Sneddon wanted MJ at all costs and it wasn't about Justice but about Just icing Michael Jackson at any costs. Aphrodite Jones deserves Props for telling the truth since the Mass Media hasn't done what it is suppose to do. the truth came out and Michael Jackson never hide or ran from nothing despite all the daily hate and the fact that the Media was calling him out of his name,etc... they Owe the Brother a Big Apology and this Book sets the record straight. it's long overdue that Michael Jackson got some fiar balance. very detailed book. Props to Mezz for doing his job as a Lawyer in the case. 
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>0979549809</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>C. Clough</user>
	<review>

I trust this author. She went into the court room a full fledged believer in the accusations and left dumb found. A few years later wrote this book.  Mr. Jackson is an easy target for indictments. He wears more make-up than the Avon lady and he dresses like Captain Crunch. He is not your average "Joe".I don't know for sure that he didn't do these terrible things. Nobody does really except for him-- and of course the accusers.What I do know, is he has been very loving to those who know him well and to those who don't, and enormously generous giving over 300 million dollars to charities around the world.Lets face it your gonna believe what you wanna believe. But if you are really in search of the truth behind all the speculations and sensationalisms that have surrounded this famous case pick this up. My heart broke for him, and yours will too.
      </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
</result>