<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mykl-s</user>
	<review>Paradiso (Bantam Classics) by Dante Alighieri (1986) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raven_moon</user>
	<review>(Review is of the Penguin Classics translation by Mark Musa, and applies to all three volumes, Inferno, Purgatorio, and Paradisio) I would not think to quibble with reviewing Dante himself - Dante is a master, and doesn't need my endorsement. I will say, however, that Musa's translation is an exceptionally sensitive one, and his comprehensive notes are an invaluable aid to the reader less familiar with Dante's broad spheres of reference. Musa is clearly a devoted scholar of Dante, and his concern for Dante's original meaning and tone is evident. This is one of the best translations of The Comedia available. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Anagarika</user>
	<review>Part Three of one of the best stories of all-time. Top Ten in my favorite books. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Qorvus</user>
	<review>To be honest, this and Purgatory bored me to tears.  I cannot recall many details, other than I found the poetic translation to be clumsy and borderline insipid.   In retrospect, I would have rather have read a prose version. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cowpeace</user>
	<review>Blurp: In dit derde deel vindt het geheele Gedicht zijne voltooiing. Het is niet alleen het 'einde', dat men hier na lezing van het geheel, bereikt, maar de geheele compositie vindt hier hare bekroning. Eerst van dit einde uit kan men het geheel overzien, begrijpen en waarderen. In den laatsten zang van zijn Paradijs ziet de dichter God, en laat hij inderdaad den lezer God zien. Hiermede heeft Dante het hoogste bereikt, wat ooit door dichtkunst, godsdienst of philosophie is beöogd. Hierdoor is Danteé gedicht een blijvend bezit voor de menschheid van alle eeuwen; een blijvend bezit niet alleen van schoonheid, maar ook, maar vooral van waarheid (uit: Inleiding).Samenv.: Dante Alighieri's Goddelijke Comedie, daterend uit het begin van de 14de eeuw, is misschien de volmaaktste dichterlijke schepping uit de wereldliteratuur. In strenge verzen beschrijft dit middeleeuwse epos Dante's magische reis door Hel, Louteringsberg en Hemel. Waar Inferno politiek van thema was en Purgatorio persoonlijk, is Paradiso vooral theologisch. Dante voltooit zijn loutering door het ware geloof te accepteren, verbeeld door Beatrice. Dantes lichaam is tijdelijk ijl gemaakt door zijn tocht over de Louteringsberg, zodat hij vanaf het aards paradijs met Beatrice ten hemel kan stijgen. Hij passeert de dampkring en de "vuurkring", de schil van vuur die volgens Ptolemaeus de aarde omgeeft (canto 1-2). Buiten de vuurkring bevinden zich negen hemelkringen, elk bevolkt door een ander type engelen. Dit laatste idee is ontleend aan Pseudo-Dionysius' De coelesti hierarchia. In canto 3 stijgt Dante op naar de hemel van de maan, die bestierd wordt door "gewone" engelen, en ontmoet hij de eerste hemelbewoners (met uitzondering van Beatrice). In tegenstelling tot de zielen in de hel en op de louteringsberg hebben de hemelingen geen menselijke gedaante meer. Gewoonlijk verblijven zij allen in de hoogste hemel, maar ze dalen af om Dante onderweg te ontmoeten.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluedream</user>
	<review>This part works beautifully as a counterpart to the Inferno -- rrrrrrright up until the part where he decides that calling something indescribable is a substitute for descriptions.I mean, who does he think he is, Lovecraft? </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gaialover2</user>
	<review>The worst vision of Heaven ever. I have no idea what happened to Dante's imagination, but apparently it can't imagine happy things well at all. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BenjaminHahn</user>
	<review>Although, the weakest of the three, Paradiso is still quite amazing for its portrayal of heaven in all its layered complexity. Naturally it is not as vexing or interesting at Purgatorio or Hell but still interesting to see who Dante wanted to place there. Plus, the ending is just hilarious.  Again, this translation is great. The Hollander's have outdone themselves. I wonder what they do now. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>selfcallednowhere</user>
	<review>Eh, this book was the least interesting of [book: The Divine Comedy] to me. Like [book: Purgatorio], it had some beautiful imagery, but just got pretty boring. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siriaeve</user>
	<review>It's not that the Paradiso is any less well written than the Inferno or the Purgatorio: it is just a lot less engaging. Rather than taking on people and personalities, Dante gets bogged down in the complexities of medieval Christian theology, and it makes for very slow going. Plus, it reintroduces Beatrice, and few literary 'romances' creep me out more than the one Dante writes for himself with Beatrice. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jeanned</user>
	<review>The one where Beatrice gets brighter and brighter </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Poemblaze</user>
	<review>The least interesting of the three sections.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lriley</user>
	<review>Of the 3 parts this is the least interesting. I know Dante comes from the 13th and 14th centuries and this may seem unfair but it left me with visions of Mussolini styled fascist spectacles. Too overwrought and too syncophantic for my blood--what is left is Dante's talent and beautiful use of language which is something but going to Hell and Purgatory is a lot more worthwhile than going to Heaven in this case. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MareMagnum</user>
	<review>Il ParadisoNella terza cantica Dante è all'ultima fase del suo viaggio ultraterreno. Guidato non più da Virgilio ma da Beatrice, attraversa il Paradiso, cioè il luogo di beatitudine eterna per le anime giuste, sede di Dio e degli angeli. Ma il Paradiso per Dante non è solo un luogo: è anche l'insieme degli angeli e dei beati, è la stessa beatitudine celeste, stato di felicità, di completezza, di perfezione spirituale determinato dalla visione di Dio. Dunque l'allegoria del viaggio funziona qui solo in parte; la stessa struttura topografica del Paradiso è meno rigida e, in definitiva, meno importante di quella di Inferno e Purgatorio. Più che raccontare uno spostamento, Dante descrive piuttosto una serie di diversi scenari che appaiono nei nove cieli, un susseguirsi di visioni. Ecco dunque la poetica della luce attraversare tutta la cantica: luce come testimonianza di Dio, come sua emanazione (recepita più o meno fortemente secondo la vicinanza all'Empireo). Le figurazioni luminose, spesso simboliche, che Dante descrive fanno parte della tradizione artistica medievale e del pensiero mistico, per il quale la visione estatica è la più alta forma di conoscenza. Oltre che sull'apparizione di luci, la visione, imparentata per modi e forme col sogno, è basata sulla metamorfosi delle immagini. Così Dante, nelle visioni che rappresenta, mostra fiumi che diventano laghi, faville che diventano angeli, fiori che si trasformano in beati. Nel Paradiso Dante ha voluto rappresentare Dio, cioè qualcosa di non pensabile razionalmente, di non raccontabile. E si è affidato alle armi letterarie dei mistici, alla letteratura dell'ineffabile, dell'indicibile, sforzando al massimo le possibilità della mente di avere sensazioni. In questo ha dato vita alla sua cantica più ambiziosa, forse anche la più ardua, senz'altro il modello insuperato per ogni scrittura che voglia mostrare ciò che le parole non possono dire.Bandella bio-bibliografica Dante Alighieri nacque a Firenze nel 1265. Dopo gli studi umanistici a Firenze e Bologna prese parte alla vita politica della Repubblica, giungendo a ricoprire nel 1300 la carica di Priore. Ma l'anno seguente, mentre era a Roma come ambasciatore presso il papa, i suoi nemici fiorentini lo fecero condannare alla confisca dei beni e all'esilio perpetuo. Cominciò così la lunga serie di peregrinazioni e soggiorni nelle corti d'Italia, conclusasi soltanto nel 1318 a Ravenna, la città in cui decise di stabilirsi definitivamente con la sua famiglia, morendovi nel 1321. Oltre alla Divina commedia (1314 Inferno, 1315 Purgatorio, 1321 Paradiso) Dante compose la Vita nova (1294), diverse Rime (1298), i trattati De vulgari eloquentia (1307) e Convivio (1307), una serie di Epistole (1316), la Monarchia (1318), le Ecloghe a Giovanni del Virgilio (1319) e la Questio de acqua et terra (1329). </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AlexTheHunn</user>
	<review>The Divine Comedy epitomized medieval attitudes.  From historical perspectives, this work serves as a window into the mentality of late middle ages in Italy, on the brink of the Renaissance.  Scholastic thinking informs Dante's approach. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>8804546522</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dgrayson</user>
	<review>As I recall, this one kind of dragged.  Or maybe it got a bit too religious for me. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>