<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>boullenger</user>
	<review>Adeptes des livres soporifiques, s'abstenir ! "La Maison du sommeil" de Jonathan Coe est un livre qui vous empêche de dormir et qui ne vous fera plus jamais envisager le sommeil de la même façon ! En termes d'intrigue et de suspense, nous avons affaire à un maître, incontestablement. Les événements insolites qui se déroulent dans la demeure d'Ashdown, perchée non loin d'une falaise accidentée, tiennent savoureusement en haleine. On soupçonne un simple enchevêtrement d'histoires, saugrenues, de cœur ; mais le sommeil (et ce qu'il révèle), la confusion entre rêve et réalité, et aussi un mystérieux roman intitulé "La maison du sommeil" s'en mêlent et là, ça se corse…  "La maison du sommeil" a la trempe d'un roman-jeu, digne du mouvement Oulipo. Jeu littéraire, jeu tout court et pas de Je. Ce roman adopte en effet la narration à la troisième personne et réunit un certain nombre de personnages assez singuliers. Sarah la narcoleptique a tendance à tenir ses rêves pour plus vrais que la réalité. Gregory, le futur savant fou, le terrifiant Dr Dudden, prétend, par ses expériences étranges et interdites, effacer de votre existence le sommeil, cette maladie mortelle évitable qui nous fait perdre un tiers de notre temps. Robert, le fougueux va subir, par amour pour Sarah, une étrange métamorphose. Sans oublier Véronica, la sœur des Lesbos, lectrice fervente de Simone de Beauvoir, Simone Weil etc., Terry le cinéphile averti et tous les autres…  Autre aspect, plutôt ludique, l'auteur prévient d'entrée de jeu que les chapitres impairs se déroulent pour l'essentiel dans les années 83-84 et que les chapitres pairs quant à eux se déroulent pendant la deuxième quinzaine de juin 1996. Loin de provoquer une sensation désagréable de coupure répétée, cette oscillation entre passé et présent se fait de manière très fluide. La frontière à la fois nette (indications numériques) et ténue (liaison syntaxique) entre chaque chapitre est même rythmée par un électro-encéphalogramme. Enfin, le roman, tout comme le sommeil, est scindé en "état de veille", "stade I", "stade II", "stade III", "stade IV", "sommeil paradoxal" etc.  Mais au-delà du jeu, c'est bien la densité des analyses psychologiques, les réflexions subtiles sur le langage (ce traître, cet agent double) et son rapport à l'inconscient et enfin un humour sporadique bien dosé qui font de ce roman autre chose qu'un poche de plus à lire à la plage cet été… </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gianoulinetti</user>
	<review>Ingegneria narrativa senz'anima. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mearso</user>
	<review>Enjoyed the multiple narratives of the characters, switching back and forth through time. Can see that this book sets the pattern for his later books.More darkly humourous than the later books </review>
	<rating>1.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss3.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>soffitta1</user>
	<review>A book about various sleep disorders. Started well, very gripping in the way odd chapters are from one time period and even from another. Information comes out slowly, heightening tension. I liked the characters, but as I got nearer the end of the book it hit the bizarre. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dinabeb</user>
	<review>Un bon conteur, qui jongle adroitement avec le passé et le présent (mais le découpage en chapitres pairs et impairs est un peu trop symétrique, à mon goût). Des idées intéressantes, mais malheureusement  pas de nouveauté dans la structure. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>antonellasbri</user>
	<review>Un libro fantastico. per me è diventato un classico, come Pirandello o pavese. Ogni tanto lo rileggo, come faccio con le poesie di Montale, anche se quelle le enfo sempre sul comodino </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cla83</user>
	<review>Engaging book, with a final surprise. the centre of th story is Sarah, a narcoleptic girl not aware of her illness, she had dreams so vivid (hypnagogig allucinantion) that she believe they are true! And sometimes she fall asleep without a real reason... That causes her a lot of trouble, and causes a lot of trouble to her friends too. And you've no idea of what kind of trouble... </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ziobrando</user>
	<review>Il mio primo romanzo di Jonathan Coe, decisamente una gradita sorpresa. Personaggi strampalati ma credibili, in grado di commuovere e sorprendere. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gerleliz</user>
	<review>I really enjoyed this book.  The alternate chapters were a little hard to get into but in the end I could not put it down.  I love the love story that is veiled through an interesting story about sleep and life's lessons. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>judyb65</user>
	<review>This took a while to warm up – I initially found the flitting back and forth alternately between two years fragmenting.  However, as the story progresses you appreciate how cleverly woven it is.  This wouldn’t rank as my favourite Jonathan Coe novel (The Rotter’s Club is hard to beat), but as usual good characters, empathy, and humour are combined to create a readable and entertaining novel. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Abi78</user>
	<review>This is a really interesting book involving sleeping disorders, freaky sexual fantasies and gender confusion! There is also a wonderfully funny bit with footnotes for one of the characters' articles going out of synch. I liked the main characters and loved the way their lives were drawn with humour and sensitivity. It kept me guessing. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pynchon82</user>
	<review>There are four major characters in this novel, all of whom knew each other in college. There's Sarah, who suffers from narcolepsy and often cannot discern the events she sees in her dreams from reality. There's Robert, who might be the one affected most by Sarah's disorder (but I can't tell you why without spoiling an awesome twist). There's Terry, film critic and insomniac who claims to not have slept in almost ten years. And Gregory, a world-renowned sleep therapist who believes that sleep is a life-shortening disease that should be eradicated.Jonathan Coe is a writer who remains focused on the details. Several things in this narrative seem unimportant until the end (a scar, an idle conversation). The novel itself is an amalgamation of genre; it's a bit chilling (one of Gregory's experiments is just downright horrifying), more than a little funny (the bit about the misnumbered footnotes makes reading the whole book worthwhile), and effectively layered. However, there's a couple of things that I don't think are explained very well and I find a plot so centered on mere coincidence to be a little problematic. Ultimately, though I enjoyed this novel. It was thought-provoking and handles many different themes effectively. Of these themes, the difference between love and obsession is one of the better drawn out. Highly recommended. I'll be continuing the search for more Jonathan Coe. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jennyo</user>
	<review>This is my third Jonathan Coe novel, and he's quickly moving up my list of favorite novelists. His books are just flat-out fun to read. They're well written with clean prose, interesting characters (though sometimes they end up being caricatures), and plot, plot, plot. He's quite good at spinning things off in many directions and tying them up neatly at the end.The House of Sleep alternates its chapters; according to the author's note, the odd-numbered chapters are set mainly in 1983-1984 and the even-numbered ones in the last two weeks of June 1996. It's very easy to follow, and the slow reveal of the way the past affects current events keeps you totally engrossed in the story.Coe can really be funny too. There's a bit near the end of the book where he shows just how important good copy-editing is that had me roaring with laughter. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>880781563X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>alarra_c</user>
	<review>I fell in love with this book. It's so rich - all these characters somehow related by a period of time, and the book traces all those meetings in the past, and also their lives from then, in alernate chapters, until it all collides; twisty and compelling and just absolutely great. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>