<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<result>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>mykl-s</user>
	<review>Dante's Inferno (The Divine Comedy, Volume 1, Hell) by Dante Alighieri (2005) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>raven_moon</user>
	<review>(Review is of the Penguin Classics translation by Mark Musa, and applies to all three volumes, Inferno, Purgatorio, and Paradisio) I would not think to quibble with reviewing Dante himself - Dante is a master, and doesn't need my endorsement. I will say, however, that Musa's translation is an exceptionally sensitive one, and his comprehensive notes are an invaluable aid to the reader less familiar with Dante's broad spheres of reference. Musa is clearly a devoted scholar of Dante, and his concern for Dante's original meaning and tone is evident. This is one of the best translations of The Comedia available. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Anagarika</user>
	<review>Inferno is my favorite installment of the trilogy, but all three are wonderful. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LASMIT</user>
	<review>I am sorry, I just couldn't read it!  I restarted the book 4 times and each time I had no idea of what I had read.  A good friend of mine told me that it would be easier to read if one had studied the bible since there is so much reference made to the biblical stories. </review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>yurioujo</user>
	<review>Excellent piece of literature, descriptive writing at its best. The author has a wild imagination. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>rodrichards</user>
	<review>I'd never read this, though references to it abound in countless books, movies, etc.  I found the translation (having not even the slightest knowledge of Italian) very readable/accessible/beautiful in parts.  Recommendation: if you want to find out the source of most of what we think about hell, go to hell...with Dante. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>t1bnotown</user>
	<review>Admittedly, I got rather annoyed with Dante while reading this.  He was so self righteous, especially towards the end.  At one point he gets mad at someone who tells him not to step on his face.  I definitely got the impression that there were a lot of political messages and that Dante was using this as a tool to complain about people.  It gets points for having an interesting concept, but I disagreed with a lot of his punishments.  The worst one, in my opinion, was the people who were stuck being itchy all the time.  That would be awful.  For the most part though, the torments were physical and could have been worse.  I was also slightly disturbed that liars were worse than murders- um, I've gotta disagree with that one. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>iayork</user>
	<review>Sayers Meets Dante: Interpreting the Poet's Voice...: This review relates to the volume 1 of Dante Alighieri's-The Divine Comedy-, Hell; Translated by Dorothy L. Sayers,Penguin Classics, 1949. 346 pp.Other reviewers have spoken to the perceived weaknessesand problems with this particular translation andvolume, with Ms. Sayers' "Introduction" and "Notes."Perhaps one should be warned before entering its portals,as constructed by Ms. Sayers, that this is not an "easy"Hell to assimilate.Yet, at the beginning of her "Introduction," she presentsthe offering in an inviting fashion: "The ideal way ofreading -The Divine Comedy- would be to start at the firstline and go straight through to the end, surrendering tothe vigour of the story-telling and the swift movementof the verse, and not bothering about any historicalallusions or theological explanatios which do not occurin the text itself. That is how Dante himself tackleshis subject."Some readers may not find Ms. Sayers' translation to beone that lends itself to "swift movement of the verse."The value here, however, is the wealth of informationprovided in both the "Introduction", the Notes, andin the map drawings which clearly help the mind's eyeunderstand the "lay-out" of Hell as depicted by Dante.The value of Ms. Sayer's "Introduction" is its clearpresentation of HER view of Dante, his work, his value,his meaning, and his emphases.She concentrates on the Images of Hell and on the Christiandoctrine implicit in the work. This translation is inkeeping with that emphasis, for it is structured, somewhat restricted, and presents "Dante's" voiceas more attuned to the didactic and lecturing. Even thevoices of the denizens of Hell have the tones of stern lesson-learning rather than evoking pity fortheir failed virtue and blind human proclivities.The problem with some readers, and some viewers ofChristianity, is trying to reconcile the idea ofstern, unrelenting, eternal Judgment and damnationfor sins with the idea of God's eternal Love, or asMs. Sayers translates the second tercet of Dante's*terza rima* on the lintel of the entrance to Hell:Justice Moved My Great Maker; God EternalWrought Me: The Power, And The UnsearchablyHigh Wisdom, And The Primal Love Supernal.Ms. Sayers will have no human shilly-shallying withDante's intent or the purpose of Hell. And that,though it may appall some readers, is to the good;for it forces the reader to confront whether or nothe or she accepts or does not the Christian doctrinalviews -- and helps the reader to understand theserious nature of choosing one's faith and one'sreligion, or not.After each Canto, Ms. Sayers uses the same veryhelpful devices for explaining the preceding Canto:first, she discusses the main Images to be found inthat particular Canto in a very clear, full, doctrinalway -- and then, she has the numbered notes whichexplain allusions and phrases which Dante uses inthe work.For instance, after Canto I, we find: "The Images.-The Dark Wood- is the image of Sin or Error -- not somuch of any specific act of sin or intellectual perversionas of that spiritual condition called "hardness of heart",in which sinfulness has so taken possession of the soul asto render it incapable of turning to God, or even knowingwhich way to turn." Similarly, after Canto III, we findthis note concerning the phrase "the good of intellect":"In the -Convivio- Dante quotes Aristotle as saying: 'truth is the good of the intellect'. What the lost soulshave lost is not the intellect itself, which still functionsmechanically, but the -good- of the intellect: i.e., the knowledge of God, who is Truth."This is an excellent edition for the scope of Ms. Sayers'medieval scholarship and doctrinal insights. Though itmay be hard sledding for the tender-hearted. Therehave always been several ways of seeing the road toHell -- in this version, once one strays from thestraight and narrow, there is only the crooked andpit-full, not pitiful. -- Robert Kilgore.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Qorvus</user>
	<review>I enjoyed the imagery presented here, a lot of which seems instantly familiar.  Nothing seemed too horrible to me though, I guess that’s a sign of the times, but entertaining nonetheless.  The who’s who of Italian society was lost on me however. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Banoo</user>
	<review>'Here any doubts must be dropped,any cowardice has to die now.We've arrived where I told you,where you'd see spirits in agony,losers of the intelligence's good.'My second excursion into hell this year (my first was by way of Yasutaka Tsutsui). I never realized there were so many Italians and Greeks in that place. This book is kind of a Who's Who of Hell. If I ever find myself lost in a forest (which happens frequently) and Virgil appears and offers to guide me out, I think I'll pass. Virgil takes the long way out, the long and inconvenient way. Virgil is a crazy man... and he's dead. One should never follow Virgil. I hope you understand my repetition and insistence on this matter. Avoid Virgil if you get lost.Canto 21 was probably one of my favorites. I like the idea of being on a bridge over bubbling hot tar filled with screaming souls that surface like dolphins while having monsters chase me. Yet another reason to avoid Virgil. You shouldn't need to take this path to get out of a forest. It's just not right. Screw what Beatrice has to say about all this. Better still... stay out of forests. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>CatyM</user>
	<review>I first tried reading this about ten years ago when I was studying medieval history, and didn't get very far.  In fact, I can tell you that I got to the end of Canto 5, because that's where the margin notes in my copy finish.  Reading it now, I can't imagine why I didn't get further.  This was a translation by Dorothy L. Sayers (first published 1949), and I found it very accessible and easy to read.  In her introduction, Sayers explains that she has stuck to the terza rima in which the original was written, sacrificing (she says) a little verbal accuracy in favour of retaining the speed and rhythm.   She also explains at some length her approach to the rhyme-scheme and metre, her use of a wide range of English vocabulary including some colloquial phrases, and the ways in which she has tried to preserve the humour and tone of the original.  I think that Sayers achieved great success in this: the vocabulary is gloriously rich, ranging from phrases which are positively Shakespearean all the way to the contemporary vernacular, and just about everything in between.  The poetry is evocative and flows well, and the various tones and changes of mood are superbly conveyed.The book has extensive notes on the significant people encountered by the character of Dante in his journey through hell, and on the symbolism and imagery used by Dante the writer, which are not only engaging and well-written but also exceedingly useful. The introduction sets out the historical context in some detail, which is also very helpful: I could have given a detailed history of the Guelfs and Ghibellines ten years ago, but this time I was more than a little reliant on this introductory information to refresh my memory.   The diagrams and maps of Dante's hell are also beneficial, as is the glossary of all the characters encountered.  Together, the poetry and notes make this a very accessible translation for those who are unused to poetry, unfamiliar with the historical figures, or both.  I found the story (if I can call it that) to be more easily understood than I had expected it to be, and also more entertaining than I had anticipated.  I did, however, find that the various circles of hell began to merge together in my mind as in some cases there was either little detail given about them or they were very similar to other circles.  I expected most of the symbolism in the book to pass me by - most symbolism generally does - but between Dante's own explanations and that in the notes I was able to appreciate far more than I expected to, and to overlook much less than I feared.  The commentary on the political situation at the time, as well as that on the Church, is very definitely partisan - but is nonetheless insightful.   I have the remainder of the Divine Comedy in the Sayers translation awaiting me on the shelf, and am now very definitely looking forward to reading it. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>StefanY</user>
	<review>As a literature minor, I know that I'm supposed to take great joy in dissecting and analyzing a great work of literature such as The Inferno, but I didn't really enjoy this book all that much. I found way too much of the storyline to be repetitive and drawn out for two long. The first half or so of the story is basically traveling from one circle of Hell to another, finding out what the sin and the punishment for the sin in that area is, meeting and talking with one or two of the sinners and relating what they did in their lives to the reason that they are here. Dante reacts to their trials either sympathetically or feeling that they deserve what they got mainly based on who they are (if they happen to be somebody from his actual life who treated him badly or had a hand in his expulsion from his home, he feels pretty justified in thinking that they are getting what they deserve.)I don't want to take away from the greatness of this piece of literature. The rhyming scheme and the contrapasso (matching up the punishments so that they fit the crime) that Dante has developed are pure genius and the poem itself is a great accomplishment. My rating is based entirely upon my personal enjoyment (or lack there of) of the work. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stunik</user>
	<review>Hell </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ds1</user>
	<review>I'm glad I did not bring the sequels.  One could get the impression that most of the people in hell are Italians. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dman999327</user>
	<review>I really liked the symbolism, although a lot of the names, places, and dates I had to refernce before and after each Canto (sometimes during). Its a great historical read and I would definitely recommend the John Ciardi translation for its poetry structure (ABA) or the Mark Musa translation of a more direct translation. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cyderry</user>
	<review>I read this book/Poem because I had always heard about it but had never read it.  So I challenged myself to read this book.   I chose the Pinsky translation for my read.  The story was very thought provoking, and disturbing as to whether any of it could  true.  As a born and raised Catholic, I chose the time of the read for the Lenten season since this is not the type of literature that I normally appreciate and I'm not sure that I do appreciate it.  I do, however, acknowledge the talent of the writer and his imagination but I was disappointed by the amount of politics involved in the story. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bluedream</user>
	<review>Ah yes, the Ciardi translation.  I feel like this is what most people are thinking of when they think of Dante.  Poetic, at the cost of accuracy. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gaialover2</user>
	<review>Not as grotesque as I thought it would be, but still brilliantly imagined. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Karlstar</user>
	<review>Despite its deserved reputation as being a bit hard to follow, if you stick with it, this is really worth reading. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>fils</user>
	<review>Even though this classic can be heavy going (not only is the text very old, it's also translated) you get a sense of satisfaction from finishing it, and the imagery stays with you long after the end. It is clever, powerful and extremely interesting- and the descriptions, symbolism and imagery are almost dream-like in their originality and composition. Highly recommended, particularly an edition with corresponding pictures (they greatly help).</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Smiley</user>
	<review>Excellent prose translation.  The essays at the end of each canto are worth the price of the book, </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>M.Campanella</user>
	<review>Poor Translation.  Notes in the rear make for an uncomfortable read. </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BenjaminHahn</user>
	<review>This is an amazing achievement. I spent so much time and energy researching this book during undergrad. So many hidden meanings, so many codes and metaphors. This translation is superior to anything else I've seen and is well bound. Its nice to have Italian right next to the English. The notes are excellent, not the penguin edition is bad, its you can tell that the Hollanders have done their homework with a passion. I can't wait to read again, but first I think some more thorough reading on the popes first. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>antimuzak</user>
	<review>An excellent translation of Dante, it reads easily and vividly conveys the depth of this poetry.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Listener42</user>
	<review>1.5</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TadAD</user>
	<review>The first time I read this was in high school.  At the time, it was a 2frac12; star book...nothing special, the teacher didn't do as much with it as she might have done, I got through it and moved on.The second time I read this was in college in a course I was auditing (therefore, no grade pressure) from a professor who not only was a well-known authority but...more important...lived, breathed, ate and slept Dante.  It made a world of difference.  The book becomes much more alive if you understand the political situation of the day, the personal relationships in Dante's life, the references to other things going on in the world at that time.I recommend reading this to anyone with any interest.  However, if you can't do it under the tutelage of someone who knows this stuff, I would recommend a well-annotated edition. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>selfcallednowhere</user>
	<review>This was my favourite thing I've read for school this semester. Vivid and fascinating. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>takieya</user>
	<review>I had a collected copy of The Divine Comedy which I gave up for these three volumes. Inferno was excellent. I felt that it lived up to the translation that I read, and surpassed it in some ways. With the addition of contemporary pop-culture references throughout, we have a Hell in a very faithful to the original work. I definitely recommend these books to anyone who’s interested in The Divine Comedy. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Othemts</user>
	<review>I took this as a challenge to read a classic that is so often referred to in other literature.  Inspired by Matthew Pearl’s Dante Club, I read the Longfellow translation in a new edition edited by Pearl himself.  I think I failed the challenge.  The poetry was beautiful and the story interesting, but most of the time I only had a vague idea of what’s going on. I certainly didn’t get most of the literary references that Dante makes much less get a better grip on understanding those Dante inspired.  Anyhow I’m saving the links below to help me further study and even reread the Inferno at some point.http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Divi...http://danteworlds.laits.utexas.edu/u...http://danteworlds.laits.utexas.edu/u... </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Djupstrom</user>
	<review>My favorite of all classics.  This is a story of loss and retribution, temptation and horror.  The imagery is amazing and the voice is strong and full of passion. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>siriaeve</user>
	<review>I can't compare this translation of the Commedia to many others, since the only other I've read more than isolated extracts from was a slightly bowdlerized late Victorian edition. Still, it seems to be a clean and simple translation, which, although it doesn't attempt to recreate the rhyming scheme of the original Italian, does reproduce a lot of the original rhythm and flow. The notes are mostly helpful, even though the insistent use of Roman forms of mythological deities, even when the Greek form is better known did get a little confusing at times. (For example, I did blink at 'Latona, the mother of Diana' for a second, before saying 'Hey, wait, Leto.' That's probably to be laid at the door of the fact that I am much more a Hellenist than I am a Latinist.) There were also a couple of points in the notes in which Musa was factually incorrect - mixing up the names of rulers or popes, for example, or placing the events of one reign in the reign of a successor, but that happened only seldom.The Commedia is one of those great, sprawling epics that I love to revel in - especially because it's one of those works that seems to be at one and the same time a portrait of the writer, and a snapshot of the civilisation he lived in at the time in which he was writing. It helps satisfy the history and the poetry geeks that dwell within me. I think it's one of the first great psychological poems, too; just so, so fascinating.The Inferno has always been my favourite canticle of the three. The Wacky Medieval Theology takes up a lot less space than it does in Paradiso, or even Purgatorio, once Beatrice takes over from Virgil. But it's mostly because it takes place in Hell that I prefer it; Hell is automatically more fun, what with the torture and the torment and the farting demons (I kid you not) </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>amandaking</user>
	<review>A classic. I wasn't particularly impressed by the prose so much as Dante's characters. I think if I read it in the original Italian I might be more than a tad impressed by the prose. But then, I don't have that copy.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ForrestFamily</user>
	<review>While there are some small gems in this book, and its influence has been so widespread over the centuries that you need to read it for that alone, this book was not particularly wonderful, or life changing, or impressive. Read as an allegory about Dante's life and times it is interesting. Read as an insight into the mindset of the age, it is revealing. But read purely for readings sake, it leaves this reader cold. </review>
	<rating>3.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss7.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>TZYuhas</user>
	<review>More a commentary on 14th century Italy than anything else, "The Divine Comedy" details three spheres of the afterlife, and the first volume of Dante's "Divine Comedy" is the decent into the Inferno.  In understanding the works of Dante one must understand the man himself.  A devout Catholic, he wrote the work as a commentary on the political, economic and social happenings of his city.  He strongly believed that his own city was on its own decent into darkness.  The Inferno gave Dante a chance to punish his enemies, etc, for eternity in one of the most graphic depictions of Hell.  Composed of 34 Cantos, the Inferno takes us through the nine rings of Hell.  Dante, along with his idol and guide Virgil, make the decent into Hell ring by ring.  From the lustful, the wrathful, the violent, to the betrayers, the reader is given a detailed look at the idea of "punishment fitting the crime".  Indeed the genius of Dante is not just in the poetry or the detail in the description, but his construction of the entire idea itself; his anti-trinity found in the devil and among others the parabola nature of his travel through hell.  It is an important work in understanding the history of Hell's development, but to learn about Dante's world, his views, and his biases.  This particular edition allows the reader to view not only the English translation but the original  Italian.  Robert Durling also provides extensive notes on each Canto which can illuminate the reader on the deeper meaning and hidden contexts in the work.  All in all it is one of the classics of literature and will continue to be a captivating work about man's greatest question.  What happens to us when we die? </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>LegalMove</user>
	<review>A nicely done translation, but at times I sensed the author tried to impose his voice over Dante's, and while he is good, he is no Dante.  I still prefer Wordsworth. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>Excalibur</user>
	<review>This book is an incredible work of literature. Dante includes current events, history, philosophy, numerology, science, and theology in his masterwork. However, it is difficult for me to rate such a disturbing, unforgiving, and at times, arrogant work of literature. I appreciate this work for its brilliance but, except for small moments (the story of Paolo and Francesca or the tragic tale of Count Ugolino) I do not enjoy it. It is also clear to me that Dante did not want the reader to enjoy this work but to see it as a potential aid to one's salvation. All of this combines for a view of this work that is, to put it lightly, complicated. Consequently, I don't feel that I can provide an arbitrary rating for this book. Suffice it to say that my appreciation for this book would be a five but my enjoyment is more like a two.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ellevee</user>
	<review>The best description of Hell ever. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kingfamily</user>
	<review>A tale for all time. Epic but personal, frightening but hopeful, chaotic but structured; these and many more paradoxes await you inside.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>antiquary</user>
	<review>Apparently a reprint from 1850s</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>stpnwlf</user>
	<review>Possible inspiration for Hieronymous Bosch's work, but a ponderous and difficult read. </review>
	<rating>2.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss5.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>iamagirldork</user>
	<review>I have tried to read this several times.  I just can't seem to finish it.  One of these days!</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>octchild</user>
	<review>The Inferno is a classic among classics. Dante's vision, along with Milton's "Paradise Lost", form the very basis for society's concept of HELL. A must read for any literary buff. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>wfzimmerman</user>
	<review>This is the Dorothy Sayers translation, which comes with her fantastic notes explaining all the allegories.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>KatieWallace</user>
	<review>I would never read another translation than the Hollanders'.  I have been reading each canto simultaneously in the original Italian and the English which in this edition are conveniently printed on facing pages.  If you don't read Italian, you should trust me that this is a wonderfully faithful translation rendered into gorgeous English verse</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dgussak</user>
	<review>delux binding.Large 4to-12.8 x 9.8 inches.32 full colour plates reproducing pen and watercolour illustrations by Blake.Printed at the Bath Press on Book design smooth paper.Bound in quarter dark brown morocco leather with tan blue silk on boards.Spine lettered in gilt.Housed in a slipcase which reproduces on of the colour plates on the front</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>gazzy</user>
	<review>This particular translation is interesting because it attempts to retain Dante's original three line rhyming scheme. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>humdog</user>
	<review>gotta love dante...he made a synthetic world in what 1200 or so?  there are maps of the inferno, even, but not in this edition. the inferno is the midlife crisis to end all midlife crises, although no red sportscars were involved. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>woods</user>
	<review>Illustrations by Gustave Dore. Altemus' Edition.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>bespen</user>
	<review>http://www.brothersjudd.com/index.cfm...</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>anodos99</user>
	<review>An excellent (rhyming) translation of Dante's epic by Dorothy L. Sayers. Very easy to read. The commentaries between cantos (by Sayers and heavily influenced by Charles Williams) are of great value for understanding both the social setting of the work and the deep philosophical and mythological imagery. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>ArmyAngel1986</user>
	<review>Dante's journey through Hell ranks in my top 5 favorite books. I especially like this translation, as it keeps the language modern enough to be readable, but is still beautiful. Also, there are plenty of foot and end notes to explain middle age-phrases and historical references many people may not be familiar with. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>valeriek</user>
	<review>I did not like Pinsky's translation, even though I realize he is very well regarded in the literary community.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>theidiot</user>
	<review>i had trouble with this one. i did not know who many of people Dante wrote about seeing on his journey, and if it were not for the notes in the back i would not have understood much at all. if you really want to experience this book as it was meant be, be prepared to do some research. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BMVCOE</user>
	<review>Ever since the eleventh grade class I worked with at Camphill Special School studied this I felt like I should read it. I'd gotten a fair way through it but kept picking up other more immediately interesting things (see the rest of this list!). But now I've finally finished it. And may I say that I hadn't quite realized how much of this was Dante's commentary on the political situation? Which I suppose was much more relevant to when the book was written. I suppose I should find a copy of The Purgatory next. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>cleverusername2</user>
	<review>Dante's Divine Comedy is a strange puzzle to sort out. I feel it was written for highly personal reasons. One that is evident is his love of Virgil and the Homeric Greek epics. He also crafted this poem as a cathartic release, as a means to slander his enemies. And man, if the measure of a man is his enemies (choose them carefully) then Dante is quite the fellow. Don’t read Divine Comedy as poetry, get the whole picture as it is more fascinating than fiction.That's what makes this edition so handy, you're tempted to read it as epic poem but this edition offers all the contextual clues you need from reliable experts.I need to read this one again, damn... </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>kaledrina</user>
	<review>Very modern translation, making the book an easy read for those intimidated by Dante. </review>
	<rating>3</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss6.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>BruceAir</user>
	<review>This recent translation of Dante's Inferno is a refreshing update of texts I labored through in college. I don't find it as poetic as  John Ciardi's version, but it's a wonderful companion to Matthew Pearl's The Dante Club: A Novel.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pickwick817</user>
	<review>I didn't enjoy this book very much.  There were a lot of references to people in politics at the time it was written (1200).  Its interesting to see Dante's viewpoint on Catholicism during that time and throughout the book Virgil and Thomas Aquinas are referred to.  I don't know too much about Catholicism then or now, so it was a little off topic for me.  I was amazed at the technical aspect of the book.  Dante refers to both mathematics in general and geometry at a fairly high level.  My edition also had plenty of notes confiriming that most of Dante's calculations for sun, star and planet positions were correct.  Seems a little technical for a religious story of a man's trip through hell, purgatory and heaven! </review>
	<rating>2</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss4.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MeredithYvonne</user>
	<review>This particular version of the Inferno is a particularly great read.  The Italian is translated on the opposing page and at the end of each section there's a explanation of what you've just read.  I didn't use the notes to explain anything, but rather they referred me to ideas that I missed on the first read through.  I've read this book 3 times and each time I find something new. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>notmyrealname</user>
	<review>Just bloody wonderful. Simple as that. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>MareMagnum</user>
	<review>Scritto nei primi quindici anni del Trecento, quando Dante non aveva ancora attenuato la rabbia per l'esilio che lo costringeva lontano da Firenze, l'Inferno è la prima tappa di quel grande viaggio metaforico che è la Commedia. Da un punto di vista narrativo gli eventi di questa prima cantica si svolgono in un arco di tempo di un giorno e mezzo: dall'alba del venerdì santo del 1300 al tramonto del sabato santo. Sono le trentasei ore più intense della letteratura italiana, forse della letteratura mondiale. Dante e la sua guida Virgilio incontrano una quantità di personaggi tratti dalla mitologia classica e cristiana, dalla storia o dalla recente cronaca fiorentina. Quasi tutti sono entrati nell'immaginario letterario e sono diventati il simbolo di un sentimento: come Francesca da Rimini e la passione amorosa, Farinata e l'impegno politico, Cavalcante e l'amore paterno, Ulisse e l'ansia conoscitiva.Ma il piano simbolico nella Commedia non riguarda solo i personaggi, per quanto indimenticabili. Riguarda soprattutto la struttura dell'Inferno. La geografia e le architetture infernali ideate da Dante, dietro l'aspetto di paesaggio realistico, sono una fenomenale macchina produttrice di senso, sia morale, sia politico, sia teologico.Narrazione, personaggi, struttura. C'è un quarto elemento che fa dell'Inferno il capolavoro che è: la lingua. Dante è davvero il padre della lingua italiana perché la sua sistemazione/creazione del volgare toscano ha fatto fare un salto, grammaticale ed espressivo, ai volgari precedenti che non ha riscontri nella storia della nostra lingua, né prima di lui né dopo.Se la lingua di Dante è passata per ogni tipo di sperimentazione, l'Inferno è il luogo dove tutte queste sperimentazioni convivono. Registro solenne, familiare, popolare si mescolano nell'Inferno in un intreccio di voci, in una totalità variegata che rimane forse, a distanza di tanti anni, la rappresentazione del mondo più efficace che sia mai stata data. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tessone</user>
	<review>Birk and Sanders' unorthodox Inferno is extraordinary. It makes this classic much more immediate, even going so far as to add a few (just a few) contemporary figures to the mix. It does not, however, strive for a limp "accessibility"—they go out on limbs, trying to capture the spirit of Dante in all his cutting-edge glory. And Birk's illustrations add a great deal to the text.This is not the definitive Dante, and the authors have no illusions about that. But the Comedy must be read through as a direct, gripping story first, before being looked at as an historical artifact, and this is the right adaptation for that purpose. Sometimes one needs to return to Dante on that basis, as I did in this reading, and I am grateful for the opportunity to do it in this way. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lindykerry</user>
	<review>Not my favorite translation </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>noramunro</user>
	<review>Splendid yes, important, yes, a useful bi-lingual format (in the Sinclair translation), absolutely.  Now, please go read Purgatorio and Paradiso.  Reading Inferno alone gives you a distorted picture of Dante's world, much as though you visited Florence and only toured the sewer system.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>jkeenley</user>
	<review>Alighieri, Dante </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AlexTheHunn</user>
	<review>The Divine Comedy epitomized medieval attitudes.  From historical perspectives, this work serves as a window into the mentality of late middle ages in Italy, on the brink of the Renaissance.  Scholastic thinking informs Dante's approach. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>AlexTheHunn</user>
	<review>The Divine Comedy epitomized medieval attitudes.  From historical perspectives, this work serves as a window into the mentality of late middle ages in Italy, on the brink of the Renaissance.  Scholastic thinking informs Dante's approach. </review>
	<rating>4</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss8.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>dgrayson</user>
	<review>It took me forever to get through this book.  However it contains great imagery, and the notes were indispensable. </review>
	<rating>4.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss9.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>pcharmed86</user>
	<review>One needs to read this just so that can fully realize the abundance of references there are to this book in modern media - really, it's ridiculous how many nods Dante gets but it is understandable. I refer to frequently, usually in the form of "you're going to the sixth circle of Hell for that!" Great way of feeling smart. Oh, and it's a good read too. </review>
	<rating>5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss10.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>lilithcat</user>
	<review>An interesting concept  -- each Canto has been translated by a different poet.  Thus, a variety of verse forms and meters are used, some poets trying Dante'sterza rima.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
	<isbn>882215312X</isbn>
	<tag/>
	<occurrences/>
	<user>tole_lege</user>
	<review>I know others don't agree, but I prefer this translation - and the notes.  Ciardi manages to render his translation in terza rima and does it well.</review>
	<rating>0.5</rating>
	<minrating>0.5</minrating>
	<maxrating>5</maxrating>
	<imgrating>http://www.librarything.com/pics/ss1.gif</imgrating>
</result>